<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2021 Book Bingo on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2021-book-bingo/</link><description>Recent content in 2021 Book Bingo on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2021-book-bingo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Scorpio Races</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-scorpio-races/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-scorpio-races/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There are moments that you&amp;rsquo;ll remember for the rest of your life and there are moments that you think you&amp;rsquo;ll remember for the rest of your life, and it&amp;rsquo;s not often they turn out to be the same moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s island life&amp;ndash;a small town, far out on the water that lives and dies by the one big event a year. Just in this case, that one event is a race involving murderous meat eating horses that come from the sea and would like eating the racers just as much as carrying them. It&amp;rsquo;s a magical combination of worldbuilding, with the quiet island life and violence of the sea horses complementing one another nicely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ashby eyed the readouts on his control screen. “I swear, our engines have never been running this smooth.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sissix spoke without looking up from her navigation controls. “That’s what happens when you take two easily-bored techs on a long haul.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Hmm. Maybe we should do this more often.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That made Sissix’s head turn. She gave him a look that could melt the hull. “Let’s not.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a great book. It&amp;rsquo;s a slice of life story, set on small starship travelling the galaxy chock full of some of the most fascinating and delightful characters I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a scifi novel in a long time. There&amp;rsquo;s not particularly a huge over-arching plot. Instead, our intrepid band of oddballs is off on a long mission (it&amp;rsquo;s a Long Way after all) to the edge (center?) of &amp;lsquo;known&amp;rsquo; space. Really, we&amp;rsquo;re just on a trip with them, through all the ups and downs, the drama and relationships. It&amp;rsquo;s exactly the sort of story I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know I was looking for. Well worth a read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cece Rios and the Desert of Souls</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/cece-rios-and-the-desert-of-souls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/cece-rios-and-the-desert-of-souls/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Since before I could remember, Mamá had taught me the legends of the criaturas. They were creatures unlike humans, children of the Desert goddess, who the Great Namer created from dust and words. Mama taught me the difference between animal criaturas, who were made to fill the desert, and dark criaturas, who were made to attack the descendants of the Sun god—us. But her advice for dealing with both types was the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a delightful book. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick read (middle grade) with lovely worldbuilding (albeit a bit of whiplash reading it back to back with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/black-sun/">Black Sun&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s got a touch of southwest US / Mexican mythology with Coyote myths, El Sombrerón//La Chupacabra/La Llorona and others, brujas, and touch of Pokemon/creature collection with whole loads of hearts and the power of one little girl trying to save her sister and instead&amp;ndash;perhaps&amp;ndash;accidentally changing the world along the way. It&amp;rsquo;s a great read and something that I&amp;rsquo;m definitely going to put onto the list to read to my children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Sun</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/black-sun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/black-sun/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Your father thought he could forbid me to wear this,” she said calmly enough, but the boy could hear the thread of pain in her voice, the places where deprivation and sorrow had left their cracks. “But your father doesn’t understand that this is the way of my ancestors, and their ancestors before them. He cannot stop a Carrion Crow woman from dressing to honor the crow god, particularly on a day as sacred as today.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a magical book. It&amp;rsquo;s got dark and beautiful worldbuilding, some absolutely bizarre and still somehow eminently relatable characters, and quite the cliffhanger of an ending (spoilers I suppose). Well worth reading.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Changeling</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/26/the-changeling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/26/the-changeling/</guid><description>&lt;p>On one level, it&amp;rsquo;s about fatherhood. Apollo grew up without a dad and vows he&amp;rsquo;s going to do better by his own son. And right from the beginning&amp;ndash;a surprise delivery no one around was quite ready for&amp;ndash;he does everything he can. As a father, with my youngest about the age of Apollo&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; when things go sideways. But we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On another level, it&amp;rsquo;s about motherhood. Emma had all sorts of issues of her own, but she and Apollo seem absolutely delightful together. So when the first signs of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/postpartum%20depression">postpartum depression&lt;/a> start, it&amp;rsquo;s terrifying and entirely too relatable to many parents out there. New babies are hard, not going to lie, and everyone deals with that completely differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a third, it&amp;rsquo;s about fairy tales and other stories. The stories we read to our children and the stories we tell ourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on a last level, it&amp;rsquo;s about magic. There are hints right from the beginning that there&amp;rsquo;s something strange in this world. From Apollo&amp;rsquo;s dreams of his absent father, to the magic inheriant in old books and libraries, to finding a postcard from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aleister%20Crowley">Aleister Crowley&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s little in the way of obviously supernatural for most of the book&amp;hellip; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t last.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Rain and Paper Cranes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/10/black-rain-and-paper-cranes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/10/black-rain-and-paper-cranes/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a strange book. It&amp;rsquo;s one part historical novel&amp;ndash;detailing the development, usage, and aftermath of the nuclear weapons detonated over Hiroshima and Nagasaki at the end of World War II&amp;ndash;one part technical manual&amp;ndash;very roughly detailing the physics and engineering behind early nuclear weapons&amp;ndash;and one part children&amp;rsquo;s book&amp;ndash;many scenes involve Fritz, the talking (and super fast) dove. We&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Poppy War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/08/the-poppy-war/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/08/the-poppy-war/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>War doesn&amp;rsquo;t determine who&amp;rsquo;s right. War determines who remains.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;hellip; is quite a book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Daemon Voices</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He is interested in the discoveries of science (“intellectual daring and imaginative brilliance without parallel”), the freedoms of democracy (in particular “the great democracy of reading and writing”), the evils of authoritarianism (“always reductive whether it’s in power or not”) and the pitfalls of education (“any education that neglects the experience of delight will be a dry and tasteless diet with no nourishment in it”). He is profoundly interested in religion, while remaining puzzled by aspects of it. “The first thing to say about the Bishop’s arguments in his book,” he writes in “God and Dust,” “is that I agree with every word of them, except the words I don’t understand; and that the words I don’t understand are those such as spirit, spiritual and God.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Philip Pullman is an interesting author, which makes Daemon Voices an interesting sort of book. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a selected collection of essays and presentation he&amp;rsquo;s given over the years on a wide range of topics. In particular, he talks a lot about Paradise Lost (makes me want to actually read it), his religious and philosophical views (and a dive into Gnosticism) and how those interact with his writing, and a bit on writing advice and his own particular style.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating look and there&amp;rsquo;s a little for everyone, so if you like what Pullman has written, you can certainly do worse than give it a chance!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below are a few interesting quotes that I highlighted for just about every essay. It&amp;rsquo;s not really the sort of book where one should worry about spoilers, but just in case that&amp;rsquo;s not a shared option, you have been warned. (Also: &lt;em>long&lt;/em>)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Wyrmling Horde</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/the-wyrmling-horde/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/the-wyrmling-horde/</guid><description>I think that for the most part The Wyrmling Horde takes everything I mentioned in Worldbinder and does a bit more of that. There are some really fascinating worldbuilding ideas being explored here, although I miss the smaller scope of just the Endowments and possibly the wizards of the early books. The characters are cool&amp;ndash;and I do actually find the inversions of several of them fascinating&amp;ndash;but we&amp;rsquo;re also missing a few faces that I really wish we would see more of.</description></item><item><title>An Alchemy of Masques and Mirrors</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/08/an-alchemy-of-masques-and-mirrors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/08/an-alchemy-of-masques-and-mirrors/</guid><description>Well that was delightful. One of the reasons I&amp;rsquo;m really glad for the 2021 Book Bingo. I don&amp;rsquo;t know when/if I would have found this book, if not for that, and I really quite enjoyed it. It&amp;rsquo;s got great steampunky worldbuilding (with some hints of body horror I honestly feel steampunk should probably have more of), royal/courtly intrigue, wonderful characters, and some delightful writing (with a French twist to the word choices that I don&amp;rsquo;t see much of).</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 1: Original Sins</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/14/hellblazer-vol.-1-original-sins/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/14/hellblazer-vol.-1-original-sins/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really do have a thing for urban fantasy specifically dealing with demons and angels, good and evil, especially if it twists it all around. Constantine does that in spades.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I watched the 2005 film well before I knew it was based on a comic (so sue me), so Keanu Reeves is forever going to be stuck in my head as the true Constantine, but I&amp;rsquo;ve also watched just about all of the new wave of DC shows, including the 2014 version of Constantine plus his appearances on Legends of Tomorrow. Not quite the same, but I still loved the character.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Sister</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/01/red-sister/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/01/red-sister/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It is important, when killing a nun, to ensure that you bring an army of
sufficient size.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transmetropolitan, Vol. 1: Back on the Street</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/transmetropolitan-vol.-1-back-on-the-street/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/transmetropolitan-vol.-1-back-on-the-street/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oooh boy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Warning: Language.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The House in the Cerulean Sea</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/18/the-house-in-the-cerulean-sea/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/18/the-house-in-the-cerulean-sea/</guid><description>&lt;p>A gnome, a sprite, a wyvern, a green blob, a were-Pomeranian, and the Antichrist get sent to live in an orphanage on an island&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sounds like the setup for a rather strange joke, but instead the punchline is a delightful, amusing, and surprisingly touching story about actually taking the time to notice and perhaps care for someone a little bit different.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gideon the Ninth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/gideon-the-ninth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/gideon-the-ninth/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>One day eighteen years ago, Gideon&amp;rsquo;s mother had tumbled down the middle of
the shaft in a dragchute and a battered hazard suite, like some moth
drifting slowly down into the dark. The suit had been out of power for a
couple of minutes. The woman landed brain-dead. All the battery power had
been sucked away by a bio-container plugged into the suit, the kind you&amp;rsquo;d
care a transplant limb in, and inside that container was Gideon, only a day
old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was obviously mysterious as hell.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Annihilation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/01/annihilation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/01/annihilation/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You must understand how I felt then, how the surveyor must have felt: We &amp;gt; were scientists, trained to observe natural phenomena and the results of &amp;gt; human activity. We had not been trained to encounter what appeared to be the &amp;gt; uncanny. In unusual situations there can be a comfort in the presence of &amp;gt; even someone you think might be your enemy. Now we had come close to the &amp;gt; edges of something unprecedented, and less than a week into our mission we &amp;gt; had lost not just the linguist at the border but our anthropologist and our &amp;gt; psychologist.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Now that is a fascinating sort of book. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially a slice of life mixed with cosmic horror. The entire story follows an expedition into the mysterious, alien Area X. There&amp;rsquo;s not really any overarching plot, other than exploring and perhaps surviving&amp;hellip; and maybe if you&amp;rsquo;re really really lucky, coming back without going mad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Six Wakes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/19/six-wakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/19/six-wakes/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a nutshell, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="28962996" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28962996.six-wakes">Six Wakes&lt;/a> is a closed room murder mystery in SPACE! With clones! What that gives us is an absolutely wonderful variation on the tropes. Because of cloning technology, you can very well have a murder mystery where the cast wake up to the gruesome (zero gee) murder of &amp;hellip; the entire cast. And because it&amp;rsquo;s a generation ship in deep space, you very well know that one of the cast absolutely has to have been the muderer&amp;hellip; Unless it was more than one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My favorite parts of the worldbuilding all really revolve around technology of cloning and how that can change the world in fascinating ways. For example, it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon for attendees at certain parties to end murdered. They&amp;rsquo;ll wake up in the morning, restored from a backup the day before with little more than a feeling of &amp;lsquo;that must have been one hell of a party&amp;rsquo; plus some potential embarrassment and go about their lives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Project Hail Mary</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/15/project-hail-mary/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/15/project-hail-mary/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful book. If your read and enjoyed &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="18007564" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18007564.the-martian"> The Martian &lt;/a> , you&amp;rsquo;ll almost certainly love &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="54493401" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54493401.project-hail-mary"> Project Hail Mary &lt;/a> . The sense of humor mixed with scientific/engineering problem solving is the main strength in both. Great fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s got a wonderful sense of humor:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mexican Gothic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/09/mexican-gothic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/09/mexican-gothic/</guid><description>&lt;p>The reviews of &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="53152636" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/53152636.mexican-gothic"> Mexican Gothic &lt;/a> are &amp;hellip; divided to say the least. There&amp;rsquo;s more than a handfull of glowing five star reviews and a smaller but still significant number that just didn&amp;rsquo;t get what the fuss was about. Halfway through&amp;hellip; I totally get it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the main problem is the absolute tonal shift that happens about halfway through the book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tales of Nezura: Book 1: The Zevolra</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/26/tales-of-nezura-book-1-the-zevolra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/26/tales-of-nezura-book-1-the-zevolra/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The skeleton that was polishing with a brush stopped and waved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Hello! You must be Maximilian! Your uncle here is delighted to be hosting you.” The teeth on the skull curved up. “The name’s Conner, in case you were wondering.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“They can talk?” I whispered to my uncle.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Borrowers Afield</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/25/the-borrowers-afield/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/25/the-borrowers-afield/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“It&amp;rsquo;s so awful and sad,” she once admitted to Tom Goodenough, “to belong to &amp;gt; a race that no sane person believes in.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="348573" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/348573.the-borrowers">The Borrowers&lt;/a> was delightful, introducing us to a family of tiny &amp;lsquo;Borrowers&amp;rsquo; who live in the floor, &amp;lsquo;borrow&amp;rsquo; all manner of tiny things, and try their best to keep their existence a secret. Unfortunately, that all comes to an end at the end of book 1, sending them off into the great outdoors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Midnight Library</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/the-midnight-library/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/the-midnight-library/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Between life and death there is a library, and within that library, the &amp;gt; shelves go on forever. Every book provides a chance to try another life you &amp;gt; could have lived. To see how things would be if you had made other choices… &amp;gt; Would you have done anything different, if you had the chance to undo your &amp;gt; regrets?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a surprisingly wonderful story. It&amp;rsquo;s something of a mix of It&amp;rsquo;s a Wonderful Life and Borges' The Library of Babel. Nora Seed finds herself in a dark place, between life and death&amp;ndash;and that place just happens to look to her like a library. A library with a book for every life she could have lived, every choice she could have made.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wild Sign</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/13/wild-sign/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/13/wild-sign/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Mercyverse books (both Mercy Thompason and Alpha &amp;amp; Omega) are one of the few series of books I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to every few years for a complete reread, or in this case, a re-listen. Something that&amp;rsquo;s made all the better when you get to the end and there are new books to add to the old favorites!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the upside, it&amp;rsquo;s a crazy ride with a whole heap of more backstory for and reason to like Leah (some reviewers say it changed her backstory, but I think it fits), more information about witches, both white and black, and a few new crazy magical beings on the block (Bigfoot! Bigfeet? And that&amp;rsquo;s not even the crazy one&amp;hellip;). It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy world and a crazy plot and it manages to keep going all the way through.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Great and Terrible Beauty</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/11/a-great-and-terrible-beauty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/11/a-great-and-terrible-beauty/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Shall I tell you a story? A new and terrible one? A ghost story? Are you &amp;gt; ready? Shall I begin? Once upon a time there were four girls. One was &amp;gt; pretty. One was clever. One charming, and one&amp;hellip;one was mysterious. But they &amp;gt; were all damaged, you see. Something not right about the lot of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That was not at all what I expected. Granted, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect much. I&amp;rsquo;ve had this book on my to read list for years and decided to finally try it without looking at anything but the cover. Instead, we got a slow building paranormal boarding school / historic urban fantasy set in around the turn of the 20th century with a portal fantasy turned surprisingly dark.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Attack on Titan, Vol. 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/26/attack-on-titan-vol.-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/26/attack-on-titan-vol.-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Off we go! I&amp;rsquo;ve heard good things about Attack on Titan, but other than some pictures of gruesome looking skinless giants, I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what I&amp;rsquo;m in for. It should be fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it appears that the world was overrun by semi intelligent, naked, sexless humanoid (I personally think it would be all the more terrifying if they had genetalia, but for ratings and the mystery, I see why they don&amp;rsquo;t) Titans, ranging from twice as tall as a person to far far larger. What&amp;rsquo;s left of humanity (that we know of) is contained in a small(ish) city with a 50m wall. Good enough&amp;ndash;untl an EVEN BIGGER TITAN APPEARS:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>