<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sea of Trolls on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/11/sea-of-trolls/</link><description>Recent content in Sea of Trolls on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/11/sea-of-trolls/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Islands of the Blessed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/11/the-islands-of-the-blessed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/11/the-islands-of-the-blessed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Here we go again, dealing once again with bad decisions made long ago coming back to bite those who made them&amp;hellip; and anyone else that might be standing nearby.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course it&amp;rsquo;s up to Jack and Thorgil to go on ANOTHER QUEST. And once again, save the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d guess that you have some purpose to fulfill and that is why you were saved. But don&amp;rsquo;t get a swelled head over it. A cabbage has a purpose when someone needs to make soup.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We get all sorts of interesting new beasties, friends, and enemies (sometimes all three). Chief among them are the Mermen and Mermaids, but also more half-trolls and even (perhaps) a god along the way, which was a take I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before, but interesting to see here.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Gods, if they&amp;rsquo;re neglected, tend to fall asleep, but they never really go away.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The cultural classes and worldbuilding, being based on our own (messy) world and history are interesting gone truly magical are still interesting and (so far as I know anyways) well researched. A joy to read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like seeing more of what happens to our characters, even if the ending is a bit bittersweet.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I remembered what Olaf always said: You must never give up, even if you&amp;rsquo;re falling off a cliff. You never know what might happen on the way down.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s stronger than the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/08/the-land-of-the-silver-apples/">second&lt;/a>, but not quite up to the level of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/01/the-sea-of-trolls/">first&lt;/a> in the series. Overall, I enjoyed the series and hope to share it with my children, perhaps in a few years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Land of the Silver Apples</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/08/the-land-of-the-silver-apples/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/08/the-land-of-the-silver-apples/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You&amp;rsquo;d better tell me about that lie, Giles,&amp;quot; said the old man, massaging his forehead. &amp;ldquo;From all the sin you keep going on about, I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s going to be spectacular.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well&amp;hellip; when you put it that way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A year has passed. Jack learns family secrets and has to go on ANOTHER QUEST. I&amp;rsquo;m actually curious to see if the backstory we get here was planned all along or developed from clues in the first book only when a second was need. It really could go either way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time, we see elves (meh) and hobgoblins (lots of fun). Along the way, we end up with another new main character: Pega. Former slave, freed by Jack, and fond of commenting on &amp;lsquo;how it all could be worse&amp;rsquo;. She&amp;rsquo;s fine&amp;hellip; but not as interesting as Thorgil, personally. (We get both though!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s another adventure through the magical land of alt ~800 AD British Isles. Weaker than the first, but still absolutely solid enough that I enjoyed reading it. Onward to the thrilling (I hope!) conclusion in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/11/the-islands-of-the-blessed/">The Islands of the Blessed&lt;/a>!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Sea of Trolls</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/01/the-sea-of-trolls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/01/the-sea-of-trolls/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a surprisingly fun book!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The year is A.D. 793; Jack and his sister have been kidnapped by Vikings and taken to the court of Ivar the Boneless and his terrifying half-troll wife; but things get even worse when Jack finds himself on a dangerous quest to find the magical Mimir&amp;rsquo;s Well in a far-off land, with his sister&amp;rsquo;s life forfeit if he fails.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I started out reading this since it&amp;rsquo;s a great (and rare) fit for the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/31/2024-book-bingo/">2024 Book Bingo&lt;/a> &amp;lsquo;Bard&amp;rsquo; square, since both Jack and his mentor are explicitly called &amp;lsquo;Bards&amp;rsquo; (even if, interestingly music is a relatively small part of their training), but it ends up being so much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s got Vikings&amp;ndash;including digging into what makes them who they are and how they think differently from the people Jack grew up with.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Just say no to pillaging.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s got monsters&amp;ndash;the Vikings for one, along with Trolls (sometimes more human that anyone), dragons, ravens, and giant spiders.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Norns keep the tree Yggdrassil alive. Without them, nothing would exist… They show up when you&amp;rsquo;re born and decide what kind of life you&amp;rsquo;re going to have.&amp;quot;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;I guess they were in a rotten mood when I came along,&amp;rdquo; Jack said. He loaded up the water bag and supplies.&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Me too,&amp;rdquo; Thorgil said gravely.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Look around you&amp;hellip;Feel the wind, smell the air. Listen to the birds and watch the sky. Tell me what&amp;rsquo;s happening in the wide world.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s got magic. Bardic magic. Shapeshifting. Talking to animals. Calling up / banishing storms. Norse mythology. Norns. Yggdrasil.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“It&amp;rsquo;s my fault,&amp;quot; said Rune. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s untrained and likely to overdo things.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Like turning the queen bald. That was a good trick, though.&amp;rdquo; Olaf smiled.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve absolutely no idea if it&amp;rsquo;s particularly historically accurate (barring the above of course :)), but it&amp;rsquo;s a fun read and I greatly enjoyed it. Now I really want to know what happens next!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: Great fun for an audiobook, lightly accented. Just enough to get into the feel of the book all the more!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second side note: I totally caught the &lt;span class="spoiler">Jack and Jill&lt;/span>
 reference from when we first learned her birth name. But man. Them just outright using that as an in universe poem was fun.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>