<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ultimate Marvel Universe on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/ultimate-marvel-universe/</link><description>Recent content in Ultimate Marvel Universe on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/ultimate-marvel-universe/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 6: Venom</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/20/ultimate-spider-man-volume-6-venom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/20/ultimate-spider-man-volume-6-venom/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that’s another packed volume. A dash of memory on tape: Peter’s father. And… apparently childhood friend Eddie Brock?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course one thing leads to another, they find the venom formula (SCIENCE this time, not alien; at least not that we know), and we very Venom suit Spider-Man. Only for a few moments and he’s already done with that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a bit quick to go from ‘oh hey, childhood friend you forgot’ to fighting Venom in the street, but I expect we’ll see more of him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus, an aside with Fury! And references to the events of the Ultimates!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 5: Public Scrutiny</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/20/ultimate-spider-man-volume-5-public-scrutiny/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/20/ultimate-spider-man-volume-5-public-scrutiny/</guid><description>&lt;p>Poor Spider-Man. School troubles, girl troubles, and super hero identify struggles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-spider-man-v5-0468c7.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just can’t catch a break.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s nice to have a relatively low level, human story—even if we still absolutely get changes that are going to ripple through the rest of the storyline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 4: Legacy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/19/ultimate-spider-man-volume-4-legacy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/19/ultimate-spider-man-volume-4-legacy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Osborn’s back and green with envy! Or maybe just green.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But have no fear…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-spider-man-v4-9aab24.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick Fury is on the case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s good, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The conflict between the Osborns, the anguish of Parker’s lives tearing him apart. It’s a solid story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The one bit left, I’m not sure what’s going on with the Gwen story line. Don’t do it Peter. Choose MJ!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 3: Double Trouble</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/17/ultimate-spider-man-volume-3-double-trouble/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/17/ultimate-spider-man-volume-3-double-trouble/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-spider-man-v3-301e23.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lol.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He’s so young.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here we have them introductions of Gwen Stacy and Eddie Brock, Doc Oc—back from the dead, Kong being not quite so dumb as everyone thinks—but no one believes him, and… for some reason a guy in a fur cloak wants to hunt Spider-Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel like these are by far the best paced of the Ultimate Marvel Universe comics so far. Plenty of action, but also time to see Parker being a kid, working a job, and introducing new characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m looking forward to what’s next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimates, Volume 2: Homeland Security</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/16/the-ultimates-volume-2-homeland-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/16/the-ultimates-volume-2-homeland-security/</guid><description>&lt;p>The one where we process the fallout from the first volume. Hulk on a murderous rampage. Hank Pym’s domestic abuse. Hard topics and certainly worthy of discussion…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just kidding. Invasion of the shape shifting Nazi aliens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As one does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s another intense story line and maybe actually shaking up a few things. I really am curious how they’ll continue to deal with Banner and Pym. Slowly I expect. But that works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also: The fact that in this continuity, Thor is thought crazy is thoroughly amusing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimates, Volume 1: Super-Human</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/15/the-ultimates-volume-1-super-human/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/15/the-ultimates-volume-1-super-human/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let’s get the team together! Iron Man! Bruce Banner! Thor? Nah. The Pyms!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/the-ultimates-v1-ef3bba.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Captain America!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now… we just need someone to fight…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s a solid opener. Enough with the meet and greet to know who is who (even if it does rely somewhat on previous superhero knowledge) and then let them fight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m looking forward to seeing where else they go from here!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Side note: holy crap that last issue they threw in there—that’s really setting us up for some interesting story lines…)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 3: World Tour</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-3-world-tour/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-3-world-tour/</guid><description>&lt;p>First off, Gambit. Hard to understand with a heart of gold. Then a quick look at what’s the Professor actually did to Magneto. Here’s a hint: actually killing him might have been kinder in the long run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then finally, we’re on to the World Tour! It’s all about proving that mutants do good for the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What could possibly go wrong…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really do fall on the ‘Professor is being an overly pacifist idiot’ side of times things. It’ll be interesting to see what’s next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, these plots really could use some more time to breath. In the span of a single volume, we&amp;rsquo;re introduced to the idea of &lt;span class="spoiler">Professor X having a wife and child&lt;/span>
to said &lt;span class="spoiler">child trying to kill everything&lt;/span>
to &lt;span class="spoiler">their eventual defeat (for now? it's unclear)&lt;/span>
. Such is comics life?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 2: Return to Weapon X</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-2-return-to-weapon-x/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-2-return-to-weapon-x/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rogue. Juggernaut. Sabertooth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-x-men-v2-f2525e.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s another crazy action packed volume. I’m amazed at how much they’re fitting into these. Almost as amazed at how any of them are supposed to fit into those outfits…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, Weapon X, S.H.I.E.L.D., what’s left of the Brotherhood, and a few new friends all together. Learning just what lines they’ll each be willing to cross…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Iron Man, Vol. 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/13/ultimate-iron-man-vol.-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/13/ultimate-iron-man-vol.-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. Iron Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The whole idea that they don’t know that Iron Man is a man in a suit rather than a robot and that for some reason Tony wants to keep it that way—and thinks that he can is a bit crazy to me&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not to mention that the healing factor (and thus Tony’s disregard for getting hurt) still feels wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A really weird/rough way to take Iron Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a bit of a bummer, since I enjoyed Card’s earlier writing (Ender’s game primarily) even if his later stuff got weird and preachy. But I still had hope…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ready to move on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Iron Man, Vol. 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-iron-man-vol.-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-iron-man-vol.-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>That is not at all what I expected. Tony Stark, born with super powers. Constant pain and a regeneration factor. It’s… quite different. Too different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think there’s a reason this was later removed from the Ultimate Marvel canon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 1: The Tomorrow People</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-x-men-vol.-1-the-tomorrow-people/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-x-men-vol.-1-the-tomorrow-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting the team together, sleeper agent Wolverine, love triangles, betrayal, mass murder, and the bluening of Beast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is an awful lot to fit into a single volume…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The philosophical differences between Professor X and his X-Men versus Magneto and his Brotherhood is quite often at the core of these stories, so it’s no surprise to see it here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only question is… what comes next?!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Elektra: Devil's Due</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/ultimate-elektra-devils-due/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/ultimate-elektra-devils-due/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-elektra-70326f.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing bad ever came of a ‘who can you trust?’&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The contrast between Matt Murdock and Elektra is really what sells these stories. Doing what’s right versus what needs to be done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope to see more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if Kingpin is involved…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Daredevil &amp; Elektra</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/ultimate-daredevil-elektra/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/ultimate-daredevil-elektra/</guid><description>&lt;p>Only &lt;strike>one volume&lt;/strike> two volumes. Interesting. Let’s go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-daredevil-and-elektra-c573e5.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elektra making new friends at college.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-daredevil-and-elektra-f7b716.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And a younger than I’m used to Matt Murdock, already fighting crime and just starting in on the law stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course things escalate quickly and of course something has to drive them apart. One of the rules of comics it seems. No one can be happy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope we see more of them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 2: Learning Curve</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/10/ultimate-spider-man-volume-2-learning-curve/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/10/ultimate-spider-man-volume-2-learning-curve/</guid><description>&lt;p>Spider-Man starts to settle in to his new life. School, a job, a bit of light vigilantism, perhaps a date with MJ…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and of course decides to set his sights on the big man himself: Mr. Fisk. Kingpin. He’s a personal favorite big (heh) bad of mine. So I’m looking forward to where this goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also I’m enjoying the teenage dynamic. So far as I’m concerned they nailed it. It’s insane, what he’s trying to do… but it feels so right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 1: Power and Responsibility</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/09/ultimate-spider-man-volume-1-power-and-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/09/ultimate-spider-man-volume-1-power-and-responsibility/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peter Parker gets beat up at school; Parker goes in a field trip to Osborn’s lab; spider goes chomp; etc. It’s the standard Spider-Man origin, especially if you (like me) started with the Sam Raimu Spider-Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you have to start somewhere right? It’s a solid story, I like the art, and we’re setting up for something big.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>