<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2015/</link><description>Recent content in 2015 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 23:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2015/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/25/downton-abbey-season-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/25/downton-abbey-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Downton Abbey Season 6 is a strange beast. On one hand, we have what feels all the cast pairing off, sometimes with long known relationships and in the cast of the Family with guys we only met in the previous season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I &lt;em>still&lt;/em> do not really understand the relationship between Mary and Henry. I think it&amp;rsquo;s mostly Mary. She certainly ebbs and flows&amp;hellip; but wow she&amp;rsquo;s a (sorry, but Edith says it too) bitch at times. On the other hand, Edith and Bertie? Delightful. If expected for the chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, the world is moving on. Is Downton Abbey going to survive? With reductions in expected staff and families around the world failing, it&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But with all those relationships &lt;em>wow&lt;/em> do the last few episodes blitz through what feels like every plotline possible in only a few hours. I do wonder if they thought they&amp;rsquo;d have a 7th season. But so it goes. For the most part, everything is tied off neatly. And for everything else&amp;hellip; apparently there are two movies?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a final note, if you&amp;rsquo;ve been lamenting the torture the writers have put the Bates&amp;rsquo; through over the year&amp;hellip; well, they&amp;rsquo;re not quite done. But there is light at the end of the tunnel, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad for that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I quite enjoyed it. Much more than I expected to, as I seem to say with all non-SF/F shows I end up watching. Still not something I would have chosen, still quite enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/13/downton-abbey-season-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/13/downton-abbey-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh goodness. Another season down and only one more to go (plus some movies?). I&amp;rsquo;m not ready!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This one has a few primarily focuses:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary and her men&amp;hellip; weird. I kind of liked both of them, but so it goes. Hints at what&amp;rsquo;s to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Isobel and Violet (of all people) getting romantically entangled. That I did not expect, much less with who. It&amp;rsquo;s fun, if sad at times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rose, speedrunning the relationship thing, all with yet another new family for people to disapprove of. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that her dating a black man went so poorly, yet this ends up much better?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course the Bates. Oh the Bates. I truly wish that Season 6 could be quiet and happy for them&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m not holding up too much hope for that one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, yet another solid season. Like I said, I&amp;rsquo;m not ready for the end! But all good things must. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VII - The Force Awakens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/04/star-wars-episode-vii-the-force-awakens/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/04/star-wars-episode-vii-the-force-awakens/</guid><description>&lt;p>Woo, new Star Wars! I remember the hype when The Force Awakens first came out. It was pretty crazy to see new Star Wars for the first time (second time?) in years. And it&amp;rsquo;s pretty dang cool. It&amp;rsquo;s shinier than the original trilogy, a bit less stuck in the weeds (trade blockades!) than the prequels, and it leans &lt;em>hard&lt;/em> on nostalgia. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s Star Wars! Could they have done something newer and more unique? Sure they could have.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ant-Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/02/ant-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/02/ant-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Continuing in the set of Marvel movies that came out after I stopped going to theaters quite so much / reviewing movies in 2014, we have Ant-Man!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a heist movie/comedy with superheroes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful movie, with a lighter, funnier theme than a lot of the movies. The cast is wonderful. Paul Rudd is hilarious and well cast as Ant-Man, Michael Douglas is a wonderful cranky old man scientist that&amp;rsquo;s been burned as Hank Pym, Corey Stoll is a wonderful crazy (spoilers) bad guy, and Evangeline Lilly is criminally underused. Eventually that will/should get better. But the real standout has to be Michael Peña as Luis. He&amp;rsquo;s hilarious. The &amp;lsquo;he said/she said&amp;rsquo; stories told with all manner of different actors but his voice are a joy to watch. He&amp;rsquo;s just that funny.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Age of Ultron</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Hawkeye: The city is flying and we&amp;rsquo;re fighting an army of robots. And I have a bow and arrow. Nothing makes sense.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Age of Ultron is an odd movie. From the perspective of a summer blockbuster/action movie, it&amp;rsquo;s solid. The opening action scene is wonderfully avengerful, there are all manner of awesome fights (the Hulk versus Iron Man fight and the final battle come to mind), and we get a few new characters.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>