<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2015/</link><description>Recent content in 2015 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2015/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VII - The Force Awakens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/04/star-wars-episode-vii-the-force-awakens/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/04/star-wars-episode-vii-the-force-awakens/</guid><description>Woo, new Star Wars! I remember the hype when The Force Awakens first came out. It was pretty crazy to see new Star Wars for the first time (second time?) in years. And it&amp;rsquo;s pretty dang cool. It&amp;rsquo;s shinier than the original trilogy, a bit less stuck in the weeds (trade blockades!) than the prequels, and it leans hard on nostalgia. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s Star Wars! Could they have done something newer and more unique?</description></item><item><title>Ant-Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/02/ant-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/02/ant-man/</guid><description>Continuing in the set of Marvel movies that came out after I stopped going to theaters quite so much / reviewing movies in 2014, we have Ant-Man!
In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a heist movie/comedy with superheroes!
It&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful movie, with a lighter, funnier theme than a lot of the movies. The cast is wonderful. Paul Rudd is hilarious and well cast as Ant-Man, Michael Douglas is a wonderful cranky old man scientist that&amp;rsquo;s been burned as Hank Pym, Corey Stoll is a wonderful crazy (spoilers) bad guy, and Evangeline Lilly is criminally underused.</description></item><item><title>Avengers: Age of Ultron</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</guid><description>Hawkeye: The city is flying and we&amp;rsquo;re fighting an army of robots. And I have a bow and arrow. Nothing makes sense.
Age of Ultron is an odd movie. From the perspective of a summer blockbuster/action movie, it&amp;rsquo;s solid. The opening action scene is wonderfully avengerful, there are all manner of awesome fights (the Hulk versus Iron Man fight and the final battle come to mind), and we get a few new characters.</description></item></channel></rss>