<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>White Sand on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/white-sand/</link><description>Recent content in White Sand on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/white-sand/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>White Sand, Volume 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/white-sand-volume-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/white-sand-volume-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onward and conclusionward! All the political machinations to save the Sand Masters (and himself) are coming to a head. It&amp;rsquo;s a fine enough central plot, even if the random assassinations / friend that doesn&amp;rsquo;t get along well with his father / scientist from the other side of the world / bodyguard that hates you and you have to win over subplots really do get to be a bit random and disorientating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s really a problem with the whole set of graphic novels though and&amp;ndash;if I remember correctly&amp;ndash;I had the same problem with the prose version years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s not a deal breaker, but I feel like the whole thing could be cleaned up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>White Sand, Volume 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/18/white-sand-volume-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/18/white-sand-volume-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the things that I feared most about getting into these stories is the big &amp;lsquo;art style change&amp;rsquo;. I see it. It&amp;rsquo;s definately different. But having read all manner of graphic novels over the last year&amp;ndash;some change &lt;em>far&lt;/em> more dramatically than this. They&amp;rsquo;re similar enough that I barely even noticed for the most part.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it still is quite beautful:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>White Sand, Volume 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/16/white-sand-volume-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/16/white-sand-volume-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>White Sand has something of an odd story. It&amp;rsquo;s the first novel Sanderson finished (and also the 7th, a complete rewrite), but in prose form was never published. You can get it if you ask him (I think signing up for the newsletter? It&amp;rsquo;s been a few years) and I read it back in 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now though, the same story has been actually published as a three volume set of graphic novels. Having gotten rather more into graphic novels over the last year, of course I had to give it a try, so here we go!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>