<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Boxcar Children on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-boxcar-children/</link><description>Recent content in The Boxcar Children on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-boxcar-children/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Benny Uncovers a Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/09/05/benny-uncovers-a-mystery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/09/05/benny-uncovers-a-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so it ends&amp;ndash;at least the original 19 books written by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/gertrude-chandler-warner/"&gt;Gertrude Chandler Warner&lt;/a&gt;, which is where I&amp;rsquo;ll be stopping for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s a rather strange story. Benny gets it in his head that he absolutely needs a summer job&amp;ndash;so he ropes Henry into going with him&amp;hellip; and the both of them end up working at the same place? With a mystery in the works to boot? Sure. It works.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mystery Behind the Wall</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/07/12/mystery-behind-the-wall/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 14:18:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/07/12/mystery-behind-the-wall/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s a cute little book. Benny’s friends all wondered off for the summer so Mrs. McGregor invites Canadian son of a friend Rory over for the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing leads to another and a telegraph between the boys’ rooms leads to the mystery of a missing coin collection. Along the way, they learn more about the mystery of the house, find a fun old local store, and of course eventually solve the mystery.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mystery in the Sand</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/19/mystery-in-the-sand/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/19/mystery-in-the-sand/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is the funniest thing,&amp;rdquo; said Benny. &amp;ldquo;Here we are at Aunt Jane and Uncle Andy&amp;rsquo;s new trailer at the beach. A day or so ago we were at home without the least idea of going anywhere at all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Aldens go to the beach, find a strange old mansion inhabited by an old anti-social woman, inject themselves into her life, and find buried treasure. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a pretty fun book and a pretty neat mystery, although not terribly deep and the insistence that everyone needs to come out of their shells is becoming increasingly obvious.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bicycle Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/06/bicycle-mystery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/06/bicycle-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Only a few weeks left in the summer, so the Boxcar Children are going on (another) adventure closer to home! This time, they&amp;rsquo;re going to ride their bikes to Aunt Jane&amp;rsquo;s and of course find a several mysteries (and a dog!) along the way. It&amp;rsquo;s really quite strange how close together everything is. They keep going by previous locations, such as Second Landing and Aunt Jane&amp;rsquo;s. New England I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a cute story and, given their current ages, seems entirely appropriate. Although just how old is Benny supposed to be to plan to ride up to 50 miles a day several days in a row? I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s something that would really make sense where we live in the midwest, but everything in New England is a bit more compact.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tree House Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/02/tree-house-mystery/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/02/tree-house-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, new neighbors move in, they&amp;rsquo;re mostly ignored by their parents (back to that in a moment), the Aldens barge in and make friends, they all build a treehouse, find a hidden room, and fix a old (kind of dumb) feud between the neighbor&amp;rsquo;s father and uncle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Snowbound Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/15/snowbound-mystery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/15/snowbound-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The children are off at a cabin in the woods and suddenly SQUIRRELS! IN THE CEILING! Oh, and they also get snowed in by a freak storm that dumps four feet of snow on them. But from the way they go on, the squirrels are totally the problem&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, the first 80% or so of the book is pretty good. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see the kids mostly out on their own and the setting is fun. The mystery is&amp;hellip; pretty terrible. The secret ingredient in family buns? Really? (And we, the read, never find out!)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Houseboat Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/08/houseboat-mystery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/08/houseboat-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A mystery on a houseboat? Sure! That actually sounds like a really fun vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grandfather&amp;rsquo;s still just throwing his money around (what does he even do for work anyways?) and the kids are impressively meddlesome. But you know what? It works.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Woodshed Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/08/the-woodshed-mystery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/08/the-woodshed-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s straight forward, with a nice bit of history for the mystery (which is a nice change) and the return of Aunt Jane (actually being married and happy, yay!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much to say. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the better ones. I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Caboose Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/01/caboose-mystery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/01/caboose-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;That was cute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a train ride across the country is on my list of things to try one day and in a caboose would be even more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Schoolhouse Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/24/schoolhouse-mystery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/24/schoolhouse-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;All right. Another instance of getting sidetracked from Grandfather&amp;rsquo;s plan by something random, stumbling into a mystery&amp;ndash;that may or may not be one&amp;ndash;, another old woman that just wants to be left alone&amp;ndash;but not from these children&amp;ndash;and more of showing off just how rich they are without realizing it. Oh these books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, they go to a very poor little island, end up buying supplies and teaching the local kids (since the Aldens know everything, much more than those poor islands), and mess up a man that everyone loved because he was buying local coins and old things for crazy rates.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mountain Top Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/15/mountain-top-mystery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/15/mountain-top-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of strange that after half a dozen books of being on their own, we now have several in a row that always have Grandfather and other adults watching over them, even as they get older and (hopefully) wiser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, the (easy mode) mountain climbing is pretty neat, getting stranded is actually pretty good from a survival perspective, and finding and exploring caves is something I&amp;rsquo;ve always found cool&amp;ndash;even if the Aldens don&amp;rsquo;t actually do much of that part.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Lighthouse Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/08/the-lighthouse-mystery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/08/the-lighthouse-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renting a lighthouse is unusual, but even more so is an unfriendly boy&amp;rsquo;s peculiar behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what&amp;rsquo;s even more unusual? Traveling home from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/08/the-woodshed-mystery/"&gt;The Woodshed Mystery&lt;/a&gt;, seeing a lighthouse for sale on the side of the road and &lt;em&gt;deciding that your grandfather should &lt;strong&gt;buy it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. And knowing that he totally could&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blue Bay Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/14/blue-bay-mystery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/14/blue-bay-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Vacation this summer? Let&amp;rsquo;s get purposely stranded on a tropical island!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s actually a lot more of the feel of the first book to this one, since they&amp;rsquo;re on the island for a few weeks without any way of getting more supplies other than what they can build and find themselves. They do have two adults along though: Grandfather and newcomer Lars Larson&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;ndash;who previously got shipwrecked here &amp;hellip; and apparently wants to go back for vacation now? Sure. And Mike again, who&amp;rsquo;s fun enough. Do any of the other children have friends to spoil with vacations from a rich grandfather?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mike's Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/07/mikes-mystery/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/07/mikes-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; the children own a town now? That&amp;rsquo;s cool. And Mike&amp;rsquo;s family (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/24/surprise-island/"&gt;Surprise Island&lt;/a&gt;) lives there. Such mystery!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, actually the mystery comes up when Mike&amp;rsquo;s house burns down. Which &amp;hellip; actually ends up working out because instead of doing laundry (which she doesn&amp;rsquo;t care for) now Mike&amp;rsquo;s mother can make pies for a living. 60 pies a day! Sure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mystery Ranch</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/03/mystery-ranch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/03/mystery-ranch/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE RELATIVES!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, apparently Grandfather has an estranged sister, living nearly on her own out in a giant ranch house somewhere or the other. She keeps running off the help, so of course Jessie and Violet (being the girls) go to help her &amp;ndash;and miraculously have no trouble doing so. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of hard to believe, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have another change of scenery. And hey, I always love reading aloud books in my &amp;lsquo;creaky old woman voice&amp;rsquo;. :D&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Yellow House Mystery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/28/the-yellow-house-mystery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/28/the-yellow-house-mystery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Remember &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/24/surprise-island/"&gt;Surprise Island&lt;/a&gt; ? Remember&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Henry said, “Grandfather, that’s one thing we can’t understand. Why didn’t we ever get to go into that little yellow house? Doesn’t it belong to you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Alden looked at his grandchildren. Then he said quietly, “That’s another story.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Surprise Island</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/24/surprise-island/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/24/surprise-island/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The second Boxcar Children book and the first of the formula that would come to define the series. It&amp;rsquo;s summer and the children are off to an adventure to an island Grandfather &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;owns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; , more or less by themselves (although two other adults live on the island). They make a house, explore, find mysteries, and generally have an idyllic time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now, tell us, Grandfather,” cried Henry. “We ran all the way home from school.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Boxcar Children</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/15/the-boxcar-children/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/15/the-boxcar-children/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, my mother would read aloud the Boxcar Children books to my brother and I. We read many many books together for many years, but the Boxcar Children are perhaps the ones I remember most. Now, perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s time to start passing that along to my own children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a child&amp;rsquo;s perspective, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful little book. The children are on a grand adventure, escapism idealized. They work together to not only survive but thrive without any adults telling them what to do. They get to make their own house in the woods and have a dog and everything ends up all right in the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>