<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blackthorn &amp; Grim on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/blackthorn--grim/</link><description>Recent content in Blackthorn &amp; Grim on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/blackthorn--grim/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dreamer's Pool</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/13/dreamers-pool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/13/dreamers-pool/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A solid book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are three conditions you must agree to meet before I grant you this opportunity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Firstly, the considerable skill you possess must be used only for good. You will not let bitterness or anger draw you down the darker ways of your craft.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Secondly, if anyone asks for your help, you will give it willingly. I do not mean solely those who come to you for assistance with their ailments, but anyone at all who seeks your aid.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And thirdly?” It occurred to me that I could be as good a liar as anyone. What was to stop me from agreeing now, and once I was out of here, doing whatever I pleased? I might yet live beyond dawn and see Mathuin brought down before nightfall. My heart began to race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thirdly, you will not seek vengeance. You will remain in Dalriada and stay away from Mathuin of Laois.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a bit of magic/folklore in an oldentimes Ireland; add in a Fae bargain (with all the complications that ensues); combine with a prince and princess who&amp;rsquo;ve never met outside of letters&amp;ndash;and seem entirely different in person; and finish it all off with fairy tale magic of Dreamer&amp;rsquo;s Pool.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>