<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2026 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2026-tv-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2026 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2026-tv-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lost: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/11/lost-season-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/11/lost-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What lies in the shadow of the statue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 5 is where it really started to get obvious that the writers of the first few seasons did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have a plan for where all of this was going to go. It manages to hold together relatively well&amp;ndash;and we do get a few answers, mixed in with all those questions&amp;ndash;but man, there are a few moments which just don&amp;rsquo;t line up with what we already thought we knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s what you get any time a show introduces &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;time travel&lt;/span&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faraday: I studied relativistic physics my entire life. One thing emerged over and over&amp;ndash;can&amp;rsquo;t change the past. Can&amp;rsquo;t do it. Whatever happened, happened. All right? But then I finally realized&amp;hellip; I had been spending so much time focused on the constants, I forgot about the variables. Do you know what the variables in these equations are, Jack?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack: No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faraday: Us. We&amp;rsquo;re the variables. People. We think. We reason. We make choices. We have free will. We can change our destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have, at first, a combination of &amp;lsquo;what is going on here&amp;rsquo; on the Island, along with a &amp;lsquo;we have to go back!&amp;rsquo; off it. And man, despite the fact that there are only the &amp;lsquo;Oceanic Six&amp;rsquo;, there are some &lt;em&gt;pretty&lt;/em&gt; complicated shifting alliances going on here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank Lapidus: In my experience, the people who go out of their way to tell you that they&amp;rsquo;re good guys are the bad guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, in the latter half, once the Island stabilizes a bit? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s where all the real trouble starts. Because the might just have made it back &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; they were trying to go. But not quite &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;*when*&lt;/span&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack: If we can do what Faraday said&amp;hellip; our plane never crashes&amp;hellip; Flight 815 lands in Los Angeles. And everyone we lost since we got here&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;d all be alive.
Kate: And what about us? We just&amp;hellip; go on living our life because we&amp;rsquo;ve never met?
Jack: All the misery that we&amp;rsquo;ve been through&amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;d just wipe it clean. Never happened.
Kate: It was not all misery.
Jack: Enough of it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s quite the set up for season 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more to go!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>