<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trenton Lee Stewart on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/trenton-lee-stewart/</link><description>Recent content in Trenton Lee Stewart on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/trenton-lee-stewart/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Mysterious Benedict Society and the Perilous Journey</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/10/the-mysterious-benedict-society-and-the-perilous-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/10/the-mysterious-benedict-society-and-the-perilous-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man those are long books. 😄 Enjoyable though.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>May your adventures bring you closer together, even as they take you far away from home.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Kate is delightful, I like seeing her growing relationship with Milligan. Constance seems to becoming slightly psychic, albeit in a way that they brush off as being very aware of the world and good at pattern matching. Sticky is more self aware while still being a wonderful brain about it all. And Reynie is growing into a solid natural leader. He already had it coming, but it&amp;rsquo;s still good to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s less contained than the first book. Rather than mostly taking place in one place, it&amp;rsquo;s more of a kidnap/mysterious plot that ends up traveling a chunk of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice change of pace, even if it feels a little contrived to get the kids on their own again.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mysterious Benedict Society</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/02/the-mysterious-benedict-society/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/02/the-mysterious-benedict-society/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that took a while to read. I read it outloud, part of a chapter a night many nights, and it still took a few months. Glad I did it though, it&amp;rsquo;s a great book, especially for kids, but even more so to read aloud with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a story about a group of children, each lost and/or alone in different ways, each brilliant (as the first section and a series of tests shows both to them and to us) and thus necessary for a &lt;em>SECRET MISSION&lt;/em>. I won&amp;rsquo;t go much more into that, but once they get out on the mission and have to prove that they are more than up to the task&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>