<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Taskmaster (All) on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/taskmaster-all/</link><description>Recent content in Taskmaster (All) on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/taskmaster-all/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taskmaster Australia: Series 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/taskmaster-australia-series-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/taskmaster-australia-series-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have no idea how I ended up watching season 2 of Taskmaster Australia before Season 1, but go with it! It&amp;rsquo;s not like there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much of an overarching plot between seasons that you have to keep up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And man, this is a fun bit. Another series, another Taskmaster! And another assistant!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom (Gleeson). And lesser Tom (Cashman) are a lot of fun together. I love that lesser Tom can never keep a straight face when teh contestants screw up. It&amp;rsquo;s delightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And oh the cast was a lot of fun. Anne and Lloyd as a couple on the show together made for some great moments. Wil and Tom being old friends is a dynamic we&amp;rsquo;ve seen before in the British version but it&amp;rsquo;s always fun. Josh was quite a wildcard at times. And Jenny was one of the reasons I came to this version of the show&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen her acts on YouTube before and she&amp;rsquo;s a wonderfully weird mix and has a lot of those &amp;lsquo;young enough to make the other contestants feel old&amp;rsquo; moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, another great season of Taskmaster. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to catch more of the Australian version! LIke season 1 &amp;#x1f604;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 18</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/20/taskmaster-series-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/20/taskmaster-series-18/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I &amp;hellip; managed to miss [[todo:Taskmaster: Series 17]] somehow. Anyways!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another delightful season. This was a fun cast. Baba was full of chaos, Rosie got away with so much crap (sometimes literally) and her team tasks with Jack were such chaos. Andy has serious mad professor vibes (mostly the hair I suppose). Emma&amp;hellip; Emma was my favorite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosie having cerebral palsy certainly started out with a different flavor to the season. But man she has a sense of humor about the whole thing. I think it took Greg and the other contestants a minute to feel out how far to go (&amp;ldquo;Is it too early in the series to mention I DON&amp;rsquo;T have cerebral palsy?&amp;rdquo; - Emma)&amp;hellip; but once they did, that was a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can tell by the way I talk, I suffer from being Northern. &amp;ndash; Rosie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, what do you want? I love this show. Another great season. Time to go back to 17!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster NZ: Series 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/11/taskmaster-nz-series-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/11/taskmaster-nz-series-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve caught up with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/taskmaster/"&gt;Taskmaster&lt;/a&gt; (for now/barring specials)&amp;hellip; well there&amp;rsquo;s the whole world of INTERNATIONAL TASKMASTER.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, New Zealand! And because&amp;hellip; well, I have no justification. I&amp;rsquo;m starting with season 3 because that&amp;rsquo;s the one that is coming out on YouTube around now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird watching a new Taskmaster and assistant after so many seasons, but so far I really like Jeremy Wells and Paul Williams. They don&amp;rsquo;t try to copy Greg Davis and Alex Horne (entirely), but rather build their own thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contestantwise, they&amp;rsquo;re all fun this series (I think I always say that). I think my favorite this series was either Chris Parker or Josh Thompson. Either such chaotic energy or generally playing it straight &amp;hellip; until doing something absolutely bonkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 16</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/06/07/taskmaster-series-16/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/06/07/taskmaster-series-16/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Another season, we&amp;rsquo;re on a roll!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great cast, and I absolutely enjoyed them all, although I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a favorite stand out quite so much as did in the previous seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor Lucy through so many of those tasks, but she took it in stride. The Sues were great, especially together. Julian&amp;ndash;so gay. And Sam Campbell was just a lot of fun&amp;ndash;and that hair the last episode. O.o&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward to one more (for now)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then of course&amp;hellip; all of the other regional Taskmasters as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 15</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/29/taskmaster-series-15/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/29/taskmaster-series-15/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re almost caught up to the present day! And what a crew to catch up on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mae Martin I think was my favorite, followed closely by Ivo Graham. Ironic given the final scores. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did love Jenny Eclair&amp;rsquo;s energy throughou the tasks though. And both Frankie and Kiell were a delight to watch as well. Really, I loved the entire cast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favorite task of the season? Wayne. The flail&amp;rsquo;y man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go watch it and find out why. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 14</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/10/taskmaster-series-14/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/10/taskmaster-series-14/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s such a delight of a season, mostly due to Fern Brady, although I enjoyed the entire cast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contestants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dara Ó Briain - Goes about the weirdest things with a smile on his face.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fern Brady - Fern is delightful. She&amp;rsquo;s a fun one to look up her independent work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Kearns - He constantly had the look of &amp;lsquo;what have I gotten myself into&amp;rsquo;. Really the whipping boy for this season.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Munya Chawawa - Zimbabwean ___. Hda a fun way of working around the tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarah Millican - Alternatively delightfully dry and actually angry at times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 13</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/16/taskmaster-series-13/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/16/taskmaster-series-13/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many quotes. So many ducks. So many chances to make Alex do &lt;em&gt;weird&lt;/em&gt; things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was another great series. I love this show. At some point I&amp;rsquo;m going to run out&amp;hellip; and have to watch the New Zealand and now Australian versions! (I can&amp;rsquo;t wait).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The contestants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ardal O&amp;rsquo;Hanlon - The older one / the Irish one. Always seemed up for doing the wackiest thing and I loved his sense of humor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridget Christie - The chaotic one. She seemed to actually be driving Alex up the wall as the series went on, which is saying something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris Ramsey - The relatable one. Gives you something to grown you among all the other oddballs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Judi Love - The one who loses at just about every task. And she&amp;rsquo;s just so delightful about it&amp;ndash;and about making Alex do much of the tasks for her.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sophie Duker - The younger one and my favorite of the series. She&amp;rsquo;s just got a delightfully weird way of looking at the tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 11</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/22/taskmaster-series-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/22/taskmaster-series-11/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Catching up / almost back to watching these in order! I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;d watched this season before, but not reviewed it, so here you go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charlotte Ritchie - She feels so out of her depth, always trying to keep things light and innocent. Bit of a running joke how she&amp;rsquo;d best fit a children&amp;rsquo;s show. She almost came close to not being &lt;em&gt;completely destroyed&lt;/em&gt; in the final scoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jamali Maddix - The rule breaker of the episode. I love how he approaches tasks. And it usually works, which isn&amp;rsquo;t always the case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lee Mack - Quite often misses things, but gets along the best with Greg Davis I think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Wozniak - The absolute star of the season. He just goes all in on whatever task you give him. And that final prize task of the series&amp;hellip; all of the hats off to you good sir.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarah Kendall - So very Australian (based on knowing very few Australians in real life). Quite a delight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good crowd. Sad to see them (especially Mike Wozniak) go.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 10</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/29/taskmaster-series-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/29/taskmaster-series-10/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m so not watching these in order. But they&amp;rsquo;re back on YouTube in the US! So let&amp;rsquo;s catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fun season. We have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daisy Mae Cooper: So pregnant. And quite often unfiltered, which is a lot of fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Johnny Vegas: You just &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; everything to go right for the guy&amp;hellip; and it so often does not. My favorite this time around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Katherine Parkinson: Impressively bad about missing parts of tasks. Felt bad for her, but didn&amp;rsquo;t want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Herring: Dry humor and weirdly competent at the tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mawaan Rizwan: The one that tries to break everything. And gives Greg Davis so many &amp;lsquo;you did &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; now&amp;rsquo; moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good season.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 12</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-12/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s quite a cast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alan Davies: The old one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desiree Burch: She certainly goes all out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guz Khan: Those eyes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morgana Robinson: So very emotive… The word that comes to mind is ‘fae’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Victoria Coren Mitchell: Subtle and hilarious when you realize it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Series reviews:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An inbalance in the poppability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that started delightfully risqué, escalates to swearing at Alex, and ended up with a prize task submission… of Personally the chair he’s sitting on. And the tasks haven’t even started yet. I expect to enjoy this series.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 9</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A great season! I loved all of the people on here. I was writing up my favorite and &amp;hellip; I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it. They&amp;rsquo;re all a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;First entry in the first task: How large are Greg Davies’ shits… We’re off to quite a season. Hiding eggplants is a wonderful task. “It’s amazing how much it compacts down into a baby’s head.” “You scored the same as Rose… and she couldn’t see.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*It&amp;rsquo;s always fascinating when something that seems so obvious in hindsight takes absolutely forever to figure out. Scavenger hunts on steroids. Jo has tremendous DGAF energy and Rose makes hilarious faces. *&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jo suggesting Mein Kampf is an important read for democracy&amp;hellip; The look on Greg Davies face! I also love when they combine tasks, such as building a solid statue&amp;hellip; and then scoring a soccer goal against it&amp;hellip; with a steamroller. Wonderful. &amp;ldquo;Now I&amp;rsquo;ve destroyed the statue. I haven&amp;rsquo;t even scored. For the second time. In 40 years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*The water feature task is one of my favorites. Oh&amp;hellip; Alex. You really make this show. I&amp;rsquo;m never going to get those out of my head. Katy&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;subtle&amp;rsquo; flirting (bra begins with B) is a lot of fun. The final task (throw your thing far but not too far) was fun. *&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aw, poor Katy Wix. Kerry Godliman is wonderful though. &amp;ldquo;And this is Monkey now&amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; KEEP IT LIGHT!&amp;rdquo; Also: &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s his name? (Alex, not missing a beat): David Baddiel.&amp;rdquo; And that&amp;rsquo;s just the prize task.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*Katherine Ryan! Missed her. Live task, sliding full glasses bar style at Greg Davies was wonderful. *&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Katy Wix is back! And she stole Kerry Godliman&amp;rsquo;s Taskmaster prize :D. And then, &amp;lsquo;Make Mount Rushmore&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip; and they all talk about Trump. We are/were a joke&amp;hellip; And it ends with a rousing game of horse or laminator (that old gem) with POSSIBLY INFINITE POINTS!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Making sound effects was lovely, especially with a live screamoff in the studio!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;So many balloons!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*&amp;ldquo;To hold aloft my smelted golden likeness and scream into the void. I AM BECOME LIGHT. I AM BECOME IMMORTAL. THE WORLD SHALL NOT FORGET MY NAME.&amp;rdquo; Oh Greg Davies. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing them all dressed up in matching suits and bowties. Did any of the other seasons do that? Why are they so orange? So many questions. Last task?! :( Last seven tasks? EXCELLENT. Quite the final task&amp;hellip; The tie breaker was delightful. *&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 7</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/07/taskmaster-series-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/07/taskmaster-series-7/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rounding out the first 8 series that are available directly on YouTube in the US, finally Series 7!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man this was a season. Man those are some characters. James Acaster has a barely contained rage beneath his humor (sometimes now so barely). Jessica Knappett, hilarious with some crazy outfits. Kerry Godliman: a wonderfully direct way to solving tasks. Phil Wang (and Phil Wang&amp;rsquo;s wang). That outfit&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a thing. And Rhod Gilbert. Perhaps the best at lateral thinking with decades of a relationship of history with Greg Davies, and an obsession with a picture of Davies in a speedo. Oh they&amp;rsquo;re all great.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally back to where it all began. We have a bit of trying to find the show&amp;rsquo;s footing. I think Romesh Ranganathan was my favorite this series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favorite task:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 2: Eat as much watermelon as possible in one minute. HULK SMASH! Also, totally throwing up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably the weakest season, but it more than gets a pass for all the wonderful things that came to be later.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-6/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I really like most of the people in this season. Alice Levine seems straight laced and perhaps sweet until she throws something at you out of left field. Asim Chaudhry hit the &amp;lsquo;you&amp;rsquo;re going to lose now&amp;rsquo;, although didn&amp;rsquo;t actually end up coming in last. Tim Vine though&amp;hellip; oh Tim Vine. There always has to be one in a crazy outfit and he performs most of the tasks in some sort of safari outfit and hat. Fun times.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/23/taskmaster-series-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/23/taskmaster-series-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh Noel Fielding. You&amp;rsquo;re &amp;hellip; a class all your own. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many other people that had so very many 1 and 5 point tasks with little in between. Having Mel Giedroyc there as well (also from the Great British Bake Off) was extra amusing. Another favorite of mine though was Hugh Dennis. So very British sense of humor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favorite tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 1: Most unusual autograph on the most unusual vegetable. Any time they try to get Greg Davies to participate in tasks is the best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 2: Beautifully destory a cake. I&amp;rsquo;m surprised at how &lt;em&gt;few&lt;/em&gt; fireworks there were.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 3: Draw a caricature of a person you can&amp;rsquo;t see. Medusa eat your heart out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 4: Knock all the rubber ducks down. Planning!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 3, Task 2: Camouflage and hide yourself. Some silly, some impressive. And then Noel just &amp;hellip; being Noel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 3, Task 5: Transfer water using only supplied items. Hidden bonus points! Moving water!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh Noel. Kind of warps the show around himself. He&amp;rsquo;s hilarious though, so it works!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/taskmaster-series-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/taskmaster-series-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Back one more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Osman is just wonderful in this season. He can really give Greg Davies a run for his money. But I think even better is Katherine Ryan. She&amp;rsquo;s snarky and hilarious. I wish they had more than one woman on the earlier seasons, but if you only have one, she was a good one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favorite tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 2: Place three exercise balls on a yoga mat on top of a hill. Watching the chaos as they blow away and amusing cheating are the best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 4: Get information from a Swede without communicating in English. Call a friend!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 2, Task 2: Eat an egg the fastest. And only one ate it raw.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 4, Task 4: Build a bridge for a potato with the supplied items. I love when they hide something that would make the task easier. Much better when they don&amp;rsquo;t find it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another short season, but a good one.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/07/taskmaster-series-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/07/taskmaster-series-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Further back! Season 3!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have as much to say about the contestants this time around, except for Paul Chowdhry. Such a resting emotionless face&amp;hellip; unless he&amp;rsquo;s full of a deep rage. It makes it hilarious. And he got robbed&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s starting to seem kinda racist. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s just my own viewing order?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few favorite moments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 3: Propel a pea the furthest distance and land on a red carpet. I love tasks where the&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 4: Make the best snowman. In the summer. It&amp;rsquo;s hilarious and surprisingly existential at times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 2, Task 2: Surprise Alex. FIREWORKS are surprising!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 3, Task 2: Fill an egg cup with sweat. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s gross.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 4, Task 2: Spread your clothes as far and wide as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to bend the rules (and spend money).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 5, Task 2: Transfer water between buckets without moving either. Cheating!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pity it&amp;rsquo;s only 5 episodes, but they&amp;rsquo;re still good ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/taskmaster-series-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/taskmaster-series-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;More out of order! This time back to Series 5!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contestants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aisling Bea: Irish names are kind of crazy looking sometimes. And so is Aisling Bea. She has a wonderful sort of manic energy throughout the show.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bob Mortimer: He has some of the most bananas ways of solving tasks. Great fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mark Watson: A wonderfully dry sense of humor. You can never quite be sure if he&amp;rsquo;s serious or messing with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nish Kumar: Poor Nish. He totally got robbed. I&amp;rsquo;m noticing a theme here&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sally Phillips: You never expect half the things she does. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason she did as well as she did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few favorite moments:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 8</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/taskmaster-series-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/taskmaster-series-8/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh Taskmaster. It&amp;rsquo;s such a wonderfully ridiculous show. Whoever decided that they should upload the episodes to YouTube for everyone* to watch should absolutely be given a shiny golden metallic head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCT5C7yaO3RVuOgwP8JVAujQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;go watch it right now&lt;/a&gt;. Each series has five different mostly British comedians competing in a number of inane tasks and being judged harshly (if humorously) by Taskmaster Greg Davis while Little Alex Horne (who actually produces the show) keeps everything more or less on track.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>