<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2003 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2003/</link><description>Recent content in 2003 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2003/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Underworld</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/15/underworld/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/15/underworld/</guid><description>&lt;p>Modern Day. Vampires versus Werewolves. That&amp;rsquo;s basically Underworld in a nutshell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily, it does it very well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Matrix Revolutions</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/14/the-matrix-revolutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/14/the-matrix-revolutions/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh the Matrix Revolutions. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/the-matrix-reloaded/">The Matrix Reloaded&lt;/a>: Part 2. We cut in right as that one ended, with Neo out for the count, robots descending on Zion, and Smith doing&amp;hellip; whatever Smith is doing. I particularly appreciate the idea of humans, programs, and machines perhaps finding common ground (which &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/the-matrix-resurrections/">The Matrix Resurrections&lt;/a> really got into).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Neo: I just have never&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rama-Kandra: &amp;hellip;heard a program speak of love?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neo: It&amp;rsquo;s a&amp;hellip; human emotion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rama-Kandra: No, it is a word. What matters is the connection the word implies. I see that you are in love. Can you tell me what you would give to hold on to that connection?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neo: Anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rama-Kandra: Then perhaps the reason you&amp;rsquo;re here is not so different from the reason I&amp;rsquo;m here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Matrix Reloaded</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/the-matrix-reloaded/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/the-matrix-reloaded/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Morpheus: [Morpheus addresses the people of Zion] Zion, hear me! It is true, what many of you have heard. The machines have gathered an army and as I speak, that army is drawing nearer to our home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[the Zion crowd becomes louder]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morpheus: Believe me when I say we have a difficult time ahead of us. But if we are to be prepared for it, we must first shed our fear of it. I stand here, before you now, truthfully unafraid. Why? Because I believe something you do not? No, I stand here without fear because I remember. I remember that I am here not because of the path that lies before me but because of the path that lies behind me. I remember that for 100 years we have fought these machines. I remember that for 100 years they have sent their armies to destroy us, and after a century of war I remember that which matters most&amp;hellip; We are still here! Today, let us send a message to that army. Tonight, let us shake this cave. Tonight, let us tremble these halls of earth, steel, and stone, let us be heard from red core to black sky. Tonight, let us make them remember, THIS IS ZION AND WE ARE NOT AFRAID!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>More Matrix! I love it!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/pirates-of-the-caribbean-the-curse-of-the-black-pearl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/pirates-of-the-caribbean-the-curse-of-the-black-pearl/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it began.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is just such a fun movie. Johnny Depp is absolutely the star of the show:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Mullroy: What&amp;rsquo;s your purpose in Port Royal, Mr. Smith?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Murtogg: Yeah, and no lies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jack Sparrow: Well, then, I confess, it is my intention to commandeer one of these ships, pick up a crew in Tortuga, raid, pillage, plunder and otherwise pilfer my weasely black guts out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Murtogg: I said no lies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mullroy: I think he&amp;rsquo;s telling the truth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Murtogg: If he were telling the truth, he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have told us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jack Sparrow: Unless, of course, he knew you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t believe the truth even if he told it to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The sheer number of wonderfully quoteable lines he has:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Norrington: No additional shot nor powder, a compass that doesn&amp;rsquo;t point north,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[looks at Jack&amp;rsquo;s sword]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Norrington: And I half expected it to be made of wood. You are without doubt the worst pirate I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jack Sparrow: But you have heard of me.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s on top of crazy pirate action (with a heart of gold buried somewhere deep in there), Geoffrey Rush&amp;rsquo;s spectacular portrayal of Barbossa, Bloom&amp;rsquo;s &amp;rsquo;everyman with a mysterious history&amp;rsquo;, and Keira Knightley&amp;rsquo;s beginning to work against the sexism inherent in the age and region (although that gets better in the sequels).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Finding Nemo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/finding-nemo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/finding-nemo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finding Nemo is a delightful children&amp;rsquo;s movie. It&amp;rsquo;s the story of a worrying dad (Marlin), a son (Nemo) trying to grow into his own self, the trouble that causes, and the lengths family can go through for one another.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>