<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1986 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/1986/</link><description>Recent content in 1986 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/1986/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aliens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/19/aliens/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/19/aliens/</guid><description>&lt;p>Where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/alien/">Alien&lt;/a> was a genre defining entry into scifi/horror, Aliens takes that a step in a different direction, keeping the horrifying alien monster roots and adding in a pile of action scenes. Space marines, big guns, and flamethrowers&amp;ndash;oh my.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, taking the (more or less) single alien of Alien and upping the ante to a whole pile of them&amp;ndash;and then blowing at least some of them away&amp;ndash;lessons the mystique. They&amp;rsquo;re not unkillable perfect monsters any more. But it&amp;rsquo;s still a good way to up the ante rather than just putting us through more of the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sigourney Weaver remains a star of the episode, this time mixing her tough surviverness with a &amp;lsquo;save the child&amp;rsquo; complex that I think just works. But this time around, we have a whole pile of soldiers, playing up every stereotype you can think of.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Vasquez: Look, man. I only need to know one thing: where they are.&lt;br>
Drake: Go, Vasquez. Kick ass.&lt;br>
Vasquez: Anytime, anywhere, man!&lt;br>
Hudson: Right, right. Somebody said &amp;ldquo;alien&amp;rdquo; she thought they said &amp;ldquo;illegal alien&amp;rdquo; and signed up!&lt;br>
Vasquez: Fuck you, man!&lt;br>
Hudson: Anytime, anywhere.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And some &lt;em>very&lt;/em> memorable lines.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Private Hudson: That&amp;rsquo;s it, man. Game over, man. Game over! What the fuck are we gonna do now? What are we gonna do?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>(You can hear it, can&amp;rsquo;t you? Even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the movie?)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ripley: I say we take off and nuke the entire site from orbit. It&amp;rsquo;s the only way to be sure.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a different feel of movie, but every bit as good as &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/alien/">Alien&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that Alien³ is a step down, but honestly, it would be hard to believe they could do it a &lt;em>third&lt;/em> time in the first place. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nutcracker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/11/nutcracker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/11/nutcracker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a truly bizarre adaptation of the Nutcracker. Or I suppose all of the other versions are bizarre, given that this is supposed to be as &amp;lsquo;close as possible&amp;rsquo; to the original Maurice Sendak version.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>