<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ben Aaronovitch on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/05/ben-aaronovitch/</link><description>Recent content in Ben Aaronovitch on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/05/ben-aaronovitch/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lies Sleeping</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/05/lies-sleeping/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/05/lies-sleeping/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Faceless Man on the run&amp;ndash;and trying to ring in&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> some new form of chaos to bring London to its knees.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Along the way, we&amp;rsquo;ll bump into new characters and, even better, fill in a few more holes in the histories of others. Each step we get closer to Molly&amp;rsquo;s tale is well appreciated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man. Lesley has some trauma to work through. I love the fact that she&amp;rsquo;s not completely evil and off the deep end, but trying desperately (in her own way) to do the right thing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hanging Tree</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/28/the-hanging-tree/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/28/the-hanging-tree/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Jeremy Beaumont-Jones had been lucky enough to be born rich. He wasn’t in the mad oligarch class but once you’re past a certain point, the sheer weight of your money sucks in wealth like a financial singularity. If you’re sensible enough not to blow it on race horses, cocaine or musical theatre, then it becomes a perpetual-motion money making machine.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The power of money&amp;ndash;and those with power of their own, which tends to lead to money in it&amp;rsquo;s own ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Peter getting caught right up to it, a favor called in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a whole mess of the posh/upper class world of London and all the problems that come with this&amp;ndash;and how much they expect to be able to pay their way out of anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It took the Fire Brigade a day and a half to secure the remains of the house enough to recover Crew Cut’s body, which was described by Dr Jennifer Vaughan as ‘suffering from crush trauma’ and by Dr Walid as ‘mostly flat’.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well. Almost anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoy seeing more of Guleed, both in her role as a cop but also her getting more into the magical world&amp;ndash;at least by proxy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see more of Lesley. That&amp;rsquo;s such a mess throughout all of these books&amp;ndash;and I really don&amp;rsquo;t know where we&amp;rsquo;re going from there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And to finally face off more literally face to face with the Faceless Man? Awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The plots and sudden resolutions continue in this book. At this point, I&amp;rsquo;m mostly used to it&amp;hellip; but only mostly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Once the telephone had been invented, it was only a matter of time before the police got in on the new technology and, first in Glasgow and then in London, the police box was born. Here a police officer in need of assistance could find a telephone link to Scotland Yard, a dry space to do “paperwork” and, in certain extreme cases, a life of adventure through space and time.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s delightful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foxglove Summer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/09/foxglove-summer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/09/foxglove-summer/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We trooped off behind her into waist high bracken, down something that was not so much a path as a statistical variation in the density of the undergrowth.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Tne one where Peter goes to the country.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I wondered just when I’d become “the starling” and why everyone who was anyone in the supernatural community had such a problem with proper nouns.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And he&amp;rsquo;s so out of his element.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two children missing and it just so happens that one of Nightingale&amp;rsquo;s former colleagues is in the area. So of course Peter has to go check in on him&amp;hellip; and gets entirely too involved in what does (of course) end up being something in the Folly&amp;rsquo;s department.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“What the hell is that?” he asked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“It’s a magic spell,” I said, and Beverley snorted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Show off,” she said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I said I was going to do magic,” I said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“But . . .” Dominic floundered around for a bit before pointing at me accusingly. “You said that there’s weird shit, but it normally turns out to have a rational explanation.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“It does,” said Beverley. “The explanation is a wizard did it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“That’s my line,” I said.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I do like the &amp;lsquo;half in the open&amp;rsquo; stance that this series takes to magic. Most people don&amp;rsquo;t know or care that magic is real, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that Peter can&amp;rsquo;t occasionally show off and actually use his tools for what they are&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There’s nothing quite like Latin for disguising the fact that you’re making it up as you go along.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Such as they are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, I really do like seeing Beverly again. She totally has a point that Peter basically ignored her for a book&amp;hellip; well, not this time around. And there are going to be reprecussions of that, just you wait.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But not for the moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What we do get is a mystery wrapped up in even more slowly extending worldbuilding. Now we know a bit more about the Rivers and more than the very little we knew about the Fae. And of all the things&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Mind you,” said Dominic, “when it comes to finding new ways to get themselves killed, sheep are bloody geniuses.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Didn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/charles-stross/">Charles Stross&lt;/a> go a similar route in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/05/equoid/">Equoid&lt;/a> (spoilers)? There&amp;rsquo;s about a year between the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I enjoyed the story, it was a neat way to expand the setting. The ending was &amp;hellip; weak. It felt like things just suddenly wrapped up right when they were getting interesting, which is a bit annoying. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Broken Homes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/broken-homes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/broken-homes/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It’s a police mantra that all members of the public are guilty of something, but some members of the public are more guilty than others.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The more things change&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, we have both Peter and Leslie as apprentices at the Folly, learning how to do magic things&amp;ndash;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I’d love to stick some high vestigia material into a mass spectrometer, but first I’d have to get myself a mass spectrometer and then I’d have to learn enough physics to interpret the bloody results.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash;and use those abilities to investigate those &lt;em>stranger&lt;/em> cases in London.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The key is unlikely juxtapositions. Lots of people read books about the occult, but if you find them alongside books by or about Isaac Newton, especially the long boring ones, then hackles are raised, flags hoisted and, more importantly, notes made in my notebook.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;the more they remain the same&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then they find a body sans face.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Attend a peace summit between Rivers/Fae. (I actually really do enjoy how fuzzy and ill defined Fae apparently are in this world. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting and feels somehow more &amp;lsquo;Fae&amp;rsquo; than you often see.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Move into an estate (British for project housing).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Peter,” she said. “When you threaten people it’s usually more effective if they don’t have to spend five minutes working out what you just said first.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a strange book.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;until quite suddenly things &lt;em>aren&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em> the same anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a brutal ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave it at that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And immediately go start the next book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Whispers Under Ground</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/29/whispers-under-ground/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/29/whispers-under-ground/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ghosts! Goblins! Murder! The FBI (in London)! The LONDON UNDERGROUND!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do continue to really love the feel of these books. It &lt;em>feels&lt;/em> like a British cop show with a combination of magical elements and the science of magic, which are all delightful things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, it&amp;rsquo;s mostly the same, although this time around, we get a lot more of Lesley stepping up to learn magic again, which is something I was hoping would happen. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing how those two grow together.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;That was Seawoll,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;Stephanopoulos is on her way down and you’re not to do anything stupid until she gets here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You burn down one central London tourist attraction, I thought, and they never let you forget it.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also interesting seeing the bits of London as a city built on people from all manners, histories, and walks of life.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My mum translated this in her head to &amp;ldquo;witchfinder,&amp;rdquo; which was good because like most West Africans, she considered witchfinding a more respectable profession than policeman.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, I like seeing ever more of teh magical world of London. There really is a feel of &amp;rsquo;this &lt;em>could&lt;/em> be&amp;rsquo; that urban fantasy doesn&amp;rsquo;t always get right. And I enjoy finding out that even the magical folks don&amp;rsquo;t know how a lot of what they do works, but our main character is &lt;em>not&lt;/em> going to let that stand.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is why magic is worse even than quantum physics. Because, while both spit in the eye of common sense, I&amp;rsquo;ve never yet had a Higgs bosun turn up and try to have a conversation with me.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fun to see even more of the magical underground (literally). It&amp;rsquo;s neat to see how different authors play with old stories (and make up their own!)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“My dad was a fairy,&amp;quot; said Zach. &amp;ldquo;And by that I don&amp;rsquo;t mean he dressed well and enjoyed musical theatre.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>One oddity: There are a ton of Lord of the Rings references throughout this book, some blatent and some more subtle. I was really fully expecting that to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chekhov%e2%80%99s%20gun">Chekhov’s gun&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; but they were just references all along? That seems weird to me and I can&amp;rsquo;t quite my finger on why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I loved it and am looking forward to the next one! Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moon Over Soho</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/28/moon-over-soho/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/28/moon-over-soho/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/05/rivers-of-london/">Rivers of London&lt;/a> got the introduction out of the way, so now it&amp;rsquo;s time for Moon Over Soho to really build out the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really love seeing Grant exploring the magic of the world. He&amp;rsquo;s doing &lt;em>science&lt;/em> to &lt;strong>magic&lt;/strong>. I do enjoy books that do that. (Plus, it&amp;rsquo;s funny!)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I had jokingly developed my own scale for vestigia based on the amount of noise Toby made when he interacted with any residual magic. I called it a yap, one yap being enough vestigia to be apparent even when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t looking for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The yap would be an SI unit, of course, and thus the standard background ambience of a Central London pub was 0.2 of a yap (0.2Y) or 200 milliyaps (200mY).&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Also, more worldbuilding about what the &amp;lsquo;Rivers&amp;rsquo; are (fae? or at least fae adjacent). More talk about vampires. And of course&amp;hellip; What&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;em>deal&lt;/em> with Nightingale?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“What&amp;rsquo;s the biggest thing you&amp;rsquo;ve zapped with a fireball?&amp;rsquo; I asked.&lt;br>
&amp;lsquo;That would be a tiger,&amp;lsquo;said Nightingale.&lt;br>
&amp;lsquo;Well don&amp;rsquo;t tell Greenpeace,&amp;rsquo; I said. &amp;lsquo;They&amp;rsquo;re an endagered species.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br>
&amp;lsquo;Not that sort of tiger,&amp;rsquo; said Nightingale. &amp;lsquo;A Panzer-kampfwagen sechs Ausf E.&amp;rsquo;&lt;br>
I stared at him. &amp;lsquo;You knocked out a Tiger tank with a fireball?&amp;rsquo;&lt;br>
&amp;lsquo;Actually I knocked out two,&amp;rsquo; said Nightingale. &amp;lsquo;I have to admit that the first one took three shots, one to disable the tracks, one through the driver&amp;rsquo;s eye slot and one down the commander&amp;rsquo;s hatch - brewed up rather nicely.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Plus, we get piles more London, this time around digging into the musical/jazz scenes. I managed to go through the first book entirely expecting Grant&amp;rsquo;s parents to be out of the picture (that&amp;rsquo;s just the way urban fantasy always seems to go), so it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see them on page and actually playing interesting roles in the story!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My Dad says that being a Londoner has nothing to do with where you&amp;rsquo;re born. He says that there are people who get off a jumbo jet at Heathrow, go through immigration waving any kind of passport, hop on the tube and by the time the train&amp;rsquo;s pulled into Piccadilly Circus they&amp;rsquo;ve become a Londoner.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Weirdest change of this series: Grant falls quickly and &lt;em>deeply&lt;/em> in &lt;del>love&lt;/del> lust with someone (from a case!) and there are a number of decently explicit on screen sex scenes. I didn&amp;rsquo;t necessary see that one coming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also plotwise, I was &amp;hellip; surprised by the ending. Not in who the big bad ended up being, more more what happened after that. It felt sudden and perhaps unearned, like we&amp;rsquo;d reached the end of the book and had to warp things up. I&amp;rsquo;m curious if we&amp;rsquo;ll get any fallout of that in future books, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really expect to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did really like the scenes with Leslie though (from the first book), especially&amp;ndash;and counter to my first point&amp;ndash;her ending. That&amp;hellip; now &lt;strong>that&lt;/strong> has some interesting potential for the series.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rivers of London</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/01/rivers-of-london/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/01/rivers-of-london/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whenever I come across a &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve read all of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/10/07/the-dresden-files/">The Dresden Files&lt;/a>, now what?&amp;rdquo; discussion, one of the series that always seems to come up is Ben Aaronovitch&amp;rsquo;s Rivers of London. They&amp;rsquo;re not &lt;em>entirely&lt;/em> the same, but I get why people cross recommend them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, we have a London cop who stumbles upon a mysterious killing, questions a ghost, gets recruited by the &amp;lsquo;magical&amp;rsquo; side of the London police, ends up meeting and befriending several rivers (see, the title! Also, it ends up making more sense in the story), and saves the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Are they really gods?&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I never worry about theological questions,&amp;rdquo; said Nightingale. &amp;ldquo;They exist, they have power and they can breach the Queen&amp;rsquo;s peace - that makes them a police matter.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>More or less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think my favorite part of the series (so far) is the humor, most especially the sheer Britishness of it (not being British, I have no idea how accurate it all is, but it&amp;rsquo;s good enough for me!).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He was from Yorkshire, or somewhere like that, and like many Northerners with issues, he&amp;rsquo;d moved to London as a cheap alternative to psychotherapy.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh, and also picking fun at it&amp;rsquo;s own genre of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You put a spell on the dog,&amp;rdquo; I said as we left the house.&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Just a small one,&amp;rdquo; said Nightingale.&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;So magic is real,&amp;rdquo; I said. &amp;ldquo;Which makes you a&amp;hellip;what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;A wizard.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Like Harry Potter?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
Nightingale sighed. &amp;ldquo;No,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;Not like Harry Potter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;In what way?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not a fictional character,&amp;rdquo; said Nightingale.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Second up, the introductions of magic. Any world where the characters try to treat magic as a science and figure out &lt;em>how in the world it &lt;strong>really&lt;/strong> works&lt;/em> is a great one in my book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s an &lt;em>awful&lt;/em> lot of hinted at worldbuilding there. I hope and expect to see a lot more of that in future books. We&amp;rsquo;ll just have to see which way all that goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also also, having recently decided that learning Latin was just a great idea as our main character (although for (un)fortunately different reasons I suppose):&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Carved above the lintel were the words SCIENTIA POTESTAS EST. Science points east, I wondered? Science is portentous, yes? Science protests too much. Scientific potatoes rule. Had I stumbled on the lair of dangerous plant geneticists?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spoilers, I guess. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I had a lot of fun with this book. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing where it goes from here!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>