<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2004 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2004/</link><description>Recent content in 2004 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2004/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lost: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/07/lost-season-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/07/lost-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man this show was huge when it first came out. I watched it then and once since, so this will be my third watch. And this time around I&amp;rsquo;m watching it with someone who (somehow) has never seen it before. To experience all the twists and turns anew with someone? Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first season is awesome. We don&amp;rsquo;t get quite as much mystery and the larger story as later seasons&amp;ndash;but that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we need. Instead, the first season is all about survival&amp;ndash;they did just crash onto a island far &lt;em>far&lt;/em> away from land after all&amp;ndash;and introducing our cast. And oh, they did that in spades.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Pilot was, of course&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> awesome. And I do love the first season giving each main character a flashback episode. Locke&amp;rsquo;s (Walkabout) in particular was quite a twist. And oh Hurley&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love the characters. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing, with a main cast of over a dozen, how they managed to give each of them (well, most of them) their own over the top backstories and room to breath. I suppose part of that is a side effect of an older style TV season&amp;ndash;when you have over 20 episodes, you have room to actually &lt;em>build&lt;/em> to something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jack is great, even if he&amp;rsquo;s got entirely too much of the perfect &amp;lsquo;Doctor savior&amp;rsquo; personality at times. Kate is great, even when she can&amp;rsquo;t stop running. Sawyer is great&amp;ndash;you love to hate him, but he might just be a good man under all that. Locke is a great mystery all around. Hurley is just great. Full stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I don&amp;rsquo;t like the rest of the characters on the island. There&amp;rsquo;s isn&amp;rsquo;t a main cast member in the first season that I don&amp;rsquo;t find worth watching&amp;ndash;and some of them still have room to grow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise, I love the slow burn introduction of &amp;lsquo;what is even going &lt;em>on&lt;/em> on this Island&amp;rsquo;. Monsters in the woods, mysterious noises, hidden structures. It has it all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And just when they get a chance to leave&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>