<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fantasy on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/writing/genres/fantasy/</link><description>Recent content in Fantasy on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 14:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/writing/genres/fantasy/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spring NaNoWriMo – So close...</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/04/01/spring-nanowrimo-so-close.../</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/04/01/spring-nanowrimo-so-close.../</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;During the month of March, I wrote 46,625 towards my newest novel. As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before, I&amp;rsquo;m writing this one by hand, so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit slower going than typing, albeit with less distractions. So falling less than 10% shy of the (admittedly pretty arbitrary) NaNoWriMo target isn&amp;rsquo;t too bad. And I did hit my own goal of six hand written pages per day (I got 6.01). So none too shabby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where do we go from here?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>March Madness NaNoWriMo - Halfway there</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/03/16/march-madness-nanowrimo-halfway-there/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 15:00:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/03/16/march-madness-nanowrimo-halfway-there/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/03/06/my-personal-nanowrimo-march-madness/"&gt;Two weeks (and change) ago&lt;/a&gt; I started writing a March version of NaNoWriMo ((Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s not really national, but it is a novel writing month, so I guess just NoWriMo?)), written long hand in a notebook rather than typed. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just give a quick status update for that, since I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually been posting it daily this time around.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My personal (NaNoWriMo) March Madness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/03/06/my-personal-nanowrimo-march-madness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/03/06/my-personal-nanowrimo-march-madness/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Back when I finished my last NaNoWriMo, I said that I&amp;rsquo;d be starting a new writing project within a couple of weeks. Well, here we are. It&amp;rsquo;s more than a couple of weeks later&amp;ndash;a bit short of two months actually. Unfortunately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t really written much. There was a short story and a few other blog posts and that&amp;rsquo;s about it. But that&amp;rsquo;s not what I want to do. I want to write.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Popocatepetl Rising</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/21/popocatepetl-rising/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 14:00:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/21/popocatepetl-rising/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With both the Cloak and the Mask, the curator jumped into the final spot of the Pentagram. Immediately everyone could feel a thrum of force as the circle began to close. Dancing blue flames spread from the bodies lying at the other four points around the circle and over the cross lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fierce wind suddenly blew across the top of the building, bringing with it a rumble of thunder. Luckily, it seemed to be further away. Another lightning strike to the roof was not something anyone wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raising her masked face to the sky, the curator began chanting in a strange tongue. Based on the artifacts she was wearing, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a stretch to say it sounded distinctly Central American.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing to a high point in her chant, she yelled &amp;ldquo;Popocatepetl! Popocatepetl ko&amp;rsquo;oten! Popocatepetl!&amp;rdquo; With a brilliant flash of light&amp;ndash;albeit less brilliant than the earlier lightning strike&amp;ndash;the circle snapped shut.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>