<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jon Watts on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/directors/jon-watts/</link><description>Recent content in Jon Watts on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/directors/jon-watts/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spider-Man: No Way Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</guid><description>Finally got around to watching this. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did, it&amp;rsquo;s hilarious and an aboslute blast of nostalgia. Similar to Avengers: Endgame, I don&amp;rsquo;t know know if this would possibly hold up without the weight of all of the movies that came before it (I doubt it), but with that weight&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s really really good.
It&amp;rsquo;s funny, it&amp;rsquo;s touching, and there are some really crazy action scenes. But the greatest strength of course comes from bringing back a half dozen villains and all three modern live action Spider-Men into one film .</description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</guid><description>As much as I loved Spider-Man: Homecoming, Spider-Man: Far From Home takes what made it great and turns it up a few levels even further.
One one level, you have Spider-Man being Spider-Man. He&amp;rsquo;s a good kid, trying to make his way in life, trying to deal with the dual life of being a highschooler and being a superhero&amp;ndash;of saving the world and perhaps getting the girl.
And then you layer all the weight of the greater MCU on top of it.</description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Homecoming</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</guid><description>That is a truly delightful Spider-Man movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird seeing him introduced after the events of Captain America: Civil War) and completely skipping how he became Spider-Man in the first place&amp;hellip; but it works. I really like the entire plot, dealing with the fallout of the Avengers / super-hero activity and how normal people try to live their lives around it&amp;ndash;and what happens when the powers that be step in and take that away from them.</description></item></channel></rss>