<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2021 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2021/</link><description>Recent content in 2021 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2021/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spider-Man: No Way Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</guid><description>Finally got around to watching this. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did, it&amp;rsquo;s hilarious and an aboslute blast of nostalgia. Similar to Avengers: Endgame, I don&amp;rsquo;t know know if this would possibly hold up without the weight of all of the movies that came before it (I doubt it), but with that weight&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s really really good.
It&amp;rsquo;s funny, it&amp;rsquo;s touching, and there are some really crazy action scenes. But the greatest strength of course comes from bringing back a half dozen villains and all three modern live action Spider-Men into one film .</description></item><item><title>Encanto</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/13/encanto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/13/encanto/</guid><description>Disney has really been doing quite well the last 12 years. Tangled, Wreck-It Ralph, Frozen, Big Hero 6, Moana, and now Encanto? (I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen Raya yet) All really solid films. Encanto specifically, I really enjoyed. It&amp;rsquo;s got great songs, fun characters, beautiful animation, and a lovely story. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to see a story based on yet another culture&amp;ndash;Columbia this time&amp;ndash;Disney is really doing that well. Overall, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t quite put it to the level of Moana, but it&amp;rsquo;s just about there.</description></item><item><title>The Matrix Resurrections</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/the-matrix-resurrections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/the-matrix-resurrections/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Whoa.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a blast of nostalgia, a bunch of mind-bending meta universe building, some awesome new characters, a few solid action scenes, and overall quite an action movie. I loved it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dune (Movie)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/20/dune-movie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/20/dune-movie/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lady Jessica Atreides: I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little death that brings obliteration. I will face my fear and I will permit it to pass over me and through me. And when it has gone past&amp;hellip; I will turn the inner eye to see its path. Where the fear has gone there will be nothing. Only I will remain.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Wow. That&amp;rsquo;s a movie with &lt;em>quite&lt;/em> a sense of scale and granduer. The ships are huge, the worms are huge, the armies are huge, the Duke is honorable, the Fremen are pious, the Baron is gross, everything is spectacular. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a bummer that we&amp;rsquo;re going to have to wait a few years for Part 2, but I think it really did need the space to breath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worldbuilding and visuals are what really makes this movie. I watched it on HBOMax, rather than in theaters, but I do have a wall sized projected screen and that really does help. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a visually stunning movie. If they re-run Part 1 in theaters, I may have to check it out next time around&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Luca</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/02/luca/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/02/luca/</guid><description>Luca is something of an odd beast. It&amp;rsquo;s a cute little movie about two young sea monster boys who journey out onto land&amp;ndash;where so long as they don&amp;rsquo;t get wet, they transform to look like humans. Wacky hijinks ensue, there&amp;rsquo;s a meetcute with a young girl, a big race scenes, some quickly resolved drama, and everyone lives happily ever after.
It&amp;rsquo;s not the most thrilling movie, which isn&amp;rsquo;t really something that you expect to see from Pixar&amp;ndash;if it had come from any other studio it would have been pretty impressive.</description></item><item><title>Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</guid><description>Well that was a surprisingly delightful movie. It takes a character I&amp;rsquo;ve at least barely heard of1 with a cast pretty much unknown to the western world2 and turns it into a wonderful combination of human drama, Lovecraftian baddies, and awesome action scenes. It&amp;rsquo;s well among my favorite MCU movies to date (only Captain America beats it out among introductions and a few others overall) and well worth the watch. After how big the MCU has gotten recently, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of nice to see a movie that almost completely stands on it&amp;rsquo;s own3.</description></item><item><title>Black Widow</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</guid><description>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been to theaters since&amp;hellip; Avengers: Endgame. Man it&amp;rsquo;s been a weird few years. Which actually wraps up Black Widow pretty well.
On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly solid action/spy movie. There are a number of spectacular action scenes, a deep dive into Black Widow&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s akin to an origin story, but filling in a character we already knew a decent amount of back rather than introducing someone new, which was nice&amp;ndash;and the introduction of a few new characters I expect we&amp;rsquo;ll see more of.</description></item><item><title>The Suicide Squad</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-suicide-squad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-suicide-squad/</guid><description>Oh, that is a glorious movie. Exactly what an R rated half-satirical superhero movie should be.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually seen the first Suicide Squad or Birds of Prey (yet), so it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as strange that they apparently kept some of the characters/actors while ignoring some events and keeping others. Other than that&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s just so enjoyable.
Starting right from the opening:
You have the Suicide Squad. Super powered criminals, given the chance to take a few years off their sentence if they&amp;rsquo;ll use their powers to do the jobs that the &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; heroes are either too busy or too &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; to do.</description></item><item><title>Space Jam: A New Legacy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/29/space-jam-a-new-legacy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/29/space-jam-a-new-legacy/</guid><description>Bugs Bunny: So, you want me, a talking cartoon bunny, to play with you, an NBA superstar, in a high-stakes basketball game?
Sounds awfully familiar.
LeBron James: Who are you talking to?
Well. That was certainly a thing.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched the original Space Jam in probably 20 years&amp;hellip; but I remember it fondly enough. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I really want to go back and watch it again. But it still does make me want to give Space Jam: A New Legacy a chance.</description></item><item><title>Mortal Kombat</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/03/mortal-kombat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 23:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/03/mortal-kombat/</guid><description>Shang Tsung: FINISH THEM!
Mortal Kombat is an odd sort of movie. With 2 dozen games, 2 previous live action and 2 animated films, and all manner of other references and media, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of backstory going on. But really, it all comes down to some sort of otherworldly nasties coming to conquer the Earth, but they can only do so if they defeat Earth&amp;rsquo;s champion(s). Other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s really a vehicle for hand to hand combat of the most violent sort.</description></item><item><title>Godzilla vs Kong</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/godzilla-vs-kong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/godzilla-vs-kong/</guid><description>You know, that was more enjoyable than I think it had any right to be. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of movie that would have been far more spectacular on a big screen, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to the theaters in a while, so I&amp;rsquo;ll take smaller.
All around, it&amp;rsquo;s a visual delight. Transporting Kong is hilarious looking. The Hollow Earth is an insane idea, but it&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful world and all of those big beasties to fight are a lot of fun to see.</description></item></channel></rss>