<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Necroscope on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/necroscope/</link><description>Recent content in Necroscope on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/necroscope/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deadspawn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/29/deadspawn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/29/deadspawn/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think I&amp;rsquo;m done with the Necroscope series, at least for the time being. And hey, technically this &lt;em>is&lt;/em> the end of the first Necroscope series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the negative side:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadspeak</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/26/deadspeak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/26/deadspeak/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh hey, turns out there is another Ferenczy. Or rather, that&amp;rsquo;s what a lot of this book felt like. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to fill out a few more of the possibilities of what might happen if a vampire spawns a mostly human child who then desperately tries to learn to be a Vampire. But at the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s starting to feel like the same story again, just with different players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another twist this time, which I at first appreciated was that Harry has lost his powers (stolen from him by Harry Jr). So for a large chunk of the story, he cannot speak to the dead except in dreams&amp;ndash;which he doesn&amp;rsquo;t remember upon waking&amp;ndash;and cannot access the Moebius Continuum at all. Given how often I&amp;rsquo;ve complained about how overpowerful the latter made him, I thought it would be good for him to lose the power, &lt;span class="spoiler">but of course I guessed he would at some point get it back. And just in time for the final battle too, making it feel like an echo of the final battle from Necroscope I&lt;/span>
. So it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Source</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/23/the-source/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/23/the-source/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Source follows a nuclear accident that manages to blow a hole in between our reality and the homeworld (more accurately home universe, since Harry cannot Moebius his way there) of the Vampires.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting watching this series progress from espionage mixed with urban fantasy and horror in the first book to a more historical urban fantasy (if that makes sense) to this one which veers a bit more into almost science fiction. We have a parallel universe, a tidally locked planet, and some really weird vampire biology. The world building around vampires continues to be the strongest part of this series (which is amusing, given that I find the Moebius Continuum and the various ESP powers to be among the weakest).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vamphyri!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/19/vamphyri/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/19/vamphyri/</guid><description>&lt;p>So that&amp;rsquo;s how the series will continue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, we get a bit more of Harry who is now sharing bodies with his infant son (it&amp;rsquo;s about that weird) and communicating with the now dead main characters from the first book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Necroscope</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/16/necroscope/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/16/necroscope/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read anything in quite this genre before. It&amp;rsquo;s basically urban fantasy, except set during the Cold War (which makes some sense, given this book was released in 1986) and with an extra helping of espionage (ESPionage) thrown in. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting change and the two styles complement one another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ve read many books where the first two chapters go quite so strongly back and forth between this is cool and that&amp;rsquo;s gross. It evened out a bit over the course of the book, but there was still a good amount of each.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>