<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Chronicles of Amber on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-chronicles-of-amber/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Chronicles of Amber on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-chronicles-of-amber/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Courts of Chaos</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/27/the-courts-of-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/27/the-courts-of-chaos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good-bye and hello, as always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So. Oberon is back. Things are still going wrong. The Pattern is breaking apart and Brand / the Courts of Chaos are trying to hurry things along.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hand of Oberon</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/26/the-hand-of-oberon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/26/the-hand-of-oberon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heredity or environment? I wondered wryly. We were all of us, to some degree, mad after his fashion. To be honest, it had to be a form of madness, to have so much and to strive so bitterly for just a little more, for a bit of an edge over the others. He carried this tendency to its extreme, that is all. He was a caricature of this mania in all of us. In this sense, did it really matter which of us was the traitor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around, Corwin et all go to the Primal Pattern (because that&amp;rsquo;s a thing now) and manage to figure out what could have caused the Black Road and all the troubles that&amp;rsquo;s been causing them. We proceed to get a pile more backstory / world building from Dworkin (  &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;Who is apparently Corwin&#39;s grandfather?&lt;/span&gt;
  ) and head off for some fun™ in the Courts of Chaos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sign of the Unicorn</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/21/sign-of-the-unicorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/21/sign-of-the-unicorn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In , Corwin went from having no memories to learning he was a Prince of Amber, to trying to wrest the throne from his brother Eric&amp;ndash;only to be blinded and thrown into prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In , Corwin escapes off the Avalon in order to use jewelers&#39; supplies to make guns to take back the throne from Eric&amp;ndash;only to end up having to save Amber rather than attack it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Guns of Avalon</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/14/the-guns-of-avalon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/14/the-guns-of-avalon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I had to find a place, a place resembling another place &amp;ndash; one which no longer existed. I located the path. I took it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In  , Corwin attacked his brother Eric in Amber. He lost and was blinded and thrown in prison. Conveniently,  &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;Princes of Amber have a remarkable ability to heal&lt;/span&gt;
  . On top of that,  &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;Dworkin (who created the Trumps and knows more about the Pattern than probably anyone) just so happens to be locked up as well and pops into his cell.&lt;/span&gt;
  . One thing leads to another, and Corwin is free. Of course he wants to take another crack at the throne. How though?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nine Princes in Amber</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/05/nine-princes-in-amber/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/05/nine-princes-in-amber/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started The Chronicles of Amber, I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what I expected. Probably a straight forward fantasy epic a la The Lord of the Rings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not exactly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
