<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>H.P. Lovecraft on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/h.p.-lovecraft/</link><description>Recent content in H.P. Lovecraft on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/h.p.-lovecraft/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>At the Mountains of Madness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/18/at-the-mountains-of-madness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/18/at-the-mountains-of-madness/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is really a great place to end my current reading of HP Lovecraft. Here we get the story of an Antarctic expedition that goes off the rails in the most Lovecraftian way possible. They find not only the madness inducing beasties but a whole civilization thereof from billions of years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, Mountains of Madness plays directly to Lovecraft&amp;rsquo;s strengths: the world building. There isn&amp;rsquo;t much in the way of plot or character (although more than in some of his stories). Instead what we get is a mix of history spanning literally billions of years with the human narrators exploring the ruins.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Shadow Out Of Time</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/04/the-shadow-out-of-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/04/the-shadow-out-of-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was kind of a bizarre story, bouncing around in time and space a bit. Then again, it sounds like perhaps the narrator had a bizarre life, bouncing around in time and space. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, an interesting read and one of the better Lovecraft stories I&amp;rsquo;ve read. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting trying to figure out how much of the story actually happened (in universe) and how much might just be some sort of mental health issues on the part of the narrator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Shadow Over Innsmouth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/23/the-shadow-over-innsmouth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/23/the-shadow-over-innsmouth/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Shadow Over Innsmouth introduces the coastal town of Innsmouth and the amphibious Deep Ones to Lovecraft&amp;rsquo;s mythos. It&amp;rsquo;s a well put together story, all about a traveler that decided to take a detour he was warned against and ends up in a town with something of a dark secret.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, the plot is relatively straight forward and even the twist at the end was sort of expected (given the narrators genealogical bent). It&amp;rsquo;s still interesting to read though and there are some really tense moments and shiver inducing descriptions of the Deep Ones.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Dunwich Horror</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/17/the-dunwich-horror/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/17/the-dunwich-horror/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reading The Dunwich Horror back to back with Call of Cthulhu is an interesting experience. The former is everything I wanted the latter to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The core of the Horror itself (Yog-Sothoth) is described just enough to be terrifying, but not so much as to be anything concrete. It impacts on the people and land around Dunwhich just keep building up, growing more and more horrible. In particular, the Whateley family&amp;hellip; Wilbur and his even more monstrous brother. &lt;em>&lt;em>shivers&lt;/em>&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Call of Cthulhu</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/11/the-call-of-cthulhu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/11/the-call-of-cthulhu/</guid><description>&lt;p>For all I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of The Call of Cthulhu, I expected more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, you have three short stories about perhaps the best known of the Old Ones. Truly ancient cults. Even Cthulhu himself rising. But it&amp;rsquo;s all just a little underwhelming, especially when read back to back with The Festival and The Colour out of Space.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Colour Out of Space</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/08/the-colour-out-of-space/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/08/the-colour-out-of-space/</guid><description>&lt;p>Who would have thought that a colour could be so terrifying&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess it helps that it&amp;rsquo;s actually some life devouring, madness inducing shade that fell to earth in a meteorite and proceeded to wreck havoc on a local farm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Festival</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/08/the-festival/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/08/the-festival/</guid><description>&lt;p>References abound to things I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of before. Arkham. The Necronomicon. The mad Arab Abdul Alhazred. Miskatonic University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is the narrator the same man as in The Nameless City? No idea. Feels like not. But it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a shared universe. One with an impressive feeling of size for only a pair of short stories thus far.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Nameless City</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/07/the-nameless-city/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/07/the-nameless-city/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. That&amp;rsquo;s Lovecraft.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the first of his that I&amp;rsquo;ve read (complete works for 99¢ on Amazon), although I&amp;rsquo;m relatively familiar with the mythos. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>