<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Martha Wells on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/martha-wells/</link><description>Recent content in Martha Wells on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/martha-wells/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Cloud Roads</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/26/the-cloud-roads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/26/the-cloud-roads/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a fascinating sort of book, especially having read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-murderbot-diaries/">The Murderbot Diaries&lt;/a> first. It&amp;rsquo;s not entirely the same thing at all&amp;ndash;fantasy rather than science fiction, with a world full of floating eyes and many different sapient races rather than aliens and murderbots&amp;ndash;but there are some bones that aren&amp;rsquo;t too dissimilar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, you have Moon. He&amp;rsquo;s a Raksura, a being capable of transforming between a more or less human form (although I don&amp;rsquo;t get the feeling there are any real &amp;lsquo;humans&amp;rsquo; in this book) and a much larger stronger winged form. He&amp;rsquo;s all on his own, not even sure what he is&amp;ndash;or where he fits in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which of course goes badly when the people he&amp;rsquo;s staying with think he&amp;rsquo;s Fell (winged &amp;rsquo;evil&amp;rsquo; creatures; I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that). And much better when another Raksura finds him and brings him back. And worse again when it turns out they don&amp;rsquo;t want him either. And better again when, of course, he saves the day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fugitive Telemetry</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/06/fugitive-telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/06/fugitive-telemetry/</guid><description>&lt;p>An odd book. It&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be #6 in the series, but really, it&amp;rsquo;s a prequel to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/network-effect/">Network Effect&lt;/a>. There&amp;rsquo;s not much you need to know between the two, so you can read them in either order and if it were up to me, I&amp;rsquo;d probably swap them (mostly because I want to know what happens next!), but it still works.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Network Effect</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/network-effect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/network-effect/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>So that was what had happened before the survey. Now we’re here, ready for the next major disaster. (Spoiler warning.)&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a full length Murderbot novel! Yay! And it gets far deeper and weirder into corners of the worldbuilding we&amp;rsquo;ve only had hints of before. I love seeing the hints of tension with the corporations and how much control they hvaqe, the weirdness that is alien remnants, and the knowledge that there are super weird problems out there that aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily directly related to Murderbot.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exit Strategy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/exit-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/exit-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Murderbot has really stirred up some trouble. Now Dr. Mesnah&amp;rsquo;s caught up in it and it&amp;rsquo;s time to come back and perhaps fix some things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like the rest, it&amp;rsquo;s a quick read with a wonderful sense of all too familiar alienness, wonderful hacking and action scenes, and a fascinating look at what it means to be a person&amp;ndash;or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth the read, but at this point, I expect you&amp;rsquo;ll already be blowing through these.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rogue Protocol</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/17/rogue-protocol/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/17/rogue-protocol/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>(There needs to be an error code that means “I received your request but decided to ignore you.”)&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I do love me some Murderbot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, we got the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/">origin story&lt;/a> and then the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/15/artificial-condition/">one where the mystery deepens&lt;/a>). Now&amp;hellip; Murderbot is really digging into where it came from &amp;hellip; and what int eh world GrayCris is doing there. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun story and I really love seeing Murderbot learn and grow as a person*. It&amp;rsquo;s all about the relationships&amp;ndash;Murderbot and all the people, Miki with it&amp;rsquo;s childlike personality that may actually be loved, and of course Dr. Mensah.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Artificial Condition</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/15/artificial-condition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/15/artificial-condition/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When constructs were first developed, they were originally supposed to have a pre-sentient level of intelligence, like the dumber variety of bot. But you can’t put something as dumb as a hauler bot in charge of security for anything without spending even more money for expensive company-employed human supervisors. So they made us smarter. The anxiety and depression were side effects.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Murderbot is out on their own! It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting change of pace from the previous story, where Muderbot was still in the role of SecUnit&amp;hellip; On the way, it runs into ART (a spaceship AI; not it&amp;rsquo;s real name, it stands for Asshole Research Transport; three guesses who that&amp;rsquo;s from&amp;hellip;) who turns out to be a great ally. Muderbot gets a few changes to act slightly less SecUnit and more Augmented Human, goes back to the planet where to some extend it all began, and ends up hiring out it&amp;rsquo;s services as private security&amp;ndash;hey, do what you know.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All Systems Red</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, I get what all the hype is about. Take a heavily armed cyborg/clone, designed entirely as muscle to defend the more squishy &amp;rsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; humans, have it turn off the software constraining it from killing everyone, add in a wonderfully snarky sense of humor&amp;hellip; and see what happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I COULD HAVE BECOME a mass murderer after I hacked my governor module, but then I realized I could access the combined feed of entertainment channels carried on the company satellites. It had been well over 35,000 hours or so since then, with still not much murdering, but probably, I don’t know, a little under 35,000 hours of movies, serials, books, plays, and music consumed. As a heartless killing machine, I was a terrible failure.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>