<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MCU Phase 4 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-phase-4/</link><description>Recent content in MCU Phase 4 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-phase-4/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spider-Man: No Way Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</guid><description>Finally got around to watching this. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did, it&amp;rsquo;s hilarious and an aboslute blast of nostalgia. Similar to Avengers: Endgame, I don&amp;rsquo;t know know if this would possibly hold up without the weight of all of the movies that came before it (I doubt it), but with that weight&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s really really good.
It&amp;rsquo;s funny, it&amp;rsquo;s touching, and there are some really crazy action scenes. But the greatest strength of course comes from bringing back a half dozen villains and all three modern live action Spider-Men into one film .</description></item><item><title>Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</guid><description>Well that was a surprisingly delightful movie. It takes a character I&amp;rsquo;ve at least barely heard of1 with a cast pretty much unknown to the western world2 and turns it into a wonderful combination of human drama, Lovecraftian baddies, and awesome action scenes. It&amp;rsquo;s well among my favorite MCU movies to date (only Captain America beats it out among introductions and a few others overall) and well worth the watch. After how big the MCU has gotten recently, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of nice to see a movie that almost completely stands on it&amp;rsquo;s own3.</description></item><item><title>Black Widow</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</guid><description>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been to theaters since&amp;hellip; Avengers: Endgame. Man it&amp;rsquo;s been a weird few years. Which actually wraps up Black Widow pretty well.
On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly solid action/spy movie. There are a number of spectacular action scenes, a deep dive into Black Widow&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s akin to an origin story, but filling in a character we already knew a decent amount of back rather than introducing someone new, which was nice&amp;ndash;and the introduction of a few new characters I expect we&amp;rsquo;ll see more of.</description></item></channel></rss>