<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>T. Kingfisher on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/</link><description>Recent content in T. Kingfisher on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nine Goblins</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/06/nine-goblins/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/06/nine-goblins/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/"&gt;T. Kingfisher&lt;/a&gt; is a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart goblins became mechanics. Dumb goblins became soldiers. Really dumb goblins became officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s this delightful little story about a world where Goblins are at war with the Humans and Elves. It&amp;rsquo;s told from the point of view of a ragtag group of Goblins who suddenly find themselves &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; behind enemy lines, having to ally themselves with &amp;hellip; a veterinarian of all things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s quite a funny book; the humor reminds me a lot of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/discworld/"&gt;Discworld&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;take that as the compliment it is. I love reading about all the goblins. They are most &lt;em&gt;certainly&lt;/em&gt; a wacky bunch of characters&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wherever a goblin happens to live, he complains about it constantly. This is actually a sign of affection. A desert goblin will complain endlessly about the beastly heat and the dreadful dryness and the spiky cactus. He will show you how his sunburn is peeling and the place where the rattlesnake bit him and the place where he bit the rattlesnake. He will be thoroughly, cheerfully, miserable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and of course the teddy bear&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bear not only had a set of stripes sewn on his arm, it was possibly the first teddy-bear in history to have received a medal for service to the elven nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the contrast of an Elven veterinarian, getting into all the dirty, messy, ugly things vets have to do (when Elves normally only concern themselves with that which is fair beautiful and true) is great fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a quick read (147 pages) and well worth the fun. Give it a try!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/28/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/28/thornhedge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Another day, another Kingfisher. And once again, I quite enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, we have a novella length story that takes Rapunzel and turns it more than a bit sideways. As the blurb says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a princess trapped in a tower. This isn&amp;rsquo;t her story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, we get Toadling. Raised by the fae with the power to turn into a frog and some other minor magics of her own, she ends up standing guard over a girl in a tower for years and years&amp;ndash;centuries really, it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely clear; nor does it particularly matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quite enjoyed the different take on the story&amp;ndash;I do love a good fairy story. I enjoyed the character of Toadling. The idea of the bramble and a gift gone awry. Not a huge fan of the idea of straight up pure evil in general and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work any better here (spoilers I suppose?). But it&amp;rsquo;s a small enough part of the story that I don&amp;rsquo;t think it particularly detracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good book. A quick read. Worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Wizard's Guide to Defensive Baking</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/04/a-wizards-guide-to-defensive-baking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/04/a-wizards-guide-to-defensive-baking/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is nearly impossibly to be sad when eating a blueberry muffin. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that&amp;rsquo;s a scientific fact.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need to read more &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/"&gt;T. Kingfisher&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/"&gt;Nettle &amp;amp; Bone&lt;/a&gt; was delightful and, if anything, A Wizard&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Defensive Baking is even better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, we have a world with a specialized sorts of wizards. You might be able to cast lightning bolts&amp;hellip; or you might have the power to animate and converse with dead horses. Or you &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; even have magical powers over&amp;hellip; bread!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s such a delightful idea and Kingfisher manages to do all sorts of fun things with it. Some obvious (Mongo eat your gingerbread heart out), some less so (Bob the sourdough starter; so delightful).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trees were full of crows and the woods were full of madmen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pit was full of bones and her hands were full of wires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that was a delightful surprise&amp;ndash;in a dark fairytale kind of way. I&amp;rsquo;ve not read any T. Kingfisher before, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have to remedy that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, Nettle &amp;amp; Bone takes the idea of a fairy godmother&amp;rsquo;s blessing at birth and twists it, bringing in the politics of unequal neighboring kingdoms; fae, their bargains, and all the twists that go with that; and a touch of demons and death magic. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun world to build a foundation on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful cast of characters. I love seeing Marra, third-born princess, sent to a religious order (sort of), and originally on her own to solve the world&amp;rsquo;s problems. Only for her to collect a motley band of strange and wonderful allies, each in their own ways: a witch, a reluctant godmother, a night, a dog made of bones, and a demon made of chicken. (It makes sense). They&amp;rsquo;re all great and I love the found family dynamic as they&amp;rsquo;re off to save the world&amp;ndash;or at least some tiny corner of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As if that weren&amp;rsquo;t enough, I love the prose and wordplay. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;written&lt;/em&gt; like a fairytale writ large. It just fits the story so well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, One of the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year and more than worth giving it a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>