<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>T. Kingfisher on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/</link><description>Recent content in T. Kingfisher on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Wizard's Guide to Defensive Baking</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/04/a-wizards-guide-to-defensive-baking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/04/a-wizards-guide-to-defensive-baking/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“It is nearly impossibly to be sad when eating a blueberry muffin. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that&amp;rsquo;s a scientific fact.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I need to read more &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/">T. Kingfisher&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/">Nettle &amp; Bone&lt;/a> was delightful and, if anything, A Wizard&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Defensive Baking is even better!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, we have a world with a specialized sorts of wizards. You might be able to cast lightning bolts&amp;hellip; or you might have the power to animate and converse with dead horses. Or you &lt;em>might&lt;/em> even have magical powers over&amp;hellip; bread!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s such a delightful idea and Kingfisher manages to do all sorts of fun things with it. Some obvious (Mongo eat your gingerbread heart out), some less so (Bob the sourdough starter; so delightful).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The trees were full of crows and the woods were full of madmen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pit was full of bones and her hands were full of wires.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was a delightful surprise&amp;ndash;in a dark fairytale kind of way. I&amp;rsquo;ve not read any T. Kingfisher before, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have to remedy that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, Nettle &amp;amp; Bone takes the idea of a fairy godmother&amp;rsquo;s blessing at birth and twists it, bringing in the politics of unequal neighboring kingdoms; fae, their bargains, and all the twists that go with that; and a touch of demons and death magic. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun world to build a foundation on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful cast of characters. I love seeing Marra, third-born princess, sent to a religious order (sort of), and originally on her own to solve the world&amp;rsquo;s problems. Only for her to collect a motley band of strange and wonderful allies, each in their own ways: a witch, a reluctant godmother, a night, a dog made of bones, and a demon made of chicken. (It makes sense). They&amp;rsquo;re all great and I love the found family dynamic as they&amp;rsquo;re off to save the world&amp;ndash;or at least some tiny corner of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As if that weren&amp;rsquo;t enough, I love the prose and wordplay. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>written&lt;/em> like a fairytale writ large. It just fits the story so well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, One of the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year and more than worth giving it a try.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>