<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2025 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/2025-tv-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2025 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/2025-tv-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Severance: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/severance-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/severance-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well, that&amp;rsquo;s quite a show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first glance, the idea is appealing. You split your memories so that you can go to work, get paid, and essentially spend your entire life &lt;em>not at work&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But then you start to think about this other you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They never leave.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They never sleep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They never have a life outside of work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that&amp;ndash;is terrifying enough even before you start getting into the whole cult&amp;rsquo;y aspects. And the hallways. And the goats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have no idea where they&amp;rsquo;re going&amp;ndash;(I hope they know)&amp;ndash;but I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to it. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taskmaster Australia: Series 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/taskmaster-australia-series-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/taskmaster-australia-series-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have no idea how I ended up watching season 2 of Taskmaster Australia before Season 1, but go with it! It&amp;rsquo;s not like there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>that&lt;/em> much of an overarching plot between seasons that you have to keep up with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man, this is a fun bit. Another series, another Taskmaster! And another assistant!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tom (Gleeson). And lesser Tom (Cashman) are a lot of fun together. I love that lesser Tom can never keep a straight face when teh contestants screw up. It&amp;rsquo;s delightful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And oh the cast was a lot of fun. Anne and Lloyd as a couple on the show together made for some great moments. Wil and Tom being old friends is a dynamic we&amp;rsquo;ve seen before in the British version but it&amp;rsquo;s always fun. Josh was quite a wildcard at times. And Jenny was one of the reasons I came to this version of the show&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen her acts on YouTube before and she&amp;rsquo;s a wonderfully weird mix and has a lot of those &amp;lsquo;young enough to make the other contestants feel old&amp;rsquo; moments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, another great season of Taskmaster. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to catch more of the Australian version! LIke season 1 &amp;#x1f604;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Love it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Agatha All Along</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/21/agatha-all-along/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/21/agatha-all-along/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that was a delight. Take Agatha (and the general fallout of her created world) from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/">WandaVision&lt;/a>, turn up the witchiness, and go on a magical mystical, somewhat terrifying adventure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating story and, honestly, if you would have left out a few scenes it would have worked perfectly well completely outside of the Marvel Cinematic Universe as well. And at this point, that&amp;rsquo;s a strong point in its favor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man Kathryn Hawn does great in this. I loved the supporting witch cast, especially Aubrey Plaza. She does unsettling and off kilter so well. And Teen&amp;ndash;he was an interesting counterpoint. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about the worldbuilding around either Rio (Plaza) or Teen (Locke), those parts felt weird, but the actors were awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;hellip; &lt;strong>the song&lt;/strong> (I don&amp;rsquo;t see this version as spoilers, but some might).&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VnjYeJ5blxo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Man that song has been stuck in my head for weeks now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I personally would have dropped the last half of the last episode, the penultimate really works better as a conclusion. This really doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a sequel (although apparently there will be a third show as a &amp;lsquo;TV trilogy&amp;rsquo; sort of thing?), but so it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>A Man on the Inside</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/05/a-man-on-the-inside/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/05/a-man-on-the-inside/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was a fun show. Created by the Michael Schur (who also did the Good Place, check it out!) and with many overlapping cast members from the Good Place, I had high hopes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I learned that it was about a man learning to live in an assisted living center, I &amp;hellip; wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure. Was there a supernatural element?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then when it dropped (in the first episode and all the promotional materials, so I don&amp;rsquo;t see it as a spoiler) that he&amp;rsquo;s going in to assisted living as a SPY! Well, I&amp;rsquo;m intriuged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun show, hilarious at times (especially with just how &lt;em>bad&lt;/em> Charles is at all this) and sad at others (it&amp;rsquo;s about old folks. Death, loneliness, and memory loss are just part of it). But it&amp;rsquo;s quite the ride all the way through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do love the cast, Ted Danson as Charles is amazing. I enjoyed Mary Elizabeth Ellis
as his daughter Emily, even if her family troubles were a weird B plot. Lilah Richcreek Estrada as Julie did &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to solve this problem whatever it takes&amp;rsquo; wonderfully, and it was fascinating to see Stephanie Beatriz as head of staff Didi. I really need to watch Brooklyn Nine-Nine at some point&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then all of the old folks inhabiting those halls&amp;hellip; Man those were some performances. I honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize any of them from other roles but I expect there are some well known names in there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful show and goes by quick. Well worth the watch!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/doctor-who-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/doctor-who-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m still re-watching Doctor Who in fits and starts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, after all that was great with Eccleston/Nine in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/02/doctor-who-season-1/">season 1&lt;/a>, how we get Tennant/Ten. Oh, I do enjoy his take on the doctor. It&amp;rsquo;s a perfect mix of a whimsical seeing what he can get away with&amp;ndash;with the absolute feel of sadness and age that a being like the Doctor really should be feeling&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And all with Rose along for the ride. Rose gets a lot of hate at times, but I really think she was a pretty good first nu-Who companion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this season, we a fair few two parters, a bunch of great episodes. &lt;a href="#4-the-girl-in-the-fireplace">The Girl in the Fireplace&lt;/a> is a great take on &amp;rsquo;the Time Travelers wife&amp;rsquo; sort of thing. &lt;a href="#5-rise-of-the-cybermen">Rise of the Cybermen&lt;/a>/&lt;a href="#6-age-of-steel">Age of Steel&lt;/a> introduces us to some old foes. &lt;a href="#8-the-impossible-planet">The Impossible Planet&lt;/a>/&lt;a href="#9-satan-pit">Satan Pit&lt;/a> &lt;em>really&lt;/em> start getting into Doctor Who as sci-fi/horror (and I love it).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="#10-love--monsters">Love &amp;amp; Monsters&lt;/a>. That&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; actually not that bad? It&amp;rsquo;s definitely one of the &amp;lsquo;Doctor-lite&amp;rsquo; episodes, which are always something interesting to try. The ending is crass and kind of terrifying to really think about&amp;ndash;rather than the laughs you might think they were going for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a solid season!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And &lt;a href="#special-the-runaway-bride">the special&lt;/a> introduces Donna! Even if she won&amp;rsquo;t be back for a bit, she&amp;rsquo;s certainly a contender for my favorite companion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Arcane: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/21/arcane-season-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/21/arcane-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well then. I absolutely loved [[Arcane: Season 1]]. I still loved Season 2&amp;hellip; but I think they may have reached just a &lt;em>bit&lt;/em> too far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The art style is still amazing. We still have the same main steampunk/magitech/brightly colored visuals (Jink&amp;rsquo;s chaotic spraypunk style in particular), but there are also more scenes this time, with different styles matching the feel. Chaotic black slashes when a monster hunts, childhood crayon feeling drawings for memories, and SPACE for&amp;hellip; well, spoilers. And oh, the glitching. Weird, but quite the style.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characters&amp;hellip; I think at it&amp;rsquo;s heart, this show is about Vi and Jinx and man do they go through a lot in this season. I already felt for Jinx&amp;ndash;even if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure she could ever be redeemed in season 1&amp;ndash;and they just turn it up. On top of that, you have Jayce/Viktor, which&amp;hellip; man that one hurt this season. Plus Vi/Cait (go them!), and Mel/her mother (this one didn&amp;rsquo;t get nearly as much time as it needed), and Ekko (this could have been a whole season&amp;hellip; or left out entirely).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mostly, I think this was the biggest problem with this season. It&amp;rsquo;s only 9 episodes, mostly short of 45 minutes. That is &lt;em>not&lt;/em> enough time to fit everything that they tried to put in this show. I could have easily watched an entire season focussing on any one of those plots above&amp;hellip; and they tried to fit it all in. We get some resolutions&amp;hellip; but so much is left undone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently there won&amp;rsquo;t be an Arcane Season 3; instead, we&amp;rsquo;ll get one or more spinoff shows in the same universe but with other stories/settings/characters. This is absolutely for the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of feel, the first season did a good job of feeling real/grounded. It was a story of class warfare and the introduction of magic into a steampunk world. It all &amp;lsquo;fit&amp;rsquo;. Here, we get quite a bit more of the more &amp;lsquo;cosmic&amp;rsquo; side of what&amp;rsquo;s apparently also kicking around in this world. I liked it, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, but it felt so much bigger and weirder than the first season that they didn&amp;rsquo;t quite fit together&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall? I still quite enjoyed Season 2. It is absolutely worth watching Season 1 and once you have&amp;hellip; well, you have to go on, right? I&amp;rsquo;ll totally check out any spin-offs that we get.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 18</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/20/taskmaster-series-18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/20/taskmaster-series-18/</guid><description>&lt;p>I &amp;hellip; managed to miss [[todo:Taskmaster: Series 17]] somehow. Anyways!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another delightful season. This was a fun cast. Baba was full of chaos, Rosie got away with so much crap (sometimes literally) and her team tasks with Jack were such chaos. Andy has serious mad professor vibes (mostly the hair I suppose). Emma&amp;hellip; Emma was my favorite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rosie having cerebral palsy certainly started out with a different flavor to the season. But man she has a sense of humor about the whole thing. I think it took Greg and the other contestants a minute to feel out how far to go (&amp;ldquo;Is it too early in the series to mention I DON&amp;rsquo;T have cerebral palsy?&amp;rdquo; - Emma)&amp;hellip; but once they did, that was a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>As you can tell by the way I talk, I suffer from being Northern. &amp;ndash; Rosie&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, what do you want? I love this show. Another great season. Time to go back to 17!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>