<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Taskmaster Australia on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/taskmaster-australia/</link><description>Recent content in Taskmaster Australia on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/taskmaster-australia/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taskmaster Australia: Series 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/taskmaster-australia-series-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/taskmaster-australia-series-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have no idea how I ended up watching season 2 of Taskmaster Australia before Season 1, but go with it! It&amp;rsquo;s not like there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>that&lt;/em> much of an overarching plot between seasons that you have to keep up with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man, this is a fun bit. Another series, another Taskmaster! And another assistant!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tom (Gleeson). And lesser Tom (Cashman) are a lot of fun together. I love that lesser Tom can never keep a straight face when teh contestants screw up. It&amp;rsquo;s delightful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And oh the cast was a lot of fun. Anne and Lloyd as a couple on the show together made for some great moments. Wil and Tom being old friends is a dynamic we&amp;rsquo;ve seen before in the British version but it&amp;rsquo;s always fun. Josh was quite a wildcard at times. And Jenny was one of the reasons I came to this version of the show&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen her acts on YouTube before and she&amp;rsquo;s a wonderfully weird mix and has a lot of those &amp;lsquo;young enough to make the other contestants feel old&amp;rsquo; moments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, another great season of Taskmaster. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to catch more of the Australian version! LIke season 1 😄.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Love it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>