<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Firebird on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/firebird/</link><description>Recent content in Firebird on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/firebird/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Million Worlds with You</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/31/a-million-worlds-with-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/31/a-million-worlds-with-you/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Fate doesn’t guarantee us a happy ending. We’re not promised to be together no matter what. But in dimension after dimension, world after world, fate gives us a &lt;em>chance&lt;/em>. Our destiny isn’t some kind of mystical prophecy. Our destiny is what we do with that chance.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/05/a-thousand-pieces-of-you/">A Thousand Pieces of You&lt;/a> introduced us to the multiverse and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/22/ten-thousand-skies-above-you/">Ten Thousand Skies Above You&lt;/a> brought it to the brink of war. Now, in A Million Worlds with You, the fighting is &lt;em>on&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The core of the story comes in two parts:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For one, we have Marguerite chasing a twisted echo of herself (who she names Wicked; I do enjoy how everyone just goes with her names throughout the book). The entire idea that Marguerite can&amp;rsquo;t jump into the same world as Wicked and has to trail behind, digging herselves out of any trouble Wicked gets them into is fascinating. But by itself, entirely reactive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So for two, we have a war between dimensions. We have some worlds that were already aware of parallel realities, but now, finally, they are beginning to work together and push back against the Triad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To war!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do love the premise. It&amp;rsquo;s solidly written and a worthwhile finish to the trilogy (although now I want more! what happens between all the worlds next?!). It &amp;hellip; was rough to start it, mostly due to all the damage Marguerite and especially Paul went through last book, but that&amp;rsquo;s sort of the the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ten Thousand Skies Above You</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/22/ten-thousand-skies-above-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/22/ten-thousand-skies-above-you/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/05/a-thousand-pieces-of-you/">A Thousand Pieces of You&lt;/a> introduced us to the multiverse&amp;ndash;and sent us on adventure across the worlds in a desperate gamble for revenge&amp;hellip; Or perhaps to save a life. Or perhaps even to fall in love.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The multiverse is infinite. So, yeah, we go through some terrible things together, and I’ve seen versions of you who are darker, and damaged, and I don’t care. I want you even when you’re broken. I want you no matter what. Your darkness, your anger, whatever it is you fear inside yourself—it doesn’t matter. I love you completely, don’t you see? I even want the worst of you because it’s &lt;em>still a part of you&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Ten Thousand Skies Above You takes that idea and expands upon it in a fascinating way. Now, it&amp;rsquo;s not just searching through the multiverse, it&amp;rsquo;s the early stages of a war between realities. Once again, it&amp;rsquo;s about saving a life, but this time, it&amp;rsquo;s less a puzzle and more a scavenger hunt, with some &lt;em>serious&lt;/em> repercussions if you don&amp;rsquo;t find all of the pieces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than a cliffhanger ending (we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that&amp;hellip;), it&amp;rsquo;s really quite a good sequel. If anything, I think I enjoyed it even more than the first.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Thousand Pieces of You</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/05/a-thousand-pieces-of-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/05/a-thousand-pieces-of-you/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I would love you in any shape, in any world, with any past. Never doubt that.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s one part jumping into parallel reality sci-fi, one part murder mystery, and one part YA adventure story (complete with love tangle).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For me at least, it works surprisingly well. I&amp;rsquo;m normally not a huge fan of love tangles taking up a large part of a story. Here, I think it works pretty well. We have the additional tension of investigating murder. Plus having the feel of previously established relationships and growth throughout the story. It works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Parallel reality / sci-fi wise, it&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; light. There&amp;rsquo;s not really much in the way of exactly &lt;em>how&lt;/em> parallel realities work and what the rules are for moving from one to another. On the other hand, as a vehicle to jump from our world (ish) to a vaguely futuristic London. To one where Russian is still in it&amp;rsquo;s full Czarist grandeur. To another where climate change has already flooded the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also interesting how on one hand you have the parallel reality &amp;rsquo;everything is possible&amp;rsquo;, contrasted throughout the entire book by:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“There are patterns within the dimensions,” Paul insisted, never looking up again. “Mathematical parallels. It’s plausible to hypothesize that these patterns will be reflected in events and people in each dimension. That people who have met in one quantum reality will be likely to meet in another. Certain things that happen will happen over and over, in different ways, but more often than you could explain by chance alone.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“In other words,” I said, “you’re trying to prove the existence of fate.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was joking, but Paul nodded slowly, like I’d said something intelligent. “Yes. That’s it exactly.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I feel like you can&amp;rsquo;t really have it both ways&amp;hellip; and the story doesn&amp;rsquo;t really either. It&amp;rsquo;s really just the latter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I really enjoyed listening to this story. I&amp;rsquo;m really curious where it goes from here. There&amp;rsquo;s certainly room for the sequels, let&amp;rsquo;s see what they do!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>