<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AoC 2021 Day 3: Binary Contraption</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/03/aoc-2021-day-3-binary-contraption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/03/aoc-2021-day-3-binary-contraption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;source-binary-diagnostichttpsadventofcodecom2021day3&#34;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://adventofcode.com/2021/day/3&#34;&gt;Binary Diagnostic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;part-1-given-a-list-of-binary-numbers-calculate-gamma-such-that-each-bit-is-the-most-common-bit-in-that-position-in-the-input-and-epsilon-which-is-the-binary-inverse-of-gamma-return-the-product&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Given a list of binary numbers, calculate gamma such that each bit is the most common bit in that position in the input and epsilon which is the binary inverse of gamma. Return the product.&lt;/h4&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AoC 2021 Day 2: Submarine Simulator</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/02/aoc-2021-day-2-submarine-simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/02/aoc-2021-day-2-submarine-simulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;source-divehttpsadventofcodecom2021day2&#34;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://adventofcode.com/2021/day/2&#34;&gt;Dive!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;part-1-simulate-a-submarine-with-3-commands-forward-n-down-n-and-up-n-that-move-forward-increase-depth-and-decrease-depth-in-that-order-calculate-the-product-of-the-final-position-and-depth&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Simulate a submarine with 3 commands: &lt;code&gt;forward N&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;down N&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;up N&lt;/code&gt; that move forward, increase depth, and decrease depth in that order. Calculate the product of the final position and depth.&lt;/h4&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AoC 2021 Day 1: Depth Finder</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/01/aoc-2021-day-1-depth-finder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/01/aoc-2021-day-1-depth-finder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;source-depth-finderhttpsadventofcodecom2021day1&#34;&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://adventofcode.com/2021/day/1&#34;&gt;Depth Finder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;part-1-given-a-list-of-numbers-count-how-many-times-sequential-numbers-increase&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Given a list of numbers, count how many times sequential numbers increase.&lt;/h4&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2021</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/01/advent-of-code-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/01/advent-of-code-2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve done an advent of code! I&amp;rsquo;ll probably backfill a few years eventually, but for now, let&amp;rsquo;s just write some code!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, these problems are wonderful to try to solve yourself. If you agree, &lt;em&gt;stop reading now&lt;/em&gt;. This post isn&amp;rsquo;t going anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to see the full form of any particular solution, you can do so on GitHub (including previous years and possibly some I haven&amp;rsquo;t written up yet): &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jpverkamp/advent-of-code&#34;&gt;jpverkamp/advent-of-code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Winter King</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/28/the-winter-king/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/28/the-winter-king/</guid>
      <description>ONCE UPON A TIME, in a land that was called Britain, these things happened.
 This is an odd one to review. It&amp;rsquo;s well written, decently paced (although I found it slow in general), and&amp;ndash;so far as I know&amp;ndash;well researched for the time period. On the other hand, I tend strongly to prefer fantasy and science fiction (which this is not, despite all the hints at the contrary) and a little more action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Mills 2021</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/27/spring-mills-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 08:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/27/spring-mills-2021/</guid>
      <description>Another Black Friday, another day out of doors. Chilly, but still well worth the exploration. The kids had a blast.
                                   View on Flickr  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bambi</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/27/bambi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/27/bambi/</guid>
      <description>Bambi is a surprisingly tricky movie to review, mostly since it relies on who&amp;rsquo;s doing the reviewing. From my perspective, it&amp;rsquo;s cute enough, but there&amp;rsquo;s next to nothing there. It&amp;rsquo;s just a bunch of cute animated animals running around for an hour. From my kids&#39; perspectives though&amp;hellip; they loved it. They were laughing out loud at the cartoon antics and cuddled right in during the storm and hunt scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellblazer, Vol. 5: Dangerous Habits</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/23/hellblazer-vol.-5-dangerous-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/23/hellblazer-vol.-5-dangerous-habits/</guid>
      <description>Weird, slow, and dark at first but then we get the Deadly Habits storyline. That’s one of the core Constantine storylines so far as I know and for good reason.
The Bogeyman Oh Constantine. What is going on with you. Dark and depressing and little happening. Sets up a story I suppose.
Dead-Boy’s Heart That’s a great issue. Took me a bit to realize it was typing Constantine. So he’s always been … a little different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Sister</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/21/holy-sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/21/holy-sister/</guid>
      <description>All leaves must fall in time, she had said. The lives we lived fall away from us, but something remains, something that is part of the tree.
 That one actually took me rather a while to get through. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, the worldbuilding is still facinating, the action is top notch, and we still get more than a bunch of all the main characters. But somehow&amp;ndash;it seems to have lost it&amp;rsquo;s focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dune</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/20/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/20/dune/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/dune.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lady Jessica Atreides: I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little death that brings obliteration. I will face my fear and I will permit it to pass over me and through me. And when it has gone past&amp;hellip; I will turn the inner eye to see its path. Where the fear has gone there will be nothing. Only I will remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow. That&amp;rsquo;s a movie with &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; a sense of scale and granduer. The ships are huge, the worms are huge, the armies are huge, the Duke is honorable, the Fremen are pious, the Baron is gross, everything is spectacular. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a bummer that we&amp;rsquo;re going to have to wait a few years for Part 2, but I think it really did need the space to breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worldbuilding and visuals are what really makes this movie. I watched it on HBOMax, rather than in theaters, but I do have a wall sized projected screen and that really does help. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a visually stunning movie. If they re-run Part 1 in theaters, I may have to check it out next time around&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pippi Goes on Board</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/19/pippi-goes-on-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/19/pippi-goes-on-board/</guid>
      <description>I actually liked this story a lot more than the first Pippi. It&amp;rsquo;s still basically the same idea: girl who is unusually strong and lives on her own gets up to hijinks, but I think that the stories this time around fit a little bit&amp;ndash;and we actually get to meet Pippi&#39;s dad--turns out he&#39;s not dead after all .
Worth continuing on. Going to have to check out the third now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature Friends at Holliday Park</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/nature-friends-at-holliday-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 09:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/nature-friends-at-holliday-park/</guid>
      <description>Meeting up with friends, in Nature! Holliday Park is a wonderful find.
                View on Flickr  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature Friends at Lilly Lake</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/nature-friends-at-lilly-lake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 09:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/nature-friends-at-lilly-lake/</guid>
      <description>More meeting up with friends, in Nature! This time at Lilly Lake (Eagle Creek Park). So pretty in the fall.
          View on Flickr  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Robot: Season 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/mr.-robot-season-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/mr.-robot-season-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/mr.robot-season-2.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Season 1 wrapped up, where do you even go from there? They finished their big goal. Dealing with the fallout is the obvious answer&amp;hellip; or ramping things up even further. We get a bit of both in Season 2, mostly with even more big twists from Elliot&amp;rsquo;s entirely confusing mind but also a plot that is both deeper and more terrifying than I would have thought at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not quite as solid as Season 1, in most part because it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as new and fresh. But it&amp;rsquo;s still very good and well worth the watch. Whatever shall we learn in Season 3?!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sons of the Oak</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/sons-of-the-oak/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/sons-of-the-oak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;144113&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/144113.sons-of-the-oak&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/sons-of-the-oak.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sons of the Oak is an odd one. After saving the world in Lair of Bones, Gaborn and Iome are loaded with enough metabolism to curse them to die in the next few years&amp;ndash;which ends up happening relatively early on. That of course leaves a power vacuum. There are those who would love to see the Earth King&amp;rsquo;s son take the crown&amp;ndash;and just as many who&amp;rsquo;d rather see him dead and take power of their on. On top of that, there&amp;rsquo;s a whole new level of darkness in the world. From Loci to strengi-saats, it&amp;rsquo;s an ever darkening world, with the Torch of Humanity having been passed down to the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve actually finished this book before. The time skip made it hard to read and I just moved on. But this time around, I&amp;rsquo;ve actually really enjoyed it. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to see how it continues. I think reading it as an audiobook has helped. It just keeps going unless you actually stop rather than stopping unless you push on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/17/star-wars-episode-iv-a-new-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/17/star-wars-episode-iv-a-new-hope/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/star-wars-episode-iv---a-new-hope.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There it is. A New Hope. The Star Wars I grew up on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vLgsf8Pei6Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man that&amp;rsquo;s a great opening. The scale of the Star Destroyer, dumping us in on the &amp;lsquo;everyman&amp;rsquo; droids, and that Vadar scene. Spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars: Episode III - Revenge of the Sith</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/15/star-wars-episode-iii-revenge-of-the-sith/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/15/star-wars-episode-iii-revenge-of-the-sith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/star-wars-episode-iii---revenge-of-the-sith.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revenge of the Sith is a somewhat fascinating story. It feels by far the darkest and most &amp;lsquo;adult&amp;rsquo; of the prequel trilogy, probably best matching the feel of A New Hope and Empire Strikes Back, but at the same time, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more humor in the early parts at least, with some truly weird and silly moments with R2 and the Battle Droids. You know&amp;hellip; I just don&amp;rsquo;t understand the droids. I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to that in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/13/the-many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/13/the-many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/the-many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh is just delightful&amp;ndash;and a blast of nostalgia on top of that. I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to actually watch all of the Disney classic growing up (still haven&amp;rsquo;t), but I definiately watched this one. And now, after reading many of the stories to my children, it&amp;rsquo;s a delight to be able to share the video form with them as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like the style of these stories. It&amp;rsquo;s a mix of animated world with the real storybook characters (Pooh et al), but also obviously in a book, as they hob from page to page. It&amp;rsquo;s not the story of style you&amp;rsquo;d always expect to work, but it really works here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellblazer, Vol. 4: The Family Man</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/07/hellblazer-vol.-4-the-family-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/07/hellblazer-vol.-4-the-family-man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Better than Volume 3 by a long shot. Starts weird but interesting and gets better from there. I’ll reiterate though that I can’t really imagine buying these by issue, especially in real time. A volume has enough meat to it to sustain a storyline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars: Episode II - Attack of the Clones</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/07/star-wars-episode-ii-attack-of-the-clones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/07/star-wars-episode-ii-attack-of-the-clones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/star-wars-episode-ii---attack-of-the-clones.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The things that I remember most about Attack of the Clones are the atmosphere of Kamino, the final battle on Genosis (mostly from the game Star Wars Battlefront), and some rather cringey burgeoning relationship dialog from Anakin and Padme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lair of Bones</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/04/the-lair-of-bones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/04/the-lair-of-bones/</guid>
      <description>The Lair of Bones
David Farland   The Lair of Bones is an epic and fitting conclusion1 to the Runeslords saga. It takes the story of Gaborn and Raj Ahten, of Runelords and reavers, of elemental powers and far darker things, and brings it all together in a series of rather epic journeys and battles, culminating with an epic&amp;ndash;if bittersweet&amp;ndash;victory of light over dark, of good over evil.
Or does it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pippi Longstocking</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/03/pippi-longstocking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/03/pippi-longstocking/</guid>
      <description>Pippi Longstocking&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an odd character. On one hand, she&amp;rsquo;s a fun loving young girl who happens to have super strength (for some reason). She&amp;rsquo;s lived a pretty crazy life and has stories from all over the world along with a tendency to get herself into (and back out of) wacky adventures and always seems to have a lot of fun doing so.
On the other hand, she&amp;rsquo;s a young girl living on her own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luca</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/02/luca/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/02/luca/</guid>
      <description>Luca is something of an odd beast. It&amp;rsquo;s a cute little movie about two young sea monster boys who journey out onto land&amp;ndash;where so long as they don&amp;rsquo;t get wet, they transform to look like humans. Wacky hijinks ensue, there&amp;rsquo;s a meetcute with a young girl, a big race scenes, some quickly resolved drama, and everyone lives happily ever after.
It&amp;rsquo;s not the most thrilling movie, which isn&amp;rsquo;t really something that you expect to see from Pixar&amp;ndash;if it had come from any other studio it would have been pretty impressive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellblazer, Vol. 3: The Fear Machine</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/01/hellblazer-vol.-3-the-fear-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/01/hellblazer-vol.-3-the-fear-machine/</guid>
      <description>Not terrible, but also not great. It starts very slowly with a hippie commune and takes a few issues to get going and gets downright weird at a few points. But enjoyable enough after that.
Onward!
Issue specific reviews, spoilers:
Touching the Earth Oh boy.
And then it goes all weird hippy commune. Sure? I don’t really get it. Imagine paying for this as a single issue…
Shepherd’s Warning Well, it’s more of the same story, but there’s potential at least!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Robot: Season 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/mr.-robot-season-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/mr.-robot-season-1/</guid>
      <description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a heck of a show. Given that I&amp;rsquo;m do computer security for a living (albeit with a bit less of the black hat revolutionary mindset) and have my own problems figuring out how brains&amp;ndash;mine and others&amp;ndash;work (albeit not nearly to that extent&amp;hellip;) I feel like the perfect audience for this show. I&amp;rsquo;m honestly impressed with how well they got the hacking in this show. It&amp;rsquo;s not 100%&amp;ndash;that would be boring&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s miles closer than two-hackers-typing-on-a-keyboard-is-faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nightmare Before Christmas</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/the-nightmare-before-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/the-nightmare-before-christmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/the-nightmare-before-christmas.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boys and girls of every age&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you like to see something strange?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come with us and you will see&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, our town of Halloween&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man I love this movie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Hundred and One Dalmatians</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/30/one-hundred-and-one-dalmatians/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/30/one-hundred-and-one-dalmatians/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/one-hundred-and-one-dalmatians.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;60 years ago. Dang. And you know? It holds up. The action is solid and story aren&amp;rsquo;t overly complicated but enjoyable, the animation really works (despite/because of the limitations of the time), and the villains are unambiguous and scary but not overly so. Perhaps best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s the story of an absolute pile of talking dogs. What&amp;rsquo;s not to love?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars: Episode I - The Phantom Menace</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/29/star-wars-episode-i-the-phantom-menace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/29/star-wars-episode-i-the-phantom-menace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/star-wars-episode-i---the-phantom-menace.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, that opening score. The title crawl. That&amp;rsquo;s a blast of nostalgia right there. I&amp;rsquo;m too young to have seen the original trilogy in theaters, but I watched the VHS tapes what felt like a million times. When The Phantom Menace came out, that was &lt;em&gt;right&lt;/em&gt; in my wheelhouse. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how many times I saw that movie in theaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you know what? It&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as it&amp;rsquo;s often rated. Granted, if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t leaning so heavily on the rest of the Star Wars franchise, well&amp;hellip; it would probably be about that bad. But I disagree that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t disserve a place in the core &amp;lsquo;Skywalker Saga&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun action movie wrapped around the rise of dark powers and corruption in the guise of&amp;ndash;a trade war and senatorial discourse of all things. It&amp;rsquo;s weird, but I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to accept it at least?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obi-Wan: You were right about one thing master. The negotiations were short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s my favorite Star Wars movie so far&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and only a hint of things to come!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knives Out</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/24/knives-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/24/knives-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/knives-out.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lieutenant Elliott: I&amp;rsquo;m sorry this is an open and shut case of suicide and quite frankly Benny we are getting to the point where I have to ask you what we&amp;rsquo;re doing here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benoit Blanc: The method? Throat slit? Typical for a suicide?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lieutenant Elliott: Yes, I mean, that&amp;rsquo;s dramatic, but look around. I mean, the guy practical lives in a Clue board.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that was a surprising yet great fun movie. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a murder mystery. Heir of the family is found dead&amp;ndash;apparent suicide. But things quickly become more complicated, with a detective (Daniel Craig as Benoit Blanc with a hilarious southern drawl that still somehow works&amp;hellip;) anonymously hired to &amp;lsquo;get to the truth&amp;rsquo;. The family is a nightmare, everyone has a reason to have offed the old man&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventures with Children</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/adventures-with-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 20:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/adventures-with-children/</guid>
      <description>On leave with the newest addition, so I&amp;rsquo;m taking the older ones out and about to let mum and baby bond. Great times. Interesting pictures.
                       View on Flickr  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Nemo</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/finding-nemo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/finding-nemo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/finding-nemo.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding Nemo is a delightful children&amp;rsquo;s movie. It&amp;rsquo;s the story of a worrying dad (Marlin), a son (Nemo) trying to grow into his own self, the trouble that causes, and the lengths family can go through for one another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellblazer, Vol. 2: The Devil You Know</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/hellblazer-vol.-2-the-devil-you-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/hellblazer-vol.-2-the-devil-you-know/</guid>
      <description>Well that’s a ride. The continuation of the Swamp Thing sexy times storyline, some more backstory on how Constantine got to be how he is, Constantine all Arthurian (for some reason), and a straight up horror story.
Weaker than volume 1 but worth continuing to volume 3!
Sex and Death Starts where we left off, with Constantine out of body and the Swamp Thing doing his mating thing… That is not a plot line I care at all about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grey Sister</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/grey-sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/grey-sister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;35530652&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35530652.grey-sister&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/grey-sister.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NONA GREY RAISES her head and regards her foe through midnight eyes. Perhaps
it is just the reflection of the torchlight but somewhere in their darkness
a red flame seems to burn. “I am my own cage.” She lifts her sword. “And I
have opened the door.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;35530652&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35530652.grey-sister&#34;&gt;Grey Sister&lt;/a&gt; takes the fantasy world&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; with a magical school full of battle nuns that we started with in &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;25895524&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25895524.red-sister&#34;&gt;Red Sister&lt;/a&gt; and turns things up a notch. Nona isn&amp;rsquo;t hiding any more just how much she can do, which is causing just about as many problems as it solves. And halfway through the books, things really escalate once again, with politics and problems outside of the convent itself coming to bear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shazam!</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/shazam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/shazam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/shazam.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was not really what I expected. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s got the heart of a super hero origin story, with Billy Batson gaining powers, learning to use them (and not lose himself or his friends/family while doing so), and fighting the big bad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squid Game</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/squid-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/squid-game/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t actually do much social media (other than a relatively limited set of subreddits), so I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually notice what was apparently a fairly large storm of people watching Squid Game, but when it came up on Honest Trailers it seemed pretty interesting. 9 episodes and I just finished Stargate Universe, so I figured, let&amp;rsquo;s give it a spin!
Let&amp;rsquo;s say&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s at once exactly what I expected, but even then had a few interesting twists and turns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sopranos: Season 6</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos-season-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos-season-6/</guid>
      <description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a lot. In order to finish all of the stories they wanted to tell&amp;ndash;but also not to have to negotiate another season&amp;rsquo;s worth of contracts with the actors, season 6 is really two seasons in one. The first is slightly shorter than the other seasons at 12 (instead of 13), while the second half is only 9. So one big season? Two small? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that much when you&amp;rsquo;re streaming them back to back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stargate Universe: Season 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/stargate-universe-season-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/stargate-universe-season-2/</guid>
      <description>Each time I rewatch Stargate (and with 17 seasons and a handful of movies, that&amp;rsquo;s something of a time commitment), I forgot just how much better Stargate Universe season 2 is than season 1. And I already liked Season 1. But 2 is where things really get on their own. The crew trapped on Destiny is really learning how to use the ship and making it their own, finding new (huge) mysteries, and actually getting a few big bads on a scale with the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld/Ori/Wraith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rescuers Down Under</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/the-rescuers-down-under/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/the-rescuers-down-under/</guid>
      <description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s an absolute blast of childhood nostalgia. We had this movie on VHS when I was little and I remember watching the heck out of it, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t otherwise seen it in decades now. Truth be told, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until recently that I realized it was even a sequel&amp;hellip;
In any case. The Rescuers (Down Under) is the story of a worldwide society of mice that take it upon themselves to rescue human children in need of help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mr. Popper&#39;s Penguins</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/15/mr.-poppers-penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/15/mr.-poppers-penguins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;61549&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/61549.mr-poppers-penguins&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/mr-poppers-penguins.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s a delightful if a bit bizarre little book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, Mr. Popper is an orderinary enough man who happens to absolutely love stories about Arctic/Antarctic expeditions. He writes a letter to Admiral Drake and&amp;hellip; gets a penguin shipped to him. One thing leads to another, he gets another penguin, they have an unusually large pile of chicks, and they go on the road.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellblazer, Vol. 1: Original Sins</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/14/hellblazer-vol.-1-original-sins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/14/hellblazer-vol.-1-original-sins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;18902412&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18902412.hellblazer-vol-1-original-sins&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-1-original-sins.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really do have a thing for urban fantasy specifically dealing with demons and angels, good and evil, especially if it twists it all around. Constantine does that in spades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched the 2005 film well before I knew it was based on a comic (so sue me), so Keanu Reeves is forever going to be stuck in my head as the true Constantine, but I&amp;rsquo;ve also watched just about all of the new wave of DC shows, including the 2014 version of Constantine plus his appearances on Legends of Tomorrow. Not quite the same, but I still loved the character.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Baby Shirts!</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/maker/3d-printing/2021-10-10-new-baby-shirts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/maker/3d-printing/2021-10-10-new-baby-shirts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to be parents (again)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time around, we made adorable big brother/big sister/little sister shirts with dinosaurs, this time we wanted to go with FLOWERS! It&amp;rsquo;ll be wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</guid>
      <description>Well that was a surprisingly delightful movie. It takes a character I&amp;rsquo;ve at least barely heard of1 with a cast pretty much unknown to the western world2 and turns it into a wonderful combination of human drama, Lovecraftian baddies, and awesome action scenes. It&amp;rsquo;s well among my favorite MCU movies to date (only Captain America beats it out among introductions and a few others overall) and well worth the watch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What If...?</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</guid>
      <description>What if…?
It&amp;rsquo;s a wacky title, but it sums up the series pretty well. Take what the MCU has spent a decade building on top of half a century of comics before that1. The comics have done all manner of continuity resets and what-ifs, so it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual to see the stories as they could have been&amp;ndash;if only one thing changed. But this is a first for the MCU. I fully expect with the coming Phase 4, we&amp;rsquo;ll see a bit more of this though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Lord of the Sith, Vol. 4: Fortress Vader</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/06/dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol.-4-fortress-vader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/06/dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol.-4-fortress-vader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;40652555&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40652555.star-wars-darth-vader---dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol-4-fortress-vader&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/star-wars-darth-vader---dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol-4-fortress-vader.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of interesting world building in this one, from a mask inhabited by a Sith Ghost (more or less; something we could use more of now that we know how often the Jedi do this), portals to a possible world beyond death, more hunting down Jedi, and Vader&amp;rsquo;s fortress&amp;ndash;which I barely remember as a thing anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a solid volume, but not quite up to the level as what came before. Still worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Lord of the Sith, Vol. 3: The Burning Seas</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/04/dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol.-3-the-burning-seas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/04/dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol.-3-the-burning-seas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;39668120&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/39668120.star-wars-darth-vader---dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol-3-the-burning-seas&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/star-wars-darth-vader---dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol-3-the-burning-seas.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating addition. It takes what we&amp;rsquo;ve already been seeing&amp;ndash; Vader solidifying his power in the time between Revenge of the Sith and A New Hope&amp;ndash;and takes us to the Mon Cala system, home of Admiral Ackbar. And yes, it is in fact a trap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating way to expand a bit of the Star Wars universe I at least didn&amp;rsquo;t know much about, getting a bit of the tension between two different intelligent life forms on one planet (which I suppose we&amp;rsquo;ve also seen on Naboo) and fleshing out a race we&amp;rsquo;ve only seen a little about before. All from the point of view of our favorite black suited, heaving breathing menace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Lord of the Sith, Vol. 2: Legacy&#39;s End</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/03/dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol.-2-legacys-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/03/dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol.-2-legacys-end/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;36040437&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36040437.vol-2-legacys-end&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/vol-2-legacys-end.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vader&amp;rsquo;s goal this time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/vader-17-2.1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Lord of the Sith, Vol. 1: Imperial Machine</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/02/dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol.-1-imperial-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/02/dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol.-1-imperial-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;35009957&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35009957.star-wars-darth-vader---dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol-1-imperial-machine&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/star-wars-darth-vader---dark-lord-of-the-sith-vol-1-imperial-machine.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another day&amp;hellip; another Darth Vader serial?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darth Vader, Vol. 4: End of Games</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/02/darth-vader-vol.-4-end-of-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/02/darth-vader-vol.-4-end-of-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;29467582&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29467582.star-wars-darth-vader-vol-4-end-of-games&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/star-wars-darth-vader-vol-4-end-of-games.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay. We&amp;rsquo;re heading towards the conclusion of this particular story arc. I really do like this length. 4 volumes has about as much oomph as a novel length story, albeit with a much higher concentration of pretty* pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that being said, Vader is making his way back into Palpatine&amp;rsquo;s good (bad?) graces&amp;ndash;but he now truly understands how the Sith work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darth Vader, Vol. 3: The Shu-Torun War</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/01/darth-vader-vol.-3-the-shu-torun-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/01/darth-vader-vol.-3-the-shu-torun-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;28118847&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28118847.star-wars-darth-vader-vol-3-the-shu-torun-war&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/star-wars-darth-vader-vol-3-the-shu-torun-war.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now this went a bit sideways. Forget the Emperor and politicking (more or less). Instead, get thrown into a rivalry on a mining planet that&amp;rsquo;s obsessed with etiquette&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/vader-3.1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Sister</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/01/red-sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/01/red-sister/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;25895524&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25895524.red-sister&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/red-sister.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important, when killing a nun, to ensure that you bring an army of
sufficient size.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worldbuildingwise:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
