<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Doctor Who on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/doctor-who/</link><description>Recent content in Doctor Who on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/doctor-who/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Doctor Who: 2008 Specials</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/30/doctor-who-2008-specials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/30/doctor-who-2008-specials/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The 2008-2010 specials!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-next-doctor"&gt;The Next Doctor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where the Doctor meets&amp;hellip; the Doctor?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Jackson Lake: There she is. My transport through time and space. The TARDIS!&lt;br&gt;
 The Doctor: You&amp;rsquo;ve got a balloon.&lt;br&gt;
 Jackson Lake: TARDIS. T - A - R - D - I - S. It stands for Tethered Aerial Release Developed in Style! Do you see?&lt;br&gt;
 The Doctor: Well, I do now. I like it. Good TARDIS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you know? Dervla Kirwan as Miss Hartigan gets a bit of flack, but if you ignore for a moment the history of the &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;Cybermen&lt;/span&gt;
, she&amp;rsquo;s quite the fun row. Plus, an absolutely giant robot in old fashioned london down. What&amp;rsquo;s not to love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="planet-of-the-dead"&gt;Planet of the Dead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Doctor, sent through a portal to a desert planet, where he has to depend on a temporary companion in jewel thief Lady Christina to get back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christina: It&amp;rsquo;s Christina Da Souza. To be precise it&amp;rsquo;s Lady Christina Da Souza.&lt;br&gt;
The Doctor: Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s handy because I&amp;rsquo;m a lord.&lt;br&gt;
Christina: Seriously, lord of where?&lt;br&gt;
The Doctor: It&amp;rsquo;s quite a big estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s yet another case (Voyage of the Damned was another one) where a companion for a special would have been &lt;em&gt;fascinating&lt;/em&gt; to keep around. So it goes though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-waters-of-mars"&gt;The Waters of Mars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed points in time don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; make sense for the Doctor. Especially given how it turns out in the end. But still, a giant marsbase and soggy zombies? What&amp;rsquo;s not to love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s yet another one of those episodes that digs just into how broken and&amp;ndash;at some level&amp;ndash;insane the Doctor is, after all those years and triumphs. And failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adelaide: But you said we die. For the future. For the human race!&lt;br&gt;
The Doctor: Yes, because there are laws. There are laws of time. Once upon a time there were people in charge of those laws but they died. They all died. Do you know who that leaves? &lt;em&gt;Me!&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s taken me all these years to realize that the laws of time are &lt;em&gt;mine&lt;/em&gt; and they will obey me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite the set up for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-end-of-time-parts-one-and-two"&gt;The End of Time (Parts One and Two)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tennats finale is coming&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Doctor: Even if I change it still feels like dying. Everything I am dies. Some new man goes sauntering away&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But on the way, we have Wilfred Mott as the Doctor&amp;rsquo;s companion? Yes please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Doctor: I&amp;rsquo;m going to die.&lt;br&gt;
Wilfred Mott: Well, so am I one day.&lt;br&gt;
The Doctor: Don&amp;rsquo;t you dare!&lt;br&gt;
Wilfred Mott: Alright, I&amp;rsquo;ll try not to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And add to that, the Master (back from he dead) and perhaps&amp;hellip; something even worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh that&amp;rsquo;s an intense pair of episodes. Even if it&amp;rsquo;s more than a &lt;em&gt;touch&lt;/em&gt; overdone at times (as all of ennats finales seem to be).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this time around, we get a victory lap of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so Ten ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Doctor: I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to Eleven!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/21/doctor-who-season-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/21/doctor-who-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh Doctor Who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This such a wonderful season (and I do say that about a lot of the seasons).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, we have Donna back as the companion. I do love that she&amp;rsquo;s not pining after the Doctor as others have been want to do. And she&amp;rsquo;s just so delightfully snarkily&amp;ndash;human. They really do play off each other well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, we have &lt;em&gt;The Fires of Pompeii&lt;/em&gt;, with both a future Doctor and a future companion (in other rolls), &lt;em&gt;Planet of the Ood&lt;/em&gt; (delightfully creepy), &lt;em&gt;The Doctor&amp;rsquo;s Daughter&lt;/em&gt; (actually his wife&amp;hellip;), &lt;em&gt;Silence in the Library&lt;/em&gt; (well, okay maybe she is), and &lt;em&gt;Midnight&lt;/em&gt; (for such a limited set it&amp;rsquo;s so intense).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are just so many solid episodes this season!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward, to the 2008-2010 specials! Man those can be a pain to find/categorize. I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure why they weren&amp;rsquo;t just considered season 4.5 or even season 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/16/doctor-who-season-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/16/doctor-who-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so I slowly continue re-watching Doctor Who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts out strong with Jadoon on the Moon in &lt;a href="#1-smith-and-jones"&gt;Smith and Jones&lt;/a&gt;, we have more of the Face of Bo (&lt;a href="#3-gridlock"&gt;Gridlock&lt;/a&gt;) and the Daleks (&lt;a href="#4-daleks-in-manhattan"&gt;Daleks in Manhattan&lt;/a&gt;; plus, that one has Andrew Garfield!), several wonderfully creepy episodes (&lt;a href="#7-42"&gt;42&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="#9-the-family-of-blood"&gt;Family of Blood&lt;/a&gt;), and a finale that was certainly spectacular even if it finally veered too much &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; and not enough science for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and of course this is the one with &lt;a href="#10-blink"&gt;Blink&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a reason this is the highest rated Doctor Who episode from the revival&amp;ndash;despite minimal time with the Doctor himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A solid season. And now it&amp;rsquo;s time for Donna!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/doctor-who-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/doctor-who-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m still re-watching Doctor Who in fits and starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, after all that was great with Eccleston/Nine in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/02/doctor-who-season-1/"&gt;season 1&lt;/a&gt;, how we get Tennant/Ten. Oh, I do enjoy his take on the doctor. It&amp;rsquo;s a perfect mix of a whimsical seeing what he can get away with&amp;ndash;with the absolute feel of sadness and age that a being like the Doctor really should be feeling&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And all with Rose along for the ride. Rose gets a lot of hate at times, but I really think she was a pretty good first nu-Who companion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this season, we a fair few two parters, a bunch of great episodes. &lt;a href="#4-the-girl-in-the-fireplace"&gt;The Girl in the Fireplace&lt;/a&gt; is a great take on &amp;rsquo;the Time Travelers wife&amp;rsquo; sort of thing. &lt;a href="#5-rise-of-the-cybermen"&gt;Rise of the Cybermen&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="#6-age-of-steel"&gt;Age of Steel&lt;/a&gt; introduces us to some old foes. &lt;a href="#8-the-impossible-planet"&gt;The Impossible Planet&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="#9-satan-pit"&gt;Satan Pit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; start getting into Doctor Who as sci-fi/horror (and I love it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="#10-love--monsters"&gt;Love &amp;amp; Monsters&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; actually not that bad? It&amp;rsquo;s definitely one of the &amp;lsquo;Doctor-lite&amp;rsquo; episodes, which are always something interesting to try. The ending is crass and kind of terrifying to really think about&amp;ndash;rather than the laughs you might think they were going for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, a solid season!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href="#special-the-runaway-bride"&gt;the special&lt;/a&gt; introduces Donna! Even if she won&amp;rsquo;t be back for a bit, she&amp;rsquo;s certainly a contender for my favorite companion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/02/doctor-who-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/02/doctor-who-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched through modern Doctor Who a few times, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a while. I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually caught the 13th Doctor yet, let alone 14 and 15&amp;hellip; Now, with the new &amp;lsquo;reboot&amp;rsquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s about time to give it another go. And a good time to review them this time around!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I love this show. It&amp;rsquo;s wacky and cheap looking at times. Tonally, we&amp;rsquo;re all over the place, from farting aliens right up to the borders (if not more so) of horror with The Empty Child. Callbacks to the old show (which I still haven&amp;rsquo;t watched, one day) and all new friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do wish we&amp;rsquo;d gotten more of Eccelston, I forgot how much I liked his Doctor. But still, it&amp;rsquo;s good to have what we have!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>