<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ultimate Marvel Universe (Post Cataclysm) on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/ultimate-marvel-universe-post-cataclysm/</link><description>Recent content in Ultimate Marvel Universe (Post Cataclysm) on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/ultimate-marvel-universe-post-cataclysm/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Secret Wars</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/25/secret-wars/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/25/secret-wars/</guid><description>&lt;p>So I picked up Secret Wars as a sort of conclusion to the Ultimate Universe. Without having read basically any of the leading material in the main Earth-616 lineup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/secret-wars-textbundle-07da17.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird and confusing what&amp;rsquo;s going on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Eventually, you more or less get the idea, but until then, it&amp;rsquo;s really like being dropped into yet another crazy chaotic patchwork world, with Doom as God.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s actually a pretty cool world&amp;ndash;truth be told&amp;ndash;with lots of variations on characters we&amp;rsquo;ve seen otherwise. I enjoy the idea of a whole army of Thors as the local police force. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But eventually, we get a few stowaways from Earth-616 and &amp;hellip; well, one* from Earth-1610 (the Ultimate Universe) I&amp;rsquo;ve been following (*: two technically, we also get Maker&amp;ndash;yay&amp;hellip;). And that&amp;rsquo;s really it. Eventually they have to save the day and rewrite time. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a way to kill off Earth-1610 and a bunch of other universes in order to simplify the overall multiverse?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kind of sucks that untold billions have to die / never have existed for that to happen&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall: Interesting enough story, especially a few issues in where what&amp;rsquo;s actually going on becomes more clear. Ending is kind of lame. The reason Miles gets to stick around (despite his being the best storyline in a while from the Ultimate Universe) is &amp;hellip; hilarious and weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to read something a bit less &amp;hellip; all encompassing for a while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate End</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/25/ultimate-end/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/25/ultimate-end/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so the Ultimate Universe ends&amp;hellip; with a weird confusing mess of a send off?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s sort of a companion to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/25/secret-wars/">Secret Wars&lt;/a>, more specifically focusing on what is happening in the Earth-1610/Ultimate Universe part of the Battleworld&amp;hellip; but it&amp;rsquo;s not really necessary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All you need to know is that this is the &amp;hellip; Ultimate End.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(You really can skip this one, it&amp;rsquo;s all right.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All-New Ultimates, Volume 2: No Gods, No Masters</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/all-new-ultimates-volume-2-no-gods-no-masters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/all-new-ultimates-volume-2-no-gods-no-masters/</guid><description>&lt;p>Meh. It worked much better in Volume 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Same team, same smaller stakes. Not going to lose states (again), but plenty of lives are on the line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s interesting seeing the team dynamics (on again, off again, half a dozen times in a single volume…).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The art for this one got weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Ultimates name still doesn’t really work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it’s weird that the Kate Bishop story line almost 100% got dropped.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward to the end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All-New Ultimates, Volume 1: Power for Power</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/22/all-new-ultimates-volume-1-power-for-power/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/22/all-new-ultimates-volume-1-power-for-power/</guid><description>So, a new team. It’s… certainly not the Ultimates, despite the name. More of a Spidey and Friends.
But you know? It works.
It’s a lot more local level, where Spider-Man really shines. It’s fun seeing Bombshell grown up a bit. Cloak and Dagger are great. Yay Jessica Drew.
And yay ish Kitty Pride? She’s been there since just about the beginning. Pretty crazy to think.
Anyways. I enjoyed it.</description></item><item><title>Miles Morales: Ultimate Spider-Man, Vol. 2: Revelations</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/21/miles-morales-ultimate-spider-man-vol.-2-revelations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/21/miles-morales-ultimate-spider-man-vol.-2-revelations/</guid><description>&lt;p>Resolution of the Parker storyline: check. Ish. I still don’t like it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miles’ father back and a bit of backstory? Awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kate Bishop’s secret? Also a nice* twist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>*not actually nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Goblin? Electro? Sabertooth? Hydra? Doom? Defeated!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a jam packed volume, just at the right scale for Spider-Man. A good one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate FF: Strangest Ever</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/17/ultimate-ff-strangest-ever/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/17/ultimate-ff-strangest-ever/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fantastic Four?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nah, Future Foundation!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a really weird story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Random incursions from random dimensions. Animal people. Cyclops super heroes. Atlanteans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And oy talk about tonal whiplash. Death and doom to animal people to kidnapping to quippy one liners to rape. All over the place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally, the art. It starts off, a bit unfinished… but I kind of like it. But then it gets even more unfinished and cartoony. Not a fan.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a vaguely interesting story wrapped up in a lot of weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not surprised this is all it got.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>