<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Russell T Davies on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/russell-t-davies/</link><description>Recent content in Russell T Davies on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/russell-t-davies/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/doctor-who-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/doctor-who-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m still re-watching Doctor Who in fits and starts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, after all that was great with Eccleston/Nine in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/02/doctor-who-season-1/">season 1&lt;/a>, how we get Tennant/Ten. Oh, I do enjoy his take on the doctor. It&amp;rsquo;s a perfect mix of a whimsical seeing what he can get away with&amp;ndash;with the absolute feel of sadness and age that a being like the Doctor really should be feeling&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And all with Rose along for the ride. Rose gets a lot of hate at times, but I really think she was a pretty good first nu-Who companion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this season, we a fair few two parters, a bunch of great episodes. &lt;a href="#4-the-girl-in-the-fireplace">The Girl in the Fireplace&lt;/a> is a great take on &amp;rsquo;the Time Travelers wife&amp;rsquo; sort of thing. &lt;a href="#5-rise-of-the-cybermen">Rise of the Cybermen&lt;/a>/&lt;a href="#6-age-of-steel">Age of Steel&lt;/a> introduces us to some old foes. &lt;a href="#8-the-impossible-planet">The Impossible Planet&lt;/a>/&lt;a href="#9-satan-pit">Satan Pit&lt;/a> &lt;em>really&lt;/em> start getting into Doctor Who as sci-fi/horror (and I love it).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="#10-love--monsters">Love &amp;amp; Monsters&lt;/a>. That&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; actually not that bad? It&amp;rsquo;s definitely one of the &amp;lsquo;Doctor-lite&amp;rsquo; episodes, which are always something interesting to try. The ending is crass and kind of terrifying to really think about&amp;ndash;rather than the laughs you might think they were going for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a solid season!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And &lt;a href="#special-the-runaway-bride">the special&lt;/a> introduces Donna! Even if she won&amp;rsquo;t be back for a bit, she&amp;rsquo;s certainly a contender for my favorite companion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/02/doctor-who-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/02/doctor-who-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve watched through modern Doctor Who a few times, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a while. I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually caught the 13th Doctor yet, let alone 14 and 15&amp;hellip; Now, with the new &amp;lsquo;reboot&amp;rsquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s about time to give it another go. And a good time to review them this time around!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, I love this show. It&amp;rsquo;s wacky and cheap looking at times. Tonally, we&amp;rsquo;re all over the place, from farting aliens right up to the borders (if not more so) of horror with The Empty Child. Callbacks to the old show (which I still haven&amp;rsquo;t watched, one day) and all new friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do wish we&amp;rsquo;d gotten more of Eccelston, I forgot how much I liked his Doctor. But still, it&amp;rsquo;s good to have what we have!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>