<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2023 Book Bingo on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2023-book-bingo/</link><description>Recent content in 2023 Book Bingo on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2023-book-bingo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Scourge Between Stars</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/the-scourge-between-stars/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/the-scourge-between-stars/</guid><description>&lt;p>Humanity screwed up. To get us out of it, we sent a generation ship to the stars. But when we got there&amp;hellip; it wasn&amp;rsquo;t any better, so they turned around to go home. On the way back&amp;hellip; well, we just might not be alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A generation ship is a great setting for a sci-fi/horror mashup. There really is nowhere to run but plenty of places to hide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea of things lurking out there between the stars? Terrifying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The feel of the book, especially as it ratchets up to the big reveal/fight scenes throughout the ship? Excellent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the only real problems I had with the book were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It was too short! Novella length, but the premise alone could certainly fill a novel.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The technology was a bit odd at times (what exactly are they doing with &amp;lsquo;jumps&amp;rsquo;?)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;span class="spoiler">The things in the dark between stars not actually being the monster? Awesome. But... what were they then?&lt;/span>

&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Worth a read though! A debut author worth following.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shadow and Bone</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Browsing through Netflix last fall, I came upon &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/25/shadow-and-bone-season-1/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a>. Watched it. Quite enjoyed it. Figured I should read the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s not bad, but I enjoyed the show more. For one, it pulls in Kaz and co, which don&amp;rsquo;t appear in this novel at all (they&amp;rsquo;re originally from the related Six of Crows books), which is a bummer. For two, the additional dynamic of Alina as half-Shu in addition to being an orphan added rather a lot to her character.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Book of Zog</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/10/the-book-of-zog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/10/the-book-of-zog/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The man scowled, but Zogrusz sensed a slight softening in his mood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I understand, stranger. I remember my first time in this room, when I felt His presence looming over me. But you cannot so blithely stroke the visage of our dread lord! Such disrespect might summon His wrath, and all of Xochintl would suffer.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“What delightful nonsense!” Zogrusz exclaimed, clapping his hands together. “Did you make it up yourself?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Zogrusz is an Eldrich Horror, a being from beyond time and space. But&amp;hellip; a nice one? That just wants to do the right thing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The book follows Zog and the quasi-Earth (it&amp;rsquo;s never entirely clear) he settles on through thousands of years (mostly with large time jumps) and the rise and fall of various religions up to (and through) and approaching cosmic horror style end of the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rosewater</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/06/rosewater/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/06/rosewater/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The idea of a singular hero and a manifest destiny just makes us lazy. There is no destiny. There is choice, there is action, and any other narrative perpetuates a myth that someone else out there will fix our problems with a magic sword and a blessing from the gods.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Rosewater has a fascinating premise. Take the world a half century in the future. Most things are the same, but there&amp;rsquo;s a bit more tech floating around, mostly. Introduce a massive alien organism that lands in London and ends up burrowing it&amp;rsquo;s way to Nigeria. From that alien blob, fill the atmosphere with alien microorganisms/cells that create their own xenosphere, enabling (among other things) psychic powers in some very small proportion of the population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Wizard's Guide to Defensive Baking</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/04/a-wizards-guide-to-defensive-baking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/04/a-wizards-guide-to-defensive-baking/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“It is nearly impossibly to be sad when eating a blueberry muffin. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that&amp;rsquo;s a scientific fact.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I need to read more &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/">T. Kingfisher&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/">Nettle &amp;amp; Bone&lt;/a> was delightful and, if anything, A Wizard&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Defensive Baking is even better!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, we have a world with a specialized sorts of wizards. You might be able to cast lightning bolts&amp;hellip; or you might have the power to animate and converse with dead horses. Or you &lt;em>might&lt;/em> even have magical powers over&amp;hellip; bread!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s such a delightful idea and Kingfisher manages to do all sorts of fun things with it. Some obvious (Mongo eat your gingerbread heart out), some less so (Bob the sourdough starter; so delightful).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stories of Your Life and Others</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/30/stories-of-your-life-and-others/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/30/stories-of-your-life-and-others/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was a delightful collection of shorts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t often read anthologies, but perhaps I should read more. I do love me some epic fantasy (I&amp;rsquo;ve read the entire &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-wheel-of-time/">The Wheel of Time&lt;/a> half a dozen times now&amp;hellip;), but there&amp;rsquo;s just something about a story that builds up quickly, gets to the point, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t stick around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think of the 8, I only bounced off 1 (which was actually a fine story, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t suspend disbelief enough for the premise) and 1 was a bit meh, just for how short it was. 6 of 8 I absolutely loved though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Absolutely worth a read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Six-Gun Snow White</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/26/six-gun-snow-white/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/26/six-gun-snow-white/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>From that day forward she never used my name. Eventually I forgot it. Mrs. H called me something new. She named me cruel and smirking, she named me not for beauty or for cleverness or for sweetness. She named me a thing I could aspire to but never become, the one thing I was not and could never be: Snow White.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was most certainly a book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take (the vague outline) the story of Snow White. Make it a Western. Things get weird.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lock In</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/lock-in/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/lock-in/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Making people change because you can’t deal with who they are isn’t how it’s supposed to be done. What needs to be done is for people to pull their heads out of their asses. You say ‘cure.’ I hear ‘you’re not human enough.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Been a bit since I last read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/old-mans-war/">any Scalzi&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;m glad to get back around to it though. Lock In is very good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, Lock In takes place in a near future Earth where a flu-like pandemic (Haden&amp;rsquo;s Syndrome) has caused &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/locked-in%20syndrome">locked-in syndrome&lt;/a> in some small percent of the world&amp;rsquo;s population (a small percent of billions is still an awful lot of people). Those affected are completely paralyzed, unable to move, while still being fully aware and conscious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily(ish) a massive global effort has figured out how to embed computer hardware in their brains so as to allow them to remotely pilot either robotic bodies (threeps&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>) or (more rarely) other humans who&amp;rsquo;ve allowed them access&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This of course is widely accepted by the rest of humanity and causes no issues whatsoever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Last Unicorn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/18/the-last-unicorn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/18/the-last-unicorn/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Haven’t you ever been in a fairy tale before?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s one of those books that just &lt;em>feels&lt;/em> like a fairy tale. An ageless story. A story passed down from long ago ages of myth and fantasy. Ages with heroes and villains and wizards and&amp;ndash;you guessed it&amp;ndash;unicorns.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dreamer's Pool</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/13/dreamers-pool/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/13/dreamers-pool/</guid><description>&lt;p>A solid book.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;There are three conditions you must agree to meet before I grant you this opportunity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Firstly, the considerable skill you possess must be used only for good. You will not let bitterness or anger draw you down the darker ways of your craft.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Secondly, if anyone asks for your help, you will give it willingly. I do not mean solely those who come to you for assistance with their ailments, but anyone at all who seeks your aid.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“And thirdly?” It occurred to me that I could be as good a liar as anyone. What was to stop me from agreeing now, and once I was out of here, doing whatever I pleased? I might yet live beyond dawn and see Mathuin brought down before nightfall. My heart began to race.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Thirdly, you will not seek vengeance. You will remain in Dalriada and stay away from Mathuin of Laois.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Take a bit of magic/folklore in an oldentimes Ireland; add in a Fae bargain (with all the complications that ensues); combine with a prince and princess who&amp;rsquo;ve never met outside of letters&amp;ndash;and seem entirely different in person; and finish it all off with fairy tale magic of Dreamer&amp;rsquo;s Pool.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>House of Suns</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/08/house-of-suns/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/08/house-of-suns/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Everything came and went, everything was new and bright with promise once and old and worn out later, and everything left a small, diminishing stain on eternity, a mark that time would eventually erase.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>House of Suns is what really great sci-fi tries to be: it takes some fascinating ideas (generally technological), sprinkles in interesting characters (although some authors seem to find that optional), and goes from there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Witch's Heart</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/23/the-witchs-heart/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/23/the-witchs-heart/</guid><description>&lt;p>It seems no matter the culture, myths and legends get weird. Norse mythology is &lt;em>absolutely&lt;/em> no exception to that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this story, we have a novelization of the story of Angrboda. Wife of Loki. Mother of monsters. She&amp;rsquo;s been around a while (it&amp;rsquo;s mythology, even she doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how long) and she just wants to be left alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like seeing a slightly more &amp;lsquo;raw&amp;rsquo; Norse mythology, especially than you get from (for example) the Marvel universe(s).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a bonkers story. You never know what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen. Being built on myths, the world is flexible at best. Rules are made to be broken. And that&amp;rsquo;s before you have gods et al with the ability to rewrite reality / see the future / move from world to world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed it. Worth a read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Space Between Worlds</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/18/the-space-between-worlds/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/18/the-space-between-worlds/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hopping between worlds&amp;ndash;with one big caveat. If you visit a world where another you is still alive, you die.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Why have I survived? Because I am a creature more devious than all the other mes put together. Because I saw myself bleeding out and instead of checking for a pulse, I began collecting her things. I survive the desert like a coyote survives, like all tricksters do.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating premise, especially when you dig just a bit deeper: Who are the people most likely able to jump? Who&amp;rsquo;s the most likely to have died on other worlds?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a story about privilege. About a world built for the rich and powerful&amp;ndash;by those who have nothing or less; those that pay everything and get nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Cara is stuck right in the middle of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Cartographers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/16/the-cartographers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/16/the-cartographers/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Cartography, at its heart, was about defining one&amp;rsquo;s place in the world by creating charts and measurements. Nell had lived her life by that idea, that everything could be mapped according to references and thereby understood. But she could see now that she had been paying attention to the wrong references.&lt;br>
It was not a map alone that made a place real.&lt;br>
It was the people.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a tricky one to review. It&amp;rsquo;ll take some minor spoilers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell (if you want to completely avoid spoilers), it&amp;rsquo;s a decent book with a fascinating premise that could have done so much more for the actual execution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zeroes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/12/zeroes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/12/zeroes/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Zeroes, not Heroes.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That was fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s the story of six American teenagers who discover they have superpowers. And fairly atypical ones too. A Voice that says exactly what needs to be said&amp;ndash;for better or for worse. Being immediately forgotten. Crashing electronics all around you. Controlling mobs. Leadership (somehow different from mobs). Seeing through others&amp;rsquo; eyes.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Maybe Flicker&amp;rsquo;s power made her think differently than most people. She saw the world from so many perspectives, and seeing was half of enlightenment.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Handmaid's Tale</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/the-handmaids-tale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/the-handmaids-tale/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nolite te bastardes carborundorum.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Take the extremist end of the American Protestant religious right. Give them everything they want (plus some) over the span of years (if not months).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Men have taken absolute power. In a world with (dramatically) declining birth rates, women are owned by the state. Their bodies are nothing more than a vessel for their wombs. They can&amp;rsquo;t travel alone, can&amp;rsquo;t be seen, can&amp;rsquo;t own property.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like any good story of this sort, it takes a potential problem&amp;ndash;an idea&amp;ndash;and turns it up to eleven. It goes steps further than anything we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in modern times&amp;ndash;or at least differently. The closest analogue I&amp;rsquo;m aware of is probably the events around the Iranian Revolution in 1979. By 1981, hijab were mandatory (there&amp;rsquo;s more to the history there; even before, hijab were seen as a method of protest against Westernization). Given this book was released in 1985, it seems&amp;hellip; potentially related.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; terrifying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the more so, for all those men (often in positions of power) that even today see it less as a cautionary tale and more something to aspire to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t let the bastards grind you down.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Girl, Serpent, Thorn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/07/girl-serpent-thorn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/07/girl-serpent-thorn/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Stories always begin the same way: There was and there was not. There is possibility in those words, the chance for hope or despair.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Take Persian mythology and worldbuilding, more than a touch of fairy tale feel, a cursed princess, demons, div (what in a Euro-centric story would be probably be fae), a touch of romance, and the spark of revolution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Under the Whispering Door</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/03/under-the-whispering-door/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/03/under-the-whispering-door/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The first time you share tea, you are a stranger.&lt;br>
The second time you share tea, you are an honored guest.&lt;br>
The third time you share tea, you become family.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; what do you call a slice of life story when the protagonist dies at the end of the first chapter?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whatever you do, &lt;em>Under the Whispering Door&lt;/em> is a delightful example thereof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wallace starts out a kind of terrible person.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The machine had broken down, and though no one was infallible, Wallace needed to switch out the part for a new one. He’d worked too hard to let it fail now. Last year had been the most profitable in the firm’s history. This year was shaping up to be even better. No matter what condition the world was in, someone always needed to be sued.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And then he dies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tress of the Emerald Sea</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take one part Princess Bride (a modern fairly tale for a grown up audience), one part Hoid as the narrator (even more Wit-like than in Stormlight), and add in weird world&amp;ndash;Sanderson style. It&amp;rsquo;s funny. It&amp;rsquo;s touching. And it&amp;rsquo;s a delight to read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Voilá. Tress of the Emerald Sea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a really good book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prodigal Son</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/prodigal-son/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/prodigal-son/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Knowledge is knowing that Frankenstein is not the monster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wisdom is knowing that Frankenstein is the monster.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A questionable phrase when applied to the original book. Full of hubris. A coward. Not really a &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; person, sure. But a monster?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, in Dean Koontz&amp;rsquo;s version&amp;hellip; yeah. Victor Frankenstein (now Victor Helios)&amp;ndash;totally the monster.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blindsight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/01/blindsight/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/01/blindsight/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vampires. In space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not at all what I expected, but at the same time, kind of awesome. I mean, look how it starts:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You wake in an agony of resurrection, gasping after a record-shattering bout of sleep apnea spanning one hundred forty days. You can feel your blood, syrupy with dobutamine and leuenkephalin, forcing its way through arteries shriveled by months on standby. The body inflates in painful increments: blood vessels dilate, flesh peels apart from flesh, ribs crack in your ears with sudden unaccustomed flexion. Your joints have seized up through disuse. You’re a stick man, frozen in some perverse rigor vitae.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vampires did this all the time, you remember. It was normal for them, it was their own unique take on resource conservation. They could have taught your kind a few things about restraint, if that absurd aversion to right angles hadn’t done them in at the dawn of civilization. Maybe they still can. They’re back now, after all—raised from the grave with the voodoo of paleogenetics, stitched together from junk genes and fossil marrow steeped in the blood of sociopaths and high-functioning autistics. One of them commands this very mission. A handful of his genes live on in your own body so it too can rise from the dead, here at the edge of interstellar space. Nobody gets past Jupiter without becoming part vampire.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is just a cool concept. The entire idea that vampires are real. The justification that they evolved torpor/hibernation to deal with not out-compenting and wiping out humanity. A natural aversion (leading to seizures) when viewing right angles (like&amp;hellip; crosses) that isn&amp;rsquo;t weeded out because nature doesn&amp;rsquo;t have many right angles. Super hardy, high processing, great for space travel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on top of that, we have virtual worlds, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_room" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Chinese room argument&lt;/a> (with an entire character base on it), normalization of multiple personalities, and all sorts of other interesting people and brains on the trip. Every single one of them is atypical in some way (or multiple ways) and digging into that is a large part of the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we haven&amp;rsquo;t even gotten to the aliens yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All in all, it&amp;rsquo;s a whole bunch of fascinating concepts all packed into a gloriously dense book. I could see any one of these carrying a novel, let alone all of them. The setting being deep space on (or beyond) the edge of the solar system makes everything claustrophobic, while the flashes of backstory give a bit of time to recover (and explain what in the world is going on with some of these characters).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed it. If any of the above intrigues you, give it a try. I will say though; warning: this is a weird book. Your milage may vary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Good Omens: The Nice and Accurate Prophecies of Agnes Nutter, Witch</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/good-omens-the-nice-and-accurate-prophecies-of-agnes-nutter-witch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/good-omens-the-nice-and-accurate-prophecies-of-agnes-nutter-witch/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Well,” said Crowley, who’d been thinking about this until his head ached, “haven’t you ever wondered about it all? You know—your people and my people, Heaven and Hell, good and evil, all that sort of thing? I mean, why?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“As I recall,” said the angel, stiffly, “there was the rebellion and—”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Ah, yes. And why did it happen, eh? I mean, it didn’t have to, did it?” said Crowley, a manic look in his eye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Anyone who could build a universe in six days isn’t going to let a little thing like that happen. Unless they want it to, of course.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Oh, come on. Be sensible,” said Aziraphale, doubtfully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“That’s not good advice,” said Crowley. “That’s not good advice at all. If you sit down and think about it sensibly, you come up with some very funny ideas. Like: why make people inquisitive, and then put some forbidden fruit where they can see it with a big neon finger flashing on and off saying THIS IS IT!?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The ANTICHRIST is born. ARMAGEDDON is coming! And all that stands in the way (for better /and/ for worse) is an angel/demon best friend combo who happen to /like/ living here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh it&amp;rsquo;s so good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve read quite a bit of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/terry-pratchett/">Terry Pratchett&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/neil-gaiman/">Neil Gaiman&lt;/a>, so reading a co-lab between them. Plus, I actually watched the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Good-Omens-Season-1/dp/B089XW1Z6Y" target="_blank" rel="noopener">show on Amazon&lt;/a> a while back, well before reading this book. From that order at least, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the particularly faithful and well done adaptations. Both being rather enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really can&amp;rsquo;t get Michael Sheet and David Tennant out of my head though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which is not a bad thing. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun ride, political/religious in exactly that fun somewhat blasphemous irreverent sort of way. I enjoy watching the ever increasing highjinks, as more plots get involved. The hundreds of years descendent of the one truly accurate prophetess. The Witch Finder Army&amp;ndash;somewhat reduced in manpower. The Four Horsemen&amp;ndash;and the dedicated deliveryman who sets them on their way. Plus the Other Four. And of course, the Antichrist himself. All these powers&amp;ndash;and no one ever taught him how to use them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun ride. You could do far worse than giving it a go!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Throne of Jade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Those men want to take Laurence from me, and put him in prison, and execute him, and I will not let them, ever, and I do not care if Laurence tells me not to squash you,&amp;quot; he added, fiercely, to Lord Barham.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Laurence and the British Government may think that Temeraire was won fairly under the articles of war&amp;hellip; but the Chinese aren&amp;rsquo;t so sure. In an effort to appease them, off Temeraire and Laurence go, halfway around the world to see if they can&amp;rsquo;t convince them otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a number of parts to really like about this book: Getting to travel the world is neat. The difference of Chinese culture, especially around dragons is fun. I like the idea of basically a Napoleonic era aircraft carrier for dragons. There are other related big beasties in the world as well!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The discussions about slavery, the differences in culture between the British and Chinese, and what that might mean for dragons were fascinating. Especially having read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/23/a-declaration-of-the-rights-of-magicians/">A Declaration of the Rights of Magicians&lt;/a> not &lt;em>that&lt;/em> long ago, it was interesting to see another take on the same period&amp;ndash;especially when we randomly get news that Pitt has died.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course, the aforequoted relationship between Temeraire and Laurence. That&amp;rsquo;s really a great part of the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a downside, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit less action packed than the first book. We get a couple of big fights, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, but it&amp;rsquo;s got a low slower pace. A bit jarring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Phoenix Extravagant</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/12/phoenix-extravagant/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/12/phoenix-extravagant/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Jebi was torn between saying &amp;lsquo;You are embarrassing me&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;I am going to take up my brush and make a painting of you that they will talk about for the next 10,000 years&amp;rsquo;. They said neither.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A world chock full of the history of China/Japan/China of a hundred years and change ago. Racism, colonialism, occupation, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A major take on artists during war. Both from the main character Gyen Jebi, an artist who fails to pass the examination for the Ministry of Art&amp;ndash;and ends up the perhaps much more interesting Ministry of Armor, making magical automata for the government. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating seeing a relatively common job turned extraordinary.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course, the mechanical dragon on the cover. Arazi. &lt;span class="spoiler">Who is also a philosopher and pacifist, because of course they are.&lt;/span>
. There&amp;rsquo;s always something fun about relatively non-human characters like that. Probably the coolest part of the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course of course, there&amp;rsquo;s love. The relationship between Jebi and their captors, Vei especially. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing the people who are perhaps all the more aware of the situation at hand and their relationships with the at times amusingly clueless Jebi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, an interesting book. I like the magic of the setting and the characters. The ending felt a little weird and weak, but it did wrap up well enough I suppose.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The studio also featured a large wall calendar with cryptic abbreviations, presumably reminders. Also doodles of gears, sprockets, and malformed genitalia, because artists were artists.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Infinite</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/the-infinite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/the-infinite/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that&amp;rsquo;s quite a conclusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You’re creating hell. And you’re putting yourself inside it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NEMESIS-1’s tone was serene. “Hell is the optimal solution.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-outside/">The Outside&lt;/a>, humanity found something Outside of the Gods&amp;rsquo; influence and managed to tear apart a large part of the world of Jai. In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/28/the-fallen/">The Fallen&lt;/a>, they learned to live with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/the-infinite/">The Infinite&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s time to learn more about the Gods themselves&amp;ndash;what they really are and how they came to be&amp;hellip; and perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s time for the Gods&amp;rsquo; reigns to end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating story and, in my opinion, perhaps the best of the trilogy. At once, we get answers for just what lead to the world that the characters live in now&amp;ndash;while at the same time opening so many more questions. What happened in the 700 years between the earliest and latest points of view in the book? What&amp;rsquo;s going on in the rest of the universe? And what happens next?!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But so far as this single story, it&amp;rsquo;s finished and well done. I always do applaud authors able to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>