<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Partials Sequence on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/partials-sequence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Partials Sequence on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/partials-sequence/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruins</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/ruins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/ruins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;17607716&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17607716.ruins&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/ruins.jpg&#34;&gt;
                &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solid ending to a solid series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think Ruins actually managed to pull things together in a way without feeling (too) rushed that none of the other YA series recently have managed to pull off. The previous plotlines (Kira&amp;rsquo;s conflicted nature, the rest of the Trust, the cure(s)) all come to a head in a way that&amp;rsquo;s still driving enough to finish the series but don&amp;rsquo;t feel like the author was just phoning it in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fragments</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/11/fragments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/11/fragments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;13170596&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13170596.fragments&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/fragments.jpg&#34;&gt;
                &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good continuation to Partials. In this book, we see Kira start to come to terms with who she is as she sets off with Samm and Heron across what&amp;rsquo;s left of the United States in search of answers&amp;ndash;only to find more than she was looking for. Meanwhile, Marcus is back home, stuck between two warring Partial factions, trying desperately to broker a piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a neat continuation. I like watching the world expand, exploring more of what happened in the decade and change since everything fell apart. We&amp;rsquo;re starting to get some answers, which of course lead to more questions. I look forward to Ruins, cautiously hoping that Wells can pull everything together for the finale.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolation</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/05/isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/05/isolation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;13645264&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13645264.isolation&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/isolation.jpg&#34;&gt;
                &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick and to the point, Isolation tells the story of Heron (who we met briefly in Partials) during the Isolation War. It gives a better picture into the Partials: how they are made, how they are trained, and why they might not only want to, but even been the right to, kill us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good story and I hope to see more of Heron in the second and third books of the Partials Sequence. It&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see how she&amp;rsquo;s grown and changed in the intervening years and how she interacts with the other human (and not) protagonists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Partials</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/partials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/partials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;12476820&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12476820.partials&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/partials.jpg&#34;&gt;
                &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of Partials takes place 11 years after humanity lost a terrible war. Basically, we created super soldiers (Partials) to fight for us. Of course, after they won the war they turned on us&amp;hellip; Worse yet, right at the same time, there was a virus which killed 99.96% of humanity&amp;ndash;including any new pregnancies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s where we start. Humanity is stuck on Long Island while the Partials are &lt;em&gt;out there&lt;/em&gt; ™. Because no babies can survive the virus, the youngest living people are 14. The main characters are roughly 16. Even stranger, in an effort to figure out how to cure the virus, the Hope Act has been enacted. All women 18 or older must get pregnant as often as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>