<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>George Lucas on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/george-lucas/</link><description>Recent content in George Lucas on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/george-lucas/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/">Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade&lt;/a> was such a good movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then they made another one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as I remembered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harrison Jones isn&amp;rsquo;t getting younger&amp;hellip; but he still really makes Indiana Jones. Full stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I bet they were expecting this film (and especially Shia LeBeouf&amp;rsquo;s Mutt) to go better and possibly pass the torch. It was an echo of the same dynamic as Indy and his father in The Last Crusade. Just not quite done as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was kind of fun to see the Soviets be the bad guys this time around and it more or less fits this new, older Indy.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Dean Charles Stanforth: I barely recognize this country anymore. The government&amp;rsquo;s got us seeing Communists in our soup. When the hysteria reaches academia, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to call it a career.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On top of that, seeing Karen Allen&amp;rsquo;s Marion Ravenwood again after all these years? And with the obvious fallout of that? That was more fun than I expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man. Cate Blanchett act the heck out of that role. But still, she just wasn&amp;rsquo;t as much a villain as previous films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;ndash;the action scenes. A bit more over the top than previous movies? Do you even &lt;em>remember&lt;/em> the roller coaster mine cart of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/">Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom&lt;/a>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed the opening in the warehouse. The nuclear bomb-fridge scene has been talked about to death. The motorcycle chase (through the library!) was a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Indiana Jones: You want to be a good archaeologist&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
[Mutt drives them out of the building on his motorcycle]&lt;br>
Indiana Jones: &amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ve got to get out of the library!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The jungle fight between the jeeps was pretty cool&amp;ndash;but the Tarzan bits? a bit much&amp;hellip; The temple was technically neat, even if it didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense. And the &lt;span class="spoiler">alien&lt;/span>
 finale wasn&amp;rsquo;t really that much weirder than centuries old knights and Nazi face melting artifacts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I think I&amp;rsquo;d place it above Temple of Doom, but below Raiders and the Last Crusade. A fun action flick and&amp;ndash;not as bad as I initially thought.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s my favorite of teh trilogy by a solid margin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s great! All the way from the introduction with a young Indy. The introduction of the whip. The hat. His love of snakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From there, we get a big world trotting mystery with some great action scenes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Are you crazy? Don&amp;rsquo;t go between them.&lt;br>
Go between them, are you crazy?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;big archeological puzzles&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But in the Latin alphabet, &amp;ldquo;Jehovah&amp;rdquo; begins with an &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;the dynamic between Indy and his father&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I suddenly remembered my Charlemagne. Let my armies be the rocks and the trees and the birds in the sky.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;Nazis&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I hate these guys.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;and a big supernatural finale.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He choose&amp;hellip; poorly.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Watch it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which of course means &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/">Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull&lt;/a> is up next&amp;hellip; hmm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="temple-of-doom">Temple of Doom&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Temple of Doom has some major middle film issues going on. Both &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/24/indiana-jones-and-the-raiders-of-the-lost-ark/">Raiders of the lost Ark&lt;/a> and The Last Crusade are far better films. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say Temple of Doom is bad, just lesser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Actionwise, there&amp;rsquo;s a ton. Gun fights, bailing out a plane, tons of bugs, several fights in a mine, and a giant drop? There is barely time to breathe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Real world ethicswise&amp;hellip; this is even worse than Raiders, which is saying something. There are a fair few &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; racist, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo; moments and a helping of &amp;ldquo;are they just evil for the sake of bring evil?&amp;rdquo; I suppose one can always go with the &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s an action movie, don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it&amp;rdquo; mindset.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Raiders of the Lost Ark</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/24/indiana-jones-and-the-raiders-of-the-lost-ark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/24/indiana-jones-and-the-raiders-of-the-lost-ark/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been a long time since I&amp;rsquo;ve watched these movies, but man do they actually hold up. From the moment the score first hits, through all the adventure and action scenes, right up to that face melting(ly awesome!) conclusion? There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of nostalgia, granted, but I still think it holds up even so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an introduction, we have it all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomb robbing!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Indiana needs his bullwhip to swing across a chasm]&lt;br>
Indiana: Give me the whip.&lt;br>
Satipo: Throw me the idol.&lt;br>
[they both see a stone door closing]&lt;br>
Satipo: No time to argue! Throw me the idol, I&amp;rsquo;ll throw you the whip!&lt;br>
Indiana: [throws the idol] Give me the whip!&lt;br>
Satipo: [drops the whip] Adiós, señor.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A fear of snakes!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Upon opening the Well of the Souls and peering down]&lt;br>
Sallah: Indy, why does the floor move?&lt;br>
Indiana: Give me your torch.&lt;br>
[Indy takes the torch and drops it in, revealing hundreds of snakes all over floor of the Well of Souls]&lt;br>
Indiana: Snakes. Why&amp;rsquo;d it have to be snakes?&lt;br>
Sallah: Asps&amp;hellip; very dangerous. You go first.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A mostly grounded world (if larger than life), before edging into the fantastical!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Indiana: The Ark of the Covenant, the chest that the Hebrews used to carry around the Ten Commandments.&lt;br>
Major Eaton: What, you mean &lt;em>the&lt;/em> Ten Commandments?&lt;br>
Indiana: Yes, the actual Ten Commandments, the original stone tablets that Moses brought down from Mt. Horeb and smashed, if you believe in that sort of thing&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
[the officers stare at him blankly]&lt;br>
Indiana: Didn&amp;rsquo;t any of you guys ever go to Sunday school?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Characterwise, Harrison Ford as Indiana Jones really makes the movie, but Karen Allens&amp;rsquo; Marion and John Rhys-Davies&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> are great supporting cast and man Ronald Lacey makes quite the villain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a pulpy adventure film. The plot is about as clearly good guys (even if Indy is totally looting) versus bad guys, loaded with some awesome action scenes along the way, and a solid ending where the good guys win. And sometimes, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a great fun movie. I&amp;rsquo;m going to rewatch them all now! (The original trilogy. I suppose I&amp;rsquo;ll have to watch the new ones too? We&amp;rsquo;ll see.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode IX - The Rise of Skywalker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/star-wars-episode-ix-the-rise-of-skywalker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/star-wars-episode-ix-the-rise-of-skywalker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Given the internet&amp;rsquo;s backlast, I exepcted a lot worse. At least to me, The Rise of Skywalker did a pretty decent job of closing the loop on the saga that began a long time ago with the rise of Palpatine and the fall of Anakin Skywalker. Really, that&amp;rsquo;s the entire story, and you get that here in spades.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were definitely some weird choices made in pacing (in particular, right at the beginning, they sort of drop the whole &amp;lsquo;Emperor is back&amp;rsquo; thing on us&amp;hellip; apparently the reveal came in &amp;hellip; Fortnite? Seriously?). We lose out on a lot of what could have been a cool story with Finn and Poe, although they&amp;rsquo;re still around at least. And I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine that losing Carrie Fisher did filming any favors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VIII - The Last Jedi</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/05/star-wars-episode-viii-the-last-jedi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/05/star-wars-episode-viii-the-last-jedi/</guid><description>&lt;p>More Star Wars! I remember being&amp;hellip; somewhat disappointed. Tonally, they got away from the nostalgia of the Force Awakens. There are still some absolutely beautiful/powerful moments (the final battles over the salt flats or whatever those were were pretty cool), but not quite as strong as it was before. And there are all sorts of things that just feel &amp;rsquo;less magical&amp;rsquo; and more movie driven than anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, I liked it a lot more. It still has some issues, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a solid enough Star Wars movie and (in my opinion) worth watching.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VII - The Force Awakens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/04/star-wars-episode-vii-the-force-awakens/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/04/star-wars-episode-vii-the-force-awakens/</guid><description>&lt;p>Woo, new Star Wars! I remember the hype when The Force Awakens first came out. It was pretty crazy to see new Star Wars for the first time (second time?) in years. And it&amp;rsquo;s pretty dang cool. It&amp;rsquo;s shinier than the original trilogy, a bit less stuck in the weeds (trade blockades!) than the prequels, and it leans &lt;em>hard&lt;/em> on nostalgia. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s Star Wars! Could they have done something newer and more unique? Sure they could have.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/19/star-wars-episode-vi-return-of-the-jedi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/19/star-wars-episode-vi-return-of-the-jedi/</guid><description>&lt;p>You know, that is a really solid movie. I know a lot of people prefer Empire, but for whatever reason, I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked Return of the Jedi more. That holds true even more, although I have to say that there are a few (possibly nostalgia fueled) particulars that I like more before the special editions changed things.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/11/star-wars-episode-v-the-empire-strikes-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/11/star-wars-episode-v-the-empire-strikes-back/</guid><description>&lt;p>Woo! Big icy battles on land in and the sky/space around Hoth, training with a real (short) Jedi Master (and they&amp;rsquo;re all supposed to be dead), meetings between old friends&amp;ndash;who may not be too thrilled about losing in cards all those years ago&amp;ndash;another confrontation between Luke and Vadar, and the big bad reveal. Which&amp;hellip; seriously. His name is literally &lt;span class="spoiler">Dark Father&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/17/star-wars-episode-iv-a-new-hope/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/17/star-wars-episode-iv-a-new-hope/</guid><description>&lt;p>There it is. A New Hope. The Star Wars I grew up on.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vLgsf8Pei6Q?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a great opening. The scale of the Star Destroyer, dumping us in on the &amp;rsquo;everyman&amp;rsquo; droids, and that Vadar scene. Spectacular.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode III - Revenge of the Sith</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/15/star-wars-episode-iii-revenge-of-the-sith/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/15/star-wars-episode-iii-revenge-of-the-sith/</guid><description>&lt;p>Revenge of the Sith is a somewhat fascinating story. It feels by far the darkest and most &amp;lsquo;adult&amp;rsquo; of the prequel trilogy, probably best matching the feel of A New Hope and Empire Strikes Back, but at the same time, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more humor in the early parts at least, with some truly weird and silly moments with R2 and the Battle Droids. You know&amp;hellip; I just don&amp;rsquo;t understand the droids. I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to that in a bit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode II - Attack of the Clones</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/07/star-wars-episode-ii-attack-of-the-clones/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/07/star-wars-episode-ii-attack-of-the-clones/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The things that I remember most about Attack of the Clones are the atmosphere of Kamino, the final battle on Genosis (mostly from the game Star Wars Battlefront), and some rather cringey burgeoning relationship dialog from Anakin and Padme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was not disappointed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode I - The Phantom Menace</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/29/star-wars-episode-i-the-phantom-menace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/29/star-wars-episode-i-the-phantom-menace/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, that opening score. The title crawl. That&amp;rsquo;s a blast of nostalgia right there. I&amp;rsquo;m too young to have seen the original trilogy in theaters, but I watched the VHS tapes what felt like a million times. When The Phantom Menace came out, that was &lt;em>right&lt;/em> in my wheelhouse. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how many times I saw that movie in theaters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And you know what? It&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as it&amp;rsquo;s often rated. Granted, if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t leaning so heavily on the rest of the Star Wars franchise, well&amp;hellip; it would probably be about that bad. But I disagree that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t disserve a place in the core &amp;lsquo;Skywalker Saga&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun action movie wrapped around the rise of dark powers and corruption in the guise of&amp;ndash;a trade war and senatorial discourse of all things. It&amp;rsquo;s weird, but I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to accept it at least?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Obi-Wan: You were right about one thing master. The negotiations were short.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s my favorite Star Wars movie so far&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and only a hint of things to come!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>