<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brent Weeks on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brent-weeks/</link><description>Recent content in Brent Weeks on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brent-weeks/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Blood Mirror</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/02/the-blood-mirror/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/02/the-blood-mirror/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Look at your mistakes long enough to learn from them, then put them behind you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On one hand, takes the storyline of the previous books and turns it up even more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Broken Eye</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/19/the-broken-eye/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/19/the-broken-eye/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Magic was useful for everything. It just killed you. You should always think of it first. Then you should decide if a little dram of death was worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Just whoa. This book got big. We see a lot more about the world and more about the powers that exist beneath the surface. The world is weird and complicated and everything we thought we knew&amp;hellip; well, i9t&amp;rsquo;s mostly right. Just incomplete.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Blinding Knife</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/29/the-blinding-knife/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/29/the-blinding-knife/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Blinding Knife is what a sequel should be. It takes the action and magic that made good and made it better while toning down a lot of the exposition and over-characterization that made it a bit of a drag at times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, the magic system has a lot more depth than it did in the first book while at the same time not spending quite as much time hitting us over the head with terms we don&amp;rsquo;t quite understand yet. Even if I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily like some of the choices (like why you can&amp;rsquo;t draft green from white light by default), it&amp;rsquo;s still a well done system. Otherwise, the worldbuilding has gotten bigger. Magical trading cards. Seers. Old Gods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Black Prism</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/28/the-black-prism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/28/the-black-prism/</guid><description>&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know that was a series until I&amp;rsquo;d finished &lt;a data-goodreads-type="author" data-goodreads-id="1370283" href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1370283.brent-weeks"> Brent Weeks &lt;/a> other series ( et al) and it came up in &amp;lsquo;related works&amp;rsquo;. Reading the summary, I almost wish I&amp;rsquo;d read them the other way around. Lightbringer seems like more of a traditional epic fantasy (albeit with an interesting magic system, see below) rather than the unrelenting grimdarkness that was The Night Angel books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that I&amp;rsquo;ve really been liking about this series thus far is the world building. In particular the magic system. The basic idea is that drafters (magic users) can take light of certain colors&amp;ndash;each person has different ranges&amp;ndash;and use those colors to do various things. Like you can make a napalm like substance out of red or a solid, smooth surface out of blue. On the down side, drafting too much of a color will eventually drive you mad&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. If I knew more about the actual physics of light, I imagine I&amp;rsquo;d be more annoyed at the technical details, but as it stands, I know just enough to think it&amp;rsquo;s a really cool idea.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beyond the Shadows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/12/beyond-the-shadows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/12/beyond-the-shadows/</guid><description>&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s over. It&amp;rsquo;s a solid series with a lot of interesting world building that kept me turning pages right up to the end and managed to wrap up a surprising number of plotlines up into a huge final battle. If that&amp;rsquo;s all you&amp;rsquo;re looking for and you&amp;rsquo;ve already read the first two books, go ahead and read this one. It&amp;rsquo;s the first two books, only bigger.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, I still don&amp;rsquo;t like Kylar. He&amp;rsquo;s too powerful almost without ill effect (other than the cost that finally gets revealed for coming back from the dead; that was a well deserved punch to the gut).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shadow's Edge</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/23/shadows-edge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/23/shadows-edge/</guid><description>&lt;p>Taken as a whole, Shadow&amp;rsquo;s Edge takes everything (the good and the bad) of the first Night Angel book and cranks it up even further. On the plus side, the good becomes even better. It was hard to put this book down. On the down side, a lot of the first part of the book where Kylar tries to run from his powers and live a normal life is honestly fairly boring. Luckily it picks back up and really goes crazy by the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are storylines all over the place. The all manage to tie together more or less, so I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly mind, but there are a few that I feel probably could have been cut to make a tighter story. Kylar&amp;rsquo;s story is interesting, obviously enough, as is that of Vi and the Godking. Sister Ariel&amp;rsquo;s story I feel could actually carry a story of its own and directly relates to the others. Logan&amp;rsquo;s time in the Hole is fascinating, but seemed to drag on forever (which I guess could have been intentional). But the storyline about the prostitute&amp;rsquo;s rebellion? All that about the Ubersword of DESTINY? I trust that eventually they&amp;rsquo;ll pay off. But within the context of this single story, the feel weird.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Way of Shadows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/05/18/the-way-of-shadows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/05/18/the-way-of-shadows/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well. That was a book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, you&amp;rsquo;re sort of tossed into the world and it takes rather a while to really figure out what was going on. For that matter, I still have a handful of questions on exactly how this world works, although I guess that&amp;rsquo;s what sequels are for.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>