<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2023 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2023-tv-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2023 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 23:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2023-tv-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Rings of Power: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/14/the-rings-of-power-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/14/the-rings-of-power-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too many storylines in this show. For episodes at a time, we may not see elves. Or dwarves. Or Gandalf-but-still-not-Gandalf. I keep getting to the start of an episode and thinking &amp;lsquo;oh hey, we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen them in a while&amp;rsquo;. But the interesting thing is that I got to the end of the episodes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s what we saw in the first season, but even more so. There are so many different threads and events&amp;ndash;things separated by decades if not centuries in the original works all crammed together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But on the other hand, we get more rings! (Up from zero &amp;#x1f604;) We get bigger battles! (Not quite Helm&amp;rsquo;s Deep, but close) More Tom Bombadil! (You&amp;rsquo;ll just have to watch to see if you think I&amp;rsquo;m making that one up) And we get more &amp;hellip; humanized orcs with families and children? I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;hellip; not entirely sure what to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall&amp;hellip; it mostly reminds me just &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; the Peter Jackson movies were. But it&amp;rsquo;s certainly watchable and I&amp;rsquo;ll catch whatever season(s) come next. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2023 Year in Reviews</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/31/2023-year-in-reviews/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/31/2023-year-in-reviews/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so another year passes. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing these for quite a while now &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="ranking"&gt;
 &lt;h3 class="title"&gt;Posts in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/series/year-in-reviews/"&gt;Year in Reviews&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/h3&gt;
 &lt;div class="content"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/31/2025-year-in-reviews/"&gt;
 2025 Year in Reviews
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/31/2024-year-in-reviews/"&gt;
 2024 Year in Reviews
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/31/2023-year-in-reviews/"&gt;
 2023 Year in Reviews
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/31/2022-year-in-reviews/"&gt;
 2022 Year in Reviews
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-tv-movies-retrospective/"&gt;
 2021 TV &amp;amp; Movies Retrospective
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-reading-retrospective/"&gt;
 2021 Reading Retrospective
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/31/2020-reading-retrospective/"&gt;
 2020 Reading Retrospective
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/31/2019-reading-list-retrospective/"&gt;
 2019 Reading List Retrospective
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/31/2018-reading-list-retrospective/"&gt;
 2018 Reading List Retrospective
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/31/2017-reading-list-retrospective/"&gt;
 2017 Reading List Retrospective
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/31/2016-reading-list-retrospective/"&gt;
 2016 Reading List Retrospective
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/2015-reading-list-retrospective/"&gt;
 2015 Reading List Retrospective
 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;so I think perhaps you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All together, I love collecting data and I find it interesting to take a moment to look through what all I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the year. And hopefully&amp;ndash;you find it interesting as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s been quite a year for reviews! This year I&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#books"&gt;Read 298 books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tv"&gt;Watch 17 seasons of TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#movies"&gt;Watched 11 movies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#board-games"&gt;Played 212 different (86 new) board games a total of 1521 times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#steam-games"&gt;Played 47 games on steam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so silly to see some stats like that. I love it. So let&amp;rsquo;s break it down a bit more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents"&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents"&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#table-of-contents"&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#books"&gt;Books&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#statistics"&gt;Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#personal-favorites"&gt;Personal Favorites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#full-list"&gt;Full list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tv"&gt;TV&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#full-list-1"&gt;Full list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#movies"&gt;Movies&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#full-list-ranked"&gt;Full list (ranked)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#board-games"&gt;Board Games&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#a-few-favorites"&gt;A few favorites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#steam-games"&gt;Steam Games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 11</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/22/taskmaster-series-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/22/taskmaster-series-11/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Catching up / almost back to watching these in order! I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;d watched this season before, but not reviewed it, so here you go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charlotte Ritchie - She feels so out of her depth, always trying to keep things light and innocent. Bit of a running joke how she&amp;rsquo;d best fit a children&amp;rsquo;s show. She almost came close to not being &lt;em&gt;completely destroyed&lt;/em&gt; in the final scoring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jamali Maddix - The rule breaker of the episode. I love how he approaches tasks. And it usually works, which isn&amp;rsquo;t always the case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lee Mack - Quite often misses things, but gets along the best with Greg Davis I think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mike Wozniak - The absolute star of the season. He just goes all in on whatever task you give him. And that final prize task of the series&amp;hellip; all of the hats off to you good sir.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarah Kendall - So very Australian (based on knowing very few Australians in real life). Quite a delight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good crowd. Sad to see them (especially Mike Wozniak) go.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 10</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/29/taskmaster-series-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/29/taskmaster-series-10/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m so not watching these in order. But they&amp;rsquo;re back on YouTube in the US! So let&amp;rsquo;s catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fun season. We have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daisy Mae Cooper: So pregnant. And quite often unfiltered, which is a lot of fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Johnny Vegas: You just &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; everything to go right for the guy&amp;hellip; and it so often does not. My favorite this time around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Katherine Parkinson: Impressively bad about missing parts of tasks. Felt bad for her, but didn&amp;rsquo;t want to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Herring: Dry humor and weirdly competent at the tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mawaan Rizwan: The one that tries to break everything. And gives Greg Davis so many &amp;lsquo;you did &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; now&amp;rsquo; moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good season.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Black Mirror: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/black-mirror-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/black-mirror-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Been meaning to watch this for years. Finally got around to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting; especially for only have three episodes in the first season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#1-the-national-anthem"&gt;The first episode&lt;/a&gt; is kind of weird and by far the least &amp;lsquo;sci-fi&amp;rsquo; of the bunch&amp;ndash;this could happen now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#2-fifteen-million-merits"&gt;The second&lt;/a&gt; though starts out as fairly straight forward near future dystopia and then goes &lt;em&gt;dark&lt;/em&gt; from there. I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href="#3-the-entire-history-of-you"&gt;the third&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;take a concept (recording everything), apply the concept to imperfect (honestly fairly terrible) people and see what breaks. It&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to season 2!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Loki: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/12/loki-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/12/loki-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Another year, another Loki. I really enjoyed &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/"&gt;Season 1&lt;/a&gt;. No idea if they could top it. And I&amp;rsquo;m still not 100% sure if they made it better, but they most certainly made it weirder. And I&amp;rsquo;m here for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cast is great of course, with Tom Hiddleston&amp;rsquo;s Loki carrying the show. I really did quite enjoy Jonathan Majors&amp;rsquo; new double role as He Who Remains but also now as Victor Timely. That&amp;rsquo;s most certainly something&amp;ndash;and makes me wonder if they can/could have actually pulled it all off, depending on if Majors sticks around in the MCU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in &lt;a href="#6-glorious-purpose"&gt;the last episode review below&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s a crazy show, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like about it. It could really change everything&amp;hellip; but I have the unfortunate feeling they&amp;rsquo;re not going to let it. We shall have to see!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Boys: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/05/the-boys-season-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/05/the-boys-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Things just keep getting more bonkers and bloody. Really, if you made it this far, you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to love Season 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Boys are (still) out to deal with Homelander&amp;hellip; and they may just have found the weapon to do it. Only this time the solution is perhaps eve more expensive than the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homelander is really the (wonderful terrible) heart of the show. Anthony Starr is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a few new supes running around (in secret). And all sorts of ones we knew about doing even more terrible and deprived things in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And in the end, the more things change, the more things stay the same. But worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Season 4. It&amp;rsquo;s weird to be caught up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Secret Invasion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/secret-invasion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/secret-invasion/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s fine. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see some spy stories in the MCU, even if they&amp;rsquo;re light on the spy stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have Fury again, even if (in hindsight) I was perfectly fine without knowing more about Fury&amp;rsquo;s backstory. And the introduction of Super Skrulls? Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really need that in the MCU. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fan of it in either of the previous story lines I&amp;rsquo;ve read them in (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/13/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-6-frightful/"&gt;Ultimate Fantastic Four&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/04/runaways-vol.-8-dead-end-kids/"&gt;Runaways&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you know what I really think bothers me about the Skrull? All through the Infinity Saga, we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to believe they&amp;rsquo;ve been here, working with Fury. And we never heard even a hint about them. I get it. They’re shapeshifters. The perfect secret agents. Still weird to add something like this after 15 years&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it had been something tied into each movie and show, leading up to an event (like the Infinity Saga), it could have worked. As it is, it really feels like the concept of an MCU is working against them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Boys: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/the-boys-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/the-boys-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Managed to get away for a bit since [[The Boys: Season 1|season 1]]; sometimes life happens (but not for everyone in the Boys&amp;hellip;). But I finally made it through season 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man this is a violent bloody show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still quite the exploration for &amp;lsquo;what if superheroes were real&amp;hellip; and terrible&amp;rsquo; that really draws you in, but now with more terrible corporations. And Nazis. Because of course we had to go there. It actually works really well, the conflict of benefiting from Nazi science is a &lt;em&gt;big deal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still really enjoy (in a twisted way) how terrifying Antony Starr plays Homelander. If he goes off the rails, what &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; are you going to do to stop him?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus show Hughie (really all of the &amp;rsquo;the Boys&amp;rsquo;) is far better than his comic counterpart. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see him well out of his comfort zone, both in relationships (especially with Starlight) and all the madcap shenanigans Butcher&amp;rsquo;s gang gets up to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plotwise, mostly Nazis, but Compound V not only getting revealed the the characters, but also going public? We haven&amp;rsquo;t nearly seen the ramifications of that. Hoping to see more of &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; in Season 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, great show. Very much deserves the R rating. Onward.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Wheel of Time: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/09/the-wheel-of-time-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/09/the-wheel-of-time-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wheel of Time turns, and ages come and pass, leaving memories that become legend. Legend fades to myth, and even myth is long forgotten when the Age that gave it birth comes again. In one Age, called the Third Age by some, an Age yet to come, an Age long past, a wind rose in the Mountains of Mist. The wind was not the beginning. There are neither beginnings nor endings to the turning of the Wheel of time. But it was a beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/"&gt;The Wheel of Time: Season 1&lt;/a&gt; had a lot of potential&amp;hellip; and also a lot of issues. Especially when it came to the last couple episodes. COVID, sure. A main actor leaving, I get it. But it&amp;rsquo;s still a rough ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it was with cautious optimism, we approached Season 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very much a new turning of the wheel. Some things they changed really do work well. It&amp;rsquo;s not the books, but it&amp;rsquo;s a new story in the same world. Some&amp;hellip; less so. But not everything is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I loved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The casting. Ishamael was great in Season 1 and even better in Season 2. Lanfear is a great counter to him. Aviendha and Elayne fit really well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It bears repeating: Ishamael and Lanfear are great. Leaning a bit more into terrifying even than the books, which quite frankly they needed. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see (and hope they don&amp;rsquo;t screw up&amp;hellip;) the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Almost&lt;/em&gt; everything about the Seanchan. They feel &amp;lsquo;off&amp;rsquo; in just the right way. The one exception&amp;hellip; the Damane pacifiers. I really don&amp;rsquo;t get that &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liandrin. She&amp;rsquo;s still terrible, but I really like how they turned up the &lt;em&gt;reason&lt;/em&gt; why she is as she is. And she&amp;rsquo;s quite the actor to pull it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things that I did not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ending. Check out the &lt;a href="#8-what-was-meant-to-be"&gt;individual review&lt;/a&gt; for more details, but &amp;hellip; this wasn&amp;rsquo;t any better than the previous season. And they don&amp;rsquo;t even have unexpected troubles to deal with. I&amp;rsquo;m starting to feel they really just don&amp;rsquo;t know how to write endings&amp;hellip; which is weird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, other than a few things, I quite enjoyed it. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Season 3. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/25/downton-abbey-season-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/25/downton-abbey-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so it ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downton Abbey Season 6 is a strange beast. On one hand, we have what feels all the cast pairing off, sometimes with long known relationships and in the cast of the Family with guys we only met in the previous season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; do not really understand the relationship between Mary and Henry. I think it&amp;rsquo;s mostly Mary. She certainly ebbs and flows&amp;hellip; but wow she&amp;rsquo;s a (sorry, but Edith says it too) bitch at times. On the other hand, Edith and Bertie? Delightful. If expected for the chaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, the world is moving on. Is Downton Abbey going to survive? With reductions in expected staff and families around the world failing, it&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with all those relationships &lt;em&gt;wow&lt;/em&gt; do the last few episodes blitz through what feels like every plotline possible in only a few hours. I do wonder if they thought they&amp;rsquo;d have a 7th season. But so it goes. For the most part, everything is tied off neatly. And for everything else&amp;hellip; apparently there are two movies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a final note, if you&amp;rsquo;ve been lamenting the torture the writers have put the Bates&amp;rsquo; through over the year&amp;hellip; well, they&amp;rsquo;re not quite done. But there is light at the end of the tunnel, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I quite enjoyed it. Much more than I expected to, as I seem to say with all non-SF/F shows I end up watching. Still not something I would have chosen, still quite enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wednesday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/25/wednesday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/25/wednesday/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh that&amp;rsquo;s a delight of a show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re creepy and they&amp;rsquo;re kooky&lt;br&gt;
Mysterious and spooky&lt;br&gt;
They&amp;rsquo;re all together ooky&lt;br&gt;
The Addams family&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An entire show with the dark worldbuilding and humor of the Addams family, focusing around Wednesday (my favorite)? Yes please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="#casting"&gt;casting&lt;/a&gt; is great&amp;ndash;especially Jenna Ortega as the lead and Emma Myers as Enid. A delightful pairing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mystery vibe is on point (and it&amp;rsquo;s right up to the end before you know &lt;em&gt;for sure&lt;/em&gt; who the baddies are).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The setting is fun&amp;ndash;even if the &amp;lsquo;outcasts&amp;rsquo; of Nevermore seem curiously non-magical a lot of the times. And then in the big final numbers, we go full on magic&amp;ndash;which also felt surprisingly weird for the Addams family. ut it works well enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to season 2.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/13/downton-abbey-season-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/13/downton-abbey-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh goodness. Another season down and only one more to go (plus some movies?). I&amp;rsquo;m not ready!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one has a few primarily focuses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary and her men&amp;hellip; weird. I kind of liked both of them, but so it goes. Hints at what&amp;rsquo;s to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isobel and Violet (of all people) getting romantically entangled. That I did not expect, much less with who. It&amp;rsquo;s fun, if sad at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rose, speedrunning the relationship thing, all with yet another new family for people to disapprove of. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that her dating a black man went so poorly, yet this ends up much better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course the Bates. Oh the Bates. I truly wish that Season 6 could be quiet and happy for them&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m not holding up too much hope for that one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, yet another solid season. Like I said, I&amp;rsquo;m not ready for the end! But all good things must. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Orville: New Horizons (Season 3)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/the-orville-new-horizons-season-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/the-orville-new-horizons-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;3 year time jump!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, there&amp;rsquo;s so much going on in this season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both large (Kaylon! Moclan! Krill! new friends and foes alike!) and small (so many relationships! new crew and old!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see how much this show has grown and changed. I just about bounced off the first few episodes, back when it was leaning hard into the humor and less into the sci-fi. But now&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see both the funny and the serious takes on all sorts of issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A delightful third season. If/when we get a Season 4, I&amp;rsquo;ll most certainly have to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/08/downton-abbey-season-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/08/downton-abbey-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oy. After all the death and craziness of Season 3 (especially that finale&amp;hellip;), the family is all off kilter now. It takes a bit to settle, and then of course we&amp;rsquo;re on for all the more trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rose brings a touch of chaos Sybil never could. I&amp;rsquo;m glad they didn&amp;rsquo;t clone her. Rose is fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, Anna and Bates just don&amp;rsquo;t get an easy life, do they&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom is in such a weird situation&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m liking his role as a sort of inbetween, of both worlds and neither. Working with Mary too. I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;hellip; curious where it goes next though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Werewolf by Night</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/05/werewolf-by-night/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/05/werewolf-by-night/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I managed to skip by this last fall, much to my now dismay. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;ndash;only sort of an MCU special; focused on the monster/&amp;lsquo;horror&amp;rsquo; side of Marvel comics rather than the super-hero business. They do open with a sillouette of the heroes we know and love&amp;hellip; before all color drains out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What comes next? An introduction to a monster hunting family/society and a competition to win the mysterious &amp;lsquo;Bloodstone&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;which gives you a sort of power over/against monsters. And then&amp;ndash;the HUNT/BATTLE ROYALE!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Orville: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/22/the-orville-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/22/the-orville-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And another season! Got away from it for a while, but it&amp;rsquo;s finally done. I&amp;rsquo;m glad they&amp;rsquo;ve managed to stay away from pure comedy and stick to a scifi show that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; funny. It&amp;rsquo;s much better that way in my opinion&amp;ndash;even if we do get some &lt;em&gt;pretty ridiculous&lt;/em&gt; bits. &lt;em&gt;The Great Release&lt;/em&gt;. I rest my case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, we get a lot more to shake up the status quo. The Moclans and their all male* society take a front seat, but we also have quite the story line for Isaac and his people, more Krill, digging into how real simulations can feel, and so much more. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the third (and final?) season!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/09/downton-abbey-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/09/downton-abbey-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, now that&amp;rsquo;s a season. It starts with a marriage, imprisonment, and money problems and only gets crazier from there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;Death&lt;/span&gt;
 is a theme as well, not once but twice. I get that sometimes &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;actors move on&lt;/span&gt;
, but they really did &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;Matthew&lt;/span&gt;
 dirty with that one&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall another solid season and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to what happens now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per episode reviews. Potential spoilers for the season as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents"&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-31"&gt;Episode #3.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-32"&gt;Episode #3.2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-33"&gt;Episode #3.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-34"&gt;Episode #3.4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-35"&gt;Episode #3.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-36"&gt;Episode #3.6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-37"&gt;Episode #3.7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-38"&gt;Episode #3.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#a-journey-to-the-highlands"&gt;A Journey to the Highlands&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;h2 id="episode-31"&gt;Episode #3.1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re finally getting married!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/07/downton-abbey-season-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/07/downton-abbey-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The season with World War I. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of changes, from war wounds to deaths to Downton becoming a temporary hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating getting to know all these stories. Oh I wish the best for them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Per episode reviews. Potential spoilers for the season as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents"&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-21"&gt;Episode 2.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-22"&gt;Episode 2.2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-23"&gt;Episode 2.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-24"&gt;Episode 2.4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-25"&gt;Episode 2.5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-26"&gt;Episode 2.6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-27"&gt;Episode 2.7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#episode-28"&gt;Episode 2.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#christmas-at-downton-abbey"&gt;Christmas at Downton Abbey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;

&lt;h2 id="episode-21"&gt;Episode 2.1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so&amp;hellip; war. Brutal away and at home for those that go, those that don&amp;rsquo;t, and those that can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/downton-abbey-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/downton-abbey-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Somehow I&amp;rsquo;m always surprised when a highly rated show is actually good. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a modern, American, middle-class point of view, the idea of the early 1900s British Aristocracy is just so strange. They do next nothing (useful) and have an entire staff to support it. The entire estate could go to a cousin they&amp;rsquo;d never met and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing they can do about it &amp;hellip; is so strange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s oddly charming?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Grantham&amp;rsquo;s are fascinating. Sybil seems good people, Edith is certainly going to figure out how to come into her own, Mary is spoiled and needlessly cruel&amp;ndash;but may be learning. Lord and Lady Grantham are fun, if somewhat alien&amp;ndash;and I do love watching Lord Grantham try and completely fail to wrangle three young adult daughters. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shining jewel of the family Dame Maggie Smith&amp;rsquo;s Dowager Countess of Grantham. Oh she&amp;rsquo;s just wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the staff, you have a whole &amp;rsquo;nother level of politics. They&amp;rsquo;re all great and terrible (as they should be) and there are every bit as many problems and politics as there are among the &amp;lsquo;family&amp;rsquo;. Turns out people are people no matter how much money they have or do not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man that&amp;rsquo;s a crazy amount to fit into seven episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward&amp;hellip; to war!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Rings of Power: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/the-rings-of-power-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/the-rings-of-power-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that’s quite the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They couldn’t/didn’t get the rights to the third age, so instead we get much older stories. Stories after the fall of Morgoth but still during the end of the era of Elves and Númenor. Before the rise of the kingdoms of Men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot crammed into eight episodes. One might argue too much. Leaves some stories a bit thin. But really, having seen them, I don’t know what I’d cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worth a watch. Looking forward to season two!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Little Drummer Boy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/08/the-little-drummer-boy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/08/the-little-drummer-boy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s cute. A fun art style that really fits these videos, it&amp;rsquo;s something I watched each year when I was younger. Great to see once again. And it&amp;rsquo;s not any more out of date than it was before then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to realize that the song only came about in the 40s and this was only made into a movie in the 60s. Especially since that means that for such a well know &amp;lsquo;Christmas&amp;rsquo; story, it&amp;rsquo;s really got very little backend religiously.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>