<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2013 00:00:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/research/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>USENIX 2013 - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/17/usenix-2013---day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2013 00:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/17/usenix-2013---day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s the third and final day. Since I had to fly out in the afternoon, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to go to as many talks today, but so it goes. There was really interesting talk that I&amp;rsquo;m sad to have missed (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity13/dismantling-megamos-crypto-wirelessly-lockpicking-vehicle-immobilizer&#34;&gt;Dismantling Megamos Crypto: Wirelessly Lockpicking a Vehicle Immobilizer&lt;/a&gt;) but it&amp;rsquo;ll be nice to be home. Here are the talks that I did make it to and found particularly interesting though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USENIX 2013 - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/16/usenix-2013---day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 00:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/16/usenix-2013---day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day &lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;s really not much more to say, so how about getting right to the interesting talks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USENIX 2013 - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/15/usenix-2013---day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 00:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/15/usenix-2013---day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps unsurprisingly, there were fewer papers today that I was particularly interested&amp;ndash;given that FOCI is directly related to my area of research. Still, computer security is a very useful field and one that I&amp;rsquo;m keen to learn more about. I only went to two of the sessions today (it&amp;rsquo;s always unfortunate when they run two interesting sessions at the same time) and here are some of the talks I found particularly interesting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOCI 2013</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/14/foci-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/14/foci-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/13/usenix/foci-2013---five-incidents-one-theme--twitter-spam-as-a-weapon-to-drown-voices-of-protest/&#34;&gt;Five incidents, one theme&lt;/a&gt;. Here are a few short summaries of the other papers that are particularly related to my own interests:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usenix/FOCI 2013 - Five incidents, one theme:  Twitter spam as a weapon to drown voices of protest</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/13/usenix/foci-2013---five-incidents-one-theme--twitter-spam-as-a-weapon-to-drown-voices-of-protest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/08/13/usenix/foci-2013---five-incidents-one-theme--twitter-spam-as-a-weapon-to-drown-voices-of-protest/</guid>
      <description>Another year, another Usenix Security Symposium. Like last year, I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting a paper at FOCI0 entitled: Five incidents, one theme: Twitter spam as a weapon to drown voices of protest:
 Social networking sites, such as Twitter and Facebook, have become an impressive force in the modern world with user bases larger than many individual countries. With such influence, they have become important in the process of worldwide politics. Those seeking to be elected often use social networking accounts to promote their agendas while those opposing them may seek to either counter those views or drown them in a sea of noise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISMA 2013 AIMS-5 - DNS Based Censorship</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/09/isma-2013-aims-5---dns-based-censorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/09/isma-2013-aims-5---dns-based-censorship/</guid>
      <description>I gave a presentation about research that I&amp;rsquo;m just starting out studying DNS-based censorship in specific around the world. In particularly, preliminary findings in China have confirmed that the Great Firewall is responding via packet injection to many queries for either Facebook or Twitter (among others). Interestingly, the pool of IPs that they return is consistent yet none of the IPs seem to resolve to anything interesting. In addition, there is fallout in South Korea where some percentage of packets go through China and thus have the same behaviors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIMS-5 - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/09/aims-5---day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 14:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/09/aims-5---day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the third and final day of AIMS-5. With the main topic being &lt;em&gt;Detection of Censorship, Filtering, and Outages&lt;/em&gt;, many of these talks were much more in line with what I know and what I&amp;rsquo;m working on. I gave my presentation as well, you can see it (along with a link to my slides) down below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIMS-5 - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/08/aims-5---day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 14:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/08/aims-5---day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s agenda had discussions on Mobile Measurements and IPv6 Annotations, none of which are areas that I find myself particularly interested in. Still, I did learn a few things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AIMS-5 - Workshop on Active Internet Measurements</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/07/aims-5---workshop-on-active-internet-measurements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 14:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/07/aims-5---workshop-on-active-internet-measurements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was the first of three days for the fifth annual &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/22/isc/caida-workshop/&#34;&gt;ISC/CAIDA Workshop&lt;/a&gt; I went to in Baltimore back in October at least, but even the ones that weren&amp;rsquo;t have still been interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting on Friday and I&amp;rsquo;ll share my slides when I get that far (they aren&amp;rsquo;t actually finished yet). I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about new work that I&amp;rsquo;m just getting off the ground focusing specifically on DNS-based censorship. There is a lot of interesting ground to cover there and this should be only the first in a series of updates about that work (I hope).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scanning for DNS resolvers</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/31/scanning-for-dns-resolvers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/31/scanning-for-dns-resolvers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a research project I&amp;rsquo;m working on, it has become necessary to scan potentially large &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cidr&#34;&gt;IPv4 prefixes&lt;/a&gt; in order to find any &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNS%20resolver&#34;&gt;DNS revolvers&lt;/a&gt; that I can and classify them as either open (accepting queries from anyone) or closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: This is a form of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/port%20scanning&#34;&gt;port scanning&lt;/a&gt; and thus has associated ethical and legal considerations. Use it at your own risk. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is available on GitHub: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jpverkamp/dnsscan&#34; title=&#34;GitHub: jpverkamp: dnsscan&#34;&gt;jpverkamp/dnsscan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>