<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Quantum Evolution on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-quantum-evolution/</link><description>Recent content in The Quantum Evolution on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-quantum-evolution/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Quantum War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/20/the-quantum-war/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/20/the-quantum-war/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/14/the-quantum-magician/"&gt;The Quantum Magician&lt;/a&gt;, Bel pulled off the ultimate heist and changed everything. In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/17/the-quantum-garden/"&gt;The Quantum Garden&lt;/a&gt;, we got a sort of sequel-prequel, that sort of kind of answered how that all came to be (time travel is weird). Finally now, in The Quantum Evolution, we&amp;rsquo;re starting to get some of the effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that by showing off his Quantum MAGIC!(tm), Bel has brought quite a lot more attention than he ever intended to Homo Quantus. And now everone wants a piece of him and his.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The characters still drive teh book. Bel and Cass remain Bel and Cas. Stills remains delightfully crass. I was delighted to see Marie again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then&amp;hellip; the Puppets. That&amp;rsquo;s quite the weird, uncomfortable part of these books and it&amp;rsquo;s even more to the fore in this one. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; probably worth something to have read it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is the last book, it&amp;rsquo;s a weird one. There&amp;rsquo;s a big epic conclusion, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel completely earned. The stakes are higher than ever, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel particularly &amp;rsquo;new&amp;rsquo; this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the first book is the best. The next two are worth reading. And I would probably read a fourth. But for now&amp;hellip; onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Quantum Garden</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/17/the-quantum-garden/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/17/the-quantum-garden/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/14/the-quantum-magician/"&gt;The Quantum Magician&lt;/a&gt; was a wonderful bit of scifi worldbuilding and technology wrapped around a heist novel. Future tech harnessing time travel and the forces driving the inflation of the universe and you have to sneak it right through a wormhole and maybe steal it all on the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no &lt;em&gt;idea&lt;/em&gt; how to top that&amp;hellip; but was curious to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out&amp;hellip; time travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a risky choice. Time travel at a small scale can be a lot of fun. It helps you pull off heists after all. And yet&amp;hellip; when you try to make it significantly larger, you really have to deal with the question: how does time travel work in this universe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s never &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; answered. Things get all sorts of quantum and fuzzy. Effects proceed causes (and sometimes you get neat little loops with no original cause at all). Other than that, I&amp;rsquo;ll let you see how they deal with it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do still love the side characters the most. We get more Scarecrow, which is fascinating. And of course Stills and anti-piss (you&amp;rsquo;ll just have to see it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the first book is stronger. But this one has some fascinating ideas and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to get the chance to live in this world for just a few hours longer. Onward to see if it can be done&amp;ndash;one more time. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Quantum Magician</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/14/the-quantum-magician/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/14/the-quantum-magician/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A con man called Gander had once taught him that there were only three bets. Sometimes, you play the cards. Sometimes, you play the player. Sometimes, you just throw the dice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quantum Magician is &amp;hellip; not what I expected. I&amp;rsquo;m sure at one point, I read the blurb, but I&amp;rsquo;ve slept since then. So all I had to go on when I picked it up just now was the title.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>