<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Discworld - Industrial Revolution on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/04/discworld-industrial-revolution/</link><description>Recent content in Discworld - Industrial Revolution on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/04/discworld-industrial-revolution/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monstrous Regiment</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/04/monstrous-regiment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/04/monstrous-regiment/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Do you think it&amp;rsquo;s possible for an entire nation to be insane?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Truth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/08/the-truth/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/08/the-truth/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There are, it has been said, two types of people in the world. There are those who, when presented with a glass that is exactly half full, say: this glass is half full. And then there are those who say: this glass is half empty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world belongs, however, to those who can look at the glass and say: What&amp;rsquo;s up with this glass? Excuse me? Excuse me? This is my glass? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so. My glass was full! And it was a bigger glass! Who&amp;rsquo;s been pinching my beer?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And at the other end of the bar the world is full of the other type of person, who has a broken glass, or a glass that has been carelessly knocked over (usually by one of the people calling for a larger glass) or who had no glass at all, because he was at the back of the crowd and had failed to catch the barman&amp;rsquo;s eye.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Moving Pictures</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/03/moving-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/03/moving-pictures/</guid><description>&lt;p>Discworld goes Hollywood. Or perhaps Hollywood comes to Discworld?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, Hollywood is a manifestation of a &amp;lsquo;Great Old Ones&amp;rsquo; esque cult where the final cultist keeping the Holy Wood from arising once again dies. One thing leads to another, trolls get dressed up as elephants, and a movie hero has to save the day.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>