<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2021 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/28/2021/</link><description>Recent content in 2021 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/28/2021/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>For All Mankind: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/28/for-all-mankind-season-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/28/for-all-mankind-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that got away from me for a bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the explosive introduction that was &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/16/for-all-mankind-season-1/">For All Mankind: Season 1&lt;/a>, with the Soviets beating the US to the moon and all that changed through that&amp;hellip; no we&amp;rsquo;re a decade in the future and things &lt;em>continue to change&lt;/em>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see Jamestown grow to a crew of around 20. The Baldwins have adapted a daughter. The chaos of escalating tensions, both on the moon and also back on Earth&amp;ndash;and all the perils of space travel, even without that. And Gordo, Danielle, and Ed, back to space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s all in the first part of the week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man this is a good show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And next season, with another time skip we may very well be going to Mars!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free Guy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/07/free-guy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/07/free-guy/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Guy: I know this world is just a game, but this place, these people, that&amp;rsquo;s all I have. So I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna be the good guy. I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be a great guy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Molotov Girl: [inhales] Wow, enjoy your lifetime supply of virginity.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Ryan Reynolds plays Ryan Reynolds playing a guy named Guy in a game&amp;ndash;but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t realize it. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; a lot of fun. Once you get the basic idea, you&amp;rsquo;ve got pretty much the entire plot, but it&amp;rsquo;s fun and well done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/attachments/free-guy-62ba5c.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a watch.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Visions</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/05/star-wars-visions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/05/star-wars-visions/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating expirment. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who got that made, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad they did. Take Star Wars, give it to a bunch of different Japanese (or Japanese inspired) animators, and make sure that nothing in this will be canon (so you can tell all sorts of stories). There aren&amp;rsquo;t any particularly deep, they&amp;rsquo;re too short for that. But beautiful, oh this series has that in spades.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a watch!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eternals</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/25/eternals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/25/eternals/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ancient aliens sent to Earth thousands of years ago to protect&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> humanity&amp;hellip; but only from very specific threats. Loki and the Chitauri? Nah. Hydra? Nope. Thanos? Of course not. A whole cast of superheroes&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and we&amp;rsquo;ve never seen them before&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&amp;ndash;and I doubt that any of the should-be-worldwide-news events in this film will make it into any of the others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you ignore all that though, it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting enough idea, especially once you start digging into the greater cosmic plot. There&amp;rsquo;s even more to unpack than we even get a chance to look at in that movie. I really do want to know where it goes next&amp;ndash;and if there will be any impact at all on the greater MCU.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: No Way Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finally got around to watching this. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did, it&amp;rsquo;s hilarious and an aboslute blast of nostalgia. Similar to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/">Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a>, I don&amp;rsquo;t know know if this would possibly hold up without the weight of all of the movies that came before it (I doubt it), but with that weight&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s really really good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s funny, it&amp;rsquo;s touching, and there are some really crazy action scenes. But the greatest strength of course comes from &lt;span class="spoiler">bringing back a half dozen villains and all three modern live action Spider-Men into one film&lt;/span>
. Would anyone have believed something that crazy possible, especially before Infinity War/Endgame? I doubt it. But it&amp;rsquo;s quite satisfying.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Encanto</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/13/encanto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/13/encanto/</guid><description>&lt;p>Disney has really been doing quite well the last 12 years. Tangled, Wreck-It Ralph, Frozen, Big Hero 6, Moana, and now Encanto? (I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen Raya yet) All really solid films. Encanto specifically, I really enjoyed. It&amp;rsquo;s got great songs, fun characters, beautiful animation, and a lovely story. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to see a story based on yet another culture&amp;ndash;Columbia this time&amp;ndash;Disney is really doing that well. Overall, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t quite put it to the level of Moana, but it&amp;rsquo;s just about there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Matrix Resurrections</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/the-matrix-resurrections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/the-matrix-resurrections/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Whoa.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a blast of nostalgia, a bunch of mind-bending meta universe building, some awesome new characters, a few solid action scenes, and overall quite an action movie. I loved it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dune (Movie)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/20/dune-movie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/20/dune-movie/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lady Jessica Atreides: I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little death that brings obliteration. I will face my fear and I will permit it to pass over me and through me. And when it has gone past&amp;hellip; I will turn the inner eye to see its path. Where the fear has gone there will be nothing. Only I will remain.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Wow. That&amp;rsquo;s a movie with &lt;em>quite&lt;/em> a sense of scale and granduer. The ships are huge, the worms are huge, the armies are huge, the Duke is honorable, the Fremen are pious, the Baron is gross, everything is spectacular. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a bummer that we&amp;rsquo;re going to have to wait a few years for Part 2, but I think it really did need the space to breath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worldbuilding and visuals are what really makes this movie. I watched it on HBOMax, rather than in theaters, but I do have a wall sized projected screen and that really does help. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a visually stunning movie. If they re-run Part 1 in theaters, I may have to check it out next time around&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Luca</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/02/luca/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/02/luca/</guid><description>&lt;p>Luca is something of an odd beast. It&amp;rsquo;s a cute little movie about two young sea monster boys who journey out onto land&amp;ndash;where so long as they don&amp;rsquo;t get wet, they transform to look like humans. Wacky hijinks ensue, there&amp;rsquo;s a meetcute with a young girl, a big race scenes, some quickly resolved drama, and everyone lives happily ever after.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not the most thrilling movie, which isn&amp;rsquo;t really something that you expect to see from Pixar&amp;ndash;if it had come from any other studio it would have been pretty impressive. But at the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid enough movie, it&amp;rsquo;s cute, and there were a few laugh out loud moments, so I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have seen it. I fully expect the children will enjoy this one&amp;ndash;although it&amp;rsquo;s rather odd watching it a week after Finding Nemo&amp;ndash;a much better movie made 20 years earlier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was a surprisingly delightful movie. It takes a character I&amp;rsquo;ve at least barely heard of&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> with a cast pretty much unknown to the western world&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and turns it into a wonderful combination of human drama, Lovecraftian baddies, and awesome action scenes. It&amp;rsquo;s well among my favorite MCU movies to date (only Captain America beats it out among introductions and a few others overall) and well worth the watch. After how big the MCU has gotten recently, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of nice to see a movie that almost completely stands on it&amp;rsquo;s own&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. It&amp;rsquo;s a big world, with parallel/pocket universes and gates to worlds chock full of truly alien baddies, but at the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s a story about family, about legacy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Widow</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been to theaters since&amp;hellip; &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/">Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a>. Man it&amp;rsquo;s been a weird few years. Which actually wraps up Black Widow pretty well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly solid action/spy movie. There are a number of spectacular action scenes, a deep dive into Black Widow&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s akin to an origin story, but filling in a character we already knew a decent amount of back rather than introducing someone new, which was nice&amp;ndash;and the introduction of a few new characters I expect we&amp;rsquo;ll see more of. After the absolutely draining intensity of Infinity War/Endgame plus just how dark the followup shows have been, it was nice to have something relatively &amp;rsquo;lighter&amp;rsquo; and smaller in scope.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Suicide Squad</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-suicide-squad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-suicide-squad/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, that is a glorious movie. Exactly what an R rated half-satirical superhero movie should be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually seen the first Suicide Squad or Birds of Prey (yet), so it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as strange that they apparently kept some of the characters/actors while ignoring some events and keeping others. Other than that&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s just so enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting right from the opening:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/2021/suicide-squad-1.jpg">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>You have the Suicide Squad. Super powered criminals, given the chance to take a few years off their sentence if they&amp;rsquo;ll use their powers to do the jobs that the &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; heroes are either too busy or too &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; to do. It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy yet awesome plot and the cast is amazing. Nathan Fillion as T.D.K&amp;ndash;his arms come off. Jai Courtney back as Boomerang&amp;ndash;he throws&amp;hellip; a boomerang. Flula Borg as Javelin&amp;ndash;likewise, with a javelin. Mayling Ng as Mongal&amp;ndash;she&amp;rsquo;s an alien or something? Pete Davidson as Blackguard&amp;ndash;who knows. And especially Sean Gunn as Weasel&amp;ndash;a humanoid&amp;hellip; weasel. And Michael Rooker as Savant&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure, expert at throwing things? Him and Sean Gunn together was amusing coming off Guardians of the Galaxy. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit I looked that one up; he&amp;rsquo;s in everything! It&amp;rsquo;s not at all the team of heroes you&amp;rsquo;d expect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Space Jam: A New Legacy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/29/space-jam-a-new-legacy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/29/space-jam-a-new-legacy/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Bugs Bunny: So, you want me, a talking cartoon bunny, to play with you, an NBA superstar, in a high-stakes basketball game?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sounds awfully familiar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LeBron James: Who are you talking to?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well. That was certainly a thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched the original Space Jam in probably 20 years&amp;hellip; but I remember it fondly enough. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I really want to go back and watch it again. But it still does make me want to give Space Jam: A New Legacy a chance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mortal Kombat</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/03/mortal-kombat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 23:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/03/mortal-kombat/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Shang Tsung: FINISH THEM!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Mortal Kombat is an odd sort of movie. With 2 dozen games, 2 previous live action and 2 animated films, and all manner of other references and media, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of backstory going on. But really, it all comes down to some sort of otherworldly nasties coming to conquer the Earth, but they can only do so if they defeat Earth&amp;rsquo;s champion(s). Other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s really a vehicle for hand to hand combat of the most violent sort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Godzilla vs Kong</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/godzilla-vs-kong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/godzilla-vs-kong/</guid><description>&lt;p>You know, that was more enjoyable than I think it had any right to be. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of movie that would have been far more spectacular on a big screen, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to the theaters in a while, so I&amp;rsquo;ll take smaller.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All around, it&amp;rsquo;s a visual delight. Transporting Kong is hilarious looking. The Hollow Earth is an insane idea, but it&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful world and all of those big beasties to fight are a lot of fun to see. &lt;spoiler>Mechagodzilla&lt;/spoiler> makes even less sense than a lot of the movie / other human ways to fight the monsters. But once again, it makes for a wonderful visual.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>