<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kate DiCamillo on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/kate-dicamillo/</link><description>Recent content in Kate DiCamillo on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/kate-dicamillo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mercy Watson: Something Wonky This Way Comes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/07/mercy-watson-something-wonky-this-way-comes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/07/mercy-watson-something-wonky-this-way-comes/</guid><description>&lt;p>After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/04/mercy-watson-goes-for-a-ride/">Mercy Watson Goes for a Ride&lt;/a>, I figured I should probably write about one of the shorter Mercy Watson stories that I really do like. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/07/mercy-watson-something-wonky-this-way-comes/">Mercy Watson: Something Wonky This Way Comes&lt;/a> is that story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, the entire gang goes to a drive in movie, wherein Bottomless Buckets of popcorn, absolutely drenched in butter are served. Of course Mercy goes off to find the butter (as is often the plot) and chaos ensues. We get to see just about everyone, which is all sorts of fun trying to read aloud with a distinct voice per character (as I do) and in the end, all is well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mercy Watson Goes for a Ride</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/04/mercy-watson-goes-for-a-ride/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/04/mercy-watson-goes-for-a-ride/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t usually review this short of a book, but I had a few words I wanted to say:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really enjoy the Mercy Watson books. They&amp;rsquo;re light and hilarious, with a cast full of wonderfully weird characters and maybe a bit of a lesson in their along for the ride.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leroy Ninker Saddles Up</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/leroy-ninker-saddles-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/leroy-ninker-saddles-up/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Yippie-i-oh. That is the life for me. A cowboy is who I was meant to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Leroy Ninker wants to be a cowboy&amp;ndash;to be a cowboy, he needs a horse. Enter: Maybelline. An old horse with four teeth and four hooves (a perfect match) that runs on compliments and grub and doesn&amp;rsquo;t stand being alone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Francine Poulet Meets the Ghost Raccoon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/13/francine-poulet-meets-the-ghost-raccoon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/13/francine-poulet-meets-the-ghost-raccoon/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Franny, you are the genuine article. You are solid. You are certain. You are like a refrigerator. You hum.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Francine Poulet is the greatest Animal Control Officer in Gizzford County and now she has to go up against her own worst enemy: self doubt, panic attacks, and facing your fears. Also a ghost racoon. But that&amp;rsquo;s not really what the story is about.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Where Are You Going, Baby Lincoln?</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/12/where-are-you-going-baby-lincoln/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/12/where-are-you-going-baby-lincoln/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve started reading chapter books to my children at night. They get to chose (from what we have) and this is where we begin. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could have chosen a better first book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/12/where-are-you-going-baby-lincoln/">Where Are You Going, Baby Lincoln?&lt;/a> tells the story of Baby Lincoln striking out on her own, taking a Necessary Journey by train to&amp;hellip; well, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter in the end, does it? (Fluxom. They&amp;rsquo;re going to Fluxom.)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>