<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dean Koontz's Frankenstein on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/dean-koontzs-frankenstein/</link><description>Recent content in Dean Koontz's Frankenstein on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/dean-koontzs-frankenstein/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Dead Town</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/24/the-dead-town/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/24/the-dead-town/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so it ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A direct sequel to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/lost-souls/"&gt;Lost Souls&lt;/a&gt;, we finish up with Victor (etc) and his nanomachine replacements out in Montana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of cool seeing the rugged, individual, hyper-&amp;ldquo;American&amp;rdquo; characters fight back. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit much at times, but I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a conclusion to even two books, let alone five&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s fine? It does tie up most of the threats. But on the other hand, it&amp;rsquo;s all build up and &amp;hellip; just ends. I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of that. And barely any of the monsters/big bads from the first three books come back&amp;hellip; Just Erika and Jocko. Of all the things to keep&amp;hellip; why Jocko?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worth finishing once I&amp;rsquo;d come that far, but it really is the sort of series you could probably finish at the first book and not miss mutch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lost Souls</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/lost-souls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/lost-souls/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pride can become arrogance. Arrogance is the father of cruelty. But in the beginning, there was also an idealism, a hope that he could change the human condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Victor Helios (né Frankenstein) is dead. Victor Leben (né Helios (né Frankenstein)) is &lt;em&gt;alive&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the events at the end of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/25/dead-and-alive/"&gt;Dead and Alive&lt;/a&gt;, we all knew there would be another book. Here it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; fine. It&amp;rsquo;s got all the bits you&amp;rsquo;d need for a thriller, but I don&amp;rsquo;t feel the villains as much. And there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not really and ending&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s very much part 1 of 2. At this point, you could easily stop at book 3&amp;hellip; or read on to finish book 5. I suppose I&amp;rsquo;m in the latter camp. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dead and Alive</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/25/dead-and-alive/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/25/dead-and-alive/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that is most certainly a book. A hard one to rate at that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, we get a conclusion of sorts of Victor Helios né Frankenstein&amp;rsquo;s mad plan to take over New Orleans (and then the world!) and replace all us flawed Old Race with his New Race&amp;hellip; and various other critters. It&amp;rsquo;s a story that&amp;rsquo;s been quite building up for three books now and it&amp;rsquo;s great to see it come to a head of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, these should all have been one giant omnibus. Cut out a few plotlines and it works. At it was, they only sort of end, up until now. And even that is generous&amp;ndash;there are an awful many plotlines still unresolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, an awful lot of this book really seemed to get away from Victor&amp;rsquo;s master plan and dig more into all of the weird things that have been going wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get Harker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; baby? of sorts! And it&amp;rsquo;s played more for laughs than anything, which I did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; expect. Takes a bit away from the previous scenes, IMO. We get the continuation of security man turns chimera, which is still pretty cool and terrifying, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t really go where I&amp;rsquo;d hope. There&amp;rsquo;s some chameleon monster. Again, cool but really underused. And we get a trash dump monster. They&amp;rsquo;ve been dumping all of these horrors&amp;ndash;and they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;designed&lt;/em&gt; to survive. So this makes sense. But I&amp;rsquo;m not at all happy with how it went. As it was, that plot alone needed an entire book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the &amp;lsquo;good guys&amp;rsquo; seem much less impactful than I&amp;rsquo;d like. Deucalion&amp;rsquo;s bouncing around causing Victor trouble, but without any &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; satisfying pay off (in my opinion). Carson and Michael and still delightful with the banter&amp;ndash;and totally outclassed&amp;ndash;but again, it only sort of goes anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit disappointed, but I suppose at this point, I&amp;rsquo;ll give the last two books a try, although I&amp;rsquo;m curious where &lt;em&gt;in the world&lt;/em&gt; you go from here. There&amp;rsquo;s an opening, but how do you tie them together?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>City of Night</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/15/city-of-night/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/15/city-of-night/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so we continue with the adventures of Helios né Frankenstein and all the troubles he&amp;rsquo;s causing for modern day New Orleans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the main plotlines, we get a lot more of Randall Six and Arnie. I like the story in general, but the pacing is strange, stretching across two books and then sort of ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get Helios and yet another Erika, along with all sorts of things starting to go wrong with the New Race. It&amp;rsquo;s pushing increasingly into Horror, especially Body Horror, and I like it. The only gotcha is that it feels rather weird for it all to be going wrong &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;. I do like seeing more variations and points of view among the New Race. They&amp;rsquo;re not all the same, no matter how much Helios wants them to be and that is fascinating. Especially when you bring Deucalion into the mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get more of Carson and Michael, now off the rails and going straight cop turned vigilante. It makes sense, given the complete inability to know who&amp;rsquo;s Old and who&amp;rsquo;s New, but it still is a bit jarring. I do love their banter. At this point, I wholly expect one or both not to survive the series, which is a bummer, but expected in this sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the weirdest thing about this book (and the series thus far) is that it really all feels like one very very long single novel. The &amp;rsquo;endings&amp;rsquo; do tend to end at least one plot thread, but there are always new things being brought up and random threads ending well before the end of a book. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I care for the style. But I&amp;rsquo;m too into the series now to stop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that being said, it&amp;rsquo;s a good book and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to where we go next!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Prodigal Son</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/prodigal-son/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/prodigal-son/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowledge is knowing that Frankenstein is not the monster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wisdom is knowing that Frankenstein is the monster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A questionable phrase when applied to the original book. Full of hubris. A coward. Not really a &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; person, sure. But a monster?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in Dean Koontz&amp;rsquo;s version&amp;hellip; yeah. Victor Frankenstein (now Victor Helios)&amp;ndash;totally the monster.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>