<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MCU Phase 3 on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-phase-3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MCU Phase 3 on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-phase-3/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ant-Man and the Wasp</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</guid>
      <description>Ant-Man and his daughter are adorable. Especially with Luis&#39; help. Luis is wonderful. Everyone playing Luis as he describes everyone. And Paul Rudd playing Janet van Dyne. Add to that the interactions with/introduction of Jimmy Woo.
 Scott Lang: Come on, Woo. I&amp;rsquo;ve got three days left. Why would I try to escape?
Jimmy Woo: Sorry, Scott, but rules are rules. You trip the perimeter alarm, we search the place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avengers: Infinity War</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</guid>
      <description>All that. Ten years. 18 movies. Dozens of huge name actors and crossovers, all leading to this. The Avengers gave us a team up, but Infinity War turned it all up to 11. The battle scenes are insane (especially that final battle in Wakanda, especially especially the return of Thor), the villain&amp;ndash;Josh Brolin as Thanos&amp;ndash;is powerful and ACTUALLY GETS A CHANCE TO WIN , and I absolutely love seeing the interplay between all of the characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Panther</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s a very solid movie. The casting is top notch, the style is wonderfully afrofuturistic, and the plot/motivation is interesting enough.
Starting with the plot/motivation, I think that the choice to have Wakanda separated from the rest of the world, all through centuries of slavery and inequality is certainly an interesting one. And I&amp;rsquo;m not at all alone.
 Nakia: I came to support you, and to honor your father.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thor: Ragnarok</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</guid>
      <description>Ooh, that poster. le kiss
Thor was &amp;hellip; fine, a weirdly downscale introduction to a kind of strange character early in the MCU. Thor: The Dark World went the other way, being too bigt and ambitious and suffering somewhat for it. So going into Thor: Ragnarok, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what we were going to get.
An absolute gem of an 80s sci fi/fantasy action superhero comedy that just works. Right from the very intro, you know it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a different sort of movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</guid>
      <description>After the surprisingly awesome Guardians of the Galaxy, it was really a question of: could they do it again? The answer, a resounding&amp;hellip; sort of?
Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 has some pretty awesome moments. The opening battle in particular is spectacular (I love the contrast of dancing Baby Groot against a big smack down in the background). And we get all piles of additional humor based around Drax&amp;rsquo;s literalness, Rocket being a racoon, &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Strange</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/10/doctor-strange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/10/doctor-strange/</guid>
      <description>Wong: While heroes like the Avengers protect the world from physical dangers, we sorcerers safeguard it against more mystical threats.
 Man, that is a visually stunning movie. The first battle with building magically twisting all over (a la Inception), the glowing magic rings, the magical doodads. I am ever thankful that superhero movies have gotten popular enough that studios will spend the big bucks on special effects. They really do look great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Captain America: Civil War</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/</guid>
      <description>Captain America: Civil War isn&amp;rsquo;t really a Captain America movie. While it deals with the Winter Solder to some extent, as much as that it&amp;rsquo;s an Iron Man movie since he killed Stark&#39;s parents... . But really, it&amp;rsquo;s an Avengers movie. Everyone shows up, takes sides, and eventually ends up a great big superhero fight. And It&amp;hellip; Is&amp;hellip; Spectacular. In my opinion, it&amp;rsquo;s the best MCU movie to this point, beating out any of the solo outings and even the first two Avengers movies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
