<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MCU Phase 3 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-phase-3/</link><description>Recent content in MCU Phase 3 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-phase-3/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As much as I loved &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/"&gt;Spider-Man: Homecoming&lt;/a&gt;, Spider-Man: Far From Home takes what made it great and turns it up a few levels &lt;em&gt;even further&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One one level, you have Spider-Man being Spider-Man. He&amp;rsquo;s a good kid, trying to make his way in life, trying to deal with the dual life of being a highschooler and being a superhero&amp;ndash;of saving the world and perhaps getting the girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then you layer all the weight of the greater MCU on top of it. This takes place just after &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/"&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a&gt;. So you have the fallout of Iron Man (Spider-Man&amp;rsquo;s mentor/Uncle Ben figure) being gone and Spider-Man having to step into &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; shoes, the first big mention of The Blip&amp;ndash;and how you deal with coming back and the world has changed, and all sorts of dealing with a Nick Fury who&amp;rsquo;s lost several of his heaviest hitters.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Homecoming</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; is a truly delightful Spider-Man movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird seeing him introduced &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the events of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/"&gt;Captain America: Civil War&lt;/a&gt;) and completely skipping how he became Spider-Man in the first place&amp;hellip; but it works. I really like the entire plot, dealing with the fallout of the Avengers / super-hero activity and how normal people try to live their lives around it&amp;ndash;and what happens when the powers that be step in and take that away from them. Excellent villain fuel. It&amp;rsquo;s a little silly that &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;the Vulture ends up being Spider-Man's crush's father...&lt;/span&gt;
, but I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s the sort of thing you expect from superhero films. Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid, fun action film.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avengers: Endgame</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s one heck of a climax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/"&gt;Avengers: Infinity War&lt;/a&gt;, Thanos won. He snapped and half of the universe died&amp;ndash;let&amp;rsquo;s ignore the logistics of that. In Endgame, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance&amp;ndash;a very small chance&amp;ndash;that they can fix it all. All they need is a little &amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tony Stark: [discussing the &amp;ldquo;Time Heist&amp;rdquo;] I believe the most likely outcome will be our collective demise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Lang: Not if we strictly follow the rules of time travel. That means no talking to our past selves, no betting on sporting events&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Captain Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Captain Marvel is a bit of an odd movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a straight up superhero origin story with a bit more of a cosmic twist than many we&amp;rsquo;ve seen (other than Guardians of the Galaxy&amp;hellip; and Thor&amp;hellip;) It&amp;rsquo;s something of a prequel&amp;ndash;in that it&amp;rsquo;s chronologically set before any of the other Marvel movies other than the beginning of Captain America. It&amp;rsquo;s got a hero in Captain Marvel with a grab bag of vaguely defined glowy energy powers with memory issues who has to go on a journey and power up to her final form.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ant-Man and the Wasp</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ant-Man and his daughter are adorable. Especially with Luis&amp;rsquo; help. Luis is wonderful. Everyone playing Luis as he describes everyone. And Paul Rudd playing Janet van Dyne. Add to that the interactions with/introduction of Jimmy Woo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Lang: Come on, Woo. I&amp;rsquo;ve got three days left. Why would I try to escape?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jimmy Woo: Sorry, Scott, but rules are rules. You trip the perimeter alarm, we search the place. Keel to stern, soup to nuts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Avengers: Infinity War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;All that. Ten years. 18 movies. Dozens of huge name actors and crossovers, all leading to this. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/"&gt;The Avengers&lt;/a&gt; gave us a team up, but Infinity War turned it all up to 11. The battle scenes are insane (especially that final battle in Wakanda, especially especially the return of Thor), the villain&amp;ndash;Josh Brolin as Thanos&amp;ndash;is powerful and &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;ACTUALLY GETS A CHANCE TO WIN&lt;/span&gt;
, and I absolutely love seeing the interplay between all of the characters.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Black Panther</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a very solid movie. The casting is top notch, the style is wonderfully afrofuturistic, and the plot/motivation is interesting enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the plot/motivation, I think that the choice to have Wakanda separated from the rest of the world, all through centuries of slavery and inequality is certainly an interesting one. And I&amp;rsquo;m not at all alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nakia: I came to support you, and to honor your father. But I can&amp;rsquo;t stay. It&amp;rsquo;s just &amp;hellip; ! found my calling out there. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen too many in need just to turn a blind eye. I can&amp;rsquo;t be happy here knowing that there&amp;rsquo;s people out there who have nothing .&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thor: Ragnarok</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ooh, that poster. &lt;em&gt;le kiss&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/"&gt;Thor&lt;/a&gt; was &amp;hellip; fine, a weirdly downscale introduction to a kind of strange character early in the MCU. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/"&gt;Thor: The Dark World&lt;/a&gt; went the other way, being too bigt and ambitious and suffering somewhat for it. So going into Thor: Ragnarok, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what we were going to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An absolute gem of an 80s sci fi/fantasy action superhero comedy that just works. Right from the very intro, you know it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a different sort of movie. They lean hard into the Norse/Asgardian mythos, with Thor in the underworld, chained up (but not concerned) by a giant flaming skeleton who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to signify the end of days. One spectacular Thor&amp;rsquo;ful action scene later and we&amp;rsquo;re back on Asgard, dealing with the missing Odin. Then we&amp;rsquo;re off to Earth, only to bump into Doctor Strange, now fully into his powers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After the surprisingly awesome &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/"&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;, it was really a question of: could they do it again? The answer, a resounding&amp;hellip; sort of?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 has some pretty awesome moments. The opening battle in particular is spectacular (I love the contrast of dancing Baby Groot against a big smack down in the background). And we get all piles of additional humor based around Drax&amp;rsquo;s literalness, Rocket being a racoon, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doctor Strange</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/10/doctor-strange/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/10/doctor-strange/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wong: While heroes like the Avengers protect the world from physical dangers, we sorcerers safeguard it against more mystical threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, that is a visually stunning movie. The first battle with building magically twisting all over (a la Inception), the glowing magic rings, the magical doodads. I am ever thankful that superhero movies have gotten popular enough that studios will spend the big bucks on special effects. They really do look great.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Captain America: Civil War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Captain America: Civil War isn&amp;rsquo;t really a Captain America movie. While it deals with the Winter Solder to some extent, as much as that it&amp;rsquo;s an Iron Man movie since &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;he killed Stark's parents...&lt;/span&gt;
. But really, it&amp;rsquo;s an Avengers movie. Everyone shows up, takes sides, and eventually ends up a great big superhero fight. And It&amp;hellip; Is&amp;hellip; Spectacular. In my opinion, it&amp;rsquo;s the best MCU movie to this point, beating out any of the solo outings and even the first two Avengers movies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>