<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shadow and Bone on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/shadow-and-bone/</link><description>Recent content in Shadow and Bone on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/shadow-and-bone/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shadow and Bone: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/25/shadow-and-bone-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/25/shadow-and-bone-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saints become martyrs before they get to be heroes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really sure what to expect. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually read the books (although now I really wanted to) and for the first episode or two, I really thought it was some sort of cheesy YA fantasy, a la Hunger Games and the ilk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a few episodes in&amp;hellip; and it really started to grow on me. The world building is fascinating, primarily the basis on a broad Asian setting, but with an emphasis on Russian roots, with some influences (in other nations) from China and India. The magic system is a bit cheesey and somewhat unexplained (so far), but at the very least it&amp;rsquo;s pretty?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, you have absolutely wonderful characters/actors. Jessie Mei Li nails it as lead Alina Starkov, Ben Barnes as General Kirigan&amp;ndash;plays his character rather well (&lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;he actually has the gravitas of old, powerful, and twisted, which not everyone can pull off&lt;/span&gt;
). But the ones that really shine are the Crows (I don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;re referred to as such in the show?): Freddy Carter as Kaz, Amita Suman as Inej and Kit Young as Jesper. There are rumors that they might get their own show and that would be &lt;strong&gt;awesome&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, worth a watch. And we&amp;rsquo;re getting Season 2, hopefully sometime next year? Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>