<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>jverkamp.com</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com" /><link rel="self" href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/feed/" /><updated>2015-10-18T00:00:00Z</updated><author><name>JP Verkamp</name></author><id>urn:uuid:f148b655-ada3-c720-0c01-ca384ab68088</id><entry><title>First Birthday Weekend</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/18/first-birthday-weekend" /><id>urn:uuid:ccff63ed-829e-870a-205d-a65987dd55a8</id><updated>2015-10-18T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My daughter's first birthday was this weekend. We spent Saturday at Pomponio State Beach and went to a pumpkin seller on Sunday. Lovely fun.</p>
<div><div class="flickr-gallery" data-set-id="72157657717114853" data-per-page="30"></div><p><a href="https://flickr.com/photos/jpverkamp/sets/72157657717114853">View on Flickr</a></p></div>]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My daughter's first birthday was this weekend. We spent Saturday at Pomponio State Beach and went to a pumpkin seller on Sunday. Lovely fun.</p>
<div><div class="flickr-gallery" data-set-id="72157657717114853" data-per-page="30"></div><p><a href="https://flickr.com/photos/jpverkamp/sets/72157657717114853">View on Flickr</a></p></div>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Yosemite</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/09/yosemite" /><id>urn:uuid:01817433-b4d9-cac5-d648-695922174b8b</id><updated>2015-10-09T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back to Yosemite, this time in the fall. A bit drier, but still beautiful.</p>
<div><div class="flickr-gallery" data-set-id="72157659203053618" data-per-page="30"></div><p><a href="https://flickr.com/photos/jpverkamp/sets/72157659203053618">View on Flickr</a></p></div>]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back to Yosemite, this time in the fall. A bit drier, but still beautiful.</p>
<div><div class="flickr-gallery" data-set-id="72157659203053618" data-per-page="30"></div><p><a href="https://flickr.com/photos/jpverkamp/sets/72157659203053618">View on Flickr</a></p></div>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Throne of the Crescent Moon</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/04/throne-of-the-crescent-moon" /><id>urn:uuid:e6d8363e-1056-6e43-dd61-f350164b74f0</id><updated>2015-10-04T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11487807-throne-of-the-crescent-moon"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/04/throne-of-the-crescent-moon/throne-of-the-crescent-moon.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I really liked this book.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11487807-throne-of-the-crescent-moon">Throne of the Crescent Moon</a> (by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/4025591.Saladin_Ahmed">Saladin Ahmed</a>) follows a band of somewhat unlikely heroes as they're off to save the day. You have an old ghul hunter (one of the last of his kind), a whirling dervish (I'd never before looked up what that actually meant), an alchemist and her mage of a husband, and a shape shifter who can take the form of a golden lion.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11487807-throne-of-the-crescent-moon"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/04/throne-of-the-crescent-moon/throne-of-the-crescent-moon.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I really liked this book.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11487807-throne-of-the-crescent-moon">Throne of the Crescent Moon</a> (by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/4025591.Saladin_Ahmed">Saladin Ahmed</a>) follows a band of somewhat unlikely heroes as they're off to save the day. You have an old ghul hunter (one of the last of his kind), a whirling dervish (I'd never before looked up what that actually meant), an alchemist and her mage of a husband, and a shape shifter who can take the form of a golden lion.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Arrayed against them; a beastie from the time of the dead gods raising a whole bunch of ghuls. Also a corrupt all powerful ruler and the Robin Hood esqe figure who may or may not be any better in the end.</p>
<p>One thing that I really loved about this book: the world. It's based on Arabic influences rather than the pseudo-European that I've seen in most of the fantasy I've read. Better yet, the Arabic influence is woven throughout the story in a way that just makes it come alive. You have sights and sounds and history and magic, all with (to me) a very new feel to it. If you've read a similar selection to me, this is worth reading just for that.</p>
<p>On top of that, I liked the relatively large ensemble cast. Even though we had five main characters and a whole pile of supporting cast (see above), I really thought that each had their own voice and I was greatly amused and intrigued with how each of them interacted with one another.</p>
<p>All together, it's a neat book. Especially after everything shakes out in the end, I wish the sequel were out already (planned release in 2016). What I think I really need is to do is to go find other fantasy novels from non-European authors...</p>
<p>Excellent.</p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>, I'm going to re-read / finish the <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/49971-kane-chronicles">The Kane Chronicles</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/15872.Rick_Riordan">Rick Riordan</a>. A combination of Percy Jackson / <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/18/the-heroes-of-olympus">The Heroes of Olympus</a> and Egyptian mythology? Count me in!</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Burlingame Gardens</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/02/burlingame-gardens" /><id>urn:uuid:c851c1a3-24ea-4554-f678-4a163d4b6fed</id><updated>2015-10-02T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Took a walk with a around Burlingame Gardens. All sorts of neat moments.</p>
<div><div class="flickr-gallery" data-set-id="72157659331994936" data-per-page="30"></div><p><a href="https://flickr.com/photos/jpverkamp/sets/72157659331994936">View on Flickr</a></p></div>]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Took a walk with a around Burlingame Gardens. All sorts of neat moments.</p>
<div><div class="flickr-gallery" data-set-id="72157659331994936" data-per-page="30"></div><p><a href="https://flickr.com/photos/jpverkamp/sets/72157659331994936">View on Flickr</a></p></div>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.8: The Market - Planning</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/01/writing-excuses-10-8-the-market-planning" /><id>urn:uuid:a4616ac5-c914-2560-3b20-675d2a0c5298</id><updated>2015-10-01T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/02/22/writing-excuses-10-8-qa-on-character/">Writing Excuses 10.8</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Sketch out the events before and after your dead-drop scene from last week and three weeks ago.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>What is in the packages?</strong></p>
<p>Black powder mixed with something that will create lots of smoke. It's an attack on the temple. When the packages are put into the flames (unopened, as is tradition), they will burn through and explode. As small as they are, it won't actually cause much damage, but that's not the point. Rather the point is to create confusion (especially with the smoke) so another agent can sneak into the temple and steal something.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/02/22/writing-excuses-10-8-qa-on-character/">Writing Excuses 10.8</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Sketch out the events before and after your dead-drop scene from last week and three weeks ago.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>What is in the packages?</strong></p>
<p>Black powder mixed with something that will create lots of smoke. It's an attack on the temple. When the packages are put into the flames (unopened, as is tradition), they will burn through and explode. As small as they are, it won't actually cause much damage, but that's not the point. Rather the point is to create confusion (especially with the smoke) so another agent can sneak into the temple and steal something.</p>
<!--more-->
<p><strong>Who sent the packages?</strong></p>
<p>The packages at first appear to be from a rival temple of another sun god. The two sun gods have a long rivalry (as might be expected). Both have enough in the terms of miracles that it's hard to prove that either is wrong, but which is the more important is up for grabs.</p>
<p>A further layer down though, the packages are actually from the Baron in charge of the city. He realizes that temple of Actris is growing too powerful, especially with the common people. He wants to play the two of them against one another without showing his own hands in things. Schemes within schemes, plots within plots.</p>
<p><strong>What are they trying to steal?</strong></p>
<p>The goal will be to steal the Staff of the Sun. It's a relic from a Holy War that took place over five centuries ago during the current empire's rise to power. The temple of Actris played a large part in that conflict and the Staff is supposed to have miraculous powers.</p>
<p><strong>Why did they choose who they did to send the packages?</strong></p>
<p>The choice of the noble was another level in the schemes on the part of the Baron. The noble gained his power from trading and is actually richer than the Baron himself (although not quite if you take into account the city's funds as well). Trying to take out a potentially powerful rival is just icing on the cake so far as the Baron is concerned.</p>
<p><strong>What will happen to the golem next?</strong></p>
<p>The golem is the only one of the three that is actually brought in for questioning in regards to this story. He tries to buy a replacement head directly, but finds that he cannot get the funds. So he's forced to return to the guild and ask for a replacement, something that no golem wants to do. They are already in the guild's clutches just by the nature of their existence, but this will require additional sacrifices. In this case, someone saw him deliver one of the packages which caused the chaos at the temple. The guild will look into it.</p>
<p>(Side note: the golem could be the serving girl from the original Shadows and Steam with only minor changes.)</p>
<p><strong>What will happen to the orphan next?</strong></p>
<p>No one seems to know that the orphan was involved in the explosion at the temple of Actris. Instead though, he runs into trouble when he tries to sell the golem's head that he picked up off the street. He doesn't at first, since he just wants to keep the shiny, but eventually he has to. At that point, he tries to sell it to the wrong person (a minor functionary in the Golemancy Guild) who can identify what it was and that there's both no way that the orphan should have it and--by city law--it already belongs to the guild anyways. All golems are guild property.</p>
<p><strong>What will happen to the noble next?</strong></p>
<p>The noble will figure out what is going on in term of the Baron trying to frame him. Initially at least though, he will not be able to figure out the other levels of the plan. Johanas (who is more than meets the eye) keeps subtly helping him behind the scenes for his own reasons, although the noble is oblivious to all of this. He does eventually manage to take power from the Baron, but only temporarily as the rivalry between the two temples of the sun gods erupts into an all out civil war.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Newsflesh Trilogy</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy" /><id>urn:uuid:54f77424-fa72-6fad-8d52-4a98f4391fe1</id><updated>2015-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7094569-feed"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/1-feed.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8429687-deadline"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/2-deadline.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11806716-blackout"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/3-blackout.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Onwards and brainwards!</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3153776.Mira_Grant">Mira Grant</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>.</p>
<p>Brains...</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7094569-feed"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/1-feed.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8429687-deadline"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/2-deadline.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11806716-blackout"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/3-blackout.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Onwards and brainwards!</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3153776.Mira_Grant">Mira Grant</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>.</p>
<p>Brains...</p>
<!--more-->
<p>I find it vaguely amusing how relatively many zombie series I've read this year. <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/03/27/white-trash-zombie">White Trash Zombie</a> (with the next October 6th!). <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/03/31/precinct-13">Precinct 13</a>. <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris">Elantris</a> (Yeah--that doesn't really count.) Still, the more the merrier when you're hungry for flesh.</p>
<p>Overall, Newsflesh is an excellent series. Basically, in the future, zombies are here and bloggers have taken over the world. Where these stories really shine is their world building. The zombie plague is an infectious disease and society has changed as a result. It actually feels like something that could just happen, which really helped to draw me into the books.</p>
<p>Also positive, there are a goodly number of plot twists throughout the series. Some are obvious in hindsight, some even in foresight. And some... Ow. Some hit right where it hurts.</p>
<p>Here are my individual reviews. Warning: <strong>spoilers</strong>. Each book's review should be relatively spoiler-free, but it's hard to talk about Deadline and Blackout without spoilers for Feed.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7094569-feed"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/1-feed.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Feed follows the story of George (yup), Shaun (also yup), and Buffy (not even kidding), three bloggers covering the story of a lifetime: a Republican Presidential candidate. Then, as it always goes in a zombie story, things go wrong.</p>
<p>I liked the characters. The bloggers are divided into a newsie (tells it like it is), an Irwin (basically the action stars of the blogging world) (yup), and a fictional (writes poetry); missing only a Stewart (satire in the news) (also yup). I really felt for all of them, even if at time they tended a bit towards caricatures of their roles. Also: evil bad guy is evil and obvious, but sometimes that's not a bad thing.</p>
<p>This is also one of the best treatments of a 'realistic' zombie outbreak that I think I've read. Society has mostly adapted to everyone being a carrier with a system of restrictions (no one can go to Yosemite) and near constant blood tests. The CDC is far more powerful and people have adapted to the idea that any mammal over 40 pounds could be your death.</p>
<p>Therein lies the first oddity with this book: Feed doesn't actually feel like a zombie novel. More than anything it feels like a novel about journalism, politics, and freedom of speech... which just so happens to happen during after the zombie apocalypse. It took me a while to realize this, but I think it makes the novel stronger as a result.</p>
<p>And then there's the twists, oh the twists. I get it, it's a zombie story. People are going to die. Just... I didn't see that coming... Wow. That's certainly one way to get me to read the sequel.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8429687-deadline"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/2-deadline.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I was curious to see where Grant would take this, after killing off a small pile of main characters in the first book. It turns out: somewhere right between what I expected and what I didn't expect at all.</p>
<p>On one hand, Shaun is crazy now. He hears George's voice in his head and answers her out loud. Everyone around him of course thinks he's crazy, but they mostly seem to give him space. I'm not sure what I think about that. Shaun is still probably my least favorite of the main characters from the first book, which is certainly suboptimal, given that he's the only one to survive... (Also, the Coke fixation is weird.) But why does everyone else keep him around?</p>
<p>On the other hand, the world building continues to be excellent. We get a few neat twists (like what the reservoir conditions might actually mean) and dig a little deeper into the conspiracy behind it all. Given that there's still one more book, we don't get quite as much of that as I'd like, but so it goes. Still though, it feels like Grant really did her homework. The zombie threat feels real. That's saying something.</p>
<p>And then... The ending. One thing I don't care about in second books of trilogies is when they don't have an ending of their own. If Deadline had ended around 80%, it would have been fine. Instead, we get the ALL NEW BIGGER AND BETTER THREAT in the last 20% or so. Don't get me wrong, I really want to know how it all shakes out, but it's still annoying.</p>
<p>And then and then... That last sentence. Say <b>what!?</b></p>
<p>Needless to say, onwards to Blackout.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11806716-blackout"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/3-blackout.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>A solid ending to a solid series. I think that I liked it more than Deadline, but less than Feed, owing entirely to one thing: George.</p>
<p>Yup, she's back. Literally the last thing that happens in Deadline gets fleshed out (heh) in Blackout as we alternate once again between Shaun's and Georgia's viewpoints. It's fairly obvious what's happened (and a neat extension of what we already know about the zombie virus), but that doesn't mean I was still rooting for her nevertheless.</p>
<p>That being said, her being back complicates Shaun's situation somewhat. He's not any less crazy and as odd as it sounds, his underlings are still just dealing with it. <spoiler>What's more, it's made explicit here that Georgia and Shaun have been sleeping together. I get it, and they're adopted rather than blood siblings, but it still feels a little off.</spoiler></p>
<p>Other than that, it's a solid conclusion to the series. We finally learn who the big bads are--although it's not a huge twist. We get a few more complications with the zombie virus with several nice showdowns across the country. The ending is less 'they all lived happily ever after' and more 'we may just survive this', but given the events of the stories, that's good enough for me. At least it's not a cliffhanger like Deadline...</p>
<p>Overall, great book, great series. Not quite on my list of favorites ever, but I'm glad I read it.</p>
<hr />
<p>Next up, we get a nice fantasy adventure based on Arabic history, rather than the European fantasy I've read piles of: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11487807-throne-of-the-crescent-moon">Throne of the Crescent Moon</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/4025591.Saladin_Ahmed">Saladin Ahmed</a></p>
<p>I'm looking forward to it.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.7: The Market - Johanas</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/28/writing-excuses-10-7-the-market-johanas" /><id>urn:uuid:fceb73f0-c971-e42a-e3c8-a1413d6368e9</id><updated>2015-09-28T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/02/15/writing-excuses-10-7-who-are-all-these-people/">Writing Excuses 10.7</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Pick one of the dead-drop characters from the exercise two weeks ago, and turn them into a secondary character. Now take one of the characters with whom they interacted, and write the same scene again, but from this new character's POV.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>My master is not always the brightest of men.</p>
<p>Not in all regards, not in all things.</p>
<p>But he paid for my mother's transition, when there was no pressing need that he do such a thing. So far as I can tell, he didn't even know what he was paying for.</p>
<p>And for that, I shall be eternally grateful.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/02/15/writing-excuses-10-7-who-are-all-these-people/">Writing Excuses 10.7</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Pick one of the dead-drop characters from the exercise two weeks ago, and turn them into a secondary character. Now take one of the characters with whom they interacted, and write the same scene again, but from this new character's POV.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>My master is not always the brightest of men.</p>
<p>Not in all regards, not in all things.</p>
<p>But he paid for my mother's transition, when there was no pressing need that he do such a thing. So far as I can tell, he didn't even know what he was paying for.</p>
<p>And for that, I shall be eternally grateful.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>For that, I shall protect him from himself.</p>
<p>The package arrived as all do, the sigils of the Parcel's Guild marking the edges. Lord Bronwin did not even seem to recognize them. Granted, it is generally I who answers the door.</p>
<p>In this instance though, Lord Bronwin was walking to the stairs when the package was delivered and as such took an inordinate interest in its contents.</p>
<p>That alone should have been enough to warn me that something was awry. Not in the sense that I recognized the package for what it was--something more subtle. My mother had always said that I had a gift for seeing what truly was.</p>
<p>Yet still, I opened the package. I couldn't very well explain such a feeling to my master. Not without more to go on than just that.</p>
<p>Inside the package, there were three smaller packages and a note. Before I could stop him, Lord Bronwin had snatched the letter from the package and began to read.</p>
<p>My uneasy feeling was confirmed. I could see in his face that it was not good news. And from the sidelong look he spared me, I was involved.</p>
<p>Still, I well knew my place. If my master required it of me, I would do it. No matter the personal cost.</p>
<hr />
<p>Without telling me precisely why, my master bid me prepare his carriage to go to market. While it was common enough for me to go to market--especially on such days when other servants of the hour could not attend to such duties--Lord Bronwin had never, to my knowledge, gone.</p>
<p>Yet an order was an order, and without seeing the letter, I had no particular reason to believe that my master was in any danger whatsoever. So of course, I was going to have to take the letter.</p>
<hr />
<p>My opportunity came just as we were leaving.</p>
<p>In order to step up into the carriage, while still holding on to all three of the individual packages, Lord Bronwin needed both of his hands. Thus he had no room to hold the letter and handed it to me. With only the barest of moments to glance at its contents, I managed to catch only a section:</p>
<p><center> ... your indiscretions shall become common knowledge. Do not send Johanas. ... </center></p>
<p>Then, my master held his waiting hand back out the door, the expectance clear in his stance.</p>
<p>I handed it back, my brain whirling with activity.</p>
<p>I wasn't sure which bothered me more.</p>
<p>The reference to 'indiscretions' or my own name.</p>
<p>At least it explained why he was being particularly short with me.</p>
<p>I would just have to help him without knowing any more. Surely I could do that.</p>
<hr />
<p>At the edge of the market, my master signaled for me to stop the carriage. I made to go to the door to let him out--despite still thinking his plan mad--but he waved me off. Instead, he asked me to find the first two I could find willing to act as couriers. Curious.</p>
<p>It took some short time, but eventually I found a golem and a young boy on the street. The golem seemed to be off duty and more than happy enough to take my--and by extension, Lord Bronwin's--money. Of course, it was hard to read anything on the expressionless, voiceless face, but once a golem agreed to a job, they were incredibly reliable.</p>
<p>The young boy, he at least seemed enthusiastic. And what was more, he didn't seem to have much in the way of bargaining skill. Two silver pennies? A steal.</p>
<p>Then we were off again. It seemed that he wanted to hand deliver one of the three smaller packages. Again, it wasn't my place to question my master, but if he were going to hand deliver one of them himself, then why not deliver all three?</p>
<p>I was still contemplating said thought when a flash of movement just before me drew my attention.</p>
<p>I only had a moment to see a golem walking directly across my path before a terrible screech and the rearing of the metal beasts pulling the carriage required all of my attention.</p>
<p>The horses were strange that way. It wasn't that they were spooked; mechanical beasts as they were, they didn't get spooked. Rather they were trying to avoid damaging either themselves or the golem who had darted in front of them.</p>
<p>At least they succeeded in one.</p>
<p>I saw the golem's head pop off and roll an arm's length away. From what I knew about golems, that wasn't actually fatal--although what does fatal mean to something that is not alive?</p>
<p>I heard my master's voice call up from the carriage. "What's the trouble?"</p>
<p>I debated a second, but only a second. My primary duty was to him, not to these packages. There was a chance that the situation would devolve. The sooner his package was delivered, the sooner we could return to the safety of his mansion.</p>
<p>"Nothing, sir," I said, already directing the steeds to continue on their way.</p>
<hr />
<p>We dropped off the package my master had kept and he had me retreat a safe distance to watch the other two. Or at least, I assume the distance was such that he thought it safe. I wouldn't have minded a few blocks more.</p>
<p>The boy arrived first. He put the package down without even really paying terribly much attention to it. Instead, he was inspecting a metalic object. It took a moment for me to place it.</p>
<p>The golem's head.</p>
<p>I shook my own.</p>
<p>The kid was in for some trouble. The Golemancy Guild was one of the strongest organizations in the city and they didn't take kindly to anyone encroaching on their turf, even unintentionally. I thought to give the boy a bit of advice, but I was sure he wouldn't take it.</p>
<p>A few minutes later, just as I was about to ask Lord Bronwin what exactly he was waiting for, the golem trotted up as well. I admit, I was surprised to see it. It was one thing to know that a golem can lose a head with little to no ill effect; it was quite another to experience it first hand, as it were.</p>
<p>Still, that meant that we had all three packages. That meant we could head home.</p>
<p>We tarried only a moment longer before Lord Bronwin signaled me onward. He seemed to be debating something, although he wouldn't go so far as to tell me.</p>
<p>Halfway home, there was a sharp report. The sound of an explosion, followed closely by two more. I waited, letting the horses trod their inexorable way home, but that was it.</p>
<p>Three.</p>
<p>Three explosions.</p>
<p>Three packages.</p>
<p>It had to be a coincidence.</p>
<p>Didn't it?</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>San Mateo Clouds</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/24/san-mateo-clouds" /><id>urn:uuid:27400fc2-efed-6f19-8dca-dcd76f9d887b</id><updated>2015-09-24T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Took an after lunch walk around San Mateo. Pretty pretty clouds.</p>
<div><div class="flickr-gallery" data-set-id="72157658635978079" data-per-page="30"></div><p><a href="https://flickr.com/photos/jpverkamp/sets/72157658635978079">View on Flickr</a></p></div>]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Took an after lunch walk around San Mateo. Pretty pretty clouds.</p>
<div><div class="flickr-gallery" data-set-id="72157658635978079" data-per-page="30"></div><p><a href="https://flickr.com/photos/jpverkamp/sets/72157658635978079">View on Flickr</a></p></div>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Elantris</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris" /><id>urn:uuid:82dbdf77-b085-bb90-6691-c7f4377e417f</id><updated>2015-09-18T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68427.Elantris"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/elantris.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13578175-the-emperor-s-soul"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/the-emperors-soul.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I know I said last post that my next series would be The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a>, and that's still the case, but in the mean time, I have a <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a> review for <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68427.Elantris">Elantris</a> (and <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13578175-the-emperor-s-soul">The Emperor's Soul</a>) by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson">Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68427.Elantris"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/elantris.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13578175-the-emperor-s-soul"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/the-emperors-soul.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I know I said last post that my next series would be The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a>, and that's still the case, but in the mean time, I have a <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a> review for <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68427.Elantris">Elantris</a> (and <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13578175-the-emperor-s-soul">The Emperor's Soul</a>) by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson">Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Since there are only two and they're not particularly directly related to one another, here are the individual reviews:</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68427.Elantris"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/elantris.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I have yet to find a Sanderson novel that I don't particularly like and Elantris is no exception.</p>
<p>Basically, Elantris focuses around the titular city; once a place of wonder and magic which. Ten years ago, all that ended and now it's populated by essentially zombies: those without heartbeats who cannot die and cannot heal. We follow a few different story lines--a princess from another land engaged to the prince who gets Elantrisified in the very beginning of the story; an attempted religious coup from multiple fronts; and the politics of a kingdom/city trying to heal after massive upheaval.</p>
<p>This is his earliest work and in some ways it shows. He actually commented recently on the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast that he co-hosts that he's learned a lot about pacing since writing Elantris. Towards the end, I definitely noticed it. In the last 10% or so of the novel, everything comes to a head all at once. I think it could have been even strong had some of the storylines come to fruition earlier.</p>
<p>I did like a lot of the characters. Sarene reminds me strongly of Shallan from The Way of Kings (perhaps because it's the most recent other Sanderson novel I've read), but I think I actually like her more. Raoden seems almost too good to be true, but keeps just enough human trivialities (especially when interacting with Sarene), that I still like him. I particularly grew to like Hrathen. It's always interesting to see how fantasy novels interact with religion.</p>
<p>More than anything, I wish this novel had a sequel. Well, it sort of does in [book: The Emperor's Soul|13578175], although that it in a completely different part of the world. It looks like there is a true sequel in the works though (<a href="http://brandonsanderson.com/faq-will-there-be-a-sequel-to-elantris/">FAQ</a>). Awesome.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13578175-the-emperor-s-soul"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/the-emperors-soul.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>If I hadn't been told, at first I wouldn't realize that The Emperor's Soul takes place in a far away corner of the same world as Elantris. But as the story wears on, and the details of the magic system are revealed, it becomes more obvious that the worlds are one and the same. I really do love how Sanderson does magic systems. I've never seen anything quite like it, especially not at the same scale. Every system seems new, yet there's a shared core to all of them. I love it.</p>
<p>Other than that, I did like the character of Shai. There's something about an artist who works entirely to know that she did it, rather than for public acclaim that I enjoy. Sneaky and subtle. Excellent. I could see a few of the twists coming (that she wouldn't escape until the last moment; the changes she made), but that didn't make it any less enjoyable.</p>
<p>One thing I'd love to see if/when that Elantris sequel comes out? A meeting between the worlds. How would a Forger interact with an Elantrian? What about a Bloodsealer? I want to know more about them.</p>
<p>"You can't always write what you know--not exactly what you know. You can, however, write what you see." -- Brandon Sanderson</p>
<hr />
<p>With that, I have only <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1268479.Warbreaker">Warbreaker</a> left among Sanderson's <a href="http://coppermind.net/wiki/Cosmere">Cosmere</a> novels<span class="footnote"><sup><a href="#footnote-1">[1]</a></sup></span> and a few of the non-Cosmere ones.  Dang, he's prolific.</p>
<p>Next up (for real this time): the <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a>.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Partials Sequence</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence" /><id>urn:uuid:4fe7f178-a6d6-ecbf-e428-078b89728673</id><updated>2015-09-16T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12476820-partials"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/1-partials.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13645264-isolation"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/0.5-isolation.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13170596-fragments"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/2-fragments.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17607716-ruins"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/3-ruins.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/70323-partials-sequence">Partials Sequence</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/2740668.Dan_Wells">Dan Wells</a>.</p>
<p>I actually found Dan Wells through the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast (co-host <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson?from_search=true&search_version=service">Brandon Sanderson</a> is another author I love) and I'm glad I did. Basically, Partials is the young adult post-apocalyptic trilogy that I'd been looking for without even realizing it.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12476820-partials"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/1-partials.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13645264-isolation"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/0.5-isolation.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13170596-fragments"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/2-fragments.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17607716-ruins"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/3-ruins.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/70323-partials-sequence">Partials Sequence</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/2740668.Dan_Wells">Dan Wells</a>.</p>
<p>I actually found Dan Wells through the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast (co-host <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson?from_search=true&search_version=service">Brandon Sanderson</a> is another author I love) and I'm glad I did. Basically, Partials is the young adult post-apocalyptic trilogy that I'd been looking for without even realizing it.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>I've always had a problem with worlds like that in <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13335037-divergent">Divergent</a> and <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2767052-the-hunger-games">The Hunger Games</a>. There's always something (the strict divisions between classes and the titular Games for two examples) that just doesn't make sense. In my opinion, Partials doesn't really have that.</p>
<p>You have a war (which ended years before the series takes place) that genetically engineered super soldiers were created to fight on behalf of humanity. After that, you have a bio-weapon / virus that wipes out 99.96% of humanity and, in this case, renders the remaining tens of thousands sterile. I would like to think it unlikely, but all of that--and the story that develops from there--seems believable for the not too distant future. All together, I enjoyed Partials even more than I expected. It's even better having listened to several seasons now of Writing Excuses--I know about Wells and the writing process he goes through than I do many authors. As mentioned in my individual review for the third book: If Divergent / The Hunger Games left you wanting more, this is it. If you haven't read either, read these instead.</p>
<p>Here are my individual reviews as I went:</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12476820-partials"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/1-partials.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>The story of Partials takes place 11 years after humanity lost a terrible war. Basically, we created super soldiers (Partials) to fight for us. Of course, after they won the war they turned on us... Worse yet, right at the same time, there was a virus which killed 99.96% of humanity--including any new pregnancies.</p>
<p>So that's where we start. Humanity is stuck on Long Island while the Partials are <i>out there</i>™. Because no babies can survive the virus, the youngest living people are 14. The main characters are roughly 16. Even stranger, in an effort to figure out how to cure the virus, the Hope Act has been enacted. All women 18 or older must get pregnant as often as possible.</p>
<p>It's an odd premise, but each part at least follows through. It's a little strange that the main characters are so good at what they do (always a problem with YA fiction), but at least the idea that they had to grow up quickly helps offset that.</p>
<p>Other than that, it's an interesting world. The action keeps things moving, especially towards the latter end of the book, and I actually feel for the characters as things keep going sideways on them. There were a few twists that followed the standard YA post-apocalyptic tropes (is that a thing now) but a few that I missed, which is nice.</p>
<p>Overall, it's perhaps not as strong as some of the other books I've read this year (although it's the best post-apocalyptic YA :)), but it's more than good enough to finish the series.</p>
<p>Onward!</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13645264-isolation"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/0.5-isolation.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Quick and to the point, Isolation tells the story of Heron (who we met briefly in Partials) during the Isolation War. It gives a better picture into the Partials: how they are made, how they are trained, and why they might not only want to, but even been the right to, kill us.</p>
<p>It's a good story and I hope to see more of Heron in the second and third books of the Partials Sequence. It'll be interesting to see how she's grown and changed in the intervening years and how she interacts with the other human (and not) protagonists.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13170596-fragments"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/2-fragments.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>A good continuation to Partials. In this book, we see Kira start to come to terms with who she is as she sets off with Samm and Heron across what's left of the United States in search of answers--only to find more than she was looking for. Meanwhile, Marcus is back home, stuck between two warring Partial factions, trying desperately to broker a piece.</p>
<p>It's a neat continuation. I like watching the world expand, exploring more of what happened in the decade and change since everything fell apart. We're starting to get some answers, which of course lead to more questions. I look forward to Ruins, cautiously hoping that Wells can pull everything together for the finale.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17607716-ruins"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/3-ruins.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>A solid ending to a solid series.</p>
<p>I think Ruins actually managed to pull things together in a way without feeling (too) rushed that none of the other YA series recently have managed to pull off. The previous plotlines (Kira's conflicted nature, the rest of the Trust, the cure(s)) all come to a head in a way that's still driving enough to finish the series but don't feel like the author was just phoning it in.</p>
<p>There were a few things that I felt were just glanced over.</p>
<p>Kira manages to succeed where a decade of scientists (including those who caused the problem in the first place) have failed. That seems strange. But it's at least lamp shaded in that they were too blind to see a solution.</p>
<p>The two new Trust members come out of nowhere and never really make much sense. Plus, they're just sort of resolved. They're interesting, but I feel like they could have done more.</p>
<p>The love triangle just vanishes. Perhaps more real world accurate and I cannot believe I'm saying this: but it was weird.</p>
<p>All together though, a solid read and a solid series. If Divergent / The Hunger Games left you wanting more, this is it. If you haven't read either, read these instead.</p>
<hr />
<p>So far, GoodReads says that I've read 71 books this year, with a total of 25,513 pages. Given that today is the 258th day of the year, that averages out to 100 pages per day and I'm right on target. Let's see if I can keep that up for the last third of the year... Especially with <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/category/writing/nanowrimo">NaNoWriMo</a> looming just over the horizon.</p>
<p>Up next, another apocalypse. Zombies this time, in The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3153776.Mira_Grant">Mira Grant</a>.</p>
<p>Brains...</p>]]></content></entry></feed>