<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>China Miéville on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/30/china-mi%C3%A9ville/</link><description>Recent content in China Miéville on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/30/china-mi%C3%A9ville/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iron Council</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/30/iron-council/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/30/iron-council/</guid><description>&lt;p>[[Perdido Street Station|One in a city]], [[The Scar|one on a boat]]&amp;hellip; and now one based around an entire civilization built around a &amp;lsquo;perpetual train&amp;rsquo;, putting down rails as it goes (and at times, tearing them up behind it).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/30/china-mi%C3%A9ville/">China Miéville&lt;/a> has some bonkers worldbuilding ideas.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I mean course you want a change, we want a change, but if a change ain’t godsdamn coming, then the next thing I wish is that I didn’t care.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Beyond that, we have a whole book about political oppression and xenophobia (the Iron Council is initially founded by the remade working on the train). It&amp;rsquo;s about the tension of a revolution that feels inevitable. We have a story about gender differences (in a world where sexual dimorphism is a huge deal for some species) and love and longing. And a story about future history. The messy way of how one ends up getting history books written about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“History&amp;hellip;” Jacobs spoke with terse authority. Brought Ori to a hush. “Is all full. And dripping. With the corpses. Of them who trusted the incorruptible.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also interesting to see the fallout of the &amp;lsquo;Contruct Uprising&amp;rsquo;. A direct consequence of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/04/perdido-street-station/">Perdido Street Station&lt;/a>. And now instead, we have &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/golems">golems&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;which in this world can be made by animating any sorts of bits of innanimate matter and giving them life/instructions. It&amp;rsquo;s cool!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, I think this may be the weakest of the three. Despite how cool an idea a &amp;lsquo;perpetual train&amp;rsquo; is, I think the story spends too much time on other people/places/things. It&amp;rsquo;s all building up, but when one of the things I love the most (and always start by describing) is left wanting? That&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a bummer. It&amp;rsquo;s still fascinating and there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of it&amp;hellip; but I wanted more!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Scar</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/22/the-scar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/22/the-scar/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Scars are not injuries, Tanner Sack. A scar is a healing. After injury, a scar is what makes you whole.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Okay, I really thought that &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/04/perdido-street-station/">Perdido Street Station&lt;/a> was one of a kind. A dark, twisted magical world, full of strange creatures, stranger magic, and some truly weird and terrible things lurking just under the surface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, &lt;em>The Scar&lt;/em> manged to do quite the job proving me wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First off, we have the setting. In Perdido Street Station, the city of New Crobuzon itself was as much as a character in the stories as any of the, well, characters. So imagine my surprise where the city is only barely mentioned this time around: instead, we have Armada, a mighty floating city built on the back of untold years of captured (and otherwise) ships lashed all together.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Vessels knocked together for hour upon hour, like bones, like someone infinitely stupid and patient at the door of an empty house.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And deep under this city? Mile long chains, designed to harness&amp;hellip; &lt;em>something&lt;/em> to the city.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>So many truths have been kept from me. This violent, pointless voyage has been sopping with blood. I feel thick and sick with it. And that is all: contingent and brutal without meaning. There is nothing to be learnt here. No ecstatic forgetting. There is no redemption in the sea.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s not even getting into dead languages, weapsons and fighting styles that harness Possibility itself, a race of deadly mosquito people, and all the other terrors one might find on (and under) the ocean.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then the characters. Bellis Coldwine, a linguist of all things (I love linguistics). An acquaintances of Isaac Dan der Grimnebulin&amp;rsquo;s (I love that name) on the run after the whole Slakemoth thing. Stuck on Armada, just looking for a way home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Silas Fennec. A traveler and so much more from New Crobuzon, with his fingers (and tongue (you&amp;rsquo;ll see)) in just about everything going on one way or another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tanner Sack. A Remade, fully adapted to life on&amp;ndash;and in&amp;ndash;the sea around Armada.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uther Doul. A mysterious figure with truly &lt;em>weird&lt;/em> sword.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Lovers. Rulers of Armada. Referred to in text as &amp;lsquo;The Lover&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;The Lover&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just love how strange and &lt;em>different&lt;/em> Miéville manages to write characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the deepest places, where physical norms collapse under the crushing water, bodies still fall softly through the dark, days after their vessels have capsized. They decay on their long journey down. Nothing will hit the black sand at the bottom of the world but algae-covered bones.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, if anything I like &lt;em>The Scar&lt;/em> even &lt;strong>more&lt;/strong> than I did &lt;em>Perdido Street Station&lt;/em>. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what&amp;rsquo;s next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perdido Street Station</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/04/perdido-street-station/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/04/perdido-street-station/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Its substance was known to me. The crawling infinity of colours, the chaos of textures that went into each strand of that eternally complex tapestry…each one resonated under the step of the dancing mad god, vibrating and sending little echoes of bravery, or hunger, or architecture, or argument, or cabbage or murder or concrete across the aether. The weft of starlings’ motivations connected to the thick, sticky strand of a young thief’s laugh. The fibres stretched taut and glued themselves solidly to a third line, its silk made from the angles of seven flying buttresses to a cathedral roof. The plait disappeared into the enormity of possible spaces.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Any time you ask about modern &amp;lsquo;weird fiction&amp;rsquo; / weird ecologies / weird cities. China Miéville and Perdido Street Station almost always come up. Turns out&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s for a good reason. Why in the world did I take so long to read this book?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, this book really shines when it comes to weird&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> worldbuilding. Half-bird, half-human creature? Not that weird. Half-bug creatures? Where the women have a scarab beetle instead of ahead and the males are non-sapient grubs? Weird. Frog people? Re-animates and constructs? Plant people? All living together in a grimy steam-powered, airship and tech and magic driven mess of a metropolis?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weird&lt;sup id="fnref1:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And wonderful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, this was exactly the sort of book that I love and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see there are other books in the same world, if not with the same characters. I want more!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conversely, if you&amp;rsquo;re not into weird fiction, more than a touch of body horror, or a book where everyone necessarily get a happy ending (or even survive the story)&amp;hellip; maybe skip this one. It&amp;rsquo;s dark. And that&amp;rsquo;s sort of the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: I listened to this on audiobook and I loved the narration. Perhaps my favorite thing? Whenever the narrator said Issac&amp;rsquo;s full name. Grimnebulin! &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Art is something you choose to make&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a bringing together of&amp;hellip; of everything around you into something that makes you more human, more khepri, whatever. More of a person.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>