<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dungeon Crawler Carl on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/dungeon-crawler-carl/</link><description>Recent content in Dungeon Crawler Carl on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/dungeon-crawler-carl/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Dungeon Anarchist's Cookbook</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/21/the-dungeon-anarchists-cookbook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/21/the-dungeon-anarchists-cookbook/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked Bautista, I thought as I finished building my train bomb, but his Tigran race made him look like a tiger that had been vomited upon by a Lisa Frank notebook. I didn’t know how anything could embarrass him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s another fun one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two major things that stand out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The titular Dungeon &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anarchist%20Cookbook"&gt;Anarchist’s Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s a fun idea already and I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting to see what more can be done with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The floor of the dungeon we spend most of the time on&amp;ndash;trains. All the trains in a chaotic snarl. Delightful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the stakes just keep rising (which, all things considered, is impressive).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carl's Doomsday Scenario</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/23/carls-doomsday-scenario/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/23/carls-doomsday-scenario/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you’ve never had a flaming, skull-faced bear on roller skates barreling at you full speed, you don’t know what you’re missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so Carl and Princess Donut descend to the third floor. With a choice of race (of course Donut will choose Cat, was there ever any doubt?) and class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NecroBard This unusual class combines one of the most-loved occupations with one of the most reviled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are going to get worse (of course) even as they get better (or at least higher level). And now, we&amp;rsquo;re getting the first hints of life in teh rest of the universe&amp;ndash;outside of the Dungeon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If that’s true,” I said, “then you’re all in that same pot.” I turned to look at the audience. “All of you. If a government is afraid of what its people say, then maybe there’s a reason for it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politics, yo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m fully expecting more of that as the series goes on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, a worthy successor to the first one and I&amp;rsquo;m still interested to see where in the &lt;em&gt;world&lt;/em&gt; this series can even go from here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dungeon Crawler Carl</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/15/dungeon-crawler-carl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/15/dungeon-crawler-carl/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goddammit Donut!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book has no right to be quite so fun as it is. Billions of people die in the first chapter, it’s full of blood and gore and formerly-living-detritus, and the entire thing feels like a video game—menus, inventory, levels, and loot boxes included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New achievement! You’ve killed an armed mob with your bare fucking hands! Holy crap, dude. That’s kinda fucked up. Reward: You’ve received a Bronze Weapon Box!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>