<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Indiana Jones on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/indiana-jones/</link><description>Recent content in Indiana Jones on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/indiana-jones/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/">Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade&lt;/a> was such a good movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then they made another one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as I remembered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harrison Jones isn&amp;rsquo;t getting younger&amp;hellip; but he still really makes Indiana Jones. Full stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I bet they were expecting this film (and especially Shia LeBeouf&amp;rsquo;s Mutt) to go better and possibly pass the torch. It was an echo of the same dynamic as Indy and his father in The Last Crusade. Just not quite done as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was kind of fun to see the Soviets be the bad guys this time around and it more or less fits this new, older Indy.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Dean Charles Stanforth: I barely recognize this country anymore. The government&amp;rsquo;s got us seeing Communists in our soup. When the hysteria reaches academia, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to call it a career.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On top of that, seeing Karen Allen&amp;rsquo;s Marion Ravenwood again after all these years? And with the obvious fallout of that? That was more fun than I expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man. Cate Blanchett act the heck out of that role. But still, she just wasn&amp;rsquo;t as much a villain as previous films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;ndash;the action scenes. A bit more over the top than previous movies? Do you even &lt;em>remember&lt;/em> the roller coaster mine cart of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/">Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom&lt;/a>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed the opening in the warehouse. The nuclear bomb-fridge scene has been talked about to death. The motorcycle chase (through the library!) was a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Indiana Jones: You want to be a good archaeologist&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
[Mutt drives them out of the building on his motorcycle]&lt;br>
Indiana Jones: &amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ve got to get out of the library!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The jungle fight between the jeeps was pretty cool&amp;ndash;but the Tarzan bits? a bit much&amp;hellip; The temple was technically neat, even if it didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense. And the &lt;span class="spoiler">alien&lt;/span>
 finale wasn&amp;rsquo;t really that much weirder than centuries old knights and Nazi face melting artifacts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I think I&amp;rsquo;d place it above Temple of Doom, but below Raiders and the Last Crusade. A fun action flick and&amp;ndash;not as bad as I initially thought.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s my favorite of teh trilogy by a solid margin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s great! All the way from the introduction with a young Indy. The introduction of the whip. The hat. His love of snakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From there, we get a big world trotting mystery with some great action scenes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Are you crazy? Don&amp;rsquo;t go between them.&lt;br>
Go between them, are you crazy?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;big archeological puzzles&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But in the Latin alphabet, &amp;ldquo;Jehovah&amp;rdquo; begins with an &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;the dynamic between Indy and his father&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I suddenly remembered my Charlemagne. Let my armies be the rocks and the trees and the birds in the sky.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;Nazis&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I hate these guys.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;and a big supernatural finale.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He choose&amp;hellip; poorly.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Watch it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which of course means &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/">Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull&lt;/a> is up next&amp;hellip; hmm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="temple-of-doom">Temple of Doom&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Temple of Doom has some major middle film issues going on. Both &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/24/indiana-jones-and-the-raiders-of-the-lost-ark/">Raiders of the lost Ark&lt;/a> and The Last Crusade are far better films. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say Temple of Doom is bad, just lesser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Actionwise, there&amp;rsquo;s a ton. Gun fights, bailing out a plane, tons of bugs, several fights in a mine, and a giant drop? There is barely time to breathe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Real world ethicswise&amp;hellip; this is even worse than Raiders, which is saying something. There are a fair few &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; racist, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo; moments and a helping of &amp;ldquo;are they just evil for the sake of bring evil?&amp;rdquo; I suppose one can always go with the &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s an action movie, don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it&amp;rdquo; mindset.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Raiders of the Lost Ark</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/24/indiana-jones-and-the-raiders-of-the-lost-ark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/24/indiana-jones-and-the-raiders-of-the-lost-ark/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been a long time since I&amp;rsquo;ve watched these movies, but man do they actually hold up. From the moment the score first hits, through all the adventure and action scenes, right up to that face melting(ly awesome!) conclusion? There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of nostalgia, granted, but I still think it holds up even so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an introduction, we have it all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomb robbing!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Indiana needs his bullwhip to swing across a chasm]&lt;br>
Indiana: Give me the whip.&lt;br>
Satipo: Throw me the idol.&lt;br>
[they both see a stone door closing]&lt;br>
Satipo: No time to argue! Throw me the idol, I&amp;rsquo;ll throw you the whip!&lt;br>
Indiana: [throws the idol] Give me the whip!&lt;br>
Satipo: [drops the whip] Adiós, señor.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A fear of snakes!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Upon opening the Well of the Souls and peering down]&lt;br>
Sallah: Indy, why does the floor move?&lt;br>
Indiana: Give me your torch.&lt;br>
[Indy takes the torch and drops it in, revealing hundreds of snakes all over floor of the Well of Souls]&lt;br>
Indiana: Snakes. Why&amp;rsquo;d it have to be snakes?&lt;br>
Sallah: Asps&amp;hellip; very dangerous. You go first.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A mostly grounded world (if larger than life), before edging into the fantastical!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Indiana: The Ark of the Covenant, the chest that the Hebrews used to carry around the Ten Commandments.&lt;br>
Major Eaton: What, you mean &lt;em>the&lt;/em> Ten Commandments?&lt;br>
Indiana: Yes, the actual Ten Commandments, the original stone tablets that Moses brought down from Mt. Horeb and smashed, if you believe in that sort of thing&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
[the officers stare at him blankly]&lt;br>
Indiana: Didn&amp;rsquo;t any of you guys ever go to Sunday school?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Characterwise, Harrison Ford as Indiana Jones really makes the movie, but Karen Allens&amp;rsquo; Marion and John Rhys-Davies&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> are great supporting cast and man Ronald Lacey makes quite the villain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a pulpy adventure film. The plot is about as clearly good guys (even if Indy is totally looting) versus bad guys, loaded with some awesome action scenes along the way, and a solid ending where the good guys win. And sometimes, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a great fun movie. I&amp;rsquo;m going to rewatch them all now! (The original trilogy. I suppose I&amp;rsquo;ll have to watch the new ones too? We&amp;rsquo;ll see.)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>