<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Megamorphs on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/megamorphs/</link><description>Recent content in Megamorphs on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/megamorphs/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>In the Time of Dinosaurs</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/06/in-the-time-of-dinosaurs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/06/in-the-time-of-dinosaurs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s right there in the title right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Animorphs try to do the right thing and instead get blown back 65 million years in the past. They almost get eaten, find a bunch of aliens no one has ever heard of (and we&amp;rsquo;ll never see again I expect), almost get eaten, go steal a nuke, almost get eaten, and eventually get home. Because what sort of series would this be if they didn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m starting to think that the Animorphs might have a time travel problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s been longer than than I thought since last time (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/11/the-stranger/">The Stranger&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/21/the-forgotten/">The Forgotten&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/">The Andalite Chronicles&lt;/a>; alternatively, it was last 65 million years from now!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s certainly an exciting story. And we get a touch of the moral issues involved in potentially changing the timeline&amp;ndash;or having to allow something terrible to happen to preserve it. Along with some much more interesting aliens than we often see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So a good story. Worthy of the heftier Megamorphs page count I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward and back&amp;hellip; TO THE FUTURE!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Andalite's Gift</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/12/the-andalites-gift/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/12/the-andalites-gift/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/megamorphs/">Megamorphs&lt;/a> book&amp;ndash;with the point of view switching each chapter rather than per book&amp;ndash;and almost twice as long! (apparently it was originally published as two books?) It&amp;rsquo;s a neat concept and a good way to shake up the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s summer time. The Animorphs are coming off a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/11/the-stranger/">big win&lt;/a>. So it&amp;rsquo;s time to relax.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until a living tornado from Saturn comes to visit&amp;ndash;seemingly focussed on finding and shredding our friendly neighborhood Animorphs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, an amnesia plot. Which morphing for some reason didn&amp;rsquo;t heal?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; fine? The other &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/megamorphs/">Megamorphs&lt;/a> books are better.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>