<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Megamorphs on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/megamorphs/</link><description>Recent content in Megamorphs on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/megamorphs/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Back to Before</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/02/back-to-before/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/02/back-to-before/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;What if&amp;ndash;instead of walking through that fateful construction site&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ellimist and Crayak/the Drode are at it again. Giving Jake a chance at a normal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all is not as it seems&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, I see it now, I see it now,&amp;rdquo; the Drode said, ignoring Marco, ignoring all of us. &amp;ldquo;Subtle as always, Ellimist. Your meddling came before, didn&amp;rsquo;t it? How could we not have seen it? Elfangor&amp;rsquo;s brother? His time-shifted son? This anomalous girl here? And the son of Visser One&amp;rsquo;s host body? A group of six supposedly random humans that contains those four! You stacked the deck!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Did I?&amp;rdquo; The Ellimist laughed. &amp;ldquo;That would have been very clever of me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know? So far as justifications for the coincidences that make stories just work&amp;ndash;that&amp;rsquo;s actually a sneakily good one. The Animorphs are talented and more than a little lucky. But all along, someone (something?) has been stacking the deck to help them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like it. More than I expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Elfangor's Secret</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/22/elfangors-secret/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/22/elfangors-secret/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Am I some kind of hideous freak of nature, a twisted concoction of mismatched parts? Or am I something new and wonderful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depends on the day. Depends on whether I&amp;rsquo;m with Melissa, wanting to make her happy, wanting her to hold my hand, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Way to bury the lede there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s another time travel story. Another Time Matrix story. Another Ellimist / Cyarak story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slightly more interesting bit this time is that time is wrong. Someone has been messing around in history and it&amp;rsquo;s up to the Animorphs to put things right.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>In the Time of Dinosaurs</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/06/in-the-time-of-dinosaurs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/06/in-the-time-of-dinosaurs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s right there in the title right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Animorphs try to do the right thing and instead get blown back 65 million years in the past. They almost get eaten, find a bunch of aliens no one has ever heard of (and we&amp;rsquo;ll never see again I expect), almost get eaten, go steal a nuke, almost get eaten, and eventually get home. Because what sort of series would this be if they didn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting to think that the Animorphs might have a time travel problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s been longer than than I thought since last time (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/11/the-stranger/"&gt;The Stranger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/21/the-forgotten/"&gt;The Forgotten&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/"&gt;The Andalite Chronicles&lt;/a&gt;; alternatively, it was last 65 million years from now!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s certainly an exciting story. And we get a touch of the moral issues involved in potentially changing the timeline&amp;ndash;or having to allow something terrible to happen to preserve it. Along with some much more interesting aliens than we often see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a good story. Worthy of the heftier Megamorphs page count I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward and back&amp;hellip; TO THE FUTURE!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Andalite's Gift</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/12/the-andalites-gift/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/12/the-andalites-gift/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The first &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/megamorphs/"&gt;Megamorphs&lt;/a&gt; book&amp;ndash;with the point of view switching each chapter rather than per book&amp;ndash;and almost twice as long! (apparently it was originally published as two books?) It&amp;rsquo;s a neat concept and a good way to shake up the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s summer time. The Animorphs are coming off a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/11/the-stranger/"&gt;big win&lt;/a&gt;. So it&amp;rsquo;s time to relax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until a living tornado from Saturn comes to visit&amp;ndash;seemingly focussed on finding and shredding our friendly neighborhood Animorphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, an amnesia plot. Which morphing for some reason didn&amp;rsquo;t heal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; fine? The other &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/megamorphs/"&gt;Megamorphs&lt;/a&gt; books are better.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>