<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Wheel of Time on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-wheel-of-time/</link><description>Recent content in The Wheel of Time on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-wheel-of-time/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Wheel of Time: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/09/the-wheel-of-time-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/09/the-wheel-of-time-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Wheel of Time turns, and ages come and pass, leaving memories that become legend. Legend fades to myth, and even myth is long forgotten when the Age that gave it birth comes again. In one Age, called the Third Age by some, an Age yet to come, an Age long past, a wind rose in the Mountains of Mist. The wind was not the beginning. There are neither beginnings nor endings to the turning of the Wheel of time. But it was a beginning.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/">The Wheel of Time: Season 1&lt;/a> had a lot of potential&amp;hellip; and also a lot of issues. Especially when it came to the last couple episodes. COVID, sure. A main actor leaving, I get it. But it&amp;rsquo;s still a rough ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it was with cautious optimism, we approached Season 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s very much a new turning of the wheel. Some things they changed really do work well. It&amp;rsquo;s not the books, but it&amp;rsquo;s a new story in the same world. Some&amp;hellip; less so. But not everything is perfect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things I loved:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The casting. Ishamael was great in Season 1 and even better in Season 2. Lanfear is a great counter to him. Aviendha and Elayne fit really well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It bears repeating: Ishamael and Lanfear are great. Leaning a bit more into terrifying even than the books, which quite frankly they needed. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see (and hope they don&amp;rsquo;t screw up&amp;hellip;) the rest.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Almost&lt;/em> everything about the Seanchan. They feel &amp;lsquo;off&amp;rsquo; in just the right way. The one exception&amp;hellip; the Damane pacifiers. I really don&amp;rsquo;t get that &lt;em>at all&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Liandrin. She&amp;rsquo;s still terrible, but I really like how they turned up the &lt;em>reason&lt;/em> why she is as she is. And she&amp;rsquo;s quite the actor to pull it off.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Things that I did not:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The ending. Check out the &lt;a href="#8-what-was-meant-to-be">individual review&lt;/a> for more details, but &amp;hellip; this wasn&amp;rsquo;t any better than the previous season. And they don&amp;rsquo;t even have unexpected troubles to deal with. I&amp;rsquo;m starting to feel they really just don&amp;rsquo;t know how to write endings&amp;hellip; which is weird.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Anyways, other than a few things, I quite enjoyed it. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Season 3. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Wheel of Time: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/</guid><description>The Wheel of Time turns, and ages come and pass, leaving memories that become legend. Legend fades to myth, and even myth is long forgotten when the Age that gave it birth comes again. In one Age, called the Third Age by some, an Age yet to come, an Age long past, a wind rose in the Mountains of Mist. The wind was not the beginning. There are neither beginnings nor endings to the turning of the Wheel of time.</description></item><item><title>A Memory of Light</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/11/a-memory-of-light/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/11/a-memory-of-light/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There are no endings, and never will be endings, to the turning of the Wheel of Time. But it was an ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And oh what an ending it was.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Towers of Midnight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/04/towers-of-midnight/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/04/towers-of-midnight/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/04/towers-of-midnight/">Towers of Midnight&lt;/a> continues the final avalanche to the Last Battle, with Lan continuing to gathering followers, the Black Tower continuing to grow more and more corrupt, Perrin confronting the Whitecloaks (it&amp;rsquo;s about time that storyline wraps up), and the newly healed Rand causing even more chaos than before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many people, when asked what they notice most about the change from Jordan&amp;rsquo;s writing to Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s mention that Mat is different. Honestly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really notice it. I like Mat&amp;ndash;Mat in all his guises. Poisoned by the dagger. Helping his friends no matter what. Son of Battle, Prince of the Ravens. He&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite characters. If he feels different under Sanderson, it almost feels like growing up. After all:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Gathering Storm</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/30/the-gathering-storm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/30/the-gathering-storm/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“The end is near,&amp;quot; Moridin said. &amp;ldquo;The Wheel has groaned its final rotation, the clock has lost its spring, the serpent heaves its final gasps.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Wow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Knife of Dreams</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/22/knife-of-dreams/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/22/knife-of-dreams/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lan told me once that Malkier lives so long as one man wears the hadori in pledge that he will fight the Shadow, so long as one woman wears the ki&amp;rsquo;sain in pledge that she will send her sons to fight the Shadow. I wear the ki&amp;rsquo;sain, Master Aldragoran. My husband wears the hadori. So do you. Will Lan Mandragoran ride to the Last Battle alone?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/22/knife-of-dreams/">Knife of Dreams&lt;/a>, in which things begin moving again as the world begins the march to the Last Battle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crossroads of Twilight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/16/crossroads-of-twilight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/16/crossroads-of-twilight/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Life is a dream, and everyone wakes eventually.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Elayne continuing to solidify her hold in Caemlyn, all while being pregnant. Okay then.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Winter's Heart</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/09/winters-heart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/09/winters-heart/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A man who trusts everyone is a fool and a man who trusts no one is a fool. We are all fools if we live long enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In my opinion, entirely too much of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/09/winters-heart/">Winter&amp;#39;s Heart&lt;/a> if taken up by Perrin attempting to rescue Faile and Elayne solidifying her grip on the Lion Throne. Either is an interesting enough plot line to carry for a little while, but they just go on and on&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d mind if either was shortened significantly or even dropped entirely if/when the Wheel of Time goes to TV.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Path of Daggers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/01/the-path-of-daggers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/01/the-path-of-daggers/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“How do you know when a woman wants to kill you?” Rand mused.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“When she knows your name?” Dobraine did not sound as if he were joking.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>A Crown of Swords</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/25/a-crown-of-swords/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/25/a-crown-of-swords/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so begins the slog.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/25/a-crown-of-swords/">A Crown of Swords&lt;/a> is by far the slowest book of the series thus far.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lord of Chaos</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/19/lord-of-chaos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/19/lord-of-chaos/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Let the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/19/lord-of-chaos/">Lord of Chaos&lt;/a> rule.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Rand is trying to rule Cairhien and Caemlyn, Tear and the Aiel. Egwene is &lt;span class="spoiler">raised Amyrlin Seat&lt;/span>
. Nynaeve discovers how to Heal that which should be impossible to heal. Mat begins to build an army and finds himself bullied into following Elayne and Nynaeve to Ebou Dar.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Fires of Heaven</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/11/the-fires-of-heaven/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/11/the-fires-of-heaven/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Fires of Heaven is mostly a book to extend what we&amp;rsquo;ve seen before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elida solidifies her control on the tower while the rebels come together to oppose her. Nynaeve tugs her braid. A lot. Elayne and Nynaeve end up in the circus (not even kidding) and with a &lt;span class="spoiler">captured Forsaken...&lt;/span>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Shadow Rising</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/28/the-shadow-rising/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/28/the-shadow-rising/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Mat snorted. “I don’t want to be any bloody hero.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Bit late for that. For all of them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Dragon Reborn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/19/the-dragon-reborn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/19/the-dragon-reborn/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Til shade is gone,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>til water is gone&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Into the shadow with teeth bared&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Screaming defiance with the last breath&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To spit in Sightblinder’s eye on the Last Day.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Great Hunt</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/11/the-great-hunt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/11/the-great-hunt/</guid><description>&lt;p>Amusingly, due to the library not having a copy of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/02/the-eye-of-the-world/">The Eye of the World&lt;/a> , the first two times I read the series, I actually started with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/11/the-great-hunt/">The Great Hunt&lt;/a> . While the Eye of the World could arguably stand alone (albeit with a somewhat unsatisfying feeling, given the sheer quantity of untapped potential in the world building), it&amp;rsquo;s in the Great Hunt that things really start getting crazy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rand is just now starting to understand what being the Dragon Reborn could mean. Perrin has a connection to the wolves, something very old, come new again. Mat is still cursed by his dagger and yet &lt;span class="spoiler">he's the one to finally sound the Horn&lt;/span>
. You have the first hints of parallel universes and world hopping, along with the World of Dreams&amp;ndash;which will turn out to be rather important to the universe all together&amp;ndash;along with a few more Forsaken coming out of the woodwork. Lanfear&amp;hellip; Lanfear proves that being loved by a power hungry hundred/thousand year old super powerful jealous woman can be&amp;hellip; interesting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Eye of the World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/02/the-eye-of-the-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/02/the-eye-of-the-world/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Wheel of Time turns and Ages come and go, leaving memories that become legend. Legend fades to myth, and even myth is long forgotten when the Age that gave it birth returns again. In the Third Age, an Age of Prophecy, the World and Time themselves hang in the balance. What was, what will be, and what is, may yet fall under the Shadow.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I first read the Wheel of Time somewhere around 2004, with only 10 of the eventual 14 books published. When &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/22/knife-of-dreams/">Knife of Dreams&lt;/a> was published in 2005, I read them all again. Likewise with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/30/the-gathering-storm/">The Gathering Storm&lt;/a> in 2009 (the first written by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a> after &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/robert-jordan/">Robert Jordan&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s death), &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/04/towers-of-midnight/">Towers of Midnight&lt;/a> in 2010, and finally &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/11/a-memory-of-light/">A Memory of Light&lt;/a> in 2013. It&amp;rsquo;s been a few years, but the series as a whole is well worth every minute to invest in a reread&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s among my favorite series I&amp;rsquo;ve ever written. This time around though (for the second time) I&amp;rsquo;ll be listening to the audiobooks.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>