<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Risen Kingdoms on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-risen-kingdoms/</link><description>Recent content in The Risen Kingdoms on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-risen-kingdoms/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Last Uncharted Sky</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/28/the-last-uncharted-sky/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/28/the-last-uncharted-sky/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/08/an-alchemy-of-masques-and-mirrors/"&gt;An Alchemy of Masques and Mirrors&lt;/a&gt; was mystery and religious fiddling and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/a-labyrinth-of-scions-and-sorcery/"&gt;A Labyrinth of Scions and Sorcery&lt;/a&gt; was a political story, culminating in a fall of power (or at least a shift), The Last Uncharted Sky shifts yet again. This time we have a (aero)nautical adventure with skyships, pirates, lost treasures, and found families. Really, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful exploration of just how wonderful and strange the world we&amp;rsquo;ve been allowed to inhabit for just a little while.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Labyrinth of Scions and Sorcery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/a-labyrinth-of-scions-and-sorcery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/a-labyrinth-of-scions-and-sorcery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/08/an-alchemy-of-masques-and-mirrors/"&gt;An Alchemy of Masques and Mirrors&lt;/a&gt; was a delightful surprise of a book, with unique/excellent worldbuilding, fun characters, great wordsmithing, and a solid mystery of a plot. A Labyrinth of Scions and Sorcery has all three once again, although we mostly lose the mystery of the of first book and get a bunch of politics instead. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s still great, it just took me a bit to get into the tonal shift.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>An Alchemy of Masques and Mirrors</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/08/an-alchemy-of-masques-and-mirrors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/08/an-alchemy-of-masques-and-mirrors/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that was delightful. One of the reasons I&amp;rsquo;m really glad for the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2021-book-bingo/"&gt;2021 Book Bingo&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know when/if I would have found this book, if not for that, and I really quite enjoyed it. It&amp;rsquo;s got great steampunky worldbuilding (with some hints of body horror I honestly feel steampunk should probably have more of), royal/courtly intrigue, wonderful characters, and some delightful writing (with a French twist to the word choices that I don&amp;rsquo;t see much of). Well worth the read and I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely going to see where this story goes next.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>