<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brian's Saga on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/brians-saga/</link><description>Recent content in Brian's Saga on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/brians-saga/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brian's Winter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/04/brians-winter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/04/brians-winter/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fall came on with a softness, so that Brian didn’t realize what was in store—a hard-spined north woods winter—until it was nearly too late.He had never thought he would be here this long. After the plane crash that marooned him in the wilderness he had lived day by day for fifty-four days, until he had found the survival pack in the plane. Then another thirty-five days through the northern summer, somehow living the same day-to-day pattern he had started just after the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically, &amp;lsquo;what if Brian&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; rescued at the end of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/22/hatchet/"&gt;Hatchet&lt;/a&gt; (and thus &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/29/the-river/"&gt;The River&lt;/a&gt; also doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen). He still gets the survival pack from the plane, but no radio for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it goes&amp;hellip; about as you&amp;rsquo;d expect? It&amp;rsquo;s very cold, but he figures out skins and furs. He does improve on his hunting supplies and learns more nature stuff?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, it&amp;rsquo;s more of the same, which honestly is okay. I liked it more than &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/29/the-river/"&gt;The River&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The River</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/29/the-river/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/29/the-river/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derek shook his head. “Not exactly. Bill and Erik are instructors, but I’m a psychologist. We work with people who may need to survive in bad situations—you know, like downed pilots, astronauts, soldiers. How to live off the land and get out safely.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What do you want with me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”Derek smiled. “You can probably guess. . . .”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian shook his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, to make it short, we want you to do it again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it went!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the idea. Brian is adjusting well enough, but still dreams of the wilderness. And now he has a chance to go back, so of course he does!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, with another along (ish), knives instead of a hatchet, and to a different lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, things have to go wrong&amp;hellip; And this time Brian finds himself needing to make a raft and go down the titular River to get help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting enough story, but I feel like there wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite as much there are in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/22/hatchet/"&gt;Hatchet&lt;/a&gt;? I&amp;rsquo;m curious what the rest have in store.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hatchet</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/22/hatchet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/22/hatchet/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patience, he thought. So much of this was patience - waiting, and thinking and doing things right. So much of all this, so much of all living was patience and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a book about patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had to keep thinking of them because if he forgot them and did not think of them they might forget about him. And he had to keep hoping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hunger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a quick read&amp;ndash;and it&amp;rsquo;s probably been 20 years since I last read it, so I figured I would give it another chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad book. It feels visceral at times, really making you aware of Brian. And knowing that&amp;ndash;because it&amp;rsquo;s that sort of book&amp;ndash;he has to survive at the end, you always have hope. Even if some of those situations are &lt;em&gt;so ridiculous&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, apparently, there are &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt; sequels? How in the world are they going to do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>