<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Garth Nix on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/garth-nix/</link><description>Recent content in Garth Nix on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/garth-nix/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Sinister Booksellers of Bath</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/12/the-sinister-booksellers-of-bath/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/12/the-sinister-booksellers-of-bath/</guid><description>&lt;p>I quite enjoyed &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/24/the-left-handed-booksellers-of-london/">The Left-Handed Booksellers of London&lt;/a>, but I&amp;rsquo;ll admit, I was a bit surprised to see that there actually was a sequel. I quite often find myself, after reading a book, wondering&amp;ndash;but what happened next?!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, here we go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the most part, The Sinister Booksellers of Bath (I do love the titles of these), is more of the same. Susan has been trying to go on and lead a normal life&amp;hellip; nope. Back into the magic! Merlin and Vivien are off doing magical things&amp;hellip; and stumble into trouble, needing Susan to help them out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do love reading about the three of them. I think Susan, growing and changing and coming to terms with her powers is really the heart of these stories and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping for even more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worldbuilding remains fantastical in a way that Garth Nix is so good at. We have a wonderful blend of real world and an underlying magic, with ancient powers, magical artifcats, and statues coming to life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m surprised but pleasantly so that the Left-Handed Booksellers had a sequel. If there&amp;rsquo;s ever a third in the future, I&amp;rsquo;ll most certainly give it a chance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But for now, onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Left-Handed Booksellers of London</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/24/the-left-handed-booksellers-of-london/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/24/the-left-handed-booksellers-of-london/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Books help us anchor our souls, or re-anchor them; particularly for us, the left-handed, given the things we have to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/12/abhorsen/">Abhorsen&lt;/a> is one of my favorite series, full stop. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-keys-to-the-kingdom/">The Keys to the Kingdom&lt;/a> were &amp;hellip; weird? But I remembered liking them well enough. And I haven&amp;rsquo;t been back to The Seventh Tower in years (since I started writing reviews). But somehow in there I managed to miss seeing the Left-Handed Booksellers of London.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun older, lighter style of urban fantasy, set in 1980s London. You have magical booksellers, a missing parent (who of course is going to be magical), and all manner of mysteries, beasties, and mysterious beasties. On top of that, some delightful side characters (Merlin St. Jacques is my favorite) and some magically described scenes.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I think Merlin has explained to you that the mythic landscape is layered, and usually quite local. Entities and environments are generally confined to a particular geographic area and often also to particular times of day or night, phases of the moon, that sort of thing. Even weather, as with the things that come out after rain, or only when it snows. And they are bound by custom and lore to behave in certain ways, to do certain things, and of course these days are mostly dormant anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I enjoyed this book. It&amp;rsquo;s not up to the level of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/01/sabriel/">Sabriel&lt;/a> and it&amp;rsquo;s sequels, but it was a fun read and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have found it. And I am curious where the apparent sequel might go, which is always a good sign.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Fantasy writers, they’re the bane of our existence!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Goldenhand</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/23/goldenhand/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/23/goldenhand/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Your librarians go into battle?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“When they must,” said Lirael. “The Library is very old, and deep, and contains many things that have been put away for good reason. Creatures, dangerous knowledge, artifacts made not wisely, but too well . . . books that should not be opened without proper preparation, some books that should never be opened at all.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Creatures?”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Clariel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/19/clariel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/19/clariel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Compared to the original trilogy, both Clariel the book and Cariel the character have a rather different feel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a book, Clariel takes place centuries before Sabriel, well before the fall of the Old Kingdom. We&amp;rsquo;re in an entirely different political landscape and rather than the general feeling of things coming back together (other than the whole end of the world thing), there&amp;rsquo;s a feel of falling apart. We&amp;rsquo;re square in the height of decadence that comes before the fall, with a failing monarchy, an Abhorsen who&amp;rsquo;d rather hunt than deal in death, and Charter Magic fallen out of fasion. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting time period to explore, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. It&amp;rsquo;s just rather different.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Abhorsen</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/12/abhorsen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/12/abhorsen/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I mentioned in , Abhorsen is really the second half of a book. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stand alone, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to. We continue where we left off in Lirael and things keep escalating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, we have a much deeper dig into the deep history of the world, into the roots of Free Magic beings and the Charter. We learn more about Mogget and the Dog both along with our big bad: Orannis, the Destroyer. On to the end of the world&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lirael</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/07/lirael/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/07/lirael/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lirael is a bit odd when it comes to a sequel. While it&amp;rsquo;s set in the same world as Sabriel (and Sabriel even has a part to play), Lirael takes place a fair few years later, following two new characters: Lirael&amp;ndash;daughter of the glacier bound seers only mentioned in Sabriel&amp;ndash;and Prince Sameth&amp;ndash;Sabriel and Touchstone&amp;rsquo;s son and Abhorsen in Waiting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once you get beyond the initial surprise at the change in topic, it&amp;rsquo;s another wonderful book. I&amp;rsquo;m honestly not sure which I prefer. Lirael is a wonderful character. She&amp;rsquo;s an outsider among an entire people who have an ability she does not, which is a recognizable situation to be in who turns into what&amp;rsquo;s effectively a battle librarian&amp;ndash;who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love a battle librarian?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sabriel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/01/sabriel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/01/sabriel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sabriel is a wonderful book. Fantasy books dealing with death magic are among my favorites, the worldbuilding is fantastic (in the truest sense of the world), and the main characters are all a lot of fun. Each time I spend long enough without reading it, I always forget just how much I enjoy reading (or in this case listening too) this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worldbuilding is great. You don&amp;rsquo;t get the sense of mechanical precision you would get from someone like Sanderson, but it&amp;rsquo;s a world that feels both magical and &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo;, which is always something I&amp;rsquo;m looking for. In particular, the idea of a magical world and a WWIish era technological world, separated by a sometimes porous wall is a neat one. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s not an uncommon trope, I have yet to find a book that does it quite as well. Especially the eponymous Sabriel&amp;rsquo;s experience being born and of one kingdom, but raised in a boarding school and with the perspective of the other. I really want to know so much more than we&amp;rsquo;re given about this history of this world&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lord Sunday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/01/05/lord-sunday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/01/05/lord-sunday/</guid><description>&lt;p>Overall, everything I was hoping for in an ending to the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We get to see a lot of Sunday and Sunday&amp;rsquo;s realm: the Incomparable Gardens. It makes as much sense as anything in the rest of the House, so just go with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Superior Saturday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/01/04/superior-saturday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/01/04/superior-saturday/</guid><description>&lt;p>I like the visuals around Saturday&amp;rsquo;s realm. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the better ones when it comes to motivation and the idea of a gigantic clockwork tower stretching upwards&amp;hellip; cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, we saw even less of Saturday than we did of Friday, which is saying something. I think she and Arthur were in the same scene for maybe a half dozen paragraphs? It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird. I assume we&amp;rsquo;ll see more of her in the next book, but it&amp;rsquo;s something of a departure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lady Friday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/01/03/lady-friday/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/01/03/lady-friday/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting throughout the whole series, Nix has managed to combine a relatively formulaic story with new twists and weird new worlds in each and every book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The House just keeps getting weirder. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how it&amp;rsquo;s even really a &amp;lsquo;House&amp;rsquo; at all. I think originally it was going to be and the Tuesday and Wednesday happened&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sir Thursday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/01/02/sir-thursday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/01/02/sir-thursday/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not much to say. Onwards and upwards for Arthur, taking on another of the Trustees and gaining another of the Keys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pretty much all of the problems in this book seemed overly easy to subdue, the Skinless Boy and Sir Thursday included. I think this has been going on for all of the rest of the books, but it seemed even more obvious in this one. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s a factor of how relatively short they are?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Drowned Wednesday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/drowned-wednesday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/drowned-wednesday/</guid><description>&lt;p>The world of the Keys to the Kingdom continues to get more interesting and weirder all at once. This time around, we have a sort of Multiversal Ocean and the Morrow Day that governs it. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting world all itself, with ships that were once other things, uplifted rats, and a very Nix&amp;rsquo;ian version of the Jonah and Whale story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s neat to finally see one of the Morrow Days that actually wants to help. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing we won&amp;rsquo;t see much of that with the other half.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Grim Tuesday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/grim-tuesday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/grim-tuesday/</guid><description>&lt;p>Of course they&amp;rsquo;re all going to take place over a week (Earth time)&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s really not much different between Mister Monday and Grim Tuesday. Arthur is starting to accept his fate while at the same time learning more about the rules of the House. It interesting to see him change even in just the first two books thus far.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mister Monday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/30/mister-monday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/30/mister-monday/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that Arthur died. He had a massive asthma attack, and, as his oxygen starved brain struggled its last, he hallucinated all of the rest. How else do you describe just how &amp;hellip; odd this book is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, I liked it. It&amp;rsquo;s weird. Garth Nix really does his Proper Nouns. Everything felt like it Meant Something, although we never quite got a perfect idea what Anything was. Most of them were close enough though; so it goes. It&amp;rsquo;s quick and the action picks you up and pulls you right through the story. When it&amp;rsquo;s over, there&amp;rsquo;s something of a feel of getting off a roller coaster, but in a good way.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>