<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Wildersongs Trilogy on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/06/the-wildersongs-trilogy/</link><description>Recent content in The Wildersongs Trilogy on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/06/the-wildersongs-trilogy/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sorcery and Small Magics</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/06/sorcery-and-small-magics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/06/sorcery-and-small-magics/</guid><description>&lt;p>A world in which magic is split between those who can write spells and those who can cast them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A forbidden spell gone horribly wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And a quest to try to undo it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s actually a really fun story. I enjoyed the magic school aspects of it and it had a nice whimsical &lt;em>magical&lt;/em> feeling to the magic that you don&amp;rsquo;t always see, even in fantasy novels. Once we get out of the school, we see more of the hidden, dangerous parts of the world, driving more to the fantastical&amp;ndash;and deadly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On another tack, this book is tagged romance and LBGT. If anything, it&amp;rsquo;s more of magical adventure story with the first hints of what could turn out to be romance&amp;ndash;but not in this book. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting thread woven through the story&amp;ndash;especially in how it&amp;rsquo;s interacting with aforementioned forbidden spell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, the interplay between our main characters&amp;ndash;Leo (writer, POV) and Grimm (caster) is fascinating. Leo&amp;rsquo;s family is rich, Grimm&amp;rsquo;s is not. Leo is born talented and refuses to apply himself; Grimm has worked &lt;em>hard&lt;/em> to get where he is and it shows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That dynamic drives the entire story and it, as much as anything, is why I&amp;rsquo;d love to see where the story goes in the (hopefully coming soon?) sequel. It&amp;rsquo;s a well enough wrapped up story, but oh, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those where I want to see what happens next!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth a read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>