<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Taskmaster on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/taskmaster/</link><description>Recent content in Taskmaster on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/taskmaster/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 9</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</guid><description>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s quite a cast.
Alan Davies: The old one. Desiree Burch: She certainly goes all out. Guz Khan: Those eyes. Morgana Robinson: So very emotive… The word that comes to mind is ‘fae’ Victoria Coren Mitchell: Subtle and hilarious when you realize it. Series reviews:
An inbalance in the poppability
Well that started delightfully risqué, escalates to swearing at Alex, and ended up with a prize task submission… of Personally the chair he’s sitting on.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 9</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</guid><description>A great season! I loved all of the people on here. I was writing up my favorite and &amp;hellip; I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it. They&amp;rsquo;re all a lot of fun.
First entry in the first task: How large are Greg Davies’ shits… We’re off to quite a season. Hiding eggplants is a wonderful task. “It’s amazing how much it compacts down into a baby’s head.” “You scored the same as Rose… and she couldn’t see.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 7</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/07/taskmaster-series-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/07/taskmaster-series-7/</guid><description>Rounding out the first 8 series that are available directly on YouTube in the US, finally Series 7!
Man this was a season. Man those are some characters. James Acaster has a barely contained rage beneath his humor (sometimes now so barely). Jessica Knappett, hilarious with some crazy outfits. Kerry Godliman: a wonderfully direct way to solving tasks. Phil Wang (and Phil Wang&amp;rsquo;s wang). That outfit&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a thing. And Rhod Gilbert.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-1/</guid><description>Finally back to where it all began. We have a bit of trying to find the show&amp;rsquo;s footing. I think Romesh Ranganathan was my favorite this series.
Favorite task:
Episode 1, Task 2: Eat as much watermelon as possible in one minute. HULK SMASH! Also, totally throwing up. It&amp;rsquo;s probably the weakest season, but it more than gets a pass for all the wonderful things that came to be later.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-6/</guid><description>I really like most of the people in this season. Alice Levine seems straight laced and perhaps sweet until she throws something at you out of left field. Asim Chaudhry hit the &amp;lsquo;you&amp;rsquo;re going to lose now&amp;rsquo;, although didn&amp;rsquo;t actually end up coming in last. Tim Vine though&amp;hellip; oh Tim Vine. There always has to be one in a crazy outfit and he performs most of the tasks in some sort of safari outfit and hat.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/23/taskmaster-series-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/23/taskmaster-series-4/</guid><description>Oh Noel Fielding. You&amp;rsquo;re &amp;hellip; a class all your own. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many other people that had so very many 1 and 5 point tasks with little in between. Having Mel Giedroyc there as well (also from the Great British Bake Off) was extra amusing. Another favorite of mine though was Hugh Dennis. So very British sense of humor.
Favorite tasks:
Episode 1, Task 1: Most unusual autograph on the most unusual vegetable.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/taskmaster-series-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/taskmaster-series-2/</guid><description>Back one more!
Richard Osman is just wonderful in this season. He can really give Greg Davies a run for his money. But I think even better is Katherine Ryan. She&amp;rsquo;s snarky and hilarious. I wish they had more than one woman on the earlier seasons, but if you only have one, she was a good one!
Favorite tasks:
Episode 1, Task 2: Place three exercise balls on a yoga mat on top of a hill.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/07/taskmaster-series-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/07/taskmaster-series-3/</guid><description>Further back! Season 3!
I don&amp;rsquo;t have as much to say about the contestants this time around, except for Paul Chowdhry. Such a resting emotionless face&amp;hellip; unless he&amp;rsquo;s full of a deep rage. It makes it hilarious. And he got robbed&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s starting to seem kinda racist. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s just my own viewing order?
A few favorite moments:
Episode 1, Task 3: Propel a pea the furthest distance and land on a red carpet.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/taskmaster-series-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/taskmaster-series-5/</guid><description>More out of order! This time back to Series 5!
Contestants:
Aisling Bea: Irish names are kind of crazy looking sometimes. And so is Aisling Bea. She has a wonderful sort of manic energy throughout the show. Bob Mortimer: He has some of the most bananas ways of solving tasks. Great fun. Mark Watson: A wonderfully dry sense of humor. You can never quite be sure if he&amp;rsquo;s serious or messing with you.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 8</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/taskmaster-series-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/taskmaster-series-8/</guid><description>Oh Taskmaster. It&amp;rsquo;s such a wonderfully ridiculous show. Whoever decided that they should upload the episodes to YouTube for everyone* to watch should absolutely be given a shiny golden metallic head.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, go watch it right now. Each series has five different mostly British comedians competing in a number of inane tasks and being judged harshly (if humorously) by Taskmaster Greg Davis while Little Alex Horne (who actually produces the show) keeps everything more or less on track.</description></item></channel></rss>