<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pendragon on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/pendragon/</link><description>Recent content in Pendragon on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/pendragon/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black Water</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/29/black-water/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/29/black-water/</guid><description>&lt;p>I tried. Really I did. But when you read as quickly as I do and realize that you&amp;rsquo;ve already spent more than a month on one book, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think most of my frustration with this book comes from the fact that Pendragon is a teenager and acts like it. He is hit in the face with a world where humanoid cats are the dominant species and humans are little more than animals and just &lt;em>cannot get it through his head&lt;/em>. Over and over, he expects the world to work one way, despite all evidence to the contrary.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Reality Bug</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/16/the-reality-bug/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/16/the-reality-bug/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onwards! This time around, Pendragon has come to the territory of Veelox, dealing with a virtual reality addiction crisis. It&amp;rsquo;s a topic that comes up over and over again in science fiction and even in real world media coverage, warning that as virtual reality gets better and better, it will be harder and harder for people to leave, leading to society decaying. Regardless of what you think about the idea of such a thing happening in the real world, it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting enough take to build the story on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, Aja is actually one of the more interesting travelers we&amp;rsquo;ve been introduced to. She&amp;rsquo;s so confident in herself at first that she nearly refuses Bobby&amp;rsquo;s help, but as could be expected, things go sideways. She seems to learn from her mistakes and finally admits that perhaps she can&amp;rsquo;t save the world all by herself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Never War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/03/the-never-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/03/the-never-war/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You want to know why we&amp;rsquo;re the ones responsible?&amp;quot; Gunny asked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I looked up into a pair of wise eyes that had seen far more than mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Because there&amp;rsquo;s nobody else,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Lost City of Faar</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/27/the-lost-city-of-faar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/27/the-lost-city-of-faar/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the continuing stories of Bobby Pendragon, this time around he has to save the ocean Territory of Cloral. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating world, where at some point in the long past, the world flooded such that everyone now lives in floating cities. They have all sorts of neat water based technology and what seems like a pretty peaceful, fun loving society. Of course things are about to go wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, things seem mostly straightforward. There&amp;rsquo;s a lost city (Farr; &lt;span class="spoiler">which of course turns out to be real&lt;/span>
), pirates, and an &amp;lsquo;accidental&amp;rsquo; plague (oh! the horrors of GMO foods!). Nothing super surprising, but still enough tension to pull you through the book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Merchant of Death</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/13/the-merchant-of-death/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/13/the-merchant-of-death/</guid><description>&lt;p>I know I&amp;rsquo;ve read / the Pendragon books before, but it&amp;rsquo;s been long enough that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even say for sure when. It might have even been back when I was the same age as the eponymous protagonist Bobby Pendragon rather than more than twice that. I think I enjoyed it quite a bit though, so worth giving it a chance to reread.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, the main characters were well enough done for the most part. They all felt distinct and for the most part felt real. The main counterpoints to that is the &amp;lsquo;big bad&amp;rsquo; of the book Saint Dane&amp;ndash;you can almost hear the mustache twirling and mwahahaing&amp;ndash;and the &amp;rsquo;little* bad&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;an overweight caricature of the &amp;lsquo;corrupt queen&amp;rsquo;, constantly eating and laughing at the slaughter&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>