<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Victor LaValle on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/victor-lavalle/</link><description>Recent content in Victor LaValle on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/victor-lavalle/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Ballad of Black Tom</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/15/the-ballad-of-black-tom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/15/the-ballad-of-black-tom/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Walking through Harlem first thing in the morning was like being a single drop of blood inside an enormous body that was waking up. Brick and mortar, elevated train tracks, and miles of underground pipe, this city lived; day and night it thrived.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>At first, it&amp;rsquo;s a story about a black man in the boroughs of New York in the 1920s. A gritty world, but somehow &lt;em>alive&lt;/em>, dripping with some wonderfully written descriptions of the people and places of the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Sleeping King is dead but dreaming.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Things take a somewhat supernatural turn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is another of those cases where I put a book on my &amp;rsquo;to read&amp;rsquo; list because it looked interesting and, before getting around to it, completely forgot it was going to be about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By the end&amp;hellip; that took a much &lt;em>darker&lt;/em> track than I was expecting&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&amp;hellip; and that&amp;rsquo;s starting from the point of view of racial disparity and violence in the 1920s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then&amp;hellip; things get even darker. But I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that for you to read.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nobody ever thinks of himself as a villain, does he? Even monsters hold high opinions of themselves.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s short. ~150 pages or a few hours audio. But I think it does a good job of hitting hard without overstaying it&amp;rsquo;s welcome. If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of cosmic horror / weird fiction, I think you&amp;rsquo;ll like it. I certainly did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Changeling</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/26/the-changeling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/26/the-changeling/</guid><description>&lt;p>On one level, it&amp;rsquo;s about fatherhood. Apollo grew up without a dad and vows he&amp;rsquo;s going to do better by his own son. And right from the beginning&amp;ndash;a surprise delivery no one around was quite ready for&amp;ndash;he does everything he can. As a father, with my youngest about the age of Apollo&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; when things go sideways. But we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On another level, it&amp;rsquo;s about motherhood. Emma had all sorts of issues of her own, but she and Apollo seem absolutely delightful together. So when the first signs of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/postpartum%20depression">postpartum depression&lt;/a> start, it&amp;rsquo;s terrifying and entirely too relatable to many parents out there. New babies are hard, not going to lie, and everyone deals with that completely differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a third, it&amp;rsquo;s about fairy tales and other stories. The stories we read to our children and the stories we tell ourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on a last level, it&amp;rsquo;s about magic. There are hints right from the beginning that there&amp;rsquo;s something strange in this world. From Apollo&amp;rsquo;s dreams of his absent father, to the magic inheriant in old books and libraries, to finding a postcard from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aleister%20Crowley">Aleister Crowley&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s little in the way of obviously supernatural for most of the book&amp;hellip; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t last.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>