<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Wheel of Time (TV) on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-wheel-of-time-tv/</link><description>Recent content in The Wheel of Time (TV) on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-wheel-of-time-tv/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Wheel of Time: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/09/the-wheel-of-time-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/09/the-wheel-of-time-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wheel of Time turns, and ages come and pass, leaving memories that become legend. Legend fades to myth, and even myth is long forgotten when the Age that gave it birth comes again. In one Age, called the Third Age by some, an Age yet to come, an Age long past, a wind rose in the Mountains of Mist. The wind was not the beginning. There are neither beginnings nor endings to the turning of the Wheel of time. But it was a beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/"&gt;The Wheel of Time: Season 1&lt;/a&gt; had a lot of potential&amp;hellip; and also a lot of issues. Especially when it came to the last couple episodes. COVID, sure. A main actor leaving, I get it. But it&amp;rsquo;s still a rough ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it was with cautious optimism, we approached Season 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very much a new turning of the wheel. Some things they changed really do work well. It&amp;rsquo;s not the books, but it&amp;rsquo;s a new story in the same world. Some&amp;hellip; less so. But not everything is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I loved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The casting. Ishamael was great in Season 1 and even better in Season 2. Lanfear is a great counter to him. Aviendha and Elayne fit really well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It bears repeating: Ishamael and Lanfear are great. Leaning a bit more into terrifying even than the books, which quite frankly they needed. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see (and hope they don&amp;rsquo;t screw up&amp;hellip;) the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Almost&lt;/em&gt; everything about the Seanchan. They feel &amp;lsquo;off&amp;rsquo; in just the right way. The one exception&amp;hellip; the Damane pacifiers. I really don&amp;rsquo;t get that &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liandrin. She&amp;rsquo;s still terrible, but I really like how they turned up the &lt;em&gt;reason&lt;/em&gt; why she is as she is. And she&amp;rsquo;s quite the actor to pull it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things that I did not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ending. Check out the &lt;a href="#8-what-was-meant-to-be"&gt;individual review&lt;/a&gt; for more details, but &amp;hellip; this wasn&amp;rsquo;t any better than the previous season. And they don&amp;rsquo;t even have unexpected troubles to deal with. I&amp;rsquo;m starting to feel they really just don&amp;rsquo;t know how to write endings&amp;hellip; which is weird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, other than a few things, I quite enjoyed it. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Season 3. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Wheel of Time: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wheel of Time turns, and ages come and pass, leaving memories that become legend. Legend fades to myth, and even myth is long forgotten when the Age that gave it birth comes again. In one Age, called the Third Age by some, an Age yet to come, an Age long past, a wind rose in the Mountains of Mist. The wind was not the beginning. There are neither beginnings nor endings to the turning of the Wheel of time. But it was a beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>