<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2018-book-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2018 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2018-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2018 Reading List Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/31/2018-reading-list-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/31/2018-reading-list-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another year of reading. Still not back to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/2015-reading-list-retrospective/&#34;&gt;glory days of 100 books in a year&lt;/a&gt;, but otherwise the second best I&amp;rsquo;ve done (beating out &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/31/2016-reading-list-retrospective/&#34;&gt;91 in 2016&lt;/a&gt;!). A solid year. I&amp;rsquo;m going to see if I can purposely try to hit 100 again next year though. Should be doable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;😄&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Darkling Plain</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/31/a-darkling-plain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/31/a-darkling-plain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;219110&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/219110.a-darkling-plain&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-darkling-plain.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it ends. I&amp;rsquo;ve had some issues with this series (mostly with some of the relationship drama present throughout), but I&amp;rsquo;m glad I finished it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characterwise, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I liked what happened to either Tom or Hester. Tom is entirely too naive. Pennyroyal literally shot him&amp;ndash;and this is likely to kill him one day. He enslaved Tom&amp;rsquo;s daughter. And he doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to care. He&amp;rsquo;s good to a fault and it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem real. Hester&amp;hellip; is crazy and violent and full of a desire for vengeance and it&amp;rsquo;s only worse this time around. This time it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel unreal&amp;ndash;what does that say about me?&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s still sad that she ended up this way. Wren and Theo I liked a lot more. I wish they would have spent less time separated nearly missing one another again and again, but it works out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Furies of Calderon</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/29/furies-of-calderon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/29/furies-of-calderon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;29396&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29396.furies-of-calderon&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/furies-of-calderon.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently I last read Furies of Calderon before I started writing reviews. That was actually the second time I read it&amp;ndash;the first time I didn&amp;rsquo;t even finish the book, putting it down. It&amp;rsquo;s something of a slow book and a bit strange. But the second time and especially once I got into the sequels, I loved it, it&amp;rsquo;s among my favorite series. This time around, I listened to it and it&amp;rsquo;s even better as an audiobook (since it just keeps right on going through the boring parts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, the story is that Codex Alera arose out of a bar bet. Take some random topic and write a story about it. In this case, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legio_IX_Hispana&#34;&gt;Lost Roman Legion&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pokemon&#34;&gt;Pokemon&lt;/a&gt;. Sounds crazy, but it kind of works. From the Roman half, you end up with essentially a Roman empire with holds and legions that have fought to tear out a land for themselves from a variety of enemies all around. From the Pokemon, you have Furies, elemental spirits of the land, sea, and air which all of the Alerans[^Tavi] have some ability to control for various tasks: the strength of an earth fury, healing with water furies, flying with air. Pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predator&#39;s Gold</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/09/predators-gold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/09/predators-gold/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On one hand, Predator&amp;rsquo;s Gold does a solid job of expanding on what was the best part of Mortal Engines: the world building all around mobile cities that eat one another. We get to see a few more cities&amp;ndash;both predators and trading cities&amp;ndash;along with more details on airships in this world. But the real worldbuilding gold&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is in the parasites that can attach themselves to cities and steal from them. It really makes the cities feel like gigantic living organisms as much as anything, which I&amp;rsquo;m sure is Reeve&amp;rsquo;s intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I very nearly put Predator&amp;rsquo;s Gold down several times during the first half of the book. There&amp;rsquo;s a rather blatant love triangle between Tom, Hester, and Freya (princess of Anchorage&amp;ndash;roving city of the north nearly destroyed by a plague in the recent past). It really doesn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense given Tom and Hester&amp;rsquo;s relationship at the end of the first book and drags on way too long. Perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s what some people read the book for&amp;hellip; but it&amp;rsquo;s really not for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Into the Drowning Deep</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/05/into-the-drowning-deep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/05/into-the-drowning-deep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;34913896&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34913896.into-the-drowning-deep&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/into-the-drowning-deep.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well. That is certainly a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It basically reads like Mira Grant thought: you know what&amp;rsquo;s kind of creepy but doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have that many books written about them? Mermaids. And just went with it. It works though. Creepy as heck at times and once things start happening around halfway through the book, they really don&amp;rsquo;t stop. The ending is a bit weak and leaves me wanting more answers, but not enough to ruin the entire book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rook</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/03/the-rook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/03/the-rook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She came to a decision, pulled her feet out of the mire, and stepped carefully over the ring of bodies that were scattered around her. They were all motionless, and all of them were wearing latex gloves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far as openings go, that was certainly one to get my attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Burning Maze</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/11/17/the-burning-maze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/11/17/the-burning-maze/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On one hand, the Apollo books are getting better. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly more of the same, bringing myths to life in the real world combined with a constant sense of the world ending, but if that&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for &amp;hellip; power to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there&amp;rsquo;s a prophecy that  &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;either Pipe or Jason&lt;/span&gt;
  is going to die. Of course you expect they&amp;rsquo;ll figure out a way around it&amp;hellip; Apollo is a (former?) god of prophecy after all? But madman that Riordan is, he actually does it. Ow. That was not at all what I expected to see in one of these books. Given the Doors of Death etc we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in these series, it&amp;rsquo;s still possible they&amp;rsquo;ll figure out a work around&amp;hellip; but still. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Prophecy</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/27/the-dark-prophecy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/27/the-dark-prophecy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; is straight up a sequal to . Pretty much all of my comments from  apply here. Apollo is still a decent but not great main character, Meg is still odd and weirdly powerful. The world still feels like something we&amp;rsquo;ve seen done better in Riordan&amp;rsquo;s other series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main different of the Dark Prophecy and the part that amused me the most: it&amp;rsquo;s almost completely set in Indianapolis. You don&amp;rsquo;t get that overly often in fiction and it&amp;rsquo;s always amusing to see it done. For someone that lives within spitting distance of Indianapolis, close enough.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goldenhand</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/23/goldenhand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/23/goldenhand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;29414640&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29414640.goldenhand&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/goldenhand.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Your librarians go into battle?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When they must,” said Lirael. “The Library is very old, and deep, and contains many things that have been put away for good reason. Creatures, dangerous knowledge, artifacts made not wisely, but too well . . . books that should not be opened without proper preparation, some books that should never be opened at all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Creatures?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clariel</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/19/clariel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/19/clariel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;20662728&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20662728.clariel&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/clariel.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to the original trilogy, both Clariel the book and Cariel the character have a rather different feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a book, Clariel takes place centuries before Sabriel, well before the fall of the Old Kingdom. We&amp;rsquo;re in an entirely different political landscape and rather than the general feeling of things coming back together (other than the whole end of the world thing), there&amp;rsquo;s a feel of falling apart. We&amp;rsquo;re square in the height of decadence that comes before the fall, with a failing monarchy, an Abhorsen who&amp;rsquo;d rather hunt than deal in death, and Charter Magic fallen out of fasion. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting time period to explore, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. It&amp;rsquo;s just rather different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abhorsen</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/12/abhorsen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/12/abhorsen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;334643&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/334643.abhorsen&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/abhorsen.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in , Abhorsen is really the second half of a book. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stand alone, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to. We continue where we left off in Lirael and things keep escalating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worldbuildingwise, we have a much deeper dig into the deep history of the world, into the roots of Free Magic beings and the Charter. We learn more about Mogget and the Dog both along with our big bad: Orannis, the Destroyer. On to the end of the world&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoe&#39;s Tale</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/11/zoes-tale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/11/zoes-tale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, Zoe&amp;rsquo;s Tale is The Last Colony told from Zoe&amp;rsquo;s point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It definitely has a different feel to it than the rest of the Old Man&amp;rsquo;s War books, matching the idea that it was written by a teenage girl (having never been one, I can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee the accuracy, but it worked for me).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lirael</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/07/lirael/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/07/lirael/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;47624&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/47624.lirael&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/lirael.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lirael is a bit odd when it comes to a sequel. While it&amp;rsquo;s set in the same world as Sabriel (and Sabriel even has a part to play), Lirael takes place a fair few years later, following two new characters: Lirael&amp;ndash;daughter of the glacier bound seers only mentioned in Sabriel&amp;ndash;and Prince Sameth&amp;ndash;Sabriel and Touchstone&amp;rsquo;s son and Abhorsen in Waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you get beyond the initial surprise at the change in topic, it&amp;rsquo;s another wonderful book. I&amp;rsquo;m honestly not sure which I prefer. Lirael is a wonderful character. She&amp;rsquo;s an outsider among an entire people who have an ability she does not, which is a recognizable situation to be in who turns into what&amp;rsquo;s effectively a battle librarian&amp;ndash;who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love a battle librarian?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabriel</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/01/sabriel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/01/sabriel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sabriel is a wonderful book. Fantasy books dealing with death magic are among my favorites, the worldbuilding is fantastic (in the truest sense of the world), and the main characters are all a lot of fun. Each time I spend long enough without reading it, I always forget just how much I enjoy reading (or in this case listening too) this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worldbuilding is great. You don&amp;rsquo;t get the sense of mechanical precision you would get from someone like Sanderson, but it&amp;rsquo;s a world that feels both magical and &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo;, which is always something I&amp;rsquo;m looking for. In particular, the idea of a magical world and a WWIish era technological world, separated by a sometimes porous wall is a neat one. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s not an uncommon trope, I have yet to find a book that does it quite as well. Especially the eponymous Sabriel&amp;rsquo;s experience being born and of one kingdom, but raised in a boarding school and with the perspective of the other. I really want to know so much more than we&amp;rsquo;re given about this history of this world&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Oracle</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/30/the-hidden-oracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/30/the-hidden-oracle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; is an odd book. As a second sequel series to first  and then the , we do get new main characters characters: Apollo, now in mortal form and Meg, surprisingly powerful plant magic demigod with some cool Roman swords. But we also get a number of guest appearances and references to previous characters: especially Percy Jackson himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting have a setting and characters we can relate to to help ground us in the new series, but on the other hand, if I wanted to read about Percy Jackson, couldn&amp;rsquo;t I just read his series again? I remember having the same problem with Heroes of Olympus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Colony</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/26/the-last-colony/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/26/the-last-colony/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After John&amp;rsquo;s story in  and Jane&amp;rsquo;s (to some extent) in , this time around we get both of them. They&amp;rsquo;re together now and raising Zoë (how&amp;rsquo;s that for a complicated family), when they&amp;rsquo;re tapped to head an entirely new colony planet Roanoke&amp;ndash;with the first city named Croatoan. Also&amp;hellip; why would they even agree to that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean&amp;hellip; come on. Either no one knows the history behind the names&amp;ndash;in which case why in the world would they be using them&amp;ndash;or they do&amp;ndash;in which case why in the world would you choose &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; to name your new colony. Granted, they turn out to want it to be lost, but still. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit annoying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ptolemy&#39;s Gate</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/ptolemys-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/ptolemys-gate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nathaniel is 17 now, the sweetheart of the government after saving everyone in  and even worse when it comes to believing the goverment&amp;rsquo;s line about the supremacy of magicians and mistreating Bartimaeus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might guess, in much the same way as in , I didn&amp;rsquo;t really care for Nathaniel. Bartimaeus is still pretty cool, but where this book really shines is seeing what Kitty has gotten up to over the past few years and actually digging into what Ptolemy was like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Amber Spyglass</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/the-amber-spyglass/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/the-amber-spyglass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; is really a sequel to  more than a conclusion to  . Most everything that I liked in the Golden Compass but was missing in The Subtle Knife is still missing here, while the new additions that annoyed me about The Subtle Knife are turned up to 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get fascinating new worlds (miniature spies with poisonous spines on their feet! creatures with wheels! how weird!) but to the most part they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to really lead to the story. Lyra&amp;hellip; is growing up and supposed to be super important to the upcoming battle, but really this is again a book about Will. And Lyra&amp;rsquo;s big part? Growing up. That&amp;rsquo;s about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief History of Time</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/17/a-brief-history-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/17/a-brief-history-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;3869&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3869.a-brief-history-of-time&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-brief-history-of-time.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oof. That&amp;rsquo;s an intense book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hawking does an impressive job of making cosmology and the Big Bang and black holes seem relatively digestable, but even for me&amp;ndash;with a strong background in mathematics, a pretty decent one in at least undergradate level physics and a stronger study specifically in quantum weirdness, albeit more from a computational perspective&amp;ndash;this book is hard to read at times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Subtle Knife</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/17/the-subtle-knife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/17/the-subtle-knife/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; takes off where  left off, with Lyra leaving her world behind, traveling across a bridge originally torn by the death of a friend. On top of that, we have a new character in Will, a boy searching for his missing father, instead finding another, must less dramatic way to travel between worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some extent, The Subtle Knife feels like an odd sequel. Where the Golden Compass centered almost entirely around Lyra, this time around, we&amp;rsquo;re split between Lyra and Will, with Will really the driving force behind the story. I don&amp;rsquo;t mind Will&amp;ndash;he&amp;rsquo;s unlikable at first, but you fell that&amp;rsquo;s mostly because&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golden Compass</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/14/the-golden-compass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/14/the-golden-compass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read  before, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a few years. On top of that, this time around, I listened to it as an audiobook (the full cast reading, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there is another). I have fond memories of this book and for the most part, they were met on re-read, which is something you don&amp;rsquo;t always get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of the book is a world where people&amp;rsquo;s spirits / souls / conscious exists as a separate being, a daemon who takes the form of an animal companion &amp;ndash;changing and mutable at first and eventually settling into a single form for adults that represents the core of who they are. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting idea and well done, to the point that it feels natural, to the point that I almost wish I could live in this world, just to see who my daemon might be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Memory of Light</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/11/a-memory-of-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/11/a-memory-of-light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;7743175&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7743175.a-memory-of-light&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-memory-of-light.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no endings, and never will be endings, to the turning of the Wheel of Time. But it was an ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And oh what an ending it was.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ghost Brigades</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/08/the-ghost-brigades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/08/the-ghost-brigades/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After I read , I went looking for the sequels. While on paper  is the second in the series, it&amp;rsquo;s surprisingly different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get a lot more of a look into the CDF and specifically Special Forces, which was something that was interesting from the first book.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towers of Midnight</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/04/towers-of-midnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/04/towers-of-midnight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; continues the final avalanche to the Last Battle, with Lan continuing to gathering followers, the Black Tower continuing to grow more and more corrupt, Perrin confronting the Whitecloaks (it&amp;rsquo;s about time that storyline wraps up), and the newly healed Rand causing even more chaos than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people, when asked what they notice most about the change from Jordan&amp;rsquo;s writing to Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s mention that Mat is different. Honestly, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really notice it. I like Mat&amp;ndash;Mat in all his guises. Poisoned by the dagger. Helping his friends no matter what. Son of Battle, Prince of the Ravens. He&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite characters. If he feels different under Sanderson, it almost feels like growing up. After all:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gathering Storm</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/30/the-gathering-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/30/the-gathering-storm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The end is near,&amp;quot; Moridin said. &amp;ldquo;The Wheel has groaned its final rotation, the clock has lost its spring, the serpent heaves its final gasps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Man&#39;s War</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/23/old-mans-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/23/old-mans-war/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did two things on my seventy-fifth birthday. I visited my wife’s grave. Then I joined the army.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Golem&#39;s Eye</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/23/the-golems-eye/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/23/the-golems-eye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To as large extent,  continues where  left off. Nathaniel is a rising star, now climbing the ranks of government and Bartimaeus is just as snarky as ever. We get quite a bit more (including POV time) from Kitty and her friends, showing that it&amp;rsquo;s not all fun and games in this particular echo of London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting that Nathaniel grew up so quickly and is in government now. To go with the inevitable comparisons to Harry Potter the first book raised, it&amp;rsquo;s as if we&amp;rsquo;d skipped right by books 2-7 and went straight to Harry&amp;rsquo;s training as an Auror. I actually really appreciate that; it&amp;rsquo;s something new. EVen if it does strain credulity somewhat. He&amp;rsquo;s 14 for crying out loud&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knife of Dreams</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/22/knife-of-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/22/knife-of-dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;13888&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13888.knife-of-dreams&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/knife-of-dreams.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lan told me once that Malkier lives so long as one man wears the hadori in pledge that he will fight the Shadow, so long as one woman wears the ki&amp;rsquo;sain in pledge that she will send her sons to fight the Shadow. I wear the ki&amp;rsquo;sain, Master Aldragoran. My husband wears the hadori. So do you. Will Lan Mandragoran ride to the Last Battle alone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;13888&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13888.knife-of-dreams&#34;&gt;Knife of Dreams&lt;/a&gt;, in which things begin moving again as the world begins the march to the Last Battle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossroads of Twilight</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/16/crossroads-of-twilight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/16/crossroads-of-twilight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;113435&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/113435.crossroads-of-twilight&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/crossroads-of-twilight.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is a dream, and everyone wakes eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elayne continuing to solidify her hold in Caemlyn, all while being pregnant. Okay then.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter&#39;s Heart</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/09/winters-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/09/winters-heart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man who trusts everyone is a fool and a man who trusts no one is a fool. We are all fools if we live long enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, entirely too much of  if taken up by Perrin attempting to rescue Faile and Elayne solidifying her grip on the Lion Throne. Either is an interesting enough plot line to carry for a little while, but they just go on and on&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d mind if either was shortened significantly or even dropped entirely if/when the Wheel of Time goes to TV.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Path of Daggers</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/01/the-path-of-daggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/01/the-path-of-daggers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How do you know when a woman wants to kill you?” Rand mused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When she knows your name?” Dobraine did not sound as if he were joking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Crown of Swords</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/25/a-crown-of-swords/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/25/a-crown-of-swords/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;13890&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13890.a-crown-of-swords&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-crown-of-swords.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so begins the slog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;13890&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13890.a-crown-of-swords&#34;&gt;A Crown of Swords&lt;/a&gt; is by far the slowest book of the series thus far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortal Engines</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/25/mortal-engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/25/mortal-engines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a dark, blustery afternoon in spring, and the city of London was chasing a small mining town across the dried-out bed of the old North Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon the city was lumbering in pursuit, a moving mountain of metal that rose in seven tiers like the layers of a wedding cake, the lower levels wreathed in engine smoke, the villas of the rich gleaming white on the higher decks, and above it all the cross on top of St. Paul’s Cathedral glinting gold, two thousand feet above the ruined earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Amulet of Samarkand</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/22/the-amulet-of-samarkand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/22/the-amulet-of-samarkand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, as if written by the hand of a bad novelist, an incredible thing happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; is a fun book. It feels someone like a grittier Harry Potter, where instead of the bright and shiny flick of a wand, you summon demons. Instead of a fantastic hidden castle in the woods, you have Arthur Underwood&amp;ndash;imagine if Harry was tutored throughout his magical career by a slightly more competent Vernon Dursley. And instead of a dark wizard coming to kill you because of an accident of your birth&amp;hellip; well, Nathaniel does a pretty good job of bringing trouble down upon his own head.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lord of Chaos</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/19/lord-of-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/19/lord-of-chaos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;35231&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35231.lord-of-chaos&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/lord-of-chaos.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;35231&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35231.lord-of-chaos&#34;&gt; Lord of Chaos &lt;/a&gt; rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rand is trying to rule Cairhien and Caemlyn, Tear and the Aiel. Egwene is &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;raised Amyrlin Seat&lt;/span&gt;
  . Nynaeve discovers how to Heal that which should be impossible to heal. Mat begins to build an army and finds himself bullied into following Elayne and Nynaeve to Ebou Dar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fires of Heaven</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/11/the-fires-of-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/11/the-fires-of-heaven/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Fires of Heaven is mostly a book to extend what we&amp;rsquo;ve seen before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elida solidifies her control on the tower while the rebels come together to oppose her. Nynaeve tugs her braid. A lot. Elayne and Nynaeve end up in the circus (not even kidding) and with a  &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;captured Forsaken...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blood Mirror</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/02/the-blood-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/02/the-blood-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at your mistakes long enough to learn from them, then put them behind you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand,  takes the storyline of the previous books and turns it up even more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pale Green Dot: Sequel to The Forest</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/01/pale-green-dot-sequel-to-the-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/01/pale-green-dot-sequel-to-the-forest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Review of .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; is the sequel to , but really they should have been (and often are) combined into a single book. The Pale Green Dot continues where The Forest left off and expands the world significantly. We see a bit behind the curtain at just what the Forest is and how the world works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forest</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/30/the-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/30/the-forest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; came out of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/2ueggh/wp_instead_of_oceans_they_are_all_big_forests/co7rxc7/&#34;&gt;/r/WritingPrompts&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[WP] Instead of Oceans, they are all big forests, that gets taller and darker instead of deeper, with more dangerous animals living further out in the forest. A person decides to cross the Mariana Trench&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Water</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/29/black-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/29/black-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;147801&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/147801.black-water&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/black-water.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried. Really I did. But when you read as quickly as I do and realize that you&amp;rsquo;ve already spent more than a month on one book, it&amp;rsquo;s time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think most of my frustration with this book comes from the fact that Pendragon is a teenager and acts like it. He is hit in the face with a world where humanoid cats are the dominant species and humans are little more than animals and just &lt;em&gt;cannot get it through his head&lt;/em&gt;. Over and over, he expects the world to work one way, despite all evidence to the contrary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shadow Rising</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/28/the-shadow-rising/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/28/the-shadow-rising/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mat snorted. “I don’t want to be any bloody hero.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bit late for that. For all of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dragon Reborn</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/19/the-dragon-reborn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/19/the-dragon-reborn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Til shade is gone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;til water is gone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Into the shadow with teeth bared&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screaming defiance with the last breath&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To spit in Sightblinder’s eye on the Last Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Hunt</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/11/the-great-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/11/the-great-hunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amusingly, due to the library not having a copy of  , the first two times I read the series, I actually started with  . While the Eye of the World could arguably stand alone (albeit with a somewhat unsatisfying feeling, given the sheer quantity of untapped potential in the world building), it&amp;rsquo;s in the Great Hunt that things really start getting crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rand is just now starting to understand what being the Dragon Reborn could mean. Perrin has a connection to the wolves, something very old, come new again. Mat is still cursed by his dagger and yet  &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;he&#39;s the one to finally sound the Horn&lt;/span&gt;
  . You have the first hints of parallel universes and world hopping, along with the World of Dreams&amp;ndash;which will turn out to be rather important to the universe all together&amp;ndash;along with a few more Forsaken coming out of the woodwork. Lanfear&amp;hellip; Lanfear proves that being loved by a power hungry hundred/thousand year old super powerful jealous woman can be&amp;hellip; interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eye of the World</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/02/the-eye-of-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/06/02/the-eye-of-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wheel of Time turns and Ages come and go, leaving memories that become legend. Legend fades to myth, and even myth is long forgotten when the Age that gave it birth returns again. In the Third Age, an Age of Prophecy, the World and Time themselves hang in the balance. What was, what will be, and what is, may yet fall under the Shadow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first read the Wheel of Time somewhere around 2004, with only 10 of the eventual 14 books published. When &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;13888&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13888.knife-of-dreams&#34;&gt;Knife of Dreams&lt;/a&gt; was published in 2005, I read them all again. Likewise with  in 2009 (the first written by &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;author&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;38550&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.brandon-sanderson&#34;&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;author&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;6252&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/6252.robert-jordan&#34;&gt;Robert Jordan&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s death),  in 2010, and finally &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;7743175&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7743175.a-memory-of-light&#34;&gt;A Memory of Light&lt;/a&gt; in 2013. It&amp;rsquo;s been a few years, but the series as a whole is well worth every minute to invest in a reread&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s among my favorite series I&amp;rsquo;ve ever written. This time around though (for the second time) I&amp;rsquo;ll be listening to the audiobooks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shepherd&#39;s Crown</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/26/the-shepherds-crown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/26/the-shepherds-crown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOR I CAN SEE THE BALANCE AND YOU HAVE LEFT THE WORLD MUCH BETTER THAN YOU FOUND IT, AND IF YOU ASK ME, said Death, NOBODY COULD DO ANY BETTER THAN THAT&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it ends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Shall Wear Midnight</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/19/i-shall-wear-midnight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/19/i-shall-wear-midnight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;7576115&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7576115.i-shall-wear-midnight&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/i-shall-wear-midnight.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiffany Aching is back! Now she&amp;rsquo;s a full witch, out on her own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course things are going to go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Broken Eye</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/19/the-broken-eye/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/19/the-broken-eye/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magic was useful for everything. It just killed you. You should always think of it first. Then you should decide if a little dram of death was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just whoa. This book got big. We see a lot more about the world and more about the powers that exist beneath the surface. The world is weird and complicated and everything we thought we knew&amp;hellip; well, i9t&amp;rsquo;s mostly right. Just incomplete.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reality Bug</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/16/the-reality-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/16/the-reality-bug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Onwards! This time around, Pendragon has come to the territory of Veelox, dealing with a virtual reality addiction crisis. It&amp;rsquo;s a topic that comes up over and over again in science fiction and even in real world media coverage, warning that as virtual reality gets better and better, it will be harder and harder for people to leave, leading to society decaying. Regardless of what you think about the idea of such a thing happening in the real world, it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting enough take to build the story on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characterwise, Aja is actually one of the more interesting travelers we&amp;rsquo;ve been introduced to. She&amp;rsquo;s so confident in herself at first that she nearly refuses Bobby&amp;rsquo;s help, but as could be expected, things go sideways. She seems to learn from her mistakes and finally admits that perhaps she can&amp;rsquo;t save the world all by herself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wintersmith</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/15/wintersmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/15/wintersmith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trouble is you can shut your eyes but you can’t shut your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiffany returns, this time slightly older and in just a bit more trouble than before. This time around, she accidentally danced with the Wintersmith (the very embodiment of winter) and, as one thing leads to another, the Wintersmith beings to fall in love, trying to become human along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hat Full of Sky</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/12/a-hat-full-of-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/12/a-hat-full-of-sky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;618145&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/618145.a-hat-full-of-sky&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-hat-full-of-sky.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do you go away? So that you can come back. So that you can see the place you came from with new eyes and extra colors. And the people there see you differently, too. Coming back to where you started is not the same as never leaving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;618145&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/618145.a-hat-full-of-sky&#34;&gt; A Hat Full of Sky &lt;/a&gt; takes  and grows from there, following Tiffany Aching as she actually starts to learn a bit more witching, while at the same time having to deal with some of the fall out from her actions in The Wee Free Men.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
