<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2026 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2026-book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2026 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2026-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brian's Winter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/04/brians-winter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/04/brians-winter/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fall came on with a softness, so that Brian didn’t realize what was in store—a hard-spined north woods winter—until it was nearly too late.He had never thought he would be here this long. After the plane crash that marooned him in the wilderness he had lived day by day for fifty-four days, until he had found the survival pack in the plane. Then another thirty-five days through the northern summer, somehow living the same day-to-day pattern he had started just after the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically, &amp;lsquo;what if Brian&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; rescued at the end of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/22/hatchet/"&gt;Hatchet&lt;/a&gt; (and thus &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/29/the-river/"&gt;The River&lt;/a&gt; also doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen). He still gets the survival pack from the plane, but no radio for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it goes&amp;hellip; about as you&amp;rsquo;d expect? It&amp;rsquo;s very cold, but he figures out skins and furs. He does improve on his hunting supplies and learns more nature stuff?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, it&amp;rsquo;s more of the same, which honestly is okay. I liked it more than &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/29/the-river/"&gt;The River&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Grimoire Grammar School Parent Teacher Association</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/04/the-grimoire-grammar-school-parent-teacher-association/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/04/the-grimoire-grammar-school-parent-teacher-association/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;See? She&amp;rsquo;ll be fine. Evander&amp;rsquo;s charming with animals, he nad half the birds in the neighborhood following him around by the time he was three. C&amp;rsquo;mon, you need to hit the wine and cheese table. And maybe skip the cheese.&amp;rdquo; Moira grabbed her arm and steered her around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; basically we have a mundane couple whose daughter is attacked (and thus turned) by a werewolf. Suddenly, they&amp;rsquo;re thrust into the magical world alongside our own, complete with kindergarten, children&amp;rsquo;s sports, marriage woes, talent shows, and PTAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just while everyone around is magical in someways, it&amp;rsquo;s at times humorous and at times entirely too on the nose combination of magic and mundane that really sets this off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You cast an invisibility spell?&amp;rdquo; Steve and his wife exchanged the classic &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re in for it now&amp;rdquo; look every pair of parents perfects.
&amp;ldquo;I just did what Daddy does when he&amp;rsquo;s eating Mommy&amp;rsquo;s chips,&amp;rdquo; the boy said guilelessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh I do love the tone of this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vivian and Daniel exchanged a glance. &amp;ldquo;Uh,&amp;rdquo; Daniel said when the silence had become a hair too long, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t actually know what skirmedge is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s a little like soccer. There&amp;rsquo;s a ball, although the ball transforms, and depending on if it&amp;rsquo;s in sphera or avis form, you can either hit it or catch it, until more than half the team crosses the patriam line—&amp;rdquo; Steve said, enthusiastically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s wizard soccer,&amp;rdquo; Madhuri cut him off as she looked up from her phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, like-&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nope, don&amp;rsquo;t say it,&amp;rdquo; she warned them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were heading for the illusionist&amp;rsquo;s table, where the kids were getting adorned with butterfly wings that opened and closed, and little spaceships that orbited their shoulders, or copyrighted cartoon character heads overlaid on top of their real ones. To think that at last year&amp;rsquo;s party for Aria, Vivian had bought a face painting kit and had been proud when she&amp;rsquo;d turned out a half-decent cheek rainbow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magical birthday parties yo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and as a side note:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dec 13 3:38 pM
Get your PJs ready! The last Friday before Winter Solstice is Cozy Day. Younger students may even bring a stuffed friend with them! (Note: stuffed friends must be inanimate.) Also, last chance to contribute to the Teachers Appreciation Fund! Last year&amp;rsquo;s blood donations were accepted in the spirit in which they were given, but we respectfully request that contributions be in a currency this year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the chapter intros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just an all around fun book, with enough series parts to really set off the humor and enough fun world building without getting bogged down. I do wish I could stay in this world just a bit longer, but for what it is, it was a great book to start the new year off with.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>