<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Faith Hunter on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/faith-hunter/</link><description>Recent content in Faith Hunter on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/faith-hunter/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Broken Soul</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/19/broken-soul/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/19/broken-soul/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s quite a book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first, it&amp;rsquo;s more of the same. Jane dealing with vampire politics and her own love life as things just keep getting a bit crazier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then we learn that the European vampires are coming to visit. And they might just want to poke their noses into various artifacts Jane has picked up through the books&amp;ndash;or that Leo has and Jane hasn&amp;rsquo;t realized yet&amp;hellip; Including another big piece of vampire history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And &lt;em>then&lt;/em> we get a whole deeper look into the metaphysics of the Jane&amp;rsquo;s universe. Light dragons. More about what the Mercy Blade actually is. More about Soul. And perhaps&amp;ndash;more about how Jane&amp;rsquo;s own history and powers might fit in with all of it. It&amp;rsquo;s going quite a different direction than most Urban Fantasy I&amp;rsquo;ve read and I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated to see where this is going.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus, it&amp;rsquo;s a major upgrade for Jane&amp;rsquo;s powers&amp;ndash;which she may very well need to survive&amp;ndash;even if it comes at quite the cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like I said, it gets crazier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on top of all &lt;em>that&lt;/em>, we actually get a bit of a straight forward&amp;ndash;well, relative to what&amp;rsquo;s come before&amp;ndash;relationship for Jane!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“For a reason or a season,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;ldquo;For a year or a lifetime. For a poem or a song. For a victorious battle or a bloody death. For honor. I would stand by you for as long as I might live.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s about time&amp;hellip; I hope the best for them, at least for a little while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy book and worth the read if you&amp;rsquo;ve already made it this far. Even if (minor spoilers) &amp;hellip; we don&amp;rsquo;t actually even &lt;em>get&lt;/em> to the European vampires for the most part!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: Almost the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/11/25/broken-souls/">second book by that title&lt;/a> I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Arts</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/18/black-arts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/18/black-arts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ooh, now that&amp;rsquo;s a fun one. It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit since we&amp;rsquo;ve seen Molly and the Trueblood family&amp;ndash;what with killing her sister gone evil and all. I missed them. The dynamic between Jane and Molly was interesting, as was the relationship between Molly and her husband Evan (from what relatively little we saw of it). And Angie is fascinating&amp;ndash;so much potential for crazy things to happen there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when Evan almost literally blows into town, blaming Jane for Molly gone missing? Only for some of Katie&amp;rsquo;s girls gone missing as well. And a new (old) vampire from out of town come visiting. All at the same time?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, things are bound to get interesting&amp;ndash;all together perhaps my favorite book of the series thus far.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blood Trade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/blood-trade/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/blood-trade/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onward in Jane&amp;rsquo;s ever increasing trials and tribulations in the world(s) of the VAMPIRES!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the upside, I really love Jane&amp;rsquo;s new found family in Eli and the Kid. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have someone close to her that she can rely on more directly than all the on again off again allies, potential lovers (as screwed up as many of those are), and other relationships she&amp;rsquo;s had through the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“And we don’t give a rat’s ass that you’re a skinwalker,” the Kid added. I heard the slap on the back of his head, and my smile went even wider. He’d braved a head slap to reassure me in that gutsy, bigmouthed way teenaged boys have. “As long as you don’t shift and get hungry enough to think about us as dinner. ’Cause, like, that would, like, totally suck.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On another upside, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to dig more into Jane&amp;rsquo;s more recent past. Not hundreds of years ago when she was born (still needing more of that), but her life as a child and a few into her badass (if lonely) way of dealing with all of that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, the Vampires continue to get more complicated. Bruiser is an Onario now? Whatever that is. Sounds neat. And whatever Soul actually is? More of that please! For whatever reason, I like injections of weird, unique things in urban fantasy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the downside, relationship drama. She &lt;em>really&lt;/em> needs to get over Rick. That&amp;rsquo;s not an option (for now). Just move on. Bruiser would be great. Leo (relationshipwise) is a whole heaping mess and I hope that&amp;rsquo;s not a serious option. Or any of the other men, really. Just&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s been six books. Move on already.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun adventure and I really look forward to what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death's Rival</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/22/deaths-rival/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/22/deaths-rival/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Walk softly and carry a big stick. Or stomp loudly and carry enough firepower to start a small war. Whatever worked.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And so continues the saga of Jane Yellowrock (and Beast!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, there&amp;rsquo;s a vampire plague, a new (old) vampire making a play for territory, and Jane accidentally making promises she certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean to&amp;ndash;and perhaps starting a war for her troubles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a solid book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Raven Cursed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/08/raven-cursed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/08/raven-cursed/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“What you did today was self-defense. That man’s death might provide short-term protection for my brother, my master, and me. And so I thank you for the sacrifice of a small piece of your soul.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Jane is still up to here in Vampire politics&amp;ndash;with the complications of Witches and Weres for good measure. But at least now, she&amp;rsquo;s back home in North Carolina. That&amp;rsquo;s got to be worth something&amp;hellip; right?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mercy Blade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/09/mercy-blade/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/09/mercy-blade/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve had plenty of chances in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/18/skinwalker/">Skinwalker&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/27/blood-cross/">Blood Cross&lt;/a> to get used to the Vampires, Witches, and &amp;hellip; well Jane and Beast of the world. We&amp;rsquo;ve even barely started to scratch the surface for how Vampires work and how they came to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So of course things have to get &lt;em>complicated&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blood Cross</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/27/blood-cross/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/27/blood-cross/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/18/skinwalker/">Skinwalker&lt;/a> we were introduced to Jane/Beast/and the various things that go bump in the New Orleans night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve got that out of the way, it&amp;rsquo;s time to turn things up. Dig into the history of Vampires in this world&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I was among the first hundred who followed the Sons of Darkness, turned by one who was among the first ten of the Cursed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Skinwalker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/18/skinwalker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/18/skinwalker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was fun. I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a good new (to me) Urban Fantasy&amp;ndash;and Jane Yellowrock (so far) hits all the right notes. The worldbuilding is neat. The plot is basic enough, but solid. I like the main character(s). And I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing where it goes from here!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the biggest/really only negative with the book is that the writing style starts out fairly rough. It evens out fairly quickly though, so I expect it&amp;rsquo;s more of both the author and the reader finding the voice of the book than anything else.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>