<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jane Yellowrock on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/jane-yellowrock/</link><description>Recent content in Jane Yellowrock on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/jane-yellowrock/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Final Heir</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/06/11/final-heir/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/06/11/final-heir/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so it ends. With a bang &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; with a whimper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, the stakes (heh (yes, I know I just did that joke)) couldn&amp;rsquo;t be higher. The Heir is coming. All the threads and mysteries of 15 books (that haven&amp;rsquo;t otherwise been killed already) are coming back to rear their ugly heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite land? You have literal angels and demons, but they&amp;rsquo;re in far less of the book than would have made an impact. You have the big bad evil skinwalkers hinted at from the very beginning, but no real direct interactions with them. And you have vampire politics&amp;hellip; but the Heir was never as interesting as the Sons of Judas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other other hand (I know), as a final book in the series, it does work. You get a decent bit of closure for most the main characters (that have survived thus far). The world has changed, almost certainly for the better&amp;ndash;and if not, certainly the more interesting. And Jane finally seems happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was the series worth the read? Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would I have preferred that the series went a different direction about when the whole &amp;lsquo;Dark Queen&amp;rsquo; idea was introduced? Probably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was the whole deal with time fascinating&amp;hellip; and then ultimately less used than it could have been. Yup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, worth the read but I&amp;rsquo;m also ready to move on to other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>True Dead</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/13/true-dead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/13/true-dead/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And now we&amp;rsquo;re wrapping up&amp;hellip; just in time to add in some random new bigger badder big bad that we&amp;rsquo;d never heard of before?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be fair, it&amp;rsquo;s the right time for it. Jane has managed to take control of vampire world and solidify her power in and around New Orleans. We need something to shake up that new status quo, if the series isn&amp;rsquo;t just going to end now. And really, there was foreshadowing that something like this might happen all the way back to the early books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still feels weird.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the plus side, seeing the new evolution of an old character was great fun, I hope we get more of that! The battles were exciting and bloody, more of that! And seeing Jane well supported and loved is something that&amp;rsquo;s she had a long time coming and well deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the flipside&amp;hellip; I miss the smaller stakes (heh) of the older books. I don&amp;rsquo;t really understand why Jane became the Dark Queen (either from a personal perspective or a metaphysical one), beyond perhaps that there&amp;rsquo;s no one else. I&amp;rsquo;m still not a huge fan of the transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still worth the read I think. And at this point, you absolutely can bet I&amp;rsquo;m going to finish the series. Only one book left. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shattered Bonds</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/19/shattered-bonds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/19/shattered-bonds/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/22/dark-queen/"&gt;Dark Queen&lt;/a&gt; did &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; a lot to shake up the world, so it&amp;rsquo;s about time to step back a bit and take a breath. After all, there&amp;rsquo;s no better time than Jane&amp;rsquo;s managing to really screw things up with her magic (finally) and is dying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now we have Shattered Bonds. The vampire world reeling, Jane dying and back in the mountains, and a new bigger badder big bad on the prowl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this points, things are all at once wrapping up (only 2 books left after this one!) and escalating to something bigger. I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge fan of Jane&amp;rsquo;s new place in the supernatural world, but even then I think it&amp;rsquo;s being dealt with in interesting ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of this book? The continued melding of Jane and Beast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, isn’t that just ducky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is not ducks&lt;/em&gt;, Beast thought. &lt;em&gt;Is vampires&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dark Queen</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/22/dark-queen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/22/dark-queen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, that was an awful lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are we kidding, we&amp;rsquo;re 12 books into a series, but not quite at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you&amp;rsquo;ve gotten this far, what are the chances that you&amp;rsquo;re going to stop now&amp;ndash;and you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t want to, just in case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you&amp;rsquo;re looking ahead to the end of the series before reading it to see if it&amp;rsquo;s still worth it&amp;hellip; well, so far it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that being said&amp;hellip; man that was a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cold Reign</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/03/cold-reign/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/03/cold-reign/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Janie, we need to get this guy out of the cage. Suggestions?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Am Beast. Not Jane.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What am I? Chopped liver?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do not need liver chopped. Have fangs and claws to chop liver.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do so enjoy the Jane/Beast dynamic. By far the best part of these books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, we have vampires coming back from the dead again that never should have, the Euro Vamps actually showing up after how many books, a crazy supernatural storm, and oh some many more timey whimey shenanigans. I&amp;rsquo;m still not entirely sure what to think about it. It&amp;rsquo;s unique, for sure. But oh, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;major&lt;/em&gt; power creep on Jane&amp;rsquo;s part. I suppose we&amp;rsquo;re getting on towards the end of the series and that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, my other favorite part of these books is the every growing Yellowrock clan. I never would have guessed it when I started this series, but the found family dynamic is so wonderful to read. They&amp;rsquo;re all interesting and I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to care for them all at least some fraction as much as Jane does. I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;hellip; not looking forward to some inevitable betrayals/deaths. :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other other than that, there is one problem I think I&amp;rsquo;ve been having with this series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gee was a bird, an Anzu, a creature once worshiped as a storm god. We had recently hunted together, both of us in Anzu form. I’d had a good long look at Anzu DNA when I shifted into the form, and that DNA was not from Earth, but it did look a lot like arcenciel DNA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When&amp;hellip; did this happen? I don&amp;rsquo;t think I remember it. There are about a billion short stories, so perhaps in one of those, but it feels kind of weird to have the mainline novels not more stand alone than that. Is it just me? (Or did I just forget something?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But really, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful series and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to where it goes from here!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shadow Rites</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/29/shadow-rites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/29/shadow-rites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And now things take a different take. We&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with it all. Vampires, weres, skinwalkers, aliens from other dimensions, thousand year old uber-vamps&amp;hellip; now it&amp;rsquo;s time to let some witches shine once again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And oh, how crazy things get. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad to see the Truebloods again. Pregnant Molly is fun. Angie Baby is scary and adorable. Evan is going to get himself revealed. And now we can good witch / evil witch with the best of them!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dark Heir</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/20/dark-heir/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/20/dark-heir/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My eyes latched onto his black ones, his desiccated lips moving. Shock thrummed through me like the single tone of a large bell, recently struck, vibrating, a pounding pulse of surprise. As the vibrations hit me, I realized that the pulse wasn’t just shock, but was part of the word I’d been hearing. Joses Bar-Judas was speaking that word. That wyrd. A spell of darkness encoded into a single word, the power released when it was spoken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so we&amp;rsquo;re introduced to a &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; old big bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting in books like these when you have relatively &amp;rsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; points of view mixed in with characters that are literally centuries/millennia old.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Broken Soul</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/19/broken-soul/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/19/broken-soul/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s quite a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, it&amp;rsquo;s more of the same. Jane dealing with vampire politics and her own love life as things just keep getting a bit crazier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then we learn that the European vampires are coming to visit. And they might just want to poke their noses into various artifacts Jane has picked up through the books&amp;ndash;or that Leo has and Jane hasn&amp;rsquo;t realized yet&amp;hellip; Including another big piece of vampire history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;em&gt;then&lt;/em&gt; we get a whole deeper look into the metaphysics of the Jane&amp;rsquo;s universe. Light dragons. More about what the Mercy Blade actually is. More about Soul. And perhaps&amp;ndash;more about how Jane&amp;rsquo;s own history and powers might fit in with all of it. It&amp;rsquo;s going quite a different direction than most Urban Fantasy I&amp;rsquo;ve read and I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated to see where this is going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, it&amp;rsquo;s a major upgrade for Jane&amp;rsquo;s powers&amp;ndash;which she may very well need to survive&amp;ndash;even if it comes at quite the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, it gets crazier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And on top of all &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;, we actually get a bit of a straight forward&amp;ndash;well, relative to what&amp;rsquo;s come before&amp;ndash;relationship for Jane!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“For a reason or a season,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;ldquo;For a year or a lifetime. For a poem or a song. For a victorious battle or a bloody death. For honor. I would stand by you for as long as I might live.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about time&amp;hellip; I hope the best for them, at least for a little while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy book and worth the read if you&amp;rsquo;ve already made it this far. Even if (minor spoilers) &amp;hellip; we don&amp;rsquo;t actually even &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; to the European vampires for the most part!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: Almost the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/11/25/broken-souls/"&gt;second book by that title&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Black Arts</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/18/black-arts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/18/black-arts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ooh, now that&amp;rsquo;s a fun one. It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit since we&amp;rsquo;ve seen Molly and the Trueblood family&amp;ndash;what with killing her sister gone evil and all. I missed them. The dynamic between Jane and Molly was interesting, as was the relationship between Molly and her husband Evan (from what relatively little we saw of it). And Angie is fascinating&amp;ndash;so much potential for crazy things to happen there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when Evan almost literally blows into town, blaming Jane for Molly gone missing? Only for some of Katie&amp;rsquo;s girls gone missing as well. And a new (old) vampire from out of town come visiting. All at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, things are bound to get interesting&amp;ndash;all together perhaps my favorite book of the series thus far.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blood Trade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/blood-trade/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/blood-trade/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Onward in Jane&amp;rsquo;s ever increasing trials and tribulations in the world(s) of the VAMPIRES!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the upside, I really love Jane&amp;rsquo;s new found family in Eli and the Kid. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have someone close to her that she can rely on more directly than all the on again off again allies, potential lovers (as screwed up as many of those are), and other relationships she&amp;rsquo;s had through the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And we don’t give a rat’s ass that you’re a skinwalker,” the Kid added. I heard the slap on the back of his head, and my smile went even wider. He’d braved a head slap to reassure me in that gutsy, bigmouthed way teenaged boys have. “As long as you don’t shift and get hungry enough to think about us as dinner. ’Cause, like, that would, like, totally suck.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another upside, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to dig more into Jane&amp;rsquo;s more recent past. Not hundreds of years ago when she was born (still needing more of that), but her life as a child and a few into her badass (if lonely) way of dealing with all of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worldbuildingwise, the Vampires continue to get more complicated. Bruiser is an Onario now? Whatever that is. Sounds neat. And whatever Soul actually is? More of that please! For whatever reason, I like injections of weird, unique things in urban fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the downside, relationship drama. She &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; needs to get over Rick. That&amp;rsquo;s not an option (for now). Just move on. Bruiser would be great. Leo (relationshipwise) is a whole heaping mess and I hope that&amp;rsquo;s not a serious option. Or any of the other men, really. Just&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s been six books. Move on already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun adventure and I really look forward to what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen next!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Death's Rival</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/22/deaths-rival/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/22/deaths-rival/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk softly and carry a big stick. Or stomp loudly and carry enough firepower to start a small war. Whatever worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so continues the saga of Jane Yellowrock (and Beast!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around, there&amp;rsquo;s a vampire plague, a new (old) vampire making a play for territory, and Jane accidentally making promises she certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean to&amp;ndash;and perhaps starting a war for her troubles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a solid book.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Raven Cursed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/08/raven-cursed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/08/raven-cursed/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What you did today was self-defense. That man’s death might provide short-term protection for my brother, my master, and me. And so I thank you for the sacrifice of a small piece of your soul.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jane is still up to here in Vampire politics&amp;ndash;with the complications of Witches and Weres for good measure. But at least now, she&amp;rsquo;s back home in North Carolina. That&amp;rsquo;s got to be worth something&amp;hellip; right?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mercy Blade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/09/mercy-blade/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/09/mercy-blade/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve had plenty of chances in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/18/skinwalker/"&gt;Skinwalker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/27/blood-cross/"&gt;Blood Cross&lt;/a&gt; to get used to the Vampires, Witches, and &amp;hellip; well Jane and Beast of the world. We&amp;rsquo;ve even barely started to scratch the surface for how Vampires work and how they came to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So of course things have to get &lt;em&gt;complicated&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blood Cross</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/27/blood-cross/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/27/blood-cross/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/18/skinwalker/"&gt;Skinwalker&lt;/a&gt; we were introduced to Jane/Beast/and the various things that go bump in the New Orleans night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve got that out of the way, it&amp;rsquo;s time to turn things up. Dig into the history of Vampires in this world&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was among the first hundred who followed the Sons of Darkness, turned by one who was among the first ten of the Cursed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Skinwalker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/18/skinwalker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/18/skinwalker/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that was fun. I&amp;rsquo;m always looking for a good new (to me) Urban Fantasy&amp;ndash;and Jane Yellowrock (so far) hits all the right notes. The worldbuilding is neat. The plot is basic enough, but solid. I like the main character(s). And I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing where it goes from here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the biggest/really only negative with the book is that the writing style starts out fairly rough. It evens out fairly quickly though, so I expect it&amp;rsquo;s more of both the author and the reader finding the voice of the book than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>