<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Memory Called Empire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/24/a-memory-called-empire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/24/a-memory-called-empire/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is dedicated to anyone who has ever fallen in love with a culture that was devouring their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically: an empire of Space Aztecs with funny Number Thing names and a proclivity towards politics and poetry (and especially political poetry)&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Empire, the world. One and the same. And if they were not yet so: make them so, for this is the right and correct will of the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;and a new Ambassador who should have memories of her maybe murdered predecessor to help her out&amp;hellip; and doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our memory is a more perfect world than the universe; it gives life back to those who no longer exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things, of course, get messy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Butcher's Masquerade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/22/the-butchers-masquerade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/22/the-butchers-masquerade/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;He just keeps going. More chaos, more levels, more &lt;em&gt;caring&lt;/em&gt; for this absolutely &lt;em&gt;ridiculous&lt;/em&gt; setup and what is going to end up to happen to Carl and Princess Donut and all their friends/enemies/fans/decapitated sex doll heads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aaaaaah!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lost: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/11/lost-season-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/11/lost-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What lies in the shadow of the statue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 5 is where it really started to get obvious that the writers of the first few seasons did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; have a plan for where all of this was going to go. It manages to hold together relatively well&amp;ndash;and we do get a few answers, mixed in with all those questions&amp;ndash;but man, there are a few moments which just don&amp;rsquo;t line up with what we already thought we knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s what you get any time a show introduces &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;time travel&lt;/span&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faraday: I studied relativistic physics my entire life. One thing emerged over and over&amp;ndash;can&amp;rsquo;t change the past. Can&amp;rsquo;t do it. Whatever happened, happened. All right? But then I finally realized&amp;hellip; I had been spending so much time focused on the constants, I forgot about the variables. Do you know what the variables in these equations are, Jack?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack: No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faraday: Us. We&amp;rsquo;re the variables. People. We think. We reason. We make choices. We have free will. We can change our destiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have, at first, a combination of &amp;lsquo;what is going on here&amp;rsquo; on the Island, along with a &amp;lsquo;we have to go back!&amp;rsquo; off it. And man, despite the fact that there are only the &amp;lsquo;Oceanic Six&amp;rsquo;, there are some &lt;em&gt;pretty&lt;/em&gt; complicated shifting alliances going on here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank Lapidus: In my experience, the people who go out of their way to tell you that they&amp;rsquo;re good guys are the bad guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, in the latter half, once the Island stabilizes a bit? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s where all the real trouble starts. Because the might just have made it back &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; they were trying to go. But not quite &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;*when*&lt;/span&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack: If we can do what Faraday said&amp;hellip; our plane never crashes&amp;hellip; Flight 815 lands in Los Angeles. And everyone we lost since we got here&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;d all be alive.
Kate: And what about us? We just&amp;hellip; go on living our life because we&amp;rsquo;ve never met?
Jack: All the misery that we&amp;rsquo;ve been through&amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;d just wipe it clean. Never happened.
Kate: It was not all misery.
Jack: Enough of it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s quite the set up for season 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more to go!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Bear and the Nightingale</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/11/the-bear-and-the-nightingale/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/11/the-bear-and-the-nightingale/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All my life,” she said, “I have been told ‘go’ and ‘come.’ I am told how I will live, and I am told how I must die. I must be a man’s servant and a mare for his pleasure, or I must hide myself behind walls and surrender my flesh to a cold, silent god. I would walk into the jaws of hell itself, if it were a path of my own choosing. I would rather die tomorrow in the forest than live a hundred years of the life appointed me. Please. Please let me help you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bear and the Nightingale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, what happens if you take a Russian fairy tale and expand it to the full length of a novel while still managing to keep both the whimsical magical aspects&amp;hellip; and all the dark bits as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We go through years, watching as our main character Vasya is born (and her mother dies), up through when she&amp;rsquo;s a teenager on the cusp of being married off&amp;ndash;or sent to a monastery. She never quite fits in and makes for a wonderful point of view into this wordl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, we see Russia &amp;lsquo;growing up&amp;rsquo; as well, abandoning the old gods and spirits of the forest in favor of the Church. It&amp;rsquo;s not the only conflict of the story (or, I&amp;rsquo;d argue, even the main one), but it does underlie the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Nothing changes, Vasya. Things are, or they are not. Magic is forgetting that something ever was other than as you willed it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a delightful, haunting sort of story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: I did not realize this was a trilogy until writing this review! More to read!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Brian's Hunt</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/09/brians-hunt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/09/brians-hunt/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Basically, this is &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/08/brians-return/"&gt;Brian’s Return&lt;/a&gt; part 2. Where he actually finishes the trip he set off on&amp;ndash;and somehow by &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; the most tragic of the five books. It&amp;rsquo;s a major tonal shift and there isn&amp;rsquo;t really any time to recover from it before the book is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get it, nature is rough sometimes. People die. But these books always had the sense of &amp;rsquo;no matter how bad it gets, you know (because it&amp;rsquo;s a book), nothing truly terrible will happen to Brian&amp;rsquo;. If that sounds great to you, consider skipping this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, we have the first hint of Brian as teenage boy with teenage boy thoughts&amp;ndash;but there just isn&amp;rsquo;t time to get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we have more hunting&amp;ndash;again, little enough time to get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, you can stop after book 1 or 3, in my opinion. So it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there ever happened to be a sixth book, I&amp;rsquo;d be interested to see the story finished, but apparently (on looking it up), Gary Paulsen passed away in 2021. Such is life. I do wonder about his other works though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Gate of the Feral Gods</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/09/the-gate-of-the-feral-gods/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/09/the-gate-of-the-feral-gods/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since that first monkey looked up into the sky and saw something twinkling up there, you meat puppets have tried to force twenty pounds of existential meaning into a ten pound sack of chaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy crap things just keep escalating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have another single level this time. Bubbles in space, each populated by a subset of crawlers that can&amp;rsquo;t (initially) interact, and each of which separated into air/earth/water/underground sections with their own puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course by the end Carl has done an excellent job of not being broken (more or less), saved people, killed even more people, and managed to summon and/or fight entirely too many (feral) gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You know what, Carl? I’ve decided something,” Donut said, finally speaking. She released Mongo, who squawked and started investigating this strange, new world. “Yeah, Donut?” “I think they’re right about you. I think you’re crazy. Like, not a little weird crazy. Not guy who eats cereal without milk crazy. But crazy, crazy. Straitjacket crazy.” I took the cat into my lap, and then I pulled her to my chest. She purred heavily into my ear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man that ending hits hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now&amp;hellip; based on the afterward, we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; going to have some complications next book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to it!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Brian's Return</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/08/brians-return/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/08/brians-return/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian sat quietly, taken by a peace he had not known for a long time, and let the canoe drift forward along the lily pads. To his right was the shoreline of a small lake he had flown into an hour earlier. Around him was the lake itself, an almost circular body of water of approximately eighty acres surrounded by northern forest&amp;ndash;pine, spruce, popular, and birch&amp;ndash;and thick brush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian is back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple years, Brian doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be doing overly well adapting back to &amp;lsquo;regular life&amp;rsquo;. So he ends up going back to the wilderness, this time at least with a few more supplies. It&amp;rsquo;s another trip on a river (this time with a canoe) with a bunch more hunting and arrow building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, it ends before it really starts and I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure what the point of this one is compared to the two. We don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; get into Brian&amp;rsquo;s headspace going back. So it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is amusing that he takes Shakespeare with him this time around though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author&amp;rsquo;s Note&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the final book about Brian, though someday I may do a nonfiction book about those parts of my life that were like Brian&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;doubt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Brian's Winter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/04/brians-winter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/04/brians-winter/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fall came on with a softness, so that Brian didn’t realize what was in store—a hard-spined north woods winter—until it was nearly too late.He had never thought he would be here this long. After the plane crash that marooned him in the wilderness he had lived day by day for fifty-four days, until he had found the survival pack in the plane. Then another thirty-five days through the northern summer, somehow living the same day-to-day pattern he had started just after the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically, &amp;lsquo;what if Brian&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;wasn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; rescued at the end of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/22/hatchet/"&gt;Hatchet&lt;/a&gt; (and thus &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/29/the-river/"&gt;The River&lt;/a&gt; also doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen). He still gets the survival pack from the plane, but no radio for help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it goes&amp;hellip; about as you&amp;rsquo;d expect? It&amp;rsquo;s very cold, but he figures out skins and furs. He does improve on his hunting supplies and learns more nature stuff?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, it&amp;rsquo;s more of the same, which honestly is okay. I liked it more than &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/29/the-river/"&gt;The River&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Grimoire Grammar School Parent Teacher Association</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/04/the-grimoire-grammar-school-parent-teacher-association/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2026/01/04/the-grimoire-grammar-school-parent-teacher-association/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;See? She&amp;rsquo;ll be fine. Evander&amp;rsquo;s charming with animals, he nad half the birds in the neighborhood following him around by the time he was three. C&amp;rsquo;mon, you need to hit the wine and cheese table. And maybe skip the cheese.&amp;rdquo; Moira grabbed her arm and steered her around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; basically we have a mundane couple whose daughter is attacked (and thus turned) by a werewolf. Suddenly, they&amp;rsquo;re thrust into the magical world alongside our own, complete with kindergarten, children&amp;rsquo;s sports, marriage woes, talent shows, and PTAs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just while everyone around is magical in someways, it&amp;rsquo;s at times humorous and at times entirely too on the nose combination of magic and mundane that really sets this off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You cast an invisibility spell?&amp;rdquo; Steve and his wife exchanged the classic &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;re in for it now&amp;rdquo; look every pair of parents perfects.
&amp;ldquo;I just did what Daddy does when he&amp;rsquo;s eating Mommy&amp;rsquo;s chips,&amp;rdquo; the boy said guilelessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh I do love the tone of this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vivian and Daniel exchanged a glance. &amp;ldquo;Uh,&amp;rdquo; Daniel said when the silence had become a hair too long, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t actually know what skirmedge is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s a little like soccer. There&amp;rsquo;s a ball, although the ball transforms, and depending on if it&amp;rsquo;s in sphera or avis form, you can either hit it or catch it, until more than half the team crosses the patriam line—&amp;rdquo; Steve said, enthusiastically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s wizard soccer,&amp;rdquo; Madhuri cut him off as she looked up from her phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, like-&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nope, don&amp;rsquo;t say it,&amp;rdquo; she warned them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were heading for the illusionist&amp;rsquo;s table, where the kids were getting adorned with butterfly wings that opened and closed, and little spaceships that orbited their shoulders, or copyrighted cartoon character heads overlaid on top of their real ones. To think that at last year&amp;rsquo;s party for Aria, Vivian had bought a face painting kit and had been proud when she&amp;rsquo;d turned out a half-decent cheek rainbow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magical birthday parties yo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and as a side note:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dec 13 3:38 pM
Get your PJs ready! The last Friday before Winter Solstice is Cozy Day. Younger students may even bring a stuffed friend with them! (Note: stuffed friends must be inanimate.) Also, last chance to contribute to the Teachers Appreciation Fund! Last year&amp;rsquo;s blood donations were accepted in the spirit in which they were given, but we respectfully request that contributions be in a currency this year.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the chapter intros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just an all around fun book, with enough series parts to really set off the humor and enough fun world building without getting bogged down. I do wish I could stay in this world just a bit longer, but for what it is, it was a great book to start the new year off with.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2025 Year in Reviews</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/31/2025-year-in-reviews/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/31/2025-year-in-reviews/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Man, time just keeps on going, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, I had reviewed 1300 books/170 movies/100 TV shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year? I&amp;rsquo;m up to 1418 book reviews, 187 movies, and 123 seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall this year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#books"&gt;Read 84 books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tv"&gt;Watched 16 seasons of TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#movies"&gt;Watched 16 movies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#board-games"&gt;Played 251 different games a total of 1807 times &amp;ndash; 91 of them new to me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#steam-games"&gt;Played 38 games on steam (25 new) with 475 new achievements!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents"&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents"&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#table-of-contents"&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#books"&gt;Books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#tv"&gt;TV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#movies"&gt;Movies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#board-games"&gt;Board Games&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#overall"&gt;Overall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#two-player-games"&gt;Two player games&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#win-rate--player-count"&gt;Win rate / player count&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#in-person"&gt;In person&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#steam"&gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#previous-years-in-review"&gt;Previous years in review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: 2008 Specials</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/30/doctor-who-2008-specials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/30/doctor-who-2008-specials/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The 2008-2010 specials!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-next-doctor"&gt;The Next Doctor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where the Doctor meets&amp;hellip; the Doctor?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Jackson Lake: There she is. My transport through time and space. The TARDIS!&lt;br&gt;
 The Doctor: You&amp;rsquo;ve got a balloon.&lt;br&gt;
 Jackson Lake: TARDIS. T - A - R - D - I - S. It stands for Tethered Aerial Release Developed in Style! Do you see?&lt;br&gt;
 The Doctor: Well, I do now. I like it. Good TARDIS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you know? Dervla Kirwan as Miss Hartigan gets a bit of flack, but if you ignore for a moment the history of the &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;Cybermen&lt;/span&gt;
, she&amp;rsquo;s quite the fun row. Plus, an absolutely giant robot in old fashioned london down. What&amp;rsquo;s not to love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="planet-of-the-dead"&gt;Planet of the Dead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Doctor, sent through a portal to a desert planet, where he has to depend on a temporary companion in jewel thief Lady Christina to get back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christina: It&amp;rsquo;s Christina Da Souza. To be precise it&amp;rsquo;s Lady Christina Da Souza.&lt;br&gt;
The Doctor: Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s handy because I&amp;rsquo;m a lord.&lt;br&gt;
Christina: Seriously, lord of where?&lt;br&gt;
The Doctor: It&amp;rsquo;s quite a big estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s yet another case (Voyage of the Damned was another one) where a companion for a special would have been &lt;em&gt;fascinating&lt;/em&gt; to keep around. So it goes though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-waters-of-mars"&gt;The Waters of Mars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed points in time don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; make sense for the Doctor. Especially given how it turns out in the end. But still, a giant marsbase and soggy zombies? What&amp;rsquo;s not to love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s yet another one of those episodes that digs just into how broken and&amp;ndash;at some level&amp;ndash;insane the Doctor is, after all those years and triumphs. And failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adelaide: But you said we die. For the future. For the human race!&lt;br&gt;
The Doctor: Yes, because there are laws. There are laws of time. Once upon a time there were people in charge of those laws but they died. They all died. Do you know who that leaves? &lt;em&gt;Me!&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s taken me all these years to realize that the laws of time are &lt;em&gt;mine&lt;/em&gt; and they will obey me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite the set up for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-end-of-time-parts-one-and-two"&gt;The End of Time (Parts One and Two)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tennats finale is coming&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Doctor: Even if I change it still feels like dying. Everything I am dies. Some new man goes sauntering away&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But on the way, we have Wilfred Mott as the Doctor&amp;rsquo;s companion? Yes please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Doctor: I&amp;rsquo;m going to die.&lt;br&gt;
Wilfred Mott: Well, so am I one day.&lt;br&gt;
The Doctor: Don&amp;rsquo;t you dare!&lt;br&gt;
Wilfred Mott: Alright, I&amp;rsquo;ll try not to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And add to that, the Master (back from he dead) and perhaps&amp;hellip; something even worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh that&amp;rsquo;s an intense pair of episodes. Even if it&amp;rsquo;s more than a &lt;em&gt;touch&lt;/em&gt; overdone at times (as all of ennats finales seem to be).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this time around, we get a victory lap of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so Ten ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Doctor: I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to Eleven!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The River</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/29/the-river/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/29/the-river/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derek shook his head. “Not exactly. Bill and Erik are instructors, but I’m a psychologist. We work with people who may need to survive in bad situations—you know, like downed pilots, astronauts, soldiers. How to live off the land and get out safely.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What do you want with me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;”Derek smiled. “You can probably guess. . . .”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brian shook his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, to make it short, we want you to do it again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it went!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the idea. Brian is adjusting well enough, but still dreams of the wilderness. And now he has a chance to go back, so of course he does!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, with another along (ish), knives instead of a hatchet, and to a different lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, things have to go wrong&amp;hellip; And this time Brian finds himself needing to make a raft and go down the titular River to get help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting enough story, but I feel like there wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite as much there are in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/22/hatchet/"&gt;Hatchet&lt;/a&gt;? I&amp;rsquo;m curious what the rest have in store.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hatchet</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/22/hatchet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/22/hatchet/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patience, he thought. So much of this was patience - waiting, and thinking and doing things right. So much of all this, so much of all living was patience and thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a book about patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had to keep thinking of them because if he forgot them and did not think of them they might forget about him. And he had to keep hoping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hunger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a quick read&amp;ndash;and it&amp;rsquo;s probably been 20 years since I last read it, so I figured I would give it another chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad book. It feels visceral at times, really making you aware of Brian. And knowing that&amp;ndash;because it&amp;rsquo;s that sort of book&amp;ndash;he has to survive at the end, you always have hope. Even if some of those situations are &lt;em&gt;so ridiculous&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, apparently, there are &lt;em&gt;4&lt;/em&gt; sequels? How in the world are they going to do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/21/doctor-who-season-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/21/doctor-who-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh Doctor Who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This such a wonderful season (and I do say that about a lot of the seasons).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, we have Donna back as the companion. I do love that she&amp;rsquo;s not pining after the Doctor as others have been want to do. And she&amp;rsquo;s just so delightfully snarkily&amp;ndash;human. They really do play off each other well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, we have &lt;em&gt;The Fires of Pompeii&lt;/em&gt;, with both a future Doctor and a future companion (in other rolls), &lt;em&gt;Planet of the Ood&lt;/em&gt; (delightfully creepy), &lt;em&gt;The Doctor&amp;rsquo;s Daughter&lt;/em&gt; (actually his wife&amp;hellip;), &lt;em&gt;Silence in the Library&lt;/em&gt; (well, okay maybe she is), and &lt;em&gt;Midnight&lt;/em&gt; (for such a limited set it&amp;rsquo;s so intense).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are just so many solid episodes this season!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward, to the 2008-2010 specials! Man those can be a pain to find/categorize. I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure why they weren&amp;rsquo;t just considered season 4.5 or even season 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Dungeon Anarchist's Cookbook</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/21/the-dungeon-anarchists-cookbook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/21/the-dungeon-anarchists-cookbook/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked Bautista, I thought as I finished building my train bomb, but his Tigran race made him look like a tiger that had been vomited upon by a Lisa Frank notebook. I didn’t know how anything could embarrass him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s another fun one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two major things that stand out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The titular Dungeon &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anarchist%20Cookbook"&gt;Anarchist’s Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s a fun idea already and I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting to see what more can be done with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The floor of the dungeon we spend most of the time on&amp;ndash;trains. All the trains in a chaotic snarl. Delightful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the stakes just keep rising (which, all things considered, is impressive).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stone and Sky</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/18/stone-and-sky/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/18/stone-and-sky/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started when Dr Brian Robertson, retired GP, enthusiastic amateur ecologist and self-confessed cryptid aficionado, stumbled over a dead sheep a few kilometres west of the town of Mintlaw, Aberdeenshire. Normally, because they are famously geniuses at finding inventive ways of getting themselves killed, a dead sheep does not cause much concern beyond irritation in the farmer and speculation as to whether it can be disposed of off the books to avoid costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is most certainly an opening paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here we are. Caught up (for now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Peter Grant (and family) on vacation in Scotland (but not really). It&amp;rsquo;s interesting having the change of view&amp;ndash;given how much the &amp;lsquo;London&amp;rsquo;ness of Rivers of London made the series&amp;ndash;right up there along with the &amp;lsquo;magical cop&amp;rsquo; half of the stories. But I liked it; it&amp;rsquo;s fun having Peter and co on an adventure and out of their element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How’re you going to lure it down?’ he asked. ‘Birdseed, chips, a nice fresh herring?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Since we’re looking for a magic bird,’ I said, ‘I’m going to lure it down with magic.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blinschell stared at me for a whole minute. As police, you learn to be almost as good a liar as any random grifter or multinational CEO, so it said something that I read every expression as it passed across his face. Suspicion … Is he taking the piss? Are the rumours true? No, I’m fairly certain he’s taking the piss. But what if he isn’t? You hear stories. Yeah, stories, right. Rumours, more like, because that’s reliable …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well. Sort of out of his element. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have Abigail all grown up (and with her own point of view chapters, that was surprising; also, with her own romance subplot, which is &amp;hellip; odd, mostly in contrast with Peter&amp;rsquo;s point of view we&amp;rsquo;ve had up until now) and the twins already old enough to be talking. And of course causing chaos along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and all manner of sea people and creatures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downright cthulian that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fun book. And it&amp;rsquo;s weird to be caught up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lost: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/17/lost-season-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/17/lost-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Survival. Mysteries. The Others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, just possibly&amp;hellip; rescue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as they said in the end of the previous season, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not Penny&amp;rsquo;s boat&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So who&amp;rsquo;s is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy this season. We get a chance to have some new characters (from the freighter come to rescue them), a bit of a shake up in terms of who&amp;rsquo;s on which side on th island, and a whole pile of &amp;lsquo;what is even going on&amp;rsquo;, split a bit between Desmond and newcomer Daniel Faraday&amp;ndash;I do enjoy his character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, we really are starting to get into the point where you question &amp;lsquo;so&amp;hellip; were they planning that all along? do even the &lt;em&gt;writers&lt;/em&gt; know what&amp;rsquo;s going on?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the answer is no? That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s a bad season though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, because of the 2008 writer&amp;rsquo;s strike, it&amp;rsquo;s a shorter season as well&amp;gt; Ramps of the tension that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favorite episodes this season?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first flashes off the island&amp;ndash;with their own level of *you did &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; now. &lt;em&gt;The Constant&lt;/em&gt;, with timey-whimey shenanigans and &lt;em&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s No Place Like Home&lt;/em&gt;, with everything coming to a tense, sometimes magical, and always chaotic end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing Lost straddle the line between science fiction and more supernatural/fantasy. I tend to like the former, but a lot of times, it&amp;rsquo;s the contrast that really does the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only two seasons left!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Mechanical</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/13/the-mechanical/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/13/the-mechanical/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder how the world might differ today if not for two hundred and fifty years of the subjugation of living, thinking beings. If the entire architecture of the modern world didn’t rest upon a fiendish foundation of imprisoning, torturing, and enslaving immortal souls. If the ingenuity you people celebrate daily hadn’t been devoted to the greatest possible affront to God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an early 1900s world, full of mechanical slaves (Clakkers) run by the Dutch. With full on mindcontrol in their &amp;lsquo;hierarchical metageas&amp;rsquo;, which compels them to act&amp;ndash;up until it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hot ache of multiple geasa smoldered in his soul. At base, the slow, steady background throb of the hierarchical metageas, a constant reminder that he served many masters. In concert with that, filling out the lowest registers of discomfort, came dozens of generic geasa, those that only came to the fore in unusual or emergency circumstances. Layered atop these came the specifics of Jax’s circumstances. Madam Schoonraad’s admonition to hurry with the packing yet preserve the leather finish of her trunks and attend her guest: a sizzling brand plunged through his eye, melting through his skull case. Mr. Schoonraad’s order that Jax attend his guest, returning to the den as necessary to top up their glasses: banked coals that flared to agonizing life every few minutes. Pastor Visser’s order to deliver the microscope: searing flames licking at the edge of Jax’s imprisoned soul. Nicolet’s insistence that she ride on his shoulders after dinner: a white-hot marlinespike scraping the back of his mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just such a fun idea (enough so that I have a similar story of my own! &amp;#x1f604;), but it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see how differently it can be implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does tend to meander a bit, with some discourses on free will and experimentation on what it means to be &amp;lsquo;human&amp;rsquo;. But oh, it ramps right up in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I somehow didn&amp;rsquo;t realize this was the first of a trilogy before I moved on to other books. I most definitely will have to come back to these to see where it goes next!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward! And remember:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clockmakers lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Arabian Nights</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/05/the-arabian-nights/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/05/the-arabian-nights/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well, that was most certainly a book!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m vaguely aware of the general idea of the Arabian Nights&amp;ndash;a woman is threatened with death and staves it off by telling such an amazing story each night&amp;hellip; And then always leaving them wanting more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except apparently within the stories, there are more story tellers. I think it got at least 4-5 layers deep before I noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And&amp;hellip; never returned to the frame story? Weird that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, the individual stories are fun enough, even if some get more than a bit questionable and/or gruesome. But I enjoyed them. I wonder how much of that is the stories and how much this particular translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lost: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/30/lost-season-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/30/lost-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Season 1 was all about surviving on the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 2 was all about mysteries. More survivors. The Hatch. A monster made of smoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we get Season 3: All about the Others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, what a season that was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learn how they live in several different guises, from the cages of &lt;em&gt;A Tale of Two Cities&lt;/em&gt; to the village/barracks of &lt;em&gt;Stranger in a Strange Land&lt;/em&gt;, to a sort of mass exodus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom: Hey, you got yourself a fish biscuit! How&amp;rsquo;d you do that?&lt;br&gt;
Sawyer: Figured out your complicated gizmos, thats how.&lt;br&gt;
Tom: It only took the bears two hours.&lt;br&gt;
[Sawyer contemplates briefly]&lt;br&gt;
Sawyer: How many of &amp;rsquo;em were there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All sorts of medical madness, in &lt;em&gt;Every Man for Himself&lt;/em&gt; and pretty much anything with Juliet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that all, one character who &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; goes through an arc this season is Locke. He&amp;rsquo;s lost his way&amp;hellip; only to find it again. And lose it. And find another. Oh Locke. You&amp;rsquo;re so very interesting, but also so hard to actually root for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sayid: Kate, if you were looking for help to find Jack, why didn&amp;rsquo;t you ask us?&lt;br&gt;
Kate: Two reasons: you don&amp;rsquo;t know where to look and you&amp;rsquo;re not motivated. And I don&amp;rsquo;t blame you. Why would you want to go on another trek across the island, risk more lives just to get Jack back?&lt;br&gt;
Locke: You&amp;rsquo;re wrong.&lt;br&gt;
Kate: Oh, really? They why didn&amp;rsquo;t you come after-&lt;br&gt;
Locke: Not about the motivation, just about knowing where to look. We got a compass bearing, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure if we follow it, it&amp;rsquo;ll lead us right to &amp;rsquo;em.&lt;br&gt;
Kate: How?&lt;br&gt;
Sayid: Because of the way the sunlight hit Mr. Eko&amp;rsquo;s stick&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my continued favorite though? Desmond. Wakes up naked. Wakes up in his flat. Wakes up and buys a ring. Oh, he&amp;rsquo;s got a complicated life, both on the island and off of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desmond Hume: See you in another life, brother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a less positive note, we have main-character-who-have-obviously-been-there-all-along Nikki and Paulo. I mean, it worked well enough for Desmond and seems to be working okay for Juliet. So why not someone else? But they come out of nowhere and get all &lt;em&gt;Expose&lt;/em&gt;d by the end. So it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that&amp;hellip; to go &lt;em&gt;Through the Looking Glass&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, this is a fun show.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Carl's Doomsday Scenario</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/23/carls-doomsday-scenario/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/23/carls-doomsday-scenario/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, if you’ve never had a flaming, skull-faced bear on roller skates barreling at you full speed, you don’t know what you’re missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so Carl and Princess Donut descend to the third floor. With a choice of race (of course Donut will choose Cat, was there ever any doubt?) and class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NecroBard This unusual class combines one of the most-loved occupations with one of the most reviled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things are going to get worse (of course) even as they get better (or at least higher level). And now, we&amp;rsquo;re getting the first hints of life in teh rest of the universe&amp;ndash;outside of the Dungeon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If that’s true,” I said, “then you’re all in that same pot.” I turned to look at the audience. “All of you. If a government is afraid of what its people say, then maybe there’s a reason for it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politics, yo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m fully expecting more of that as the series goes on!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, a worthy successor to the first one and I&amp;rsquo;m still interested to see where in the &lt;em&gt;world&lt;/em&gt; this series can even go from here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wicked</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/23/wicked/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/23/wicked/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Munchkinland Kid: But, Miss Glinda?&lt;br&gt;
Glinda: Yes?&lt;br&gt;
Munchkinland Kid: Why does wickedness happen?&lt;br&gt;
Glinda: That&amp;rsquo;s a good question, one many people find confusifying. Are people born wicked? Or do they have wickedness thrust upon them? After all, The Wicked Witch had a childhood. She had a father, who, by the way, had been appointed governor of Munchkinland. And she had a mother, as so many do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of the Wicked Witch of the West (who wasn&amp;rsquo;t always so Wicked), her time at university (which, for some reason, is called Shiz), and her unlikely friendship with Galinda (before she was Glinda).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s basically the Broadway play writ silver screen and you know, it actually works pretty well. There is room for a lot of visuals you can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; pull off on a stage, along with some face work and camera shots likewise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storywise, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly classic (at this point), &amp;lsquo;what if the villan wasn&amp;rsquo;t evil, how did they get here?&amp;rsquo; sort of story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiyero: I&amp;rsquo;ll say this much, she doesn&amp;rsquo;t give a twig what anyone thinks.
Glinda: Of course she does. She just pretends not to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mix all that with a sassy Elphaba (who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be the Wicked one) and a somewhat clueless entirely self centered Glinda (who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be the Good one)&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elphaba: Fine, let&amp;rsquo;s get this over with: no, I am not seasick; no, I did not eat grass as a child; and yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been green.&lt;br&gt;
Glinda: Well, I, for one, am&amp;hellip; So sorry, that you have been forced to live with&amp;hellip; this.&lt;br&gt;
Elphaba: Is that so?&lt;br&gt;
Glinda: Yes! And it is my intention to major in sorcery. So, if at some point, you wanted to address the, um&amp;hellip; Problem&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
Elphaba: Problem.&lt;br&gt;
Glinda: &amp;hellip; perhaps I could help.&lt;br&gt;
[the whole Shiz students clap and praise her, while Elphaba analyzes the reaction]&lt;br&gt;
Elphaba: Offering to help someone that you don&amp;rsquo;t know with skills that you don&amp;rsquo;t have, I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone is duly impressed.&lt;br&gt;
Glinda: I could care less what others think.&lt;br&gt;
Elphaba: Couldn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;br&gt;
Glinda: What?&lt;br&gt;
Elphaba: You couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less what other people think. Though, I&amp;hellip; I doubt that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t really expect anything new and interesting, but it&amp;rsquo;s solidly done. And hey, some great songs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And best of all? By finally watching it now, part 2 is already out. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>KPop Demon Hunters</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/17/kpop-demon-hunters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/17/kpop-demon-hunters/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better sit down for the show &amp;lsquo;cause I&amp;rsquo;m gonna show you
How it&amp;rsquo;s done, done, done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that was a delightful surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve of course &lt;em&gt;heard&lt;/em&gt; of KPop Demon Hunters, but I hadn’t really paid that much attention to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then one of the songs was suggested to me on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they got stuck in my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumi: It is annoyingly catchy, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I finally watched it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dungeon Crawler Carl</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/15/dungeon-crawler-carl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/15/dungeon-crawler-carl/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goddammit Donut!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book has no right to be quite so fun as it is. Billions of people die in the first chapter, it’s full of blood and gore and formerly-living-detritus, and the entire thing feels like a video game—menus, inventory, levels, and loot boxes included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New achievement! You’ve killed an armed mob with your bare fucking hands! Holy crap, dude. That’s kinda fucked up. Reward: You’ve received a Bronze Weapon Box!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Abyss</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/06/the-abyss/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/06/the-abyss/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So James Cameron has been doing that whole water thing for quite a while, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually thought this was a horror movie. Taking a look at the marketing material and the cover, I think you might see why. And really, there’s a lot of tension to it. A crew trapped deep under the ocean. The darkness and the pressure barely held at bay, readying to come in and crush them all given a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s terrifying enough, even without any deep see monsters or whatnot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bud: When it comes to the safety of these people, there&amp;rsquo;s me and then there&amp;rsquo;s God, understand?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throw into that mankind’s worst enemy—mankind itself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s quite the adventure/thriller. It’s just not a horror movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the setting, the characters give you reasons to care, and the stakes are a lot of fun. The ending does get a bit woohoo/cheesy, but I suppose it had to go somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This definitely goes on the long list of ‘there’s a reason why people still remember/recommend this movie almost 40 years later’. It’s a solid underwater sci fi classic and I’m glad to have watched it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dune: Part Two</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/03/dune-part-two/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/03/dune-part-two/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are not prepared for what is to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dune: Part Two is a lot like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/20/dune-movie/"&gt;the first half&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s visually stunning and there are some intense scenes&amp;hellip; but it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a complete movie, even if this one actually does have a decent ending compared to the first. On to part 3 I suppose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scenewise, I love seeing the deserts. The sandworms. The Fremen&amp;rsquo;s homes in the sand.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lost: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/30/lost-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/30/lost-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Locke: [screaming] What am I supposed to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so my third watch of Lost continues!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 1 was all about the crash on the island. About survival, with only the beginnings of weirdness around the edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Season 2? Now we&amp;rsquo;re really getting into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Orientation&lt;/em&gt;, we get our first hints of the Hatch. Desmond is such a fun character, even if (&lt;em&gt;spoilers&lt;/em&gt;!) he&amp;rsquo;s not in as much of this seasons as later ones. And oh, later on, we have &lt;em&gt;Lockdown&lt;/em&gt;. Now &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; is a wonderful mystery of an episode. And the whole season does have an excellent dynamic between Jack and Locke. Man of Science. Man of Faith. (And really, which is which?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Locke: Why do you find it so hard to believe?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack Shephard: Why do you find it so easy?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Locke: It&amp;rsquo;s never been easy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get a few new characters from the tail section (&lt;em&gt;The Other 48 Days&lt;/em&gt;). Mr. Eko is such an intense foil to Locke in particular. And the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do also get two amazing Hugo backstory centered episodes: &lt;em&gt;Everybody Hates Hugo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dave&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo: Did either of you see a bald guy in slippers with a coconut come through here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlie: No. But I did see a polar bear on roller skates with a mango.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s such a fun character, in spite (because?) of everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Maternity Leave&lt;/em&gt;, we get a bit more about the medical mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then in the end&amp;hellip; we &lt;em&gt;Live Together, Die Alone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Season 3!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Demon's Bluff</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/28/demons-bluff/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/28/demons-bluff/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the witches who had suffered, not the demons. All because, in their fear, the witches had broken the most important rule: first, do no harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so now, we get a story all about the fallout of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/09/demons-of-good-and-evil/"&gt;Demons of Good and Evil&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, just kidding. It’s a time travel story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could be home in an hour if all went well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;record scratch&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Announcer voice]: She was not, in fact, home in an hour.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amongst Our Weapons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/26/amongst-our-weapons/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/26/amongst-our-weapons/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Things I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; love about this series?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole concept of an ‘Everyman’ cop, thrown into a magical world and doing his best to apply a scientific mindset to the whole thing. He’s discovering magic and we’re discovering it along with him. And even after 9 books now, it still hasn’t gotten old!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That some magical phenomena that seem visible to the naked eye don’t register either on chemical film or a photosensor array is something we’ve known for some time. Our current theory – that is, mine and my cousin Abigail’s – is that no photons are being emitted or bouncing off the ghost, or the unicorn or the burning spear of a vengeful angel. What we think we see is, in fact, our brain’s interpretation of input from different senses – the one with which we ‘sense’ vestigia and ghosts, et cetera. We’ve even run up a tentative experimental protocol and one day, when we have time, we might even get to carry it out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/16/doctor-who-season-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/16/doctor-who-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so I slowly continue re-watching Doctor Who.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts out strong with Jadoon on the Moon in &lt;a href="#1-smith-and-jones"&gt;Smith and Jones&lt;/a&gt;, we have more of the Face of Bo (&lt;a href="#3-gridlock"&gt;Gridlock&lt;/a&gt;) and the Daleks (&lt;a href="#4-daleks-in-manhattan"&gt;Daleks in Manhattan&lt;/a&gt;; plus, that one has Andrew Garfield!), several wonderfully creepy episodes (&lt;a href="#7-42"&gt;42&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="#9-the-family-of-blood"&gt;Family of Blood&lt;/a&gt;), and a finale that was certainly spectacular even if it finally veered too much &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; and not enough science for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and of course this is the one with &lt;a href="#10-blink"&gt;Blink&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a reason this is the highest rated Doctor Who episode from the revival&amp;ndash;despite minimal time with the Doctor himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A solid season. And now it&amp;rsquo;s time for Donna!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kyana Woodstock: One More Day of Peace and Music</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/15/kyana-woodstock-one-more-day-of-peace-and-music/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/15/kyana-woodstock-one-more-day-of-peace-and-music/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose the proverbial &amp;ldquo;greatest book of all time&amp;rdquo; is The Bible (and/or the Quran?). These collections contain a series of sometimes random, rambling stories, yet they all reinforce a key overarching theme. Debates continue as to whether The Bible is pure fact—a series of &amp;ldquo;memoirs&amp;rdquo; documenting events around that central theme—or fictionalized to reinforce the same message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry Potter, by many accounts, comes in second as one of the greatest books ever written. There’s no debate about this one; it was crafted purely as a work of fiction. But again, it’s a series of stories that follow close friends as they navigate their life journeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That &amp;hellip; is quite a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a memior of Andrew Verkamp&amp;ndash;a boy who &lt;del&gt;grew&lt;/del&gt; threw up in rural southern Indiana. And to read it, it&amp;rsquo;s honestly a bit of a surprise he made it this far. From a runaway chainsaw to a cabin in the woods, from childhood drinking to biting a head off a turkey. And that&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many of these stories will translate well if you didn&amp;rsquo;t grow up in that particular time and place, but at the very least it&amp;rsquo;s just like a train crash&amp;ndash;in all the best ways. You know, for some reason, that you perhaps shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be enjoying this quite so much&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to look away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDITOR&amp;rsquo;S NOTE: I assume any legal implications from that evening have long since exceeded the statute of limitations, and this public confession has no legal basis. If it does, just forget I said anything. It was a snowy night, and obviously, I was safe at home cuddled up in bed that night (just ask Mom and Dad). That&amp;rsquo;s the story, and I am sticking to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other, it&amp;rsquo;s the story of Kyana Woodstock&amp;ndash;25 years of a local mirror of that famous concert now itself more than half a century gone. Growing from a TV in the backyard to a 30&amp;rsquo;+ screen, hundreds of guests, live music, and entirely too many fireworks to a professional venue with licensing fees, insurance worries, and seats for 1500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s structurally a strange book, taking half the time to even get to the title&amp;rsquo;s point. It&amp;rsquo;s a touch &amp;lsquo;stream of consciousness&amp;rsquo; at times and you&amp;rsquo;re never quite sure where (or when) the next story is going to take you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t your average blah, blah, blah book. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s a random &amp;ldquo;kamikaze&amp;rdquo; style of seemingly unrelated &amp;ldquo;pukes&amp;rdquo; of brain thoughts, all weaving into a &amp;lsquo;sorta&amp;rsquo; seamless collection of recollections. Four books in one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But oh, is it a ride alone the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: You might be able to guess from author&amp;rsquo;s name (and the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;in the book&lt;/em&gt;) that this is my father. I also helped a bit to edit the book and read an earlier version before this one. Heck, I even wrote one of the chapters (apparently). So take this all with a &lt;del&gt;grain&lt;/del&gt; heaping spoonful of salt. But like I said&amp;ndash;once you get start, it&amp;rsquo;s a hard book to put down.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Starship's Mage</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/14/starships-mage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/14/starships-mage/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This place is always awe-inspiring to me,” Jenna said quietly from the edge of the room, and Damien glanced up from the impossibly perfect model of the ship to look at her. “I don’t understand any of how what you do works, but this room…this is the key to the stars.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That was the Compact,” Damien half-whispered, reveling in the power pulsing around him. “Peace between Mage and Mundane, between Mars and Earth…and in exchange, we gave you the stars.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, Starship&amp;rsquo;s Mage is (surprisingly?) hard sci fi. You have starship&amp;rsquo;s dealing with spin induced gravity, limits on acceleration so as not to crush your crew, and no&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; faster than light communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, you have magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Um, sir, what is that plaque supposed to do?” he asked, intentionally changing the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s a security spell,” the Captain explained, seizing on the topic change. “It detects if anyone enters the office with hostile intent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damien traced the flow of energy through the runes and shook his head again. “You might want to have your senior Mage look at it,” he told the Captain. “The scribe used future imperative tenses instead of future-probabilistic. It’s actually slightly encouraging the chance of violence, not predicting it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s laced throughout the story in a relatively light way&amp;ndash;especially considering that one of the main characters &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a mage. But right where it counts? In the ability to actually &lt;em&gt;travel&lt;/em&gt; faster than light? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s where magic comes into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a weirdly fascinating idea and makes me want more of it. Just how many hijinks can you get up to, mixing scifi and fantasy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storywise, it&amp;rsquo;s quite the adventure, starting with pirates and a crew on the run and only escalating from there. The final three way chase/showdown is quite spectacular&amp;ndash;only to drop one heck of a cliffhanger. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort that you could leave off and (mostly) have a solid standalone book, but at the same time leaves you wanting more. Which I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One gotcha that at first I thought I was going to be annoyed about was the idea that Damien was a special/one of a kind/chosen one mage. He could do things no other mage could do. I won&amp;rsquo;t go too far into it&amp;ndash;spoilers!&amp;ndash;but suffice it to say that he&amp;rsquo;s not the only &amp;lsquo;impossible&amp;rsquo; thing in this universe&amp;hellip; and the sequels promise more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, a fun story with some fascinating world building. And it&amp;rsquo;s for that alone that I want to read more. It turns out that there are already 18 books in this series (with another &lt;em&gt;60&lt;/em&gt; from the other over the last decade and change). So we&amp;rsquo;ll have to see where it goes next!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Demons of Good and Evil</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/09/demons-of-good-and-evil/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/09/demons-of-good-and-evil/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s amusing. We went right from her birthday to his in just a few books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we have to deal with the fallout&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of not only Hodin but also that werewolf cursed idol from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/a-fistful-of-charms/"&gt;oh so long ago&lt;/a&gt;. And the return of that &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; demon born witch&amp;ndash;Lee. Remember when Rachel sold him out to Al to save her own skin? And also (again) vampire politics and weres. And Trent&amp;rsquo;s elf politics and daughters. And Al&amp;rsquo;s part versus Hodin last book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, what a complicated life they weave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, another solid adventure! And oh man does the fall out of this book hit hard for some reason. I do enjoy a book where you realize it&amp;rsquo;s possible that some characters might die (even if &lt;em&gt;generally&lt;/em&gt; not main characters (&lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; Kistin &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt;)), but oy does it hurt sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thought (since it&amp;rsquo;s been on my mind): this is yet another book where &amp;rsquo;never killing&amp;rsquo; versus Rachel&amp;rsquo;s more &amp;lsquo;creative&amp;rsquo; solutions comes up front and center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m sorry it came to this,” Cassie whispered, and the wolf’s remaining ear swiveled. There was intelligence in her gaze, but it was that of a wolf. &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;Parker&lt;/span&gt;
 was no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; a touch even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; permanent than Constance or Hodin, no? And those were bad enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m curious if/when Rachel is going to actually cross that &amp;rsquo;never killed&amp;rsquo; line. It feels like it&amp;rsquo;s coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s crazy to think that (as of now), there&amp;rsquo;s only one more. I don&amp;rsquo;t even know what I&amp;rsquo;ll be listening to next! Perhaps a few one offs, rather than entire 18 book series&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lost: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/07/lost-season-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/07/lost-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man this show was huge when it first came out. I watched it then and once since, so this will be my third watch. And this time around I&amp;rsquo;m watching it with someone who (somehow) has never seen it before. To experience all the twists and turns anew with someone? Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first season is awesome. We don&amp;rsquo;t get quite as much mystery and the larger story as later seasons&amp;ndash;but that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we need. Instead, the first season is all about survival&amp;ndash;they did just crash onto a island far &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; away from land after all&amp;ndash;and introducing our cast. And oh, they did that in spades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pilot was, of course&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; awesome. And I do love the first season giving each main character a flashback episode. Locke&amp;rsquo;s (Walkabout) in particular was quite a twist. And oh Hurley&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the characters. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing, with a main cast of over a dozen, how they managed to give each of them (well, most of them) their own over the top backstories and room to breath. I suppose part of that is a side effect of an older style TV season&amp;ndash;when you have over 20 episodes, you have room to actually &lt;em&gt;build&lt;/em&gt; to something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack is great, even if he&amp;rsquo;s got entirely too much of the perfect &amp;lsquo;Doctor savior&amp;rsquo; personality at times. Kate is great, even when she can&amp;rsquo;t stop running. Sawyer is great&amp;ndash;you love to hate him, but he might just be a good man under all that. Locke is a great mystery all around. Hurley is just great. Full stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I don&amp;rsquo;t like the rest of the characters on the island. There&amp;rsquo;s isn&amp;rsquo;t a main cast member in the first season that I don&amp;rsquo;t find worth watching&amp;ndash;and some of them still have room to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I love the slow burn introduction of &amp;lsquo;what is even going &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; on this Island&amp;rsquo;. Monsters in the woods, mysterious noises, hidden structures. It has it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just when they get a chance to leave&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Peter Nimble and His Fantastic Eyes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/02/peter-nimble-and-his-fantastic-eyes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/02/peter-nimble-and-his-fantastic-eyes/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter stood back up. &amp;lsquo;Well, that was a perfectly useless conversation,&amp;rsquo; he said with a sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, there is a wonderful thing in this world called &amp;lsquo;foresight.&amp;rsquo; It is a gift treasured above all others because it allows one to know what the future holds. most people with foresight end up wielding immense power in life, often becoming great rulers or librarians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that was a fun&amp;ndash;if weirdly surreal at times&amp;ndash;little adventure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Trouble with the Cursed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/02/trouble-with-the-cursed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/02/trouble-with-the-cursed/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so here we are, the third (already?) of the continued Hollows Universe. This time around, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the fallout of taking over the city from the vampires, all sorts of chaos with Hodin, and (finally?) the introduction of a new Pixie to perhaps balance Jenks out a bit. Plus, I am enjoying seeing more of Pike in a (mostly) non-sexual/romantic relationship with Rachel, running the city together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, it&amp;rsquo;s quite a story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first, I&amp;rsquo;ve long had an on again/off again debate about Rachel refusing to kill anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I smiled at my warrior-poet, wishing it was that easy. But I’d never killed anyone. At least, no one who hadn’t wanted to be dead—and I wasn’t going to start now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, how &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; is cursing someone into a mouse any better? Especially if there&amp;rsquo;s no plan whatsoever to return them to human form?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book has another example of that (I&amp;rsquo;ll leave who and how as spoilers). And I suppose the main thing to consider is that&amp;ndash;well, barring some magic of course&amp;ndash;death is permanent. It&amp;rsquo;s possible that people do in fact grow and change (we see more than enough fo that in Trent and Al), but not if they&amp;rsquo;re dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting issue to grapple with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hodin—you remember him?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tips of Vivian’s hair began to float as she tapped the nearest ley line. I could feel her aura tingling, and I put a few more inches between us as we slowly followed Stef. “Red eyes,” she said, pulling the petals off, one by one. “Cosmic powers. Living in your church. Looks like a skinny biker dude poet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do enjoy Vivian and Rachel&amp;rsquo;s relationship. And I&amp;rsquo;m perhaps exactly as intrigued by and also annoyed by Hodin as I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be. So much potential to counter Al and the other demons. But in the end, it&amp;rsquo;s not who you were born as or even what you&amp;rsquo;ve done long past. It&amp;rsquo;s who you are &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; that counts. And I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s all the problem, now isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the last? Jenks has been alone for a few books now. In a pixie&amp;rsquo;s life, that&amp;rsquo;s practically forever. So the introduction of a new counter to him (and I fully expect eventually more)? Wonderful. And Getty can well keep him on his toes. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, another solid entry!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m almost caught up now. Not sure what to think about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Isles of the Emberdark</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/20/isles-of-the-emberdark/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/20/isles-of-the-emberdark/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A trapper, a dragon, a ghost, a feathered man, and a hive mind meet on an island no one can find in a sea that only sort of exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s not even the setup for a joke, but rather a spectacular example of everything the scifi future &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-cosmere/"&gt;The Cosmere&lt;/a&gt; is moving towards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen bits and pieces of Cosmere crossovers and magic turned technology, especially in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/27/the-lost-metal/"&gt;The Lost Metal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-stormlight-archive/"&gt;The Stormlight Archive&lt;/a&gt;, but this is really the first book we&amp;rsquo;ve gotten where the (magi)tech, interworld conflict, and mixmatched crews from many worlds are front and center&amp;ndash;and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At it&amp;rsquo;s core, Isles of the Emberdark is a sequel to the short &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/24/sixth-of-the-dusk/"&gt;Sixth of the Dusk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;which I reread in preparation, although it turns out that wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessary. The entirety of the latter is included as flashback in the former. so it goes. An islander culture, plants and animals that want nothing more than to kill you and eat you (yes, even the plants), and the cost of being left behind as technology runs ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this time around, in addition to Dusk, we also have the aforementioned starship crew. I love a good scifi found family story (this reminds me of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/wayfarers/"&gt;Wayfarers&lt;/a&gt;) with wacky rather different crew growing together and learning to depend on one another. The more &amp;lsquo;alien&amp;rsquo;, the better. Emberdark has that in spades. It&amp;rsquo;s wonderful worldbuilding and I hope a hint of even more to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characterwise, I love Dusk. Full on &amp;lsquo;it wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually a question, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the need to answer&amp;rsquo; and everything. Starling (dragon&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;!) is our scifi point of view and she&amp;rsquo;s just such a fun positive influence, in spite of everything. We don&amp;rsquo;t get quite as much of Nazh as I&amp;rsquo;d like (from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/24/shadows-for-silence-in-the-forests-of-hell/"&gt;Shadows for Silence&lt;/a&gt;), but what we do is full of &amp;lsquo;but how does &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; work. Chrysalis (a Dysian Aimian!) is a favorite &amp;lsquo;weird&amp;rsquo; character and a vehicle for exploring xenophobia. And that&amp;rsquo;s not even everyone&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:3"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:4"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;! It&amp;rsquo;s just such a mix and I think done rather well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is probably my favorite Cosmere story in a while. I&amp;rsquo;ve loved seeing how Sanderson has taken the idea of a shared universe with related, high details almost &amp;lsquo;sciency&amp;rsquo; hard magic and brought it forward in time&amp;ndash;and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing where it can go next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Aliens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/19/aliens/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/19/aliens/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/alien/"&gt;Alien&lt;/a&gt; was a genre defining entry into scifi/horror, Aliens takes that a step in a different direction, keeping the horrifying alien monster roots and adding in a pile of action scenes. Space marines, big guns, and flamethrowers&amp;ndash;oh my.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, taking the (more or less) single alien of Alien and upping the ante to a whole pile of them&amp;ndash;and then blowing at least some of them away&amp;ndash;lessons the mystique. They&amp;rsquo;re not unkillable perfect monsters any more. But it&amp;rsquo;s still a good way to up the ante rather than just putting us through more of the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sigourney Weaver remains a star of the episode, this time mixing her tough surviverness with a &amp;lsquo;save the child&amp;rsquo; complex that I think just works. But this time around, we have a whole pile of soldiers, playing up every stereotype you can think of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vasquez: Look, man. I only need to know one thing: where they are.&lt;br&gt;
Drake: Go, Vasquez. Kick ass.&lt;br&gt;
Vasquez: Anytime, anywhere, man!&lt;br&gt;
Hudson: Right, right. Somebody said &amp;ldquo;alien&amp;rdquo; she thought they said &amp;ldquo;illegal alien&amp;rdquo; and signed up!&lt;br&gt;
Vasquez: Fuck you, man!&lt;br&gt;
Hudson: Anytime, anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; memorable lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private Hudson: That&amp;rsquo;s it, man. Game over, man. Game over! What the fuck are we gonna do now? What are we gonna do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(You can hear it, can&amp;rsquo;t you? Even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the movie?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ripley: I say we take off and nuke the entire site from orbit. It&amp;rsquo;s the only way to be sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a different feel of movie, but every bit as good as &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/alien/"&gt;Alien&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that Alien³ is a step down, but honestly, it would be hard to believe they could do it a &lt;em&gt;third&lt;/em&gt; time in the first place. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Million Dollar Demon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/18/million-dollar-demon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/18/million-dollar-demon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And&amp;hellip; away we go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the last couple of books, we&amp;rsquo;ve had more than a few shake ups to the power structure of Cincinnati and the Hollows. The return of the demons&amp;ndash;and the death of one master vampire and the whole &amp;lsquo;vampire soul&amp;rsquo; binding mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sn now when when a new crazy (even by vampire standards) master vampire is sent to take power? Well, it just stands to reason that Rachel is going to have to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing Rachel start to stand up and actually take on the power and responsibility that she&amp;rsquo;s been flirting with (and fighting off) for all these books is a worthwhile change. I do hope it sticks. It&amp;rsquo;s a different level of story, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s about time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, we have the ongoing Hodin/Al hate triangle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t know how you survive your ignorance,” he muttered. “I’ve warned you once. Now I’m telling you. If you don’t want to talk to Al, fine. I don’t want to talk to him most days. But you will not take Hodin as your mentor. He is dangerous.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urban fantasy is famous for having love triangles all over the place, so this is certainly a fun inversion to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m really curious to see where that goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, another solid entry and I&amp;rsquo;m curiously optimistic to see where Harrison takes it from here!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Alien</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/15/alien/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/15/alien/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That transmission—Mother&amp;rsquo;s deciphered part of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like an S.O.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it, then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I—It looks like a warning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m gonna go out after them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, by the time it takes to get there, you&amp;rsquo;ll—they&amp;rsquo;ll know if it&amp;rsquo;s a warning or not, yes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost 50 years and it&amp;rsquo;s impressively how well Alien hold ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, the tech is a product of the time, looking impressively retrofuturistic, given the ways we&amp;rsquo;ve actually advanced since then. And the pacing is a bit slow and the jump scares not quite so scary in comparison to more modern scifi horror films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there&amp;rsquo;s a reason Alien is widely thought of as a progenitor of the scifi/horror genre. It&amp;rsquo;s just a really good film. The effects and design hold up and Sigourney Weaver&amp;rsquo;s Ripley is a powerhouse of a performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A solid movie&amp;ndash;and I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow managed to never watch &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of the sequels. As they say, the second best time to do anything you&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to do is &lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Wind and Truth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/12/wind-and-truth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/12/wind-and-truth/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An oath could be broken, but a promise? A promise stood as long as you were still trying. A promise understood that sometimes your best wasn’t enough. A promise cried with you when all went to Damnation. A promise came to help when you could barely stand. Because a promise knew that sometimes, being there was all you could offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so ends the first half of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-stormlight-archive/"&gt;The Stormlight Archive&lt;/a&gt;. I first read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/02/06/the-way-of-kings/"&gt;The Way of Kings&lt;/a&gt; in 2014, around when &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/15/words-of-radiance/"&gt;Words of Radiance&lt;/a&gt; came out. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve re-read the series again each time (for &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/02/oathbringer/"&gt;Oathbringer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/21/rhythm-of-war/"&gt;Rhythm of War&lt;/a&gt;) and each time there are new details that I&amp;rsquo;d missed or that didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense until some future reveal in a later book put things together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; the series all told, each book at over a 1000 words. Wind and Truth is over 1300. There is just so much worldbuilding&amp;ndash;thousands of years of history&amp;ndash;magicbuilding&amp;ndash;probably the one thing Sanderson is best known for&amp;ndash;and characterbuilding&amp;ndash;you get a mental illness and &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; get a mental illness, and &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; get a mental illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wind and Truth takes that all up to yet another level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the worldbuilding scale, we finally get a chance to visit the Spiritual Realm. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit, I think it&amp;rsquo;s perhaps the least interesting realm to me&amp;ndash;the Cognitive Realm is so much cooler&amp;ndash;but it was a piece I think we needed. And a vehicle to actually make use of flashbacks and fill in a lot of the backstory of how Roshar ended up in the mess it is in now. I think we spent a bit more time here than I would have liked, but I won&amp;rsquo;t argue it wasn&amp;rsquo;t interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magicwise (and characterwise), we get Kaladin and Szeth off to collect all the &lt;del&gt;MacGuffins&lt;/del&gt; Honorblades and save Sinovar. A lot of people have commented on Kaladin&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m his therapist&amp;rdquo; character journey, but I think it actually works. He&amp;rsquo;s a soldier and a healer&amp;ndash;and this is a chance for him to grow into something more. They&amp;rsquo;re just such a weird pairing to see though. Especially once you add in a talking sword and a law obsessed immortal&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What are you? &amp;hellip; are you his spren? His god?”&lt;br&gt;
“No,” Kaladin said. “I’m his therapist.”&lt;br&gt;
“&amp;hellip; What is that?”&lt;br&gt;
“I honestly have no idea,” Kaladin admitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise characterwise, I think that my favorite couple this time around were Shallan and Adolin, despite getting quite a bit less&amp;ndash;but also more (heh)&amp;ndash;together time than one might hope. Shallan is&amp;ndash;quite honestly&amp;ndash;a mess, but her learning to deal with that and quite literally come to find herself is a fascinating story and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see that moving forward. And seeing her grow into a more confident version of herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Murder?” Pattern said, placing another soldier. He’d built a surprisingly tall pyramid. “Oh, you mean murder! Shallan is good at murder. Yes, mmmmm…”&lt;br&gt;
“Pattern,” she said, “please don’t say it that way.”&lt;br&gt;
“She is good,” Pattern corrected himself, “at making people who were once alive and threatening, unalive and unthreatening. Mmmm. Very good at it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Adolin&amp;ndash;to be one of the finest swordsmen in a world where gods and immortals have come to battle&amp;ndash;well, he&amp;rsquo;s just such a fun character. His interactions in particular with Yanagawn was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s not all! I won&amp;rsquo;t go into everything&amp;ndash;after all, if you&amp;rsquo;ve already read 4000 pages of this series, you&amp;rsquo;re going to read it (or not) regardless of what I have to say&amp;ndash;but there is just so much to this story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And oh&amp;hellip; the ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She didn’t know what terrified her more. The idea of some powerful, all-knowing deity that controlled everything—destroying her free will, yet for some reason still leaving the entire world in so much pain. Or the knowledge that there were beings who ruled the cosmere with immense power—but they had all the foibles, flaws, and limited morality of anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;hellip; is going to shake things up methinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a bummer to realize that we won&amp;rsquo;t get another Stormlight Archive until (currently) ~2031. But on the other hand, another era of Mistborn! And hey, if I&amp;rsquo;m feeling Stormlight deficient, there&amp;rsquo;s always time for another reread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m a storyteller,” Wit said, with a flip of his fingers. “I have the right to redefine words.”&lt;br&gt;
“That’s stupid.”&lt;br&gt;
“That’s literature.”&lt;br&gt;
“It’s confusing.”&lt;br&gt;
“The more confusing, the better the literature.”&lt;br&gt;
“That might be the most pretentious thing I’ve ever heard.”&lt;br&gt;
“Aha!” Wit said, pointing. “Now you’re getting it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>American Demon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/02/american-demon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/02/american-demon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So. That&amp;rsquo;s how Harrison is going to come back to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-hollows/"&gt;The Hollows&lt;/a&gt; after that epilogue&amp;ndash;it was &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/AllJustADream" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;all just a dream&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually (mostly) liked that epilogue, so it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a bummer. But if you&amp;rsquo;re going to go back to mostly status quo, well then I suppose you have to do something. I do wonder if that actually means that anyone that showed up in the &amp;lsquo;dream&amp;rsquo; can actually still die off now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/19/the-witch-with-no-name/"&gt;The Witch with No Name&lt;/a&gt; Rachel saved the world! And now she has to deal with the fallout from that. Zombies, mysterious murders, new frenemies, and once again seeing how in the &lt;em&gt;world&lt;/em&gt; demons are going to re-integrate into the world, oh my?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Jesus, Rachel,” Edden coaxed, but I was having none of it. “Don’t take this personally. You can’t deny that forcing couples to kill one another is demonic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s in it for them?” I asked, waving Ivy’s carefully assembled information. “Demons don’t do anything unless it’s for a profit.” Frustrated, I slapped the reports against his chest, and he fumbled for them. “And neither do I anymore,” I said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, things go sideways. Because even after everything&amp;ndash;even after it nearly ending the world more than once&amp;ndash;Rachel is still &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt; at listening to the people she&amp;rsquo;s supposed to trust and acting fully on passion first, thinking things through&amp;hellip; sometime&amp;ndash;maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characterwise, one theme that we continue to seem in this series is the possibility of redemption. You have literal murderers (Trent and Al in particular), but they really are trying to be better people. So how does that work? Are they allowed to work towards a better life? Do they have to pay for what they&amp;rsquo;ve done? What price is high enough murder and thousands of years of torture and slave trading?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s what we do here,” Jenks said. “All are innocent until proven guilty. Even demons.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hodin’s feet scuffed the old wood floor. “How . . . quaint.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, Rachel and Trent are cute together. I hope they get a few books at least to be happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Stop,” Trent demanded again, frowning at Quen. “Everyone, stop. Relax. Rachel, you can kill me in a few minutes. I want to talk first. You like to talk, don’t you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the girls are so cute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because you’re a demon princess,” Lucy said, playing with my curling hair, and from the closet came Trent’s grunt of surprise. “And demon princesses are brave.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel constantly worried about Trent leaving for Ellasbeth and blaming herself for all the elf politics things is growing old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think my biggest negative for this entry comes in the ending. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of mechanical talk about what a soul is and messing with souls, but heroic or not, there&amp;rsquo;s a sacrifice play towards the end that I&amp;rsquo;m hoping gets resolved quickly&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s fun to keep going. I can only imagine having a fairly definite end, waiting the six years between the books and then learning you actually get more! No break for me though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Witch with No Name</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/19/the-witch-with-no-name/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/19/the-witch-with-no-name/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so it &amp;hellip; ends?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/19/the-witch-with-no-name/"&gt;The Witch with No Name&lt;/a&gt; was to be &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-hollows/"&gt;The Hollows&lt;/a&gt; grand finale. And it certainly feels like that. Blowing up the past, shaking up the power structure of not only the demons and elves but also the vampires, saving the world, saving magic itself, and changing everything. It&amp;rsquo;s one &lt;em&gt;heck&lt;/em&gt; of a busy book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head up, I stomped along, eyeing the few pedestrians. Slowly my good mood was tarnished. Love died in the shadows, and it shouldn’t cost so much to keep it in the sun. But as Trent would say, anything gotten cheap wouldn’t last, so do what you need to do to be happy and deal with the consequences. That if love was easy, everyone would find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vampires are a big part of this book&amp;ndash;dealing with what vampire &amp;lsquo;souls&amp;rsquo; are, especially for those that have died their first death. The &amp;rsquo;living vampires&amp;rsquo; in this series have been cool worldbuilding the whole time. In the end, the solution to that is a neat way to tie up a problem I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know I had. I really do wonder how long Harrison had been planning that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But of course, don&amp;rsquo;t leave out the demons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Al leaned close, voice dangerous as he whispered, “We don’t forget, Rachel, and it’s not as if it was our ancestors who were betrayed. It was us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is so much more about the very beginning of the demons here&amp;ndash;and reminders that they&amp;rsquo;re very nearly extinct&amp;ndash;and have been around a &lt;em&gt;long&lt;/em&gt; time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Al is a great second example (after Trent) of us, the readers, coming to know and love the villains of the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Rachel is a pus bucket full of miracles,” the demon added, eyes rolling. “Thank you, Bis. I don’t know these new lines yet.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;hellip; has done some really terrible things over his thousands of years. But he&amp;rsquo;s cute with the girls and nice to Rachel, so we&amp;rsquo;re just supposed to forgive that? He really does seem to have changed. This is a hard one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember a few books back when Rachel called on the witches of San Francisco to ring their bells and work together to help her&amp;ndash;and nothing. This time around, it&amp;rsquo;s the demons she&amp;rsquo;s calling out to. And I think that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much where this series has gone. Demons may do some terrible things&amp;ndash;but in the end, they&amp;rsquo;re also just people. Super long lived powerful people, but still people. And people of all stripes can be good&amp;ndash;or evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love how much crazy stuff happens in this book. I love that it was set up as a finale, given Harrison the permission to do some &lt;em&gt;crazy&lt;/em&gt; things that you normally don&amp;rsquo;t see that often in long running series. And I do appreciate getting a happy ever after epilogue (see &lt;a href="#the-ending"&gt;later&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, that&amp;rsquo;s quite the book. It actually gives a good point where you could end. And a lot of people probably thought that &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; the end. But I have the benefit of having read these a decade later, and there&amp;rsquo;s more! We&amp;rsquo;ll just have to see how in the &lt;em&gt;world&lt;/em&gt; Harrison handles that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</description></item><item><title>False Value</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/17/false-value/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/17/false-value/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’d be amazed how often the police never get to the bottom of a case. You can investigate a crime, identify a suspect, and put together enough evidence to send them up the steps to await Her Majesty’s pleasure and still never know all the whys and wherefores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/05/lies-sleeping/"&gt;a minute&lt;/a&gt; since I last read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/rivers-of-london/"&gt;Rivers of London&lt;/a&gt;, but&amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;re back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time around, we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with the fallout of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/05/lies-sleeping/"&gt;Lies Sleeping&lt;/a&gt;, most especially a certain death. Or&amp;ndash;perhaps just using that as an excuse for Peter to go under cover, deep into the tech bro scene of London?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how the stories are (slowly) changing as we go. Peter feels older and more serious. That&amp;rsquo;s not quite to say that he&amp;rsquo;s going not still cracking jokes and making random scifi/fantasy references (&lt;em&gt;so many&lt;/em&gt; Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide references&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:3"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:4"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:5"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;), but he&amp;rsquo;s also now dealing with the responsibilities of a growing Folly&amp;ndash;and of course the responsibilities of Bev&amp;rsquo;s growing Bulge (she&amp;rsquo;s pregnant :p)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magic is almost impossible to do when you’re pissed, although you can bet many have tried. So drinking with a rival practitioner can be considered, if not a peace offering, then at least a sign that you’re not planning to fight them straight away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, the &amp;lsquo;undercover&amp;rsquo; bits are a different sort of policing than we&amp;rsquo;ve gotten thus far. It&amp;rsquo;s one of teh most compelling parts of this series, so I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s one of those weird truths you learn early on as police that quite a high percentage of the public have all the survival instincts of a moth in a candle factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Structurewise, we spend the first chapter of the story wandering what exactly we missed&amp;ndash;made even worse with a several month gap&amp;ndash;and it only gets worse when we start bouncing back and forth between two storylines a couple of months apart. Honestly, I see what Aaronovitch was going there, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it actually helped the story &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worldbuildingwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a neat bit of tech/magic mashup. Minor spoilers (in my opinion):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
’What do you think?’ asked Skinner.&lt;br /&gt;
‘That thing just passed the fucking Turing Test,’ I said.&lt;br /&gt;
‘Multiple times,’ he said. ‘Under properly controlled conditions.’&lt;br /&gt;
‘Fuck me,’ I said. ‘You’ve got a working AI.’&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amusing that, given all the &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;recent advances specifically with LLMs&lt;/span&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, all the thoughts on the &amp;rsquo;techbro&amp;rsquo; industry and all the problems that come with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These techbros have tunnel vision,’ said Stephen. ‘They’re so fucking busy with their dreams of the future they don’t stop to think about where they are or what the fuck they’re doing.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last decade in this world. He&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; not wrong a lot of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, tech people naming things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magratheean Ape-Descended Life Form Utilisation Service&amp;hellip; MADLFUS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I enjoyed it! And we&amp;rsquo;re almost up to the present date! I&amp;rsquo;m curious to see what&amp;rsquo;s next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Random thought:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because, in America, small towns run their own police departments pretty much unsupervised and a few had hit upon the idea of charging wannabe cops a fee to become peace officers.&lt;br&gt;
‘You’re having me on,’ I said.&lt;br&gt;
‘Nope,’ said Reynolds. ‘Meet Lake Arthur, population 430. Current police force a hundred plus – most of whom aren’t residents.’&lt;br&gt;
For 400 dollars you could get a badge and the right to carry a concealed firearm. Rumour had it Elon Musk had bought one for himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is &amp;hellip; that really a thing? Also&amp;hellip; the Musk bit certainly aged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also also:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Somebody else came during the night and magicked them,’ I said.
‘Is that a real term – “magicked?”’ asked Guleed.
‘And it’s spelt with a “k”, too,’ I said. ‘But the technical term is actually “enchanted”. Only the trouble with that word is that everyone starts thinking glass slippers and spinning wheels.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Moana 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/16/moana-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/16/moana-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Moana 2! Now with more &amp;rsquo;this was supposed to be a TV show'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So basically, we have the introduction&amp;ndash;oh how great was the first Moana?!&amp;ndash;, the baby sister, the quest&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, collecting the party and heading out, a series of semi-connected adventures, the fake out failure, and the season finale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moana 2 was apparently supposed to be a TV show and&amp;hellip; in a lot of ways, it shows? The film has the feel of a bunch of plot lines one after another, none particularly given room to breathe (or dopped entirely) and only a bit related. Which&amp;hellip; is exactly how TV shows are structured.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Undead Pool</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/08/the-undead-pool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/08/the-undead-pool/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minor spoilers, mostly for the romance bits of the series&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a decade (for people reading along as the series came out) / six months (for me), &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;they're finally together&lt;/span&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, the elf looks good in the sun,” Jenks smart-mouthed, the pixy currently sitting on the bottom of my hooped earrings and out of the moderate wind. “When you going to put us all out of your misery and boink him?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given how it all started, you could totally expe4ct it coming&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m actually really rooting for them. I think they&amp;rsquo;ve both become better people through the books. Rachel is at least marginally less terrible at rushing into things and Trent is not outright murdering people quite so often. #goals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it does lead to all sorts of fun politics. See, she&amp;rsquo;s a demon and he&amp;rsquo;s an elf. And the demons and elves &lt;strong&gt;hate&lt;/strong&gt; one another. Something something, thousands of years of war and slavery. So of course this is going to come with all sorts of drama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red finally gave up trying to bolt, and Trent settled into the saddle. The last couple of months with Trent had been… interesting. With Ellasbeth threatening to stay, I was seeing things in the light of “last time” and I was shocked to realize I didn’t like it, especially not with Landon’s threat. If not for the different tax bracket thing, or that he was going to be engaged, or that because of me, he’d lose everything if he didn’t marry Ellasbeth…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s just the romance part&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; we have magic going amuck, going quite a bit deeper into how elf magic works&amp;ndash;and just what/if their &amp;lsquo;goddess&amp;rsquo; actually is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Duh. You think I’m going to trash anything Newt gives me? The woman is crazy, not stupid.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel of course has to save the day, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a bit of a mess to get there. Rachel is really leveling up. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite a &amp;lsquo;chosen one&amp;rsquo; plot, but given how unique she is in this entire world, it&amp;rsquo;s a near cousin of it. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to think about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But storywise, it&amp;rsquo;s quite an action packed adventure. Romancewise&amp;ndash;like I said&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing how this all shakes out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Etude nodded, and as Jenks buried himself in my hair, I closed my eyes to block out the dizzy sensation. Behind me, I felt the train race on without the mystics. The splinter was following me, harrowing, nipping, stabbing at my heels. Ill and nauseated, I hung in Etude’s grip, thinking that I should have just called the damn eagles from the beginning and done this alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A solid book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Never Whistle at Night: An Indigenous Dark Fiction Anthology</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/03/never-whistle-at-night-an-indigenous-dark-fiction-anthology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/03/never-whistle-at-night-an-indigenous-dark-fiction-anthology/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Indigenous people believe that one should never whistle at night. This belief takes many forms: for instance, Native Hawaiians believe it summons the Hukai’po, the spirits of ancient warriors, and Native Mexicans say it calls Lechuza, a witch that can transform into an owl. But what all these legends hold in common is the certainty that whistling at night can cause evil spirits to appear—and even follow you home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A collection of two dozen horror (and otherwise dark fiction) stories by a wide variety of indigenous authors. Three of which I&amp;rsquo;d read before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/rebecca-roanhorse/"&gt;Rebecca Roanhorse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/darcie-little-badger/"&gt;Darcie Little Badger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/cherie-dimaline/"&gt;Cherie Dimaline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any anthology there are some stories in here that I didn&amp;rsquo;t care much for&amp;ndash;and some that really hit hard. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating new look (for me) into all sorts of new and interesting creepy things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And all too often, you might just find that people are people. And people are scarier than any monster out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for these next pages, let these writers take you by the hand, lead you into the darkness at the heart of—let me put some quotation marks around it—“America.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ever After</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/30/ever-after/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/30/ever-after/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone needed someone to watch their back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the world&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;ndash;and it might just be Rachel&amp;rsquo;s fault&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now she has to do the impossible, save the world&amp;ndash;magic itself&amp;ndash;face off against Ku&amp;rsquo;Sox&lt;sup id="fnref:3"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and somehow work with both Trent and Al at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What could &lt;em&gt;possibly&lt;/em&gt; go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(A lot. A lot could go wrong.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Perfect Blood</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/27/a-perfect-blood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/27/a-perfect-blood/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So Rachel&amp;rsquo;s still alive and full on recognized as a demon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except demons &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; live in reality. They have no rights. They don&amp;rsquo;t exist. And they most certainly register cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh the paperwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I should’ve kept my mouth shut,” he said, shooting a quick glance at the knots, and I shrugged. Perhaps, but there was no sense in crying over squished tomatoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh. And Rachel&amp;rsquo;s avoiding her magic, Trent&amp;rsquo;s embracing his, and an anti-interland hate group is of course up to &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Million Dollar Baby</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/17/million-dollar-baby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/17/million-dollar-baby/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Another novella from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/into-the-woods-tales-from-the-hollows-and-beyond/"&gt;Into the Woods&lt;/a&gt;: The story of what Jenks and Trent were up to during &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/13/pale-demon/"&gt;Pale Demon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ELF QUEST!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really quite spoilery (for Pale Demon) to really get into what that &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; means, but the short version is that we get another major magical heist novel, which is all sorts of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trent and Jenks are a surprisingly fun combo. It&amp;rsquo;s nice every once in a while to have parts about Rachel without having her on screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No, not really.” One hand holding his wings tight to his body, Jenks turned to look behind him at their forward progress. “Rachel makes enough mistakes in one week to fill a twenty-yard dump truck.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and more elf politics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He trusted people. He trusted quite a few, and quite a few had “screwed him over” as Jenks put it. The difference was that when people betrayed him, sometimes other people died. And then other people thought it was his fault. He was tired of it. Everything he had was at risk for the next four hours. Quen said he was not his father, but he was doing the same damning things. &amp;hellip; The Goddess help him, they had to come out of the closet if only so he could stop killing people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fun short story! And with even &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; implications to the broader Hollows universe than Pale Demon. It&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see how that all shakes out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>