<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 11</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/22/taskmaster-series-11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/22/taskmaster-series-11/</guid><description>Catching up / almost back to watching these in order! I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;d watched this season before, but not reviewed it, so here you go.
Charlotte Ritchie - She feels so out of her depth, always trying to keep things light and innocent. Bit of a running joke how she&amp;rsquo;d best fit a children&amp;rsquo;s show. She almost came close to not being completely destroyed in the final scoring. Jamali Maddix - The rule breaker of the episode.</description></item><item><title>Heidi</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/20/heidi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/20/heidi/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a cute little story of a little girl with quite the tough start on life, finding (and bringing out) love in everyone she meets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heidi is just so innocent and fun. Her grandfather is the prototypical gruff old man with a heart of gold. Peter&amp;ndash;the Goat General&amp;ndash;is hilarious and a fun counter to the overwhelming wholesomeness. Clara you just want the best for&amp;ndash;and yay magical mountain air!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s not much in the way of plot, but that&amp;rsquo;s all right. You&amp;rsquo;re still going to get a chance to live vicariously through Heidi for a few hours.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s probably a lesson in there touching on ideas of homeschooling, parental rights, and living outdoors and off the land, but really, it&amp;rsquo;s more a matter of the times (written in 1880) than anything. Take it as you will.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth the read, especially if you have little ones.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Broken Soul</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/19/broken-soul/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/19/broken-soul/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s quite a book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first, it&amp;rsquo;s more of the same. Jane dealing with vampire politics and her own love life as things just keep getting a bit crazier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then we learn that the European vampires are coming to visit. And they might just want to poke their noses into various artifacts Jane has picked up through the books&amp;ndash;or that Leo has and Jane hasn&amp;rsquo;t realized yet&amp;hellip; Including another big piece of vampire history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And &lt;em>then&lt;/em> we get a whole deeper look into the metaphysics of the Jane&amp;rsquo;s universe. Light dragons. More about what the Mercy Blade actually is. More about Soul. And perhaps&amp;ndash;more about how Jane&amp;rsquo;s own history and powers might fit in with all of it. It&amp;rsquo;s going quite a different direction than most Urban Fantasy I&amp;rsquo;ve read and I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated to see where this is going.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus, it&amp;rsquo;s a major upgrade for Jane&amp;rsquo;s powers&amp;ndash;which she may very well need to survive&amp;ndash;even if it comes at quite the cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like I said, it gets crazier.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on top of all &lt;em>that&lt;/em>, we actually get a bit of a straight forward&amp;ndash;well, relative to what&amp;rsquo;s come before&amp;ndash;relationship for Jane!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“For a reason or a season,&amp;quot; he said. &amp;ldquo;For a year or a lifetime. For a poem or a song. For a victorious battle or a bloody death. For honor. I would stand by you for as long as I might live.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s about time&amp;hellip; I hope the best for them, at least for a little while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy book and worth the read if you&amp;rsquo;ve already made it this far. Even if (minor spoilers) &amp;hellip; we don&amp;rsquo;t actually even &lt;em>get&lt;/em> to the European vampires for the most part!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: Almost the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/11/25/broken-souls/">second book by that title&lt;/a> I&amp;rsquo;ve reviewed!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fire Ice</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/18/fire-ice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/18/fire-ice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another day (week?), another Cussler. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve read this one before, but that&amp;rsquo;s sort of the appeal of all of these books&amp;ndash;some quasihistorical inciting incident (that happens on or near the oceans) then jump to the present time to find the resulting shipwreck and deal with the secret organization (for example) that&amp;rsquo;s trying to RULE THE WORLD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time with more Russia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have the daughters of Nikolai II, last Emperor of Russia&amp;ndash;on the run with all the royal jewels, including one very shiny crown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cut to the modern era, we have a Russian spy who&amp;rsquo;s gone toe to toe with Kurt Austin several times over the years, a manic trying to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/methane%20clathrate">blow up the ocean floor&lt;/a> and cause &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/tsunamis">tsunamis&lt;/a>, and gangs of modern neo-&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cossacks">Cossacks&lt;/a> trying to bring back Mother Russia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s exactly what it says on the tin&amp;ndash;a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/numa-files/">NUMA Files&lt;/a> novel&amp;ndash;and quite the adventure for all that. Formulaic, but a fun listen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars Vol. 3: Rebel Jail</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/11/star-wars-vol.-3-rebel-jail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/11/star-wars-vol.-3-rebel-jail/</guid><description>&lt;p>Backstory! Work Obi-Wan and Luke’s uncle. A prison hidden tucked right up against a sun. Hearding Nerfs. Sana, Leia, and Aphra… working together?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a decent enough adventure with quite the set pieces. I just wish I had more time in Obi-Wan’s backstory now!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/star-wars-2015-v3-textbundle-17ed10.png" alt="">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vader Down</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/07/vader-down/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/07/vader-down/</guid><description>&lt;p>And now things get complicated… Vader Down is a crossover between &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/star-wars-2015/">Star Wars (2015)&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/star-wars-darth-vader-2015/">Star Wars: Darth Vader (2015)&lt;/a> and a single standalone issue. It’s a neat story, but out so I wish there were easier to read on Marvel Unlimited…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out Anakin can still fly…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/star-wars-vader-down-textbundle-413633.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, Vader is forced down. One thing leads to another and the Rebellion decides that an entire battalion might be needed to keep him down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may not be enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s nice to see Dr. Aphra again. Been a a bit. And oh the droids.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For as annoying as it is to switch from series to series, that’s quite an enjoyable story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title> Star Wars Vol. 2: Showdown on the Smuggler's Moon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/04/star-wars-vol.-2-showdown-on-the-smugglers-moon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/04/star-wars-vol.-2-showdown-on-the-smugglers-moon/</guid><description>&lt;p>The continuing in between adventures of all our original trilogy friends!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a fun one, a dueling pair of adventures and a bit of backstory bridging the original trilogy and the prequels. I think that’d be an interesting era to read more about. How exactly did things go &lt;em>so badly&lt;/em> so quickly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blue Gold</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/03/blue-gold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/03/blue-gold/</guid><description>In this century wars will not be fought over oil, as in the past, but over water. The situation is becoming desperate. The world&amp;rsquo;s water is strained by population growth. There is no more fresh water on earth than two thousand years ago when the population was three percent of its current size.
Oof.
Serpent started us down the road of an alternative to Dirk Pitt with the NUMA Files.</description></item><item><title>Star Wars Vol. 1: Skywalker Strikes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/01/star-wars-vol.-1-skywalker-strikes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/01/star-wars-vol.-1-skywalker-strikes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s read another &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-star-wars/">Marvel Star Wars&lt;/a> series! This time, getting a bit away from Vadar, we have Star Wars (2015). Set (initially) right after A New Hope, we have the fallout of the (first) Death Star and the whole gang out on a variety of adventures!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun start. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing where they go from here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 10</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/29/taskmaster-series-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/29/taskmaster-series-10/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m so not watching these in order. But they&amp;rsquo;re back on YouTube in the US! So let&amp;rsquo;s catch up.
It&amp;rsquo;s a fun season. We have:
Daisy Mae Cooper: So pregnant. And quite often unfiltered, which is a lot of fun. Johnny Vegas: You just want everything to go right for the guy&amp;hellip; and it so often does not. My favorite this time around. Katherine Parkinson: Impressively bad about missing parts of tasks.</description></item><item><title>Serpent</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/25/serpent/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/25/serpent/</guid><description>“Nereus, the Old Man of the Sea,” Nina murmured, cocking her head in thought. “There’s a quote from Hesiod, the Greek poet: ‘A trusty and gentle god who thinks just and kindly thoughts and never lies.”
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve read any Clive Cussler. Turns out there are even a few new Dirk Pitt books I&amp;rsquo;ll have to catch up on. But even then, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t actually read any of his second related series: The NUMA Files.</description></item><item><title>The Sunlit Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/23/the-sunlit-man/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/23/the-sunlit-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so ends the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/year-of-sanderson/">Year of Sanderson&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/">Tress&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/yumi-and-the-nightmare-painter/">Yumi&lt;/a> already hinted at new and interesting worlds in the far future of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-cosmere/">The Cosmere&lt;/a>, but the connections were (relatively) small parts of the story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Sunlit man is a bit more tied in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still in the far future. And oh, the hints we get at where the Cosmere is going&amp;hellip; but this time, we have a protagonist we&amp;rsquo;ve met before, chock full of references to stories we&amp;rsquo;ve seen&amp;ndash;and a few that haven&amp;rsquo;t happened yet. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into who it is&amp;ndash;spoilers!&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s a neat surprise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid story as all the Cosmere secret projects have been. I think I prefer Tress and Yumi over Sunlit Man, but it&amp;rsquo;s by absolutely no means a bad book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think my only real negative is&amp;hellip; I want more! More of protagonist. More of the Night Brigade. More of this weird offshoot society. More worldbuilding and magic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I&amp;rsquo;m worried we won&amp;rsquo;t see more/any of this for at the very least a very long time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still very worth the read.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>Black Arts</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/18/black-arts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/18/black-arts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ooh, now that&amp;rsquo;s a fun one. It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit since we&amp;rsquo;ve seen Molly and the Trueblood family&amp;ndash;what with killing her sister gone evil and all. I missed them. The dynamic between Jane and Molly was interesting, as was the relationship between Molly and her husband Evan (from what relatively little we saw of it). And Angie is fascinating&amp;ndash;so much potential for crazy things to happen there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when Evan almost literally blows into town, blaming Jane for Molly gone missing? Only for some of Katie&amp;rsquo;s girls gone missing as well. And a new (old) vampire from out of town come visiting. All at the same time?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, things are bound to get interesting&amp;ndash;all together perhaps my favorite book of the series thus far.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Mirror: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/black-mirror-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/black-mirror-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Been meaning to watch this for years. Finally got around to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting; especially for only have three episodes in the first season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#1-the-national-anthem">The first episode&lt;/a> is kind of weird and by far the least &amp;lsquo;sci-fi&amp;rsquo; of the bunch&amp;ndash;this could happen now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#2-fifteen-million-merits">The second&lt;/a> though starts out as fairly straight forward near future dystopia and then goes &lt;em>dark&lt;/em> from there. I like it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And &lt;a href="#3-the-entire-history-of-you">the third&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;take a concept (recording everything), apply the concept to imperfect (honestly fairly terrible) people and see what breaks. It&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to season 2!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Last Star</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/the-last-star/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/the-last-star/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s always been this way&amp;hellip; We bear the unbearable. We endure the unendurable. We do what must be done until we ourselves are undone.
Whelp. That&amp;rsquo;s where The 5th Wave ends. Honestly, the first book was really quite good. The second was fine. And the third was &amp;hellip; marginally better?
But really, the ending kind of came out of left field, we got too much and not enough of the alien invaders all at the same time, and &amp;hellip; other than (mostly) Ringer, I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly care about what happens next to any of the protagonists.</description></item><item><title>Blood Trade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/blood-trade/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/blood-trade/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onward in Jane&amp;rsquo;s ever increasing trials and tribulations in the world(s) of the VAMPIRES!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the upside, I really love Jane&amp;rsquo;s new found family in Eli and the Kid. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have someone close to her that she can rely on more directly than all the on again off again allies, potential lovers (as screwed up as many of those are), and other relationships she&amp;rsquo;s had through the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“And we don’t give a rat’s ass that you’re a skinwalker,” the Kid added. I heard the slap on the back of his head, and my smile went even wider. He’d braved a head slap to reassure me in that gutsy, bigmouthed way teenaged boys have. “As long as you don’t shift and get hungry enough to think about us as dinner. ’Cause, like, that would, like, totally suck.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On another upside, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to dig more into Jane&amp;rsquo;s more recent past. Not hundreds of years ago when she was born (still needing more of that), but her life as a child and a few into her badass (if lonely) way of dealing with all of that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, the Vampires continue to get more complicated. Bruiser is an Onario now? Whatever that is. Sounds neat. And whatever Soul actually is? More of that please! For whatever reason, I like injections of weird, unique things in urban fantasy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the downside, relationship drama. She &lt;em>really&lt;/em> needs to get over Rick. That&amp;rsquo;s not an option (for now). Just move on. Bruiser would be great. Leo (relationshipwise) is a whole heaping mess and I hope that&amp;rsquo;s not a serious option. Or any of the other men, really. Just&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s been six books. Move on already.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun adventure and I really look forward to what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Origins of The Wheel of Time: The Legends and Mythologies that Inspired Robert Jordan</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/origins-of-the-wheel-of-time-the-legends-and-mythologies-that-inspired-robert-jordan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/origins-of-the-wheel-of-time-the-legends-and-mythologies-that-inspired-robert-jordan/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-wheel-of-time/">The Wheel of Time&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Robert Jordan built an absolutely wonderful world. And when he passed away, Brandon Sanderson (with the help of Jordan&amp;rsquo;s wife and team) managed to do what I really wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure was possible and managed to &lt;em>finish&lt;/em> it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Infinite Sea</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/the-infinite-sea/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/the-infinite-sea/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>That’s the cost. That’s the price. Get ready, because when you crush the humanity out of humans, you’re left with humans with no humanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other words, you get what you pay for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/10/the-5th-wave/">The 5th Wave&lt;/a> had an interesting premise with a lot of potential: alien spaceship shows up; 4 waves of death and destruction kill 99.99% of humanity. This is the story of all that unfolding, plus what happens next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Infinite Sea takes that&amp;hellip; and continues it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loki: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/12/loki-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/12/loki-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year, another Loki. I really enjoyed &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/">Season 1&lt;/a>. No idea if they could top it. And I&amp;rsquo;m still not 100% sure if they made it better, but they most certainly made it weirder. And I&amp;rsquo;m here for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cast is great of course, with Tom Hiddleston&amp;rsquo;s Loki carrying the show. I really did quite enjoy Jonathan Majors&amp;rsquo; new double role as He Who Remains but also now as Victor Timely. That&amp;rsquo;s most certainly something&amp;ndash;and makes me wonder if they can/could have actually pulled it all off, depending on if Majors sticks around in the MCU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I mentioned in &lt;a href="#6-glorious-purpose">the last episode review below&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s a crazy show, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like about it. It could really change everything&amp;hellip; but I have the unfortunate feeling they&amp;rsquo;re not going to let it. We shall have to see!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>The 5th Wave</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/10/the-5th-wave/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/10/the-5th-wave/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>After the 1st wave, only darkness remains.&lt;br>
After the 2nd, only the lucky escape.&lt;br>
And after the 3rd, only the unlucky survive.&lt;br>
After the 4th wave, only one rule applies: trust no one.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the world (as we know it). The aliens came and killed off most of humanity&amp;ndash;in some actually fairly interesting ways. This is the story of what comes next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first, it&amp;rsquo;s the story of Cassie after the end of the world. How she survives each wave (not told in order), how things keep getting worse, and then finally how she starts to find some &lt;em>other&lt;/em> survivors.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I would kill for a cheeseburger. Honestly. If I stumbled across someone eating a cheeseburger, I would kill them for it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But then we start getting a few more points of view. More survivors and their own stories of death. Child soldiers. Human* survivors every bit as bad as the aliens. A possible look into what comes next.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>How do you rid the Earth of humans? Rid the humans of their humanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Honor Among Thieves</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/08/dungeons-dragons-honor-among-thieves/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/08/dungeons-dragons-honor-among-thieves/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Edgin: We must never stop failing, because the minute we do, we&amp;rsquo;ve failed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s such a fun movie. It takes the delightful chaos of an idolized Dungeons and Dragons session, leans hard into the worldbuilding of the Forgotten Realms (without strictly requiring you know anything about it); and cranks up the visuals up to 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s gobs of humor, some pretty crazy action scenes, and a big &amp;rsquo;evil skybeam&amp;rsquo; action scene that every movie nowdays seems to have. Really, there are just so many great individual scenes. The initial view of the prison&amp;ndash;and the prison break. Fighting a certain dragon. Asking exactly five questions of the dead (it goes exactly as you&amp;rsquo;d expect).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characters and casting were really quite fun too. Chris Pine&amp;rsquo;s Edgin the bard really sells teh movie, but I loved the over the top paladin feel of Regé-Jean Page&amp;rsquo;s Xenk and Daisy Head&amp;rsquo;s bonkers Sofina. Michelle Rodriguez as a barbarian? Yes please. Hugh Grant as Hugh Grant? A delightful surprise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s great. Give it a watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Xenk: You may have forsworn your oath, but your oath hasn&amp;rsquo;t forsworn you.&lt;br>
&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
Edgin: Just because that sentence is symmetrical, it doesn’t make it not nonsense.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Boys: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/05/the-boys-season-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/05/the-boys-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things just keep getting more bonkers and bloody. Really, if you made it this far, you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to love Season 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Boys are (still) out to deal with Homelander&amp;hellip; and they may just have found the weapon to do it. Only this time the solution is perhaps eve more expensive than the cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Homelander is really the (wonderful terrible) heart of the show. Anthony Starr is amazing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a few new supes running around (in secret). And all sorts of ones we knew about doing even more terrible and deprived things in general.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And in the end, the more things change, the more things stay the same. But worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Season 4. It&amp;rsquo;s weird to be caught up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ink Blood Sister Scribe</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/04/ink-blood-sister-scribe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/04/ink-blood-sister-scribe/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Abe Kalotay died in his front yard in late February, beneath a sky so pale it seemed infected. There was a wintery wet snowbite to the still air and the sprawled-open pages of the book at his side had grown slightly damp by the time his daughter Joanna came home and found his body lying in the grass by their long dirt driveway.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s quite the opening. Such beautiful language for something so dark. Which really sums up the book in a lot of ways.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thornhedge</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/28/thornhedge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/28/thornhedge/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another day, another Kingfisher. And once again, I quite enjoyed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time, we have a novella length story that takes Rapunzel and turns it more than a bit sideways. As the blurb says:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a princess trapped in a tower. This isn&amp;rsquo;t her story.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Instead, we get Toadling. Raised by the fae with the power to turn into a frog and some other minor magics of her own, she ends up standing guard over a girl in a tower for years and years&amp;ndash;centuries really, it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely clear; nor does it particularly matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I quite enjoyed the different take on the story&amp;ndash;I do love a good fairy story. I enjoyed the character of Toadling. The idea of the bramble and a gift gone awry. Not a huge fan of the idea of straight up pure evil in general and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work any better here (spoilers I suppose?). But it&amp;rsquo;s a small enough part of the story that I don&amp;rsquo;t think it particularly detracts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good book. A quick read. Worth it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rule of Wolves</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/27/rule-of-wolves/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/27/rule-of-wolves/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hate it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, not the book, I actually quite liked the book. It&amp;rsquo;s never an easy task to bring together as many different plotlines as you have when you&amp;rsquo;re the second book of the third series set in the same world&amp;ndash;and I think Bardugo did it well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, I hate that one particular death in this book. They did &lt;em>not&lt;/em> have to die.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which I suppose means that it worked? Except&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel like it changed anything, other than to annoy me, the reader. So it goes I suppose.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Secret Invasion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/secret-invasion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/secret-invasion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s fine. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see some spy stories in the MCU, even if they&amp;rsquo;re light on the spy stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have Fury again, even if (in hindsight) I was perfectly fine without knowing more about Fury&amp;rsquo;s backstory. And the introduction of Super Skrulls? Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really need that in the MCU. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fan of it in either of the previous story lines I&amp;rsquo;ve read them in (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/13/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-6-frightful/">Ultimate Fantastic Four&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/04/runaways-vol.-8-dead-end-kids/">Runaways&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you know what I really think bothers me about the Skrull? All through the Infinity Saga, we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to believe they&amp;rsquo;ve been here, working with Fury. And we never heard even a hint about them. I get it. They’re shapeshifters. The perfect secret agents. Still weird to add something like this after 15 years&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If it had been something tied into each movie and show, leading up to an event (like the Infinity Saga), it could have worked. As it is, it really feels like the concept of an MCU is working against them here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Boys: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/the-boys-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/the-boys-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Managed to get away for a bit since [[The Boys: Season 1|season 1]]; sometimes life happens (but not for everyone in the Boys&amp;hellip;). But I finally made it through season 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man this is a violent bloody show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still quite the exploration for &amp;lsquo;what if superheroes were real&amp;hellip; and terrible&amp;rsquo; that really draws you in, but now with more terrible corporations. And Nazis. Because of course we had to go there. It actually works really well, the conflict of benefiting from Nazi science is a &lt;em>big deal&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still really enjoy (in a twisted way) how terrifying Antony Starr plays Homelander. If he goes off the rails, what &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> are you going to do to stop him?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus show Hughie (really all of the &amp;rsquo;the Boys&amp;rsquo;) is far better than his comic counterpart. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see him well out of his comfort zone, both in relationships (especially with Starlight) and all the madcap shenanigans Butcher&amp;rsquo;s gang gets up to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, mostly Nazis, but Compound V not only getting revealed the the characters, but also going public? We haven&amp;rsquo;t nearly seen the ramifications of that. Hoping to see more of &lt;em>that&lt;/em> in Season 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, great show. Very much deserves the R rating. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Darth Vader, Vol. 7: Unbound Force</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/darth-vader-vol.-7-unbound-force/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/darth-vader-vol.-7-unbound-force/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v7-textbundle-bfbe5d.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah… no.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just about stopped right there—not a huge fan of the Sabe plot line. It gets better though; until…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v7-textbundle-e718db.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The what now?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Darth Vader, Vol. 6: Return of the Handmaidens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/25/darth-vader-vol.-6-return-of-the-handmaidens/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/25/darth-vader-vol.-6-return-of-the-handmaidens/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Handmaidens. Hired to look like Padme; now they’re impersonating one another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v6-textbundle-07f7e6.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good times. Silly names. But that’s Star Wars for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death's Rival</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/22/deaths-rival/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/22/deaths-rival/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Walk softly and carry a big stick. Or stomp loudly and carry enough firepower to start a small war. Whatever worked.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And so continues the saga of Jane Yellowrock (and Beast!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, there&amp;rsquo;s a vampire plague, a new (old) vampire making a play for territory, and Jane accidentally making promises she certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean to&amp;ndash;and perhaps starting a war for her troubles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a solid book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Lions of Al-Rassan</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/21/the-lions-of-al-rassan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/21/the-lions-of-al-rassan/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It was a day that would be remembered all her life by Jehane bet Ishak, the physician, for reasons over and above those of her fellow citizens in that proud, notoriously rebellious town: she lost her urine flask in the afternoon, and a part of her heart forever before the moons had set. The flask, for reasons of family history, was not a trivial matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That is a dense book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have a land in turmoil, warring city states, religious fervor, and the potential (perhaps a bit more than that) of a looming holy war.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Time and steady governance would bring Jad back into Al-Rassan, the king had declared, not burnings and destruction. Ibero wasn’t entirely sure how that meshed with holy doctrine, but he kept silent in the N
presence of his betters.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>You have a half dozen points of view, from a warrior poet to a general to a physician to a young boy and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I am increasingly unlikely to be best remembered, ibn Khairan decided ruefully, entering his home, for my poetry.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>All tangled together in one glorious tangle of a plot.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>King of Scars</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/20/king-of-scars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/20/king-of-scars/</guid><description>&lt;p>All good things must end, it seems. We had our fun with Kaz and crew in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/">Six of Crows&lt;/a>. And now we shift focus once again, back to Ravka.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In some ways, it&amp;rsquo;s a continuation of the storyline of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a>, following the new King Nikolai as he deals with securing his throne in a nation deeply in debt with enemies on all sides. Plus, we get a lot more Zoya (who I did &lt;em>not&lt;/em> expect to like as much as I did) and at least some more of Genya and David (I do love their relationship).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another fascinating aspect of that storyline is that we get to dig much more into the mystical/religious underpinnings of the world. Six of Crows never really went there, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely something that came up in Shadow and Bone. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to feel like you know how magic works in the world&amp;ndash;and then realizing that you know nothing after all&amp;hellip; (both as a reader and as the characters).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will warn though: this part got &lt;em>weird&lt;/em>. All sorts of new and interesting (or I suppose old and interesting) metaphysics and magic we hadn&amp;rsquo;t really dug into before. A bit jarring&amp;ndash;both for the reader and for the characters involved&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a completely different direction, we also have a main storyline with Nina from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/">Six of Crows&lt;/a> (of all the characters, hers isn&amp;rsquo;t the first story I would have chosen to continue, but it is interesting). She&amp;rsquo;s still messed up / something new and now she&amp;rsquo;s off to Fjerda to continue to try to save the world. Newcomer Hanna is a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid book. It&amp;rsquo;s weird how disjoint the two storylines are&amp;ndash;they don&amp;rsquo;t really interact at all, although I see how they&amp;rsquo;ll likely come together in [[todo:Rule of Wolves]]. I kept finding myself annoyed when we switch from one to another.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/14/downton-abbey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/14/downton-abbey/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Royal Family comes to Downton Abbey.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Anna Bates: Is it always like this?&lt;br>
Richard Ellis: A royal visit is like a swan on a lake. Grace and serenity above, demented kicking down below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s basically a film length episode of Downton Abbey. And that&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I would have preferred it stay on the small screen, but if that isn&amp;rsquo;t in the cards, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to at least have a chance to have one last* (grand) hurrah for the characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Darth Vader, Vol. 5: The Shadow's Shadow</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/12/darth-vader-vol.-5-the-shadows-shadow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/12/darth-vader-vol.-5-the-shadows-shadow/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sabe!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v5-textbundle-1f9451.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It seems the Handmaidens freed a number of former slaves from Tattooine. Including some familiar very minor characters from episode 1.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A great way to… blackmail Vader into doing a good thing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v5-textbundle-f081b2.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For all Vader touts order over chaos… he certainly does have a flair for shaking things up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also: an ‘artificial life force draining storm’ is so very Star Wars sounding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a fine story. Interesting to see the complexity Vader is struggling with even now/then.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Wheel of Time: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/09/the-wheel-of-time-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/09/the-wheel-of-time-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Wheel of Time turns, and ages come and pass, leaving memories that become legend. Legend fades to myth, and even myth is long forgotten when the Age that gave it birth comes again. In one Age, called the Third Age by some, an Age yet to come, an Age long past, a wind rose in the Mountains of Mist. The wind was not the beginning. There are neither beginnings nor endings to the turning of the Wheel of time. But it was a beginning.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/">The Wheel of Time: Season 1&lt;/a> had a lot of potential&amp;hellip; and also a lot of issues. Especially when it came to the last couple episodes. COVID, sure. A main actor leaving, I get it. But it&amp;rsquo;s still a rough ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it was with cautious optimism, we approached Season 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s very much a new turning of the wheel. Some things they changed really do work well. It&amp;rsquo;s not the books, but it&amp;rsquo;s a new story in the same world. Some&amp;hellip; less so. But not everything is perfect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things I loved:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The casting. Ishamael was great in Season 1 and even better in Season 2. Lanfear is a great counter to him. Aviendha and Elayne fit really well.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It bears repeating: Ishamael and Lanfear are great. Leaning a bit more into terrifying even than the books, which quite frankly they needed. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see (and hope they don&amp;rsquo;t screw up&amp;hellip;) the rest.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Almost&lt;/em> everything about the Seanchan. They feel &amp;lsquo;off&amp;rsquo; in just the right way. The one exception&amp;hellip; the Damane pacifiers. I really don&amp;rsquo;t get that &lt;em>at all&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Liandrin. She&amp;rsquo;s still terrible, but I really like how they turned up the &lt;em>reason&lt;/em> why she is as she is. And she&amp;rsquo;s quite the actor to pull it off.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Things that I did not:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The ending. Check out the &lt;a href="#8-what-was-meant-to-be">individual review&lt;/a> for more details, but &amp;hellip; this wasn&amp;rsquo;t any better than the previous season. And they don&amp;rsquo;t even have unexpected troubles to deal with. I&amp;rsquo;m starting to feel they really just don&amp;rsquo;t know how to write endings&amp;hellip; which is weird.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Anyways, other than a few things, I quite enjoyed it. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Season 3. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Darth Vader, Vol. 4: Crimson Reign</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/09/darth-vader-vol.-4-crimson-reign/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/09/darth-vader-vol.-4-crimson-reign/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v4-textbundle-6d8ec1.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So forget Luke and Han Vader is apparently going after this Crimson Dawn now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Except:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v4-textbundle-99b49e.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They’re everywhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Should be right up Vader’s alley.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Add to that the return of Sabe. It’s an unexpectedly interesting way to tie into Vader’s past. One just had to wonder if/&lt;em>when&lt;/em> she’ll learn the truth of Vader’s identity…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still not quite as good as the first two volumes but an enjoyable read nevertheless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On thing I particularly enjoy about the comics is just how varied and alien the universe can feel:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v4-textbundle-5f40a5.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a nice contrast to how human centric the movies and shows have to be. Easier to draw a bug/lizard/ten foot ball droid than to put them on film.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Darth Vader, Vol. 3: War of the Bounty Hunters</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/08/darth-vader-vol.-3-war-of-the-bounty-hunters/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/08/darth-vader-vol.-3-war-of-the-bounty-hunters/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vader is after Solo now…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v3-textbundle-a96877.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With some interesting “allies”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus an appearance by the one and only (I assume) IG-88!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Coolest part:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v3-textbundle-e568a4.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vader getting &lt;del>hacked&lt;/del> sliced! He’s ‘more machine now than man’ so it fits. They could have done so much more with it…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The introduction (for me at least) of the Crimson Dawn is interesting as well. A Million Stronger than One. A neat idea to contrast the ‘only two there are’ Sith and the Big Damn Heroes of the Rebellion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A bit more out there than the previous two volumes but I enjoyed it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Raven Cursed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/08/raven-cursed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/08/raven-cursed/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“What you did today was self-defense. That man’s death might provide short-term protection for my brother, my master, and me. And so I thank you for the sacrifice of a small piece of your soul.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Jane is still up to here in Vampire politics&amp;ndash;with the complications of Witches and Weres for good measure. But at least now, she&amp;rsquo;s back home in North Carolina. That&amp;rsquo;s got to be worth something&amp;hellip; right?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Darth Vader, Vol. 2: Into the Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/06/darth-vader-vol.-2-into-the-fire/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/06/darth-vader-vol.-2-into-the-fire/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vader learned Luke was his son… and ran off across the Galaxy, tracking down anyone he could that might have hidden the truth from him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v2-textbundle-a28ead.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Emperor was not thrilled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So he tears Vader apart over again, sends him back to Mustafar (planet of his both in a way), and forbids him the force.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things only get more epic from here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a whirlwind of Vader passing test after trial, showing off just why he’s one of the most powerful beings in the Galaxy. Until we return to Exegol—2 years after the Rise of Skywalker; trying to fill in some of the mess that one made of continuity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vader is a weird choice for a protagonist, but likewise weirdly compelling. He is (at this point) unabashedly evil, yet I find myself rooting for him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Darth Vader, Vol. 1: Dark Heart of the Sith</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/05/darth-vader-vol.-1-dark-heart-of-the-sith/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/05/darth-vader-vol.-1-dark-heart-of-the-sith/</guid><description>&lt;p>Darth Vader, shortly after Luke escapes him in The Empire Strikes Back. Realizing that perhaps he doesn’t actually &lt;em>know&lt;/em> what happened to Padme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Off to trawl through the past. With… quite the droid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v1-textbundle-108da3.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a fascinating look into Vader forced to dig into Anakin’s past. On Tattoine. On—and under—Naboo. Work the Handmaidens and other from Padme’s life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A fascinating mix. I’m curious where it goes next!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: I can’t imagine reading these issue by issue… dang that’s a cliffhanger in issue 1…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dead Man Logan, Vol. 2: Welcome Back, Logan</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/04/dead-man-logan-vol.-2-welcome-back-logan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/04/dead-man-logan-vol.-2-welcome-back-logan/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends as it began. Logan and a Hulk, in the Wastelands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/dead-man-logan-2-69c695.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The best part? Saberteeth. So many Sabertooths. Sabertoothipode?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crooked Kingdom</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/02/crooked-kingdom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/02/crooked-kingdom/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Crows remember human faces. They remember the people who feed them, who are kind to them. And the people who wrong them too. They don’t forget. They tell each other who to look after and who to watch out for.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/">Six of Crows&lt;/a> took the world of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> and instead gave us one heck of a heist book. Really, it all circled around one big, impossible heist. Plan everything, get in, plans fall apart, make new plans, and pull off the impossible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s one heck of an impressive book and I really enjoyed it, but it left an awful lot of plot thread hanging open&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which makes Crooked Kingdom all the more cathartic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Six of Crows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No mourners.&lt;br>
No funerals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among them, it passed for &amp;lsquo;good luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s such a good book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It takes the world of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> and completely ignores the at times overly YA political and religions machinations of that particular trilogy in favor of a somewhat darker and grittier heist novel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the most part, you really don&amp;rsquo;t need to have read Shadow and Bone first. There are a few references to the &amp;lsquo;Ravkan Civil War&amp;rsquo; and even to Sankta Alina, but other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s a new world. There are still Grisha, but they&amp;rsquo;re far less &amp;lsquo;miliary&amp;rsquo;, instead using (and hiding) their powers in all manner of interesting ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And while the heist elements were &lt;em>strong&lt;/em> (an impossible job, planning going absolutely sideways, and double triple crossing left and right) we also get all sorts of interesting backstory. Each of the main characters has chapters in their voice, but in the action going now, and explaining how they got into this mess in the first place. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot, but in a good way!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One gotcha is that, while the main heist plot is more than adequately contained in the book, it very much is the first half of a duology. It managed to just make me want to read the second&amp;hellip; but don&amp;rsquo;t go into this looking for a stand alone novel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what really shines are the characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dead Man Logan, Vol. 1: Sins of the Father</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/26/dead-man-logan-vol.-1-sins-of-the-father/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/26/dead-man-logan-vol.-1-sins-of-the-father/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so he has an expiration date:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/dead-man-logan-1-textbundle-1f9c64.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel like it’s been a long time coming. He either has to figure out some way to heal… or move on from this world that isn’t even his in the first place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/25/downton-abbey-season-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/25/downton-abbey-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Downton Abbey Season 6 is a strange beast. On one hand, we have what feels all the cast pairing off, sometimes with long known relationships and in the cast of the Family with guys we only met in the previous season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I &lt;em>still&lt;/em> do not really understand the relationship between Mary and Henry. I think it&amp;rsquo;s mostly Mary. She certainly ebbs and flows&amp;hellip; but wow she&amp;rsquo;s a (sorry, but Edith says it too) bitch at times. On the other hand, Edith and Bertie? Delightful. If expected for the chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, the world is moving on. Is Downton Abbey going to survive? With reductions in expected staff and families around the world failing, it&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But with all those relationships &lt;em>wow&lt;/em> do the last few episodes blitz through what feels like every plotline possible in only a few hours. I do wonder if they thought they&amp;rsquo;d have a 7th season. But so it goes. For the most part, everything is tied off neatly. And for everything else&amp;hellip; apparently there are two movies?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a final note, if you&amp;rsquo;ve been lamenting the torture the writers have put the Bates&amp;rsquo; through over the year&amp;hellip; well, they&amp;rsquo;re not quite done. But there is light at the end of the tunnel, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad for that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I quite enjoyed it. Much more than I expected to, as I seem to say with all non-SF/F shows I end up watching. Still not something I would have chosen, still quite enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Betsy-Tacy and Tib</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/25/betsy-tacy-and-tib/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 20:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/25/betsy-tacy-and-tib/</guid><description>&lt;p>Betsy-Tacy and Tib is &amp;hellip; pretty much exactly what you&amp;rsquo;d expect. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/05/betsy-tacy/">Betsy-Tacy&lt;/a>, but now with more Tib. A new girl moves in, they become instant best friends, hijinks ensue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once again, it&amp;rsquo;s a delightful book to read with my own little one. I enjoy seeing what messes the children get into. And although they do get in trouble from time to time, we&amp;rsquo;re reminded that &lt;em>it&amp;rsquo;s okay to be children&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: my absolute favorite story is when they decide to cook. It goes as well as one might expect! 😄&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ruin and Rising</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/24/ruin-and-rising/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/24/ruin-and-rising/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that&amp;rsquo;s quite an ending. After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> set the stage and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/19/siege-and-storm/">Siege and Storm&lt;/a> raised the stakes, Ruin and Rising really brings everything home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have the increasing religious fever of Alina as Saint&amp;ndash;whether or not that&amp;rsquo;s what she wants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have what&amp;rsquo;s left of Alina&amp;rsquo;s friends and allies trying desperately to hold off the ever more powerful&amp;ndash;and ever more unhinged&amp;ndash;Darkling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We finally get some real history, digging deeper into where the Darkling came from&amp;hellip; and perhaps how Alina fits into it all as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have more adventures; a desperate bid to find the third Amplifier that may well save the day&amp;ndash;or doom them all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally&amp;ndash;obvious seeing as it&amp;rsquo;s the final novel in the trilogy&amp;ndash;we have victory. But at what cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s by a decent margin my favorite of the three. A solid conclusion, in my opinion. Now I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the other series in the same world. Six of Crows especially to see where those threads in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/25/shadow-and-bone-season-1/">the show&lt;/a> came from and King of Scars for a &amp;lsquo;what comes next&amp;rsquo;. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Siege and Storm</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/19/siege-and-storm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/19/siege-and-storm/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When people say impossible, they usually mean improbable.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> had quite the ending. The Darkling showing his true allegiance, death and destruction, Alina and Mal on the run&amp;hellip; So of course in Siege and Storm they get captured by pirates (&lt;em>cough&lt;/em> I mean &lt;em>privateers&lt;/em>), the Darkling shows up again, they go meet the royal family, the Darkling shows up again, and in the end&amp;hellip; things just keep ending up getting worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s really a solid step up from Shadow and Bone. It&amp;rsquo;s still got a YA core, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely edging on the darker end of it all&amp;ndash;which I really enjoy. I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely looking forward to where this goes next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wolverine: Old Man Logan, Vol. 10: End of the World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/15/wolverine-old-man-logan-vol.-10-end-of-the-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/15/wolverine-old-man-logan-vol.-10-end-of-the-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>Part one:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/old-man-logan-10-textbundle-1a3a18.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Obviously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Burning time, but it’s a fun enough adventure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Part two:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/old-man-logan-10-textbundle-84c10d.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so it ends as it started. Logan and a Hulk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Decent for closure even if the actual ending was abrupt at best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward… to Dead Man Logan.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2023 Book Bingo Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/15/2023-book-bingo-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/15/2023-book-bingo-retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;p>BINGO!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here we go. Bingo: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2023-book-bingo/">2023 Book Bingo&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#bingo-card">Bingo Card&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#mini-reviews">Mini-reviews&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-stats">Some stats&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>
&lt;h2 id="bingo-card">Bingo Card&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1>2023 Book Bingo&lt;/h1>
&lt;button class="bingo-toggle">Toggle Display Mode&lt;/button>
&lt;table class="bingo">&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/the-handmaids-tale/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-handmaid-s-tale.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
The Handmaid&amp;#39;s Tale
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/margaret-atwood">Margaret Atwood&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Title with a Title (Hard: Not a title of royalty)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/12/zeroes/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/zeroes.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Zeroes
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/scott-westerfield">Scott Westerfield&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Superheroes (Hard: Not DC or Marvel)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/01/blindsight/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/blindsight.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Blindsight
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peter-watts">Peter Watts&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Bottom of the TBR (Hard: Always hard mode, this is hard enough)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/16/the-cartographers/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-cartographers.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
The Cartographers
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peng-shepherd">Peng Shepherd&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Magical Realism or Literary Fantasy (&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/4bhiua/proposed_magical_realism_recommendation_list/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">examples&lt;/a>) (Hard: Not from the examples)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/04/a-wizards-guide-to-defensive-baking/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-wizard-s-guide-to-defensive-baking.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
A Wizard&amp;#39;s Guide to Defensive Baking
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher">T. Kingfisher&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Young Adult (Hard: Published in the last 5 years)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/12/phoenix-extravagant/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/phoenix-extravagant.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Phoenix Extravagant
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/yoon-ha-lee">Yoon Ha Lee&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Mundane Jobs (Hard: Does not take place on Earth)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/throne-of-jade.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Throne of Jade
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/naomi-novik">Naomi Novik&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Published in the 00s (Hard: Not top 30 on the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/11mvwsa/rfantasy_top_novels_2023_results/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best of 2023 list&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/good-omens-the-nice-and-accurate-prophecies-of-agnes-nutter-witch/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/good-omens-the-nice-and-accurate-prophecies-of-agnes-nutter-witch.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Good Omens: The Nice and Accurate Prophecies of Agnes Nutter, Witch
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/terry-pratchett">Terry Pratchett&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/neil-gaiman">Neil Gaiman&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Angels and Demons (Hard: Angel or demon protagonist)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/30/stories-of-your-life-and-others/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/stories-of-your-life-and-others.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Stories of Your Life and Others
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ted-chiang">Ted Chiang&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Five SFF Shorts (Hard: An entire anthology)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/prodigal-son/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/prodigal-son.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Prodigal Son
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dean-koontz">Dean Koontz&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Horror (Hard: Not Stephen King or H.P. Lovecraft)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/10/the-book-of-zog/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-book-of-zog.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
The Book of Zog
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/alec-hutson">Alec Hutson&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Self-Published / Indie Publisher (Hard: Fewer than 100 ratings or an AMA)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/07/girl-serpent-thorn/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/girl-serpent-thorn.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Girl, Serpent, Thorn
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/melissa-bashardoust">Melissa Bashardoust&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Set in the Middle East / Middle Eastern SFF (Hard: Author of Middle Eastern heritage)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/the-scourge-between-stars/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-scourge-between-stars.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
The Scourge Between Stars
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ness-brown">Ness Brown&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Published in 2023 (Hard: Debut)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/18/the-space-between-worlds/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-space-between-worlds.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
The Space Between Worlds
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/micaiah-johnson">Micaiah Johnson&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Multiverse and Alternate Realities (Hard: Travel is not through a literal door)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/06/rosewater/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/rosewater.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Rosewater
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/tade-thompson">Tade Thompson&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>POC Author (Hard: In a futuristic, sci-fi world)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/08/house-of-suns/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/house-of-suns.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
House of Suns
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/alastair-reynolds">Alastair Reynolds&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>&lt;strike>Book Club / Readalong (Hard: With participation)&lt;/strike>&lt;br>&lt;br>Set in Space (Hard: Characters not originally from Earth)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/26/six-gun-snow-white/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/six-gun-snow-white.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Six-Gun Snow White
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/catherynne-m.-valente">Catherynne M. Valente&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Novella (Hard: Not published by Tordotcom)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/18/the-last-unicorn/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-last-unicorn.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
The Last Unicorn
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peter-s.-beagle">Peter S. Beagle&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Mythical Beasts (Hard: No dragons or dragon-like creatures)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/shadow-and-bone.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Shadow and Bone
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/leigh-bardugo">Leigh Bardugo&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Elemental Magic (Hard: Not &lt;em>Shades of Magic&lt;/em> or &lt;em>Codex Alera&lt;/em>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/23/the-witchs-heart/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-witch-s-heart.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
The Witch&amp;#39;s Heart
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/genevieve-gornichec">Genevieve Gornichec&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Myths and Retellings (Hard: Not Greek or Roman)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/03/under-the-whispering-door/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/under-the-whispering-door.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Under the Whispering Door
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.j.-klune">T.J. Klune&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Queernorm Setting (Hard: Not futuristic)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/tress-of-the-emerald-sea.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Tress of the Emerald Sea
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Coastal or Island Setting (Hard: Features sea-faring)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/13/dreamers-pool/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/dreamer-s-pool.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Dreamer&amp;#39;s Pool
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/juliet-marillier">Juliet Marillier&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Druids (Hard: Not the &lt;em>Iron Druid Chronicles&lt;/em>)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/lock-in/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/lock-in.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
Lock In
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/john-scalzi">John Scalzi&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Featuring Robots (Hard: Robot protagonist)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/the-infinite/">
&lt;figure class="hard-mode">
&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-infinite.jpg">
&lt;figcaption>
The Infinite
&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/a>&lt;p>by
&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ada-hoffmann">Ada Hoffmann&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Hard Mode ✓&lt;/p>&lt;hr>&lt;p>Sequel (Hard: Book 3+)&lt;/p>
&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;style>
h1, h2, h3 {
clear: both;
}
figure.cover-image {
float: left;
margin-right: 1em;
}
figure.cover-image img {
height: 100px;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="mini-reviews">Mini-reviews&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>‡ are my favorites, ∿ I listened to the audiobook. Full reviews + all reviews for each author are linked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ &lt;strong>Sequel (HM: Book 3+)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/the-infinite/">The Infinite&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ada-hoffmann/">Ada Hoffmann&lt;/a>. Sci-fi with post-singularity AI acting as gods and a touch of cosmic horror. Interesting discussions about neurodiversity. My favorite of the series and a solid conclusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Mundane Jobs (Not on Earth)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/12/phoenix-extravagant/">Phoenix Extravagant&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/yoon-ha-lee/">Yoon Ha Lee&lt;/a>. A parallel to the China/Japan conflicts of a century ago and the jobs and sacrifices normal people (esp. artists) have to make during times of war and occupation. Also, Arazi (the dragon on the cover) really sells the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>Published in the 00s (HM: (HM: Not top 30 on &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/11mvwsa/rfantasy_top_novels_2023_results/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this list&lt;/a>)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/">Throne of Jade&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/naomi-novik/">Naomi Novik&lt;/a>. What if the Napoleanic Wars, but with DRAGONS. This one now with more travel to China. It&amp;rsquo;s a neat concept and I like throughout the series how the idea is explored in a number of different cultures, although as the series goes on, it starts to wear a bit thin. Temeraire and Laurence (dragon and &amp;hellip; handler? it&amp;rsquo;s complicated) are really the soul of these books. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/temeraire/">Temeraire&lt;/a> is the first book in the series; but I&amp;rsquo;d previously read that years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ &lt;strong>Angels and Demons (HM: Protagonist)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/good-omens-the-nice-and-accurate-prophecies-of-agnes-nutter-witch/">Good Omens: The Nice and Accurate Prophecies of Agnes Nutter, Witch&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/neil-gaiman/">Neil Gaiman&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/terry-pratchett/">Terry Pratchett&lt;/a>. A mix of the wonderful worldbuilding of Pratchett and Gaiman that builds on both their strengths to build a fun ride, political/religious in exactly that fun somewhat blasphemous irreverent sort of way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Bottom of TBR&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/01/blindsight/">Blindsight&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peter-watts/">Peter Watts&lt;/a>. Vampires. In Space. It&amp;rsquo;s such a bonkers idea that I want more of it. Plus you get a surprisingly solid scientific reasoning for a lot of Vampire myths, a discussion on AI and the Chinese Room argument, talk about multiple personalities. It&amp;rsquo;s dense and a bit chaotic and weird. I liked it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Horror (HM: Not King or Lovecraft)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/prodigal-son/">Prodigal Son&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dean-koontz/">Dean Koontz&lt;/a>. What if Frankenstein survived into the modern era and tried to conquer the world Invasion of the Frankenbodysnatchers style. It&amp;rsquo;s a solid Dean Koontz book, which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read in years now. The problem is that it tries to fit far too many threads into one story and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work without the sequels (and only barely works with them). Another book dealing with autism, dealt with mostly well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ &lt;strong>Coastal or Island Setting (HM: Features Seafaring)&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/">Tress of the Emerald Sea&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a>. The feel of Princess Bride told through through the narrative lense of Hoid (which won&amp;rsquo;t make the least bit of sense if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read much of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s Cosmere I suppose). I&amp;rsquo;ve read and enjoyed just about all of Sanderson and he&amp;rsquo;s got 4 novels out this year, so of course I have to use one of them. It&amp;rsquo;s delightful, touching little story and probably worth a read even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the rest of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s work, although the ending will be weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>Queernorm Setting (HM: Not Futuristic)&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/03/under-the-whispering-door/">Under the Whispering Door&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.j.-klune/">T.J. Klune&lt;/a>. So… what do you call a slice of life story when the protagonist dies at the end of the first chapter? Whatever you do, Under the Whispering Door is a delightful example thereof. Despite taking place within our world, I would say it&amp;rsquo;s Queernorm within the much reduced setting of the story (the tea house and this specific corner of the afterishlife).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Set in the Middle East (HM: By an author of Middle Eastern heritage)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/07/girl-serpent-thorn/">Girl, Serpent, Thorn&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/melissa-bashardoust/">Melissa Bashardoust&lt;/a>. Take Persian mythology and worldbuilding, more than a touch of fairy tale feel, a cursed princess, demons, div (what in a Euro-centric story would be probably be fae), a touch of romance, and the spark of revolution. It’s an interesting world, an interesting premise, and you really want everything to go right in the end. I like the variety of non-humans. They feel the same as dozens of stories I read before–and yet, being based on a different set of myths and legends, different. All at the same time. It’s fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Title with a Title (HM: Not Royalty)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/the-handmaids-tale/">The Handmaid&amp;#39;s Tale&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/margaret-atwood/">Margaret Atwood&lt;/a>. Take the extremist end of the American Protestant religious right. Give them everything they want (plus some) over the span of years (if not months). Like any good story of this sort, it takes a potential problem–an idea–and turns it up to eleven. It goes steps further than anything we’ve seen in modern times–or at least differently. And all the more telling when you feel people in today&amp;rsquo;s world taking it as inspiration rather than a cautionary tale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Superheroes (HM: Not DC or Marvel)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/12/zeroes/">Zeroes&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/scott-westerfield/">Scott Westerfield&lt;/a>. The story of six American teenagers who discover they have superpowers. What I like most perhaps was the entire idea of the title: “Zeroes, not Heroes”. They’re not superheroes. (oops, guess it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit after all). I also enjoyed how diverse the cast was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Magical Realism or Literary Fantasy (HM: Not from &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/4bhiua/proposed_magical_realism_recommendation_list/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this list&lt;/a>)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/16/the-cartographers/">The Cartographers&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peng-shepherd/">Peng Shepherd&lt;/a>. Plus side: I love the premise. Take the idea of phantom settlements / copyright traps. Now make it so that if you happen to have the right map–you can actually get to those phantom settlements. I may have to check out Paper Towns. Minus side: it takes forever to actually get to the magic of the book. You (as the reader) are sure there’s more to them than you’d think, either having read the blurb–or just being aware of the book’s genre. But for how magical a concept it is, we barely get anything to do with them until halfway through the book and even then we’re only touching the surface. I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s Magical Realism for you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>Multiverse and Alternate Realities (HM: Not through a literal door)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/18/the-space-between-worlds/">The Space Between Worlds&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/micaiah-johnson/">Micaiah Johnson&lt;/a>. Hopping between worlds–with one big caveat. If you visit a world where another you is still alive, you die. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating digging into the idea that the best world hoppers are those raised under circumstances where they &lt;em>should have died&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Myths and Retellings (HM: Not Greek or Roman)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/23/the-witchs-heart/">The Witch&amp;#39;s Heart&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/genevieve-gornichec/">Genevieve Gornichec&lt;/a>. It seems no matter the culture, myths and legends get weird. Norse mythology is absolutely no exception to that. In this story, we have a novelization of the story of Angrboda. Wife of Loki. Mother of monsters. She’s been around a while (it’s mythology, even she doesn’t know how long) and she just wants to be left alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>Set in Space (HM: Not from Earth)&lt;/strong> (replacing Book Bingo/Readalong): &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/08/house-of-suns/">House of Suns&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/alastair-reynolds/">Alastair Reynolds&lt;/a>. In House of Suns, we have the story of a small subset of humanity writ large. The speed of light is the ultimate limit. Planets are decades apart; the galaxy hundreds of thousands of years around. So how do you continue that oh so human drive for exploration and expansion? Well in House of Suns, you create a thousand clones. Imprint them all with your memories. And send them out into the universe. Set it up so that ever few decades/centuries/millenia, they meet up, share all they’ve been to. What other branches of humanity have risen–or fallen? What other miracles of technology have been discovered? Who’s fallen in love? Sci-fi at it&amp;rsquo;s finest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Druids (HM: Not Iron Druid)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/13/dreamers-pool/">Dreamer&amp;#39;s Pool&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/juliet-marillier/">Juliet Marillier&lt;/a>. Take a bit of magic/folklore in an oldentimes Ireland; add in a Fae bargain (with all the complications that ensues); combine with a prince and princess who’ve never met outside of letters–and seem entirely different in person; and finish it all off with fairy tale magic of Dreamer’s Pool. It&amp;rsquo;s got an interesting cast and a nice fairy tale sort of plot, if a bit incomplete feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Mythical Beasts (HM: Not dragons)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/18/the-last-unicorn/">The Last Unicorn&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peter-s.-beagle/">Peter S. Beagle&lt;/a>. It’s one of those books that just feels like a fairy tale. An ageless story. A story passed down from long ago ages of myth and fantasy. Ages with heroes and villains and wizards and–you guessed it–unicorns. It’s beautifully written (for the most part; there are certainly parts that feel overdone), chock full of wonderfully fantastic descriptions and metaphors that just sort of stick around. I really enjoy the characters, especially the titular Last Unicorn&amp;ndash;they don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>feel&lt;/em> human; which I appreciate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Featuring Robots (HM: Robot protagonist)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/lock-in/">Lock In&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/john-scalzi/">John Scalzi&lt;/a>. A near future Earth where a flu-like pandemic (Haden’s Syndrome) has caused locked-in syndrome in some small percent of the world’s population (a small percent of billions is still an awful lot of people). Those affected are completely paralyzed, unable to move, while still being fully aware and conscious. Luckily(ish) a massive global effort has figured out how to embed computer hardware in their brains so as to allow them to remotely pilot either robotic bodies (threeps) or (more rarely) other humans who’ve allowed them access. This of course is widely accepted by the rest of humanity and causes no issues whatsoever. It&amp;rsquo;s arguable if the human minds in robotic bodies (the threeps) counts for the square, but if Murderbot counts, I would think this does too? It&amp;rsquo;s their body (although that&amp;rsquo;s a decent plot point in itself).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Novella (HM: Not Tordotcom)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/26/six-gun-snow-white/">Six-Gun Snow White&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/catherynne-m.-valente/">Catherynne M. Valente&lt;/a>. Take (the vague outline) the story of Snow White. Make it a Western. Things get weird. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting premise and certainly an interesting writing style&amp;ndash;although not my favorite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>5 SFF Shorts (HM: An Anthology)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/30/stories-of-your-life-and-others/">Stories of Your Life and Others&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ted-chiang/">Ted Chiang&lt;/a>. Story of Your Life became the film Arrival, which got me to read the book. The rest are also really good, including some really interesting alternate takes on religion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>YA (HM: Published in the last 5 years)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/04/a-wizards-guide-to-defensive-baking/">A Wizard&amp;#39;s Guide to Defensive Baking&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/">T. Kingfisher&lt;/a>. A world with weirdly specialized sorts of wizards. You might be able to cast lightning bolts… or you might have the power to animate and converse with dead horses. Or you might even have magical powers over… bread! It’s such a delightful idea and Kingfisher manages to do all sorts of fun things with it. Some obvious (Mongo eat your gingerbread heart out), some less so (Bob the sourdough starter; so delightful). I need to read more Kingfisher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>POC Author (HM: Furturistic Sci/fi)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/06/rosewater/">Rosewater&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/tade-thompson/">Tade Thompson&lt;/a>. A fascinating premise. Take the world a half century in the future. Most things are the same, but there’s a bit more tech floating around, mostly. Introduce a massive alien organism that lands in London and ends up burrowing it’s way to Nigeria. From that alien blob, fill the atmosphere with alien microorganisms/cells that create their own xenosphere, enabling (among other things) psychic powers in some very small proportion of the population. Writ rather more gritty than I was expecting with a complicated structure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Self/Indie published (HM: Fewer than 100 ratings)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/10/the-book-of-zog/">The Book of Zog&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/alec-hutson/">Alec Hutson&lt;/a>. Zogrusz is an Eldrich Horror, a being from beyond time and space. But… a nice one? That just wants to do the right thing? It&amp;rsquo;s surprisingly adorable with some interesting cosmic level universebuilding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Elemental Magic (HM: Not Shades of Magic or Codex Alera)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/leigh-bardugo/">Leigh Bardugo&lt;/a>. Rather YA and the TV show is better (partially because it pulls from the other series in the same world as well). But I did enjoy the Russian influenced worldbuilding and the slightly more flexible than many YA contemporaries groupings. Has a lot of potential for the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Published in 2023 (HM: Debut)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/the-scourge-between-stars/">The Scourge Between Stars&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ness-brown/">Ness Brown&lt;/a>. A generation ship with something going bump in the night? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it always night in space? In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s nicely terrifying if rather short (at novella length). Feels &lt;em>very&lt;/em> similar to Alien, but that&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing. A solid debut.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(I originally read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/29/venco/">VenCo&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/cherie-dimaline/">Cherie Dimaline&lt;/a> for this spot, but realized as I was writing this post that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit hard mode.)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="some-stats">Some stats&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Audiobooks: 14. The rest were all ebooks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Borrowed on Libby: 21. Libraries are the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Series (that I read the rest of):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>All 3 of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/21/the-outside/">The Outside&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ada-hoffmann/">Ada Hoffmann&lt;/a> (between 2022 and 2023 bingos).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All 9 of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/temeraire/">Temeraire&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/naomi-novik/">Naomi Novik&lt;/a> (reread the first; rest this year).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All 5 of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/dean-koontzs-frankenstein/">Dean Koontz&amp;#39;s Frankenstein&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dean-koontz/">Dean Koontz&lt;/a>. Duh. 😄&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>New (to me) authors: 15&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/alec-hutson/">Alec Hutson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/catherynne-m.-valente/">Catherynne M. Valente&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/cherie-dimaline/">Cherie Dimaline&lt;/a> (replaced with a different story for hard mode, but I did read for the bingo)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/genevieve-gornichec/">Genevieve Gornichec&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/juliet-marillier/">Juliet Marillier&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/leigh-bardugo/">Leigh Bardugo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/margaret-atwood/">Margaret Atwood&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/melissa-bashardoust/">Melissa Bashardoust&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/micaiah-johnson/">Micaiah Johnson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ness-brown/">Ness Brown&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peng-shepherd/">Peng Shepherd&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peter-s.-beagle/">Peter S. Beagle&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peter-watts/">Peter Watts&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/tade-thompson/">Tade Thompson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ted-chiang/">Ted Chiang&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Repeat authors for book bingo: 5&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ada-hoffmann/">Ada Hoffmann&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/21/the-outside/">The Outside&lt;/a> for 2022&amp;rsquo;s Features Mental Health.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/naomi-novik/">Naomi Novik&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/">A Deadly Education&lt;/a> for 2022&amp;rsquo;s Anti-Hero.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/">T. Kingfisher&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/">Nettle &amp;amp; Bone&lt;/a> for 2022&amp;rsquo;s Author Uses Initials.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.j.-klune/">T.J. Klune&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/18/the-house-in-the-cerulean-sea/">The House in the Cerulean Sea&lt;/a> for 2021&amp;rsquo;s Found Family.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/yoon-ha-lee/">Yoon Ha Lee&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/22/the-vela/">The Vela&lt;/a> for 2022&amp;rsquo;s Two or More Authors.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Other repeat authors: 7&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/alastair-reynolds/">Alastair Reynolds&lt;/a>. Originally &amp;lsquo;read&amp;rsquo; him on the Escape Pod podcast. Also Revelation Space.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve read everything he&amp;rsquo;s written (except Alcatraz). First time a new book fit a Bingo square though.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dean-koontz/">Dean Koontz&lt;/a>. Read a lot of him before I started writing reviews, although only this series since.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/john-scalzi/">John Scalzi&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/23/old-mans-war/">Old Man&amp;#39;s War&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/neil-gaiman/">Neil Gaiman&lt;/a>. All sorts of things. and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/scott-westerfield/">Scott Westerfield&lt;/a>. Read Uglies et al years ago; didn&amp;rsquo;t even realize it was the same author.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/terry-pratchett/">Terry Pratchett&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/discworld/">Discworld&lt;/a>. All of it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>