<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2022 Book Bingo Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/13/2022-book-bingo-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/13/2022-book-bingo-retrospective/</guid><description>BINGO!
One year ago, I started my (second) 2022 Book Bingo. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how I did!
2022 Book Bingo Toggle Display Mode Foundryside (Hard Mode)
A book on r/Fantasy&amp;rsquo;s Top LGBTQIA List (Hard: A book/series with ten votes or less)
The Bone Ships (Hard Mode)
Weird Ecology (Hard: Not written by Jeff VanderMeer or China Miéville)
The Vela (Hard Mode)
Two or More Authors (Hard: Three or More)
A Declaration of the Rights of Magicians (Hard Mode)</description></item><item><title>Ultimate Iron Man, Vol. 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/13/ultimate-iron-man-vol.-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/13/ultimate-iron-man-vol.-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. Iron Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The whole idea that they don’t know that Iron Man is a man in a suit rather than a robot and that for some reason Tony wants to keep it that way—and thinks that he can is a bit crazy to me&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not to mention that the healing factor (and thus Tony’s disregard for getting hurt) still feels wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A really weird/rough way to take Iron Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a bit of a bummer, since I enjoyed Card’s earlier writing (Ender’s game primarily) even if his later stuff got weird and preachy. But I still had hope…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ready to move on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Legends &amp; Lattes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/legends-lattes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/legends-lattes/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>After twenty-two years of adventuring, Viv had reached her limit of blood and mud and bullshit. An ore&amp;rsquo;s life was strength and violence and a sudden, sharp end - but she&amp;rsquo;d be damned if she&amp;rsquo;d let hers finish that way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was time for something new.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A retired orc barbarian and a succubus with artistic flair open a coffee shop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nope, not even a joke. Instead, it’s the heart of one of the best examples of cozy fantasy I’ve read yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I haven’t even mentioned the ratkin with their heavenly cinnamon rolls, the hob carpenter (hm), and a shy bard with a flair for experimental music.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Iron Man, Vol. 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-iron-man-vol.-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-iron-man-vol.-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>That is not at all what I expected. Tony Stark, born with super powers. Constant pain and a regeneration factor. It’s… quite different. Too different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think there’s a reason this was later removed from the Ultimate Marvel canon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 1: The Tomorrow People</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-x-men-vol.-1-the-tomorrow-people/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-x-men-vol.-1-the-tomorrow-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting the team together, sleeper agent Wolverine, love triangles, betrayal, mass murder, and the bluening of Beast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is an awful lot to fit into a single volume…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The philosophical differences between Professor X and his X-Men versus Magneto and his Brotherhood is quite often at the core of these stories, so it’s no surprise to see it here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only question is… what comes next?!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Letters from a Shipwreck in the Sea of Suns and Moons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/letters-from-a-shipwreck-in-the-sea-of-suns-and-moons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/letters-from-a-shipwreck-in-the-sea-of-suns-and-moons/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We are the interviewers. For a story.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And who am I?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You are the old sailor who remembers being a young sailor on Unicorn, a three masted schooner out of San Francisco plying the Pacific waters.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That sounds familiar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You are Clarence St. Elmo, for a name. You are a bad poet lost in the sea of time, a castaway on an island where the dead gods wander.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That sounds awful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>And beyond a name, on that side of things, past the mirror and the window and the words, you are the Keeper of Shipwreck Light in the Sea of Suns and Moons.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, I knew that.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;hellip; is a truly delightfully weird book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It jumps around in structure and time between letters from a sailor to the girl he left back home&amp;ndash;to said sailor being interviewed by &amp;hellip; someone&amp;ndash;to stories about a most mysterious shipwreck and the island he came to inhabit thereafter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Structurally, it&amp;rsquo;s very strange and at times hard to figure out what in the world is going on&amp;ndash;but that&amp;rsquo;s all intentional. It&amp;rsquo;s really quite worth it in the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s not much more I can say without spoiling the whole thing&amp;ndash;that is, if I really actually understood what and how, if anything, of the story actually happened. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth a read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Consider Phlebas</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/consider-phlebas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/consider-phlebas/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Culture: a &amp;ldquo;a utopian, post-scarcity space society of humanoid aliens, and advanced superintelligent artificial intelligences living in artificial habitats spread across the Milky Way galaxy&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture%20series">Culture series&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Besides, it left the humans in the Culture free to take care of the things that really mattered in life, such as sports, games, romance, studying dead languages, barbarian societies and impossible problems, and climbing high mountains without the aid of a safety harness.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;d think (or at least I did) from that description that we&amp;rsquo;d have everything starting in a state of wonder and harmony&amp;hellip; and only then watch things go to hell (because otherwise, where&amp;rsquo;s the story?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So imagine my surprise where (in Consider Phlebas), we start in the middle of a war between the Culture and another group (the Idirans) told from the point of a view of a shape shifting secret agent (more or less) who ends up with a crew of mercenaries (no, they&amp;rsquo;re a &amp;lsquo;Free Company&amp;rsquo;), goes through a few disastrous missions with them, almost gets eaten by a disgusting gigantic blob of a religious cult leader, breaks into a card game where the stakes are real human lives, and finally comes back to a graveyard system and then just about everyone dies.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Experience as well as common sense indicated that the most reliable method of avoiding self-extinction was not to equip oneself with the means to accomplish it in the first place.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I &amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t even know what to say.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Elektra: Devil's Due</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/ultimate-elektra-devils-due/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/ultimate-elektra-devils-due/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-elektra-70326f.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing bad ever came of a ‘who can you trust?’&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The contrast between Matt Murdock and Elektra is really what sells these stories. Doing what’s right versus what needs to be done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope to see more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if Kingpin is involved…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Daredevil &amp; Elektra</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/ultimate-daredevil-elektra/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/ultimate-daredevil-elektra/</guid><description>&lt;p>Only &lt;strike>one volume&lt;/strike> two volumes. Interesting. Let’s go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-daredevil-and-elektra-c573e5.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Elektra making new friends at college.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-daredevil-and-elektra-f7b716.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And a younger than I’m used to Matt Murdock, already fighting crime and just starting in on the law stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course things escalate quickly and of course something has to drive them apart. One of the rules of comics it seems. No one can be happy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope we see more of them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 2: Learning Curve</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/10/ultimate-spider-man-volume-2-learning-curve/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/10/ultimate-spider-man-volume-2-learning-curve/</guid><description>&lt;p>Spider-Man starts to settle in to his new life. School, a job, a bit of light vigilantism, perhaps a date with MJ…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and of course decides to set his sights on the big man himself: Mr. Fisk. Kingpin. He’s a personal favorite big (heh) bad of mine. So I’m looking forward to where this goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also I’m enjoying the teenage dynamic. So far as I’m concerned they nailed it. It’s insane, what he’s trying to do… but it feels so right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 1: Power and Responsibility</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/09/ultimate-spider-man-volume-1-power-and-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/09/ultimate-spider-man-volume-1-power-and-responsibility/</guid><description>&lt;p>Peter Parker gets beat up at school; Parker goes in a field trip to Osborn’s lab; spider goes chomp; etc. It’s the standard Spider-Man origin, especially if you (like me) started with the Sam Raimu Spider-Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you have to start somewhere right? It’s a solid story, I like the art, and we’re setting up for something big.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shaman</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/08/shaman/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/08/shaman/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There are no secrets, there is no mystery. We make that all up. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s all right there in front of us. You have to have enough food to get through winter and spring. That&amp;rsquo;s what it all comes down to. You have to live in a way that will gather enough food each fall to get through winter.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Take a survival story (a la Gary Paulsen&amp;rsquo;s Hatchet), re-tune it for a world where survival is life rather than a temporary situation (ten thousand or so years ago), sprinkle in an oddly modern feeling narrator, and make it super horny&amp;hellip; voila. Shaman.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I at once rather enjoyed it and was rather annoyed by good parts of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 11: Homeschooling</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/06/runaways-vol.-11-homeschooling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/06/runaways-vol.-11-homeschooling/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v11-8a6ca4.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh boy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New family! Gert? (We’ve done not-Alex already)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then it just ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Super depressing. Just stop at volume 8.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 10: Rock Zombies</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/06/runaways-vol.-10-rock-zombies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/06/runaways-vol.-10-rock-zombies/</guid><description>&lt;p>Music laced with spells turns anyone who has plastic surgery ugly. Not even kidding. Also zombies, but apparently they’re not actually dead (killing of like half of LA is apparently too much). So … just ugly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s… fine?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I didn’t even take any pretty pictures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we weren’t down to one more volume and a new writer…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 9: Dead Wrong</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/06/runaways-vol.-9-dead-wrong/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/06/runaways-vol.-9-dead-wrong/</guid><description>&lt;p>That is quite an art shift.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v9-f542e7.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And quite a cosmic plot line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How do you even deal with billions dead somewhere out there across the universe?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and I feel like Chase got stupider. In a bad way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v9-edbd5f.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s something of a reason… but he was off even before Scatter’ing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fine, but I liked the earlier works. We’ll see how it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Betsy-Tacy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/05/betsy-tacy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/05/betsy-tacy/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“When Betsy is happy,” her mother said, “she is happier than anyone else in the world.” Then she added, “And she’s almost always happy.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A cute book to read with younger children. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s the story about Tacy (she&amp;rsquo;s shy) and Betsy (she tells everyone that Tacy is shy). They go on adventures, have a clubhouse, and eventually find another new friend&amp;ndash;just in time to start another book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 8: Dead End Kids</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/04/runaways-vol.-8-dead-end-kids/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/04/runaways-vol.-8-dead-end-kids/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you’re (perpetually) on the run and need a favor, who do you call?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kingpin… apparently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So of course things go all sorts of sideways. And of course time travel gets involved—because comics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Delightful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so ends the 2005-2008 run. Onwards!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Succulents and Spells</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/03/succulents-and-spells/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/03/succulents-and-spells/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Marigold took a deep breath. &amp;ldquo;My name is Marigold Ann Nightfield. I use she/her pronouns. I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD
candidate in biomedical science.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laurel offered her hand across the table, and Marigold took it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Laurel Windflower. She/her as well.&amp;rdquo; She didn’t mention the incomplete MA she&amp;rsquo;d been postponing, for one reason or another, for the past two years. &amp;ldquo;So, is your PhD in monster biology or something?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That was delightful. It&amp;rsquo;s a cozy urban fantasy, light and cute with just enough touches of something bigger and more dangerous out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth a read. And at a novella length 100 pages, it&amp;rsquo;s worth trying just to see if you like it. And if you do, there are a handful more to dig deeper! (I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 7: Live Fast</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/02/runaways-vol.-7-live-fast/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/02/runaways-vol.-7-live-fast/</guid><description>&lt;p>You know, I didn’t expect turning 18 and then &lt;em>immediately&lt;/em> turning to the dark side as a plot line. Fits though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v7-1e72b0.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But he at last has &lt;em>good intentions&lt;/em> and all that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So of course it’s up to friends old and new to try to stop Chase from doing any number of dumber than average even for him things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A solid story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onwards!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin and Other Stories</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/02/skin-and-other-stories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/02/skin-and-other-stories/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="skin-and-other-stories">Skin and Other Stories&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m really only familiar with stories like Charlie and the Chocolate Factory and James and the Giant Peach. They&amp;rsquo;re certainly fantastical stories with a number of fairly subtle dark twists to them, but still well within the realm of children&amp;rsquo;s stories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well&amp;hellip; it turns out he wrote some more adult, much more tense ones at all. It&amp;rsquo;s somewhere in that border realm between realism, fantasy, and horror, not quite terrifying but certainly creepy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The stories are quick and always have the creepy sort of twist, although I&amp;rsquo;ll admit there were a few I just don&amp;rsquo;t really get. So it goes. Still worth it, in my opinion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Year Zero</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/02/year-zero/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/02/year-zero/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“The terms of this contract shall apply past the end of time and the edge of Earth; all throughout the universe; in perpetuity; in any media, whether now known, or hereafter devised; or in any form, whether now known, or hereafter devised.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Take a sci-fi universe that&amp;rsquo;s got just enough &amp;lsquo;it&amp;rsquo;s that way because it&amp;rsquo;s amusing&amp;rsquo; in it to feel an awful lot like Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy, build the story around the idea that aliens are bad at music, really dig into the music industry lawsuits from around the year 2000 (applied across space and time), and tell the story from the point of view of a low level copyright lawyer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Voila. Year Zero.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“No, we haven’t stopped the spread of pirated music or movies online, nor have we slowed it even slightly. But we do get paid pornographically vast sums for trying our very best.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 6: Parental Guidance</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/01/runaways-vol.-6-parental-guidance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/01/runaways-vol.-6-parental-guidance/</guid><description>&lt;p>The one where we finally get a hint at what’s been going on with the other new Pride.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v6-3469d1.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That never does go well. Plus short bits with Molly on her own and Karolina in space! The gang is back (ish)!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until as the cover says… one of them has to die.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 5: Escape to New York</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/28/runaways-vol.-5-escape-to-new-york/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/28/runaways-vol.-5-escape-to-new-york/</guid><description>&lt;p>The one where Karolina is apparently engaged to someone from way out of town, Cloak and Dagger are back and need help (field trip!), and we get a few moments of some of the Big Names in Marvel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a cute story, well contained with a bit leading up to what’s coming I’m looking forward to… but Karolina just vanishing into space was… kind of weird. I like her. Hope she’s back soon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 4: True Believers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/26/runaways-vol.-4-true-believers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/26/runaways-vol.-4-true-believers/</guid><description>&lt;p>The one with the time travel, yo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v4-3a5f94.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bit more traditional super hero flare, but still with a Runaways twist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s a big bad in the future and our intrepid heroes(ish) have to find him as a teenager and … deal with him. Because that worked out so well the last two times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus all sorts of b-tier / c-tier hero cameos… I have no idea which of these were made up for this story and which have decades long comics ruins of their own. And some rather higher level villains about. Now that was a surprise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A fun ride.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Cloud Roads</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/26/the-cloud-roads/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/26/the-cloud-roads/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a fascinating sort of book, especially having read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-murderbot-diaries/">The Murderbot Diaries&lt;/a> first. It&amp;rsquo;s not entirely the same thing at all&amp;ndash;fantasy rather than science fiction, with a world full of floating eyes and many different sapient races rather than aliens and murderbots&amp;ndash;but there are some bones that aren&amp;rsquo;t too dissimilar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, you have Moon. He&amp;rsquo;s a Raksura, a being capable of transforming between a more or less human form (although I don&amp;rsquo;t get the feeling there are any real &amp;lsquo;humans&amp;rsquo; in this book) and a much larger stronger winged form. He&amp;rsquo;s all on his own, not even sure what he is&amp;ndash;or where he fits in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which of course goes badly when the people he&amp;rsquo;s staying with think he&amp;rsquo;s Fell (winged &amp;rsquo;evil&amp;rsquo; creatures; I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that). And much better when another Raksura finds him and brings him back. And worse again when it turns out they don&amp;rsquo;t want him either. And better again when, of course, he saves the day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Evershore</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/25/evershore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/25/evershore/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Like the Saint says, if you don’t have anything to say, you might scare your flightleader into thinking you’re dead.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The one with Jerkface and the Kitsen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like all of the Starsight novellas, we have a focus on what else has been going on while Spena has been doing her &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/cytonic/">Cytonic&lt;/a> things. This time&amp;ndash;as you might guess&amp;ndash;with Jerkface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s actually really great to see his point of view and especially to see just how much he&amp;rsquo;s grown throughout the books. He was always a leader, but he&amp;rsquo;s really coming into it now&amp;ndash;and really realizing that sometimes, just maybe, the books might be &lt;em>wrong&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do also love seeing more of the Kitsen. They&amp;rsquo;re really building up a regular anti-Superiority alliance there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the biggest bummer now is having to wait for Defiant to come out this November&amp;hellip; Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 3: The Good Die Young</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/25/runaways-vol.-3-the-good-die-young/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/25/runaways-vol.-3-the-good-die-young/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finally getting some answers!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v3-1440de.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Who (and why) the Pride &lt;strong>are&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v3-e7b707.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what they mean when they say it’s all for the children…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/downton-abbey-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/downton-abbey-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Somehow I&amp;rsquo;m always surprised when a highly rated show is actually good. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From a modern, American, middle-class point of view, the idea of the early 1900s British Aristocracy is just so strange. They do next nothing (useful) and have an entire staff to support it. The entire estate could go to a cousin they&amp;rsquo;d never met and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing they can do about it &amp;hellip; is so strange.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s oddly charming?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Grantham&amp;rsquo;s are fascinating. Sybil seems good people, Edith is certainly going to figure out how to come into her own, Mary is spoiled and needlessly cruel&amp;ndash;but may be learning. Lord and Lady Grantham are fun, if somewhat alien&amp;ndash;and I do love watching Lord Grantham try and completely fail to wrangle three young adult daughters. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The shining jewel of the family Dame Maggie Smith&amp;rsquo;s Dowager Countess of Grantham. Oh she&amp;rsquo;s just wonderful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among the staff, you have a whole &amp;rsquo;nother level of politics. They&amp;rsquo;re all great and terrible (as they should be) and there are every bit as many problems and politics as there are among the &amp;lsquo;family&amp;rsquo;. Turns out people are people no matter how much money they have or do not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a crazy amount to fit into seven episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward&amp;hellip; to war!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 2: Teenage Wasteland</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/runaways-vol.-2-teenage-wasteland/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/runaways-vol.-2-teenage-wasteland/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v2-505090.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so the team grows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They’re so amusingly teenager. Angst and boy / girl issues contrasting against their parents trying to find / capture / kill then. Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s fun watching them try to grow up fast. I have no idea how they end up getting out of this mess… or what their parents are really up to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which is the best part!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magical Midlife Madness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/magical-midlife-madness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/magical-midlife-madness/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But the truth was, I didn’t feel accepted. I didn’t feel acknowledged for my service in raising the next generation, for my active role in the community, or even for being human sometimes. I felt utterly ignored. I felt invisible or, worse, frowned upon. Most of the time, when I looked in the mirror, I saw only my flaws. I saw all the things that advertisements and social media said was wrong with me. I wanted to focus on what was right about this version of myself, like the way I’d learned to take life a little slower and enjoy each moment. Like my appreciation for people’s differences, and for beauty found in unlikely places. For my friendships, new and old. I wanted it to be okay that I wasn’t worried about beauty anymore, or worried about looking young. I just wanted to look like me, however me looked in any given year.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Take your normal urban fantasy fair: our world, but with a few twists&amp;ndash;gargoyles for one, this time. Add in your &amp;rsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; point of view about to get their world rocked. This time around make them a 40 year old woman recently gone through a divorce. Make sure that none of this really gets moving until the last third or so of the book (better if you&amp;rsquo;re going to read the whole series I suppose).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Magical Midlife Madness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fine and I expect there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to like about the rest of the series, but to me the entire thing just sort of existed. Not that much happened, there was entirely too much wish fulfillment, and too much focus on &amp;lsquo;it&amp;rsquo;s okay to be 40&amp;rsquo; (which it totally is, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, just not chapters and chapters worth).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not a bad book. It&amp;rsquo;s not the kind of book for me. I won&amp;rsquo;t be reading the rest of the series. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Vela</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/22/the-vela/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/22/the-vela/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Eratos wasn’t the only dying world, just the one dying fastest—the tiny colony on Samos had been gone for a decade, and after Eratos would be Hypatia and then Gan-De, and maybe the Inner Ring would finally come to care when it was their turn to freeze to death as the sun collapsed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A leisurely extinction. One that allowed everyone to push any inconvenience to another place or another generation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Vela is part of a fascinating sort of new/old model: serialized fiction. In this case &lt;a href="https://www.realm.fm/">Realm.fm (formerly Serial Box)&lt;/a> is putting out piles of audio fiction by a number of well known authors chapter by chapter. And yet&amp;hellip; somehow I read the ebook version from the library. I really should check out the audio versions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, The worldbuilding (as in the above quote) in the Vela is fascinating. A nearish-future tech sci-fi universe where humanity has managed to extract enough resources from the local star to freeze out the outer planets, wrecking all manner of havoc among the people that live out there. There&amp;rsquo;s all manner of classism, racism, and other racisms to digest&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Set against the backdrop of a missing starship (the Vela) and the two unlikely companions (Asala and Niko) who are sent to go find it. I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see Becky Chambers as one of the authors here, I really love how she does &amp;lsquo;people stories&amp;rsquo;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet read the other three authors, but they&amp;rsquo;re all on my to-read shelf already and higher up now. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between Asala (hard bitten mercenary/sniper) and Nike (child of the president; hacker) throughout the stories is really the shining jewel of the series. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the slight (IMO) variations between how the different authors see and write them, but it&amp;rsquo;s still well worth reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well well worth a read. Or a listen. And Season 2 is on Realm? Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People spoke about the death of planets as if the rock itself would shatter, but the truth was never so dramatic. The entire sphere wasn&amp;rsquo;t in danger of ceasing to exist. All that mattered was the inner goings-on of that tiny strip of gauze, that onion skin of atmosphere clinging to the rocky surface like morning dew. The narrowest of margins on which everything depended.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Runaways, Vol. 1: Pride and Joy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/21/runaways-vol.-1-pride-and-joy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/21/runaways-vol.-1-pride-and-joy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reading volume 1, issue 1:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v1-eeae62.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh that’s fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/runaways-v1-569e60.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh that’s even better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s a very promising start to a fascinating story. The kids are fun and I like seeing the mix of teenage dynamics with mysterious new powers and problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No idea what their parents are really up to, but that’s the point, no?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602: Witch Hunter Angela</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/20/marvel-1602-witch-hunter-angela/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/20/marvel-1602-witch-hunter-angela/</guid><description>&lt;p>The last of the 1602 stories, so far as I know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A truly odd story of two women hunting. I … don’t actually know so they are in the original continuity. So I’m not sure what changes here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Various panels making our clear that the characters are aware of our time and that they aren’t in it… is an odd choice. Related to the above perhaps?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The art changes style from part to part and some of it absolutely gorgeous in a haunting sort of way, other parts oddly surreal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I enjoyed it, if perhaps the least of this run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602: Spider-Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/20/marvel-1602-spider-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/20/marvel-1602-spider-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s straight up Spider-Man, 400 years ago. Octavius, Lizard, Goblin, Fisk. All the villains you’d expect in about to the ways you’d expect them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s enjoyable, but not exactly groundbreaking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My one (strong dislike) is replacing Virginia Dare with Mary Jane Watsonne. So not necessary… a problem with comics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cytonic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/cytonic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/cytonic/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Stories say something. About us, and about where we came from. They’re a reminder that we have a past, a history. And a future.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was certainly a thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/28/skyward/">Skyward&lt;/a> introduced us to some far future humans trapped on a planet by terrifying aliens. Spensa learns how to fight, teachers her friends and allies how to be awesome, and saves the day from the aliens!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/">Starsight&lt;/a>, we get off world. We&amp;rsquo;re introduced us to some of those same aliens. Turns out they&amp;rsquo;re people, more or less just like us. So Spensa learns how to spy, teachers her new friends and allies how to be awesome, and saves the day from the Eldrich Horrors From Beyond Space!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So of course in Cytonic&amp;hellip; Spensa goes Beyond Space. She adventures through all manners of weird environments, meets a bunch of Pirates From Beyond Space&amp;hellip; And learns to fight, teachers her friends and allies how to be awesome, and saves the universe?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m starting to sense a pattern here.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>All people must accept that we have the potential to do terrible things. It is part of seeing our place in the universe, our heritage, and our natures. But in that acceptance we gain strength, for potential can be refused. Any hero who could have been a monster is more heroic for the choices he or she made to walk another road.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602: Fantastick Four</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/marvel-1602-fantastick-four/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/marvel-1602-fantastick-four/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Four of the Fantastick. A story I’m more or less familiar with, only from various movies rather than the comics. Here, they’re in the world created by time travel to 1602. Doom wants to travel beyond the edge of the world to heal his face and takes Shakespeare along for the ride.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interesting enough story. Weird to involve Shakespeare.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602: New World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/18/marvel-1602-new-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/18/marvel-1602-new-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/17/marvel-1602/">Marvel 1602&lt;/a> established a world where time travel managed to accidentally cause various heroes to be born around the year 1602, now in New World we see more fallout if that story. The 1602 Master Spider of course, but also Lord Iron, Master Jameson and his broadsheet, and, of course, the Hulk—who needs no puny time periodic appropriate name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It feels like somewhat smaller a story than the original 1602 and more like we’re reading something that we’ve seen before, just with a new coat of paint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still fun though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/17/marvel-1602/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/17/marvel-1602/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sir Nicholas Fury, with his servant Peter Parquagh. Stephen Strange, master of medicines. A blind man jumping around in the night. Sister Wanda, with her red habit. Witchbreed. So many new takes on old friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh. And dinosaurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/marvel-1602-8f5230.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As things escalate, it turns out there may very well be a reason everything is out of time… as there always had to be in a comic book. It’s neat when you get there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read. It’s certainly an interesting ride.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hawkeye, Volume 6: Hawkeyes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/05/hawkeye-volume-6-hawkeyes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/05/hawkeye-volume-6-hawkeyes/</guid><description>&lt;p>One part now:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/hawkeye-2012-v6-c76564.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One part future:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/hawkeye-2012-v6-fba351.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One part America (Chavez)!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/hawkeye-2012-v6-69e746.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a neat story, finishing up the story of Project Communion from volume 5, digging into how very much baggage both Hawkeyes carry, and really giving their working together a chance to (eventually) shine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Lord of the Rings: The Rings of Power</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/the-lord-of-the-rings-the-rings-of-power/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/the-lord-of-the-rings-the-rings-of-power/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that’s quite the thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They couldn’t/didn’t get the rights to the third age, so instead we get much older stories. Stories after the fall of Morgoth but still during the end of the era of Elves and Númenor. Before the rise of the kingdoms of Men.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s a lot crammed into eight episodes. One might argue too much. Leaves some stories a bit thin. But really, having seen them, I don’t know what I’d cut.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a watch. Looking forward to season two!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hawkeye, Volume 5: All-New Hawkeye</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/hawkeye-volume-5-all-new-hawkeye/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/hawkeye-volume-5-all-new-hawkeye/</guid><description>&lt;p>Project Communion&amp;ndash;whatever that is. The implication that S.H.I.E.L.D. isn’t really much better than H.Y.D.R.A. sometimes. Hawkeyes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a solid mostly self contained adventure. I enjoyed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not a huge fan of the pastel flashbacks. Hard to read at best. The story is neat—origin story!—but I want to skip it just because of the style.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ReDawn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/redawn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/redawn/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A prisoner could be convinced that they lived in a paradise, if the prison was pretty enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>ReDawn is a lot like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/">Sunreach&lt;/a> in that it&amp;rsquo;s a cousin to the main Skyward books, really expanding the universe and letting us know what the rest of Skyward flight (and others) were getting up to while Spensa was&amp;hellip; otherwise occupied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around&amp;hellip; the point of view is Alanik, the near human alien that crashed into Detritus right at the beginning of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/">Starsight&lt;/a>, enabling the events of that book.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I didn’t know enough about human politics to know who was correct, but I did know enough about politics in general to guess that everyone would interpret the law in the way that best suited themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s facinating to have a point of view from someone who grew up in this universe on an alien world (bubbles of air around giant trees!) with an alien culture&amp;ndash;that in this case is actually tied to humanity throughout the past. It gives us a way to dig more into the relationships (especially the &amp;lsquo;relationships&amp;rsquo;) between the humans all the more, which I enjoyed a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;hellip; learning more about the Taynix / slugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty fun story, well worth it&amp;rsquo;s place as a Skyward sidestory novella!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hawkeye, Volume 4: Rio Bravo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/01/hawkeye-volume-4-rio-bravo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/01/hawkeye-volume-4-rio-bravo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Down on his luck, eh? Oh the fallout from buying the building. Standing up to the goons. Poor &lt;span class="spoiler">Gil&lt;/span>
. :/&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In comics everything ends up connected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we get deaf Hawkeye storyline. Not quite the same as the show, but its neat seeing inspirations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s quite the story and good to see some closure of sorts. For now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hawkeye, Volume 3: L.A. Woman</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/01/hawkeye-volume-3-l.a.-woman/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/01/hawkeye-volume-3-l.a.-woman/</guid><description>&lt;p>A conversation with my children:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>e: what are you reading?&lt;br>
J: Hawkeye&lt;br>
…&lt;br>
z: what are you reading?&lt;br>
e: hawk pie&lt;br>
z: why are you reading pot pie&lt;br>
e: hawk pie&lt;br>
z: no that isn’t right&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And now, a quick interluded with the &lt;em>other&lt;/em> Hawkeye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/hawkeye-2012-v3-391282.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Broke in LA. Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course she finds her own trouble. And gets herself out of it. More or less. I like comics Kate Bishop. The real strengths are the Hawkeyes together though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Build Your Own Redis with C/C++</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/31/build-your-own-redis-with-c/c-/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/31/build-your-own-redis-with-c/c-/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stumbled on &lt;a href="https://build-your-own.org/">Build Your Own Redis with C/C++&lt;/a>. Decided to read it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To some extent&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what the point is. It does definitely go into a lot of the networking and data structure details you&amp;rsquo;d need to build your own Redis. So it certainly lives up to the name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, I feel like a lot of the book is spent down in the weeds, implementing some of the less important details of how Redis works. At that level, it&amp;rsquo;s a generic networking/data structures book with Redis as the example. Which works, just not something that I need at this point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hawkeye, Volume 2: Little Hits</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/31/hawkeye-volume-2-little-hits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/31/hawkeye-volume-2-little-hits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Clint is in over his head. Again. Tracksuit mafia. Managing a building. Installing AV equipment. Valentine’s Day. Women.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/hawkeye-2012-v2-905413.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dog gets it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Poor &lt;span class="spoiler">Gil&lt;/span>
. :/&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a neat story, if somewhat incomplete.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hawkeye, Volume 1: My Life as a Weapon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/30/hawkeye-volume-1-my-life-as-a-weapon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/30/hawkeye-volume-1-my-life-as-a-weapon/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Avengers don’t really make any sense… Hawkeye least of all. It’s the Disney+ series in a nutshell. Let’s see how the comics did it first…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, so I can see how the bones are the same, but it’s a different story. Hawkeye (s)? Check. Clint and Kate. They’re cute together; platonically. Dog? Check. Tracksuit mafia? Bro. Fisk? CHECK. Bad guy auction? Check.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it’s really good. I’m looking forward to where this goes next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunreach</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s cute. Part teenage romance, part &amp;lsquo;how in the world do we take care of these random alien slugs anyways&amp;rsquo;. Well worth a piece of the Skyward universe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All-New X-Men, Vol. 7: The Utopians</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/28/all-new-x-men-vol.-7-the-utopians/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/28/all-new-x-men-vol.-7-the-utopians/</guid><description>&lt;p>So we have a trainingish montage with Jean and Magik, two issues were saw already, and a big character moment for Bobby…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/all-new-x-men-7-9c940b.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>… which is cute way to do it I suppose. If it had any other impact.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy &amp; X-Men: The Black Vortex</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/27/guardians-of-the-galaxy-x-men-the-black-vortex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/27/guardians-of-the-galaxy-x-men-the-black-vortex/</guid><description>&lt;p>X-Men! Guardians! What could possibly go wrong?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/all-new-x-men-6-5-8b3cd0.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What already went wrong…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell: the Black Vortex. A magical MacGuffin that can apparently make anyone… more. It’s up to our heroes (more or less) to…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/all-new-x-men-6-5-7c96ad.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Destroy it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Use it?!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And off we go on a wild ride that’s only sort of an X-Men story in that they’re at least in it (in various stages of powered up). But it’s still a neat one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward and back to the main line once again.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>