<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Star Wars: Visions</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/05/star-wars-visions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/05/star-wars-visions/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating expirment. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who got that made, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad they did. Take Star Wars, give it to a bunch of different Japanese (or Japanese inspired) animators, and make sure that nothing in this will be canon (so you can tell all sorts of stories). There aren&amp;rsquo;t any particularly deep, they&amp;rsquo;re too short for that. But beautiful, oh this series has that in spades.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a watch!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unwritten, Vol. 4: Leviathan</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/29/the-unwritten-vol.-4-leviathan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/29/the-unwritten-vol.-4-leviathan/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onward marches the story, ever stranger. Hints of what Tommy can (and must) do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onwards and upwards!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Am Groot</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/28/i-am-groot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/28/i-am-groot/</guid><description>&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re ~3 minute shorts (with 3+ minutes of credits each) about a young reincarnation of a tree-person who can&amp;rsquo;t talk, other than to say &amp;lsquo;I Am Groot&amp;rsquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I was expecting, but for what they are&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;re cute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth the 15 minutes to watch them all. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fruits Basket: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/27/fruits-basket-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/27/fruits-basket-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I started the second season&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, we do get a bit of backstory with parent issues (oh so many parent issues), the rest of the zodiac (more or less), and some answers about Akito.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, there are piles of weird age issues (I know this is apparently an anime staple; that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it better) and episode after episode dedicated to &amp;hellip; the student council of all things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We made it through 15 episodes of this season. Fin. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Everything Everywhere All at Once</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/23/everything-everywhere-all-at-once/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/23/everything-everywhere-all-at-once/</guid><description>&lt;p>Laundry and taxes. Hotdog fingers and Raccacoonie. Googly third eyes and sex toy fueled kung fu fights. The truest &lt;em>everything&lt;/em> bagel there ever was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well that was a delightfully &lt;em>weird&lt;/em> movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If anything at all of that sounds interesting (especially the &lt;em>weird&lt;/em> part) and you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen this movie yet, go see it. Don&amp;rsquo;t spoil it. I&amp;rsquo;ll wait.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shorts - Shifting Shadows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/13/shorts-shifting-shadows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/13/shorts-shifting-shadows/</guid><description>&lt;p>With book #13 of the Mercy Thompson series (&lt;em>Soul Taken&lt;/em>) coming out later this month, I&amp;rsquo;ve been relistening to the rest of the series (and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably hit the &lt;em>Alpha &amp;amp; Omega&lt;/em> series on my way). Between the two, they&amp;rsquo;re either my top or second favorite urban fantasy series out there (the other being the Dresden Files) and I&amp;rsquo;ve reread each a number of times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around though, I decided to hit all of the short stories and novellas as well, primarily collected in &lt;em>Shifting Shadows&lt;/em>. Rather than one post per book, I&amp;rsquo;m just going to put them all in this one post, ordered chronologically within the Mercyverse. Any I haven&amp;rsquo;t read yet, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave as placeholders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good stories all and none seem critical for enjoying the main series if you skip over them. A bit more backstory, particularly for more minor characters though, which is appreciated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll try for minor spoilers at most, but I&amp;rsquo;m not always the most caring about that. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Land Before Time</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/13/the-land-before-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/13/the-land-before-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve never actually watched any of the &lt;em>Land Before Time&lt;/em> movie. They just didn&amp;rsquo;t really come up in our childhood. On watching them now with my own children&amp;ndash;I see why they exist and why some children would get absolutely stuck on them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor: Love and Thunder</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/31/thor-love-and-thunder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/31/thor-love-and-thunder/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/">Thor&lt;/a> was probably the most underwhelming of Phase 1, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/">Thor: The Dark World&lt;/a> tried to go more fantasy and was mostly forgettable, and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/">Thor: Ragnarok&lt;/a> was a blast. Getting better all the time, so &amp;hellip; what about &lt;em>Thor: Love and Thunder&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good question. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to love about the movie: Hemsworth&amp;rsquo;s sense of humor, Portman back and then some, Thompson&amp;rsquo;s awesome and slightly awkward Valkyrie. And of course Bale plays a solidly terrifying baddy in Gorr.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, there is a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of movie to get through here, probably more than a bit too much. A cancer plot, succession jealousy, a threat spanning across the Galaxy (or at least the gods thereof)&amp;ndash;heck, the idea that gods are just &lt;em>a thing&lt;/em> now, Thor unpacking even more trauma. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot to put into a single movie and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>quite&lt;/em> work. It&amp;rsquo;s still a solid enough flick, but not nearly up to what &lt;em>Ragnarok&lt;/em> did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, pretty impressive for the first 4th solo outing in the MCU. Because that&amp;rsquo;s a thing we can say now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/29/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/29/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. That&amp;rsquo;s what what you get if you take a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/directors/sam-raimi">director best known for his horror movies&lt;/a>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and let them loose in the MCU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like it. 😄&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Out of the Blue</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/28/out-of-the-blue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/28/out-of-the-blue/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take part gay teenage lifeguard lover of rom-coms, just broken up with the Love Of His Life(tm), add a non-binary (because they all are) mermaid, sent on a month long &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rumspringa">Rumspringa&lt;/a> to the surface, make it into a love story (of course) with all the (teenage) relationship twists and turns that entails&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&amp;hellip; and you have &lt;em>Out of the Blue&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That &amp;hellip; is not at all the sort of book I normally find myself drawn to (I picked it up for the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2022-book-bingo/">2022 Book Bingo&lt;/a>), but you know&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s actually kind of sweet. And now that it&amp;rsquo;s over, I think I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have read it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Underworld: Rise of the Lycans</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/27/underworld-rise-of-the-lycans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/27/underworld-rise-of-the-lycans/</guid><description>&lt;p>Always interesting when a series decides to go back and do a prequel. For this though, given that we&amp;rsquo;re specifically dealing with centuries old immortals (especially ones killed in the previous films, thus not exactly available for any more sequels), there&amp;rsquo;s certainly room for it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fruits Basket: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/26/fruits-basket-season-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/26/fruits-basket-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I expect there are those who really love it, but &amp;hellip; this is not a show for me. I don’t like most of the characters (and &lt;em>really&lt;/em> don’t like some of them), most of the plots are entirely too high school, and the magic of the world/zodiac is criminally underused/explored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eternals</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/25/eternals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/25/eternals/</guid><description>That&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating movie.
Ancient aliens sent to Earth thousands of years ago to protect1 humanity&amp;hellip; but only from very specific threats. Loki and the Chitauri? Nah. Hydra? Nope. Thanos? Of course not. A whole cast of superheroes2 and we&amp;rsquo;ve never seen them before3&amp;ndash;and I doubt that any of the should-be-worldwide-news events in this film will make it into any of the others.
If you ignore all that though, it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting enough idea, especially once you start digging into the greater cosmic plot.</description></item><item><title>Ms. Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ms. Marvel is not particularly earth-shattering. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t deal with the end of the world and only barely with the greater MCU (although there is a decent bit of &amp;lsquo;how the world changes with superheroes in it, like Ant-Man&amp;rsquo;s podcast and Avengercon).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What it is though? A awful lot of fun. Iman Vellani as Kamala Khan is just an absolute delight and really looks like she had a great time in the role. The whole supporting cast is great as well, especially Kamala&amp;rsquo;s family and friends Bruno and Nakia.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Kamala Khan: [whispers] I&amp;rsquo;m a super hero.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[She runs off gleefully]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed this. Especially when it leaned into the Muslim + Pakistani culture and the family dynamics of the whole thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: I don’t need anyone on my side. I’m not even concerned if God is on my side as long as I am on His side. God is always right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Agent Deever: I don’t have time for Quranic quotes. Excuse me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: Actually, that was Abraham Lincoln.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The big fights and greater threats were kind of cheesey and didn&amp;rsquo;t mesh as well (especially the big showpiece in the final episode), but the down to earth human parts of being a teenager superhero? Awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so hard to rank these any more, since there&amp;rsquo;s just so much to love in the MCU. I think Ms. Marvel ends up pretty squarely in the middle of the pack&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;d still say it&amp;rsquo;s worth a watch. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Last Argument of Kings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/last-argument-of-kings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/last-argument-of-kings/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I have learned all kinds of things from my many mistakes. The one thing I never learn is to stop making them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And so it ends&amp;hellip; for now. Some of our old friends (more or less) are dead, some are broken, and some &amp;hellip; miraculously seem to have gotten everything they wanted in life. There are more surprises and political shifts than one knows how to deal with, a chunk more of world building around the First and Second Laws, and all manner of battles and death and destruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It remains fascinating what Abercrombie can do with characters. Glokta is a terrible person&amp;ndash;and he makes us root for him. Logen is a berserker in the truest sense&amp;ndash;and he makes us feel sorry for him. Jezal is excellent at failing upward&amp;ndash;and he makes us feel sorry for him. It&amp;rsquo;s all around amazing and the real strength of the series.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Underworld: Evolution</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/underworld-evolution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/underworld-evolution/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quite an interesting contrast compared to the first &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/15/underworld/">Underworld&lt;/a>. Where the first was a straight forward vampire/werewolf urban fantasy action flick, Evolution tries to be more. We get deeper worldbuilding, more backstory&amp;ndash;especially for Selene&amp;ndash;and more hints that the entire world is changing. It works&amp;hellip; well enough?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Underworld</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/15/underworld/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/15/underworld/</guid><description>&lt;p>Modern Day. Vampires versus Werewolves. That&amp;rsquo;s basically Underworld in a nutshell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Luckily, it does it very well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/14/the-first-fifteen-lives-of-harry-august/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/14/the-first-fifteen-lives-of-harry-august/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take the timeloop premise of Groundhog Day (et al), apply it to lifetimes, add a few neat worldbuilding twists, break things up with a cataclysm coming back through time&amp;hellip; and you have The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August. I love all of those things, so of course, I love this book as well. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unwritten, Vol. 3: Dead Man's Knock</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/10/the-unwritten-vol.-3-dead-mans-knock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/10/the-unwritten-vol.-3-dead-mans-knock/</guid><description>&lt;p>He&amp;rsquo;s on the run and&amp;ndash;eventually&amp;ndash;starting to accept his destiny. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to get further into who everyone is and how the world works. I&amp;rsquo;m curious where things will go next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Snake Falls to Earth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/06/a-snake-falls-to-earth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/06/a-snake-falls-to-earth/</guid><description>I do love stories that take mythology I don&amp;rsquo;t know as well and expands on it. In this case, the Lipan (Apache) people of what became the southwestern US down into Mexico. The idea of a world inhabited by animal people&amp;ndash;those that can shape shift between an animal and a human form&amp;ndash;that was once connected to Earth&amp;hellip; and now is not.
“And if they don’t?” I muttered. “Pfft. You’re a cottonmouth,” she snickered.</description></item><item><title>The Galaxy, and the Ground Within</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/22/the-galaxy-and-the-ground-within/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/22/the-galaxy-and-the-ground-within/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People – a group comprised of every sapient species, organic or otherwise – were chaos, but chaos was good. Chaos was the only sensible conclusion. There was no law that was just in every situation, no blanket rule that could apply to everyone, no explanation that accounted for every component. This did not mean that laws and rules were not helpful, or that explanations should not be sought, but rather that there should be no fear in changing them as needed, for nothing in the universe ever held still.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh, I do love these books. Especially on audio. There just such a delightful take on the sci-fi &amp;lsquo;slice of life&amp;rsquo; genre. Once again, it&amp;rsquo;s a new cast and new stories, with loose tiebacks to the previous characters (seeing Pei and hearing her talk about Ashby is a nice change of view). Chambers really shines at taking a bunch of weird and wonderful aliens, sticking them in a tight space (this time what&amp;rsquo;s essentially a &amp;lsquo;space truck stop&amp;rsquo;) for a few days, and seeing what happens. Nothing earthshaking&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> or deadly&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, but a lot of interpersonal drama. It&amp;rsquo;s great. Worth a read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unwritten, Vol. 2: Inside Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/22/the-unwritten-vol.-2-inside-man/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/22/the-unwritten-vol.-2-inside-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things are starting to move now! Prison, dedicated journalists, some real magic, and death. I’ll still trying to figure out the rules, but I’m enjoying it so far!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Outside</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/21/the-outside/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/21/the-outside/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Well, it did what Outside usually did in stories. Showed up. Violated all the known laws of physics. Killed some people and drove the rest mad.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s certainly an interesting book. It&amp;rsquo;s one part autism as &amp;lsquo;different, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay and sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s a superpower and sometimes it sucks&amp;rsquo;, one part cosmic horror, and one part fascinating worldbuilding with technoreligion writ large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it didn&amp;rsquo;t quite feel finished to me. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of setup, but the ending drew somewhere between a true horror ending and something much &amp;lsquo;better&amp;rsquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s potential for a sequel there, but without it, it could have been better. Still an enjoyable enough read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Before They Are Hanged</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/before-they-are-hanged/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/before-they-are-hanged/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We should forgive our enemies, but not before they are hanged.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Before They Are Hanged takes &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/31/the-blade-itself/">The Blade Itself&lt;/a> and takes everything up a notch. It&amp;rsquo;s still a dark and twisted world, there are still terrible people on all sides&amp;hellip; but now we have even more hints and worldbuilding on darker things coming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a worthwhile continuation to the first story and I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to see where it goes next. The narration in particular remains well worth it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unwritten, Vol. 1: Tommy Taylor and the Bogus Identity</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/the-unwritten-vol.-1-tommy-taylor-and-the-bogus-identity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/the-unwritten-vol.-1-tommy-taylor-and-the-bogus-identity/</guid><description>Well that’s a start. A world where Tommy Taylor is a modern hidden world fantasy even bigger than Harry Potter… until the author disappears, leaving behind disillusioned son Tom Taylor. There are more than hints of a darker truth behind the story, hidden worlds within hidden worlds. And a section at the end establishing how far back in time the truth goes.
So far, a fascinating sort of story. Well written and illustrated.</description></item><item><title>Constantine</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/constantine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/constantine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I went through and read the entire (modern) catalogue of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/14/hellblazer-vol.-1-original-sins/">Hellblazer&lt;/a> and rewatched &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/the-matrix/">The Matrix&lt;/a>. So&amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s give the 2005 Constantine film another try!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Rage of Dragons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/the-rage-of-dragons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/the-rage-of-dragons/</guid><description>&lt;p>African-inspired Bronze-age fantasy with piles of caste based tensions, crazy sword battles, interesting magic, demons, dragons, and the distinct feeling that the &amp;lsquo;good guys&amp;rsquo; might not actually be that good after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m reminded a lot of Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game (which I love and need to re-read at some point) in that you have a surprisingly good soldier that manages to train harder and break the rules, breaking down society as he goes. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot darker though and Tau (said soldier) is motivated almost entirely by vengeance. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; a lot to read at times, but it fits. Man he&amp;rsquo;s stupid at times for it though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a great book and worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Matrix Revolutions</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/14/the-matrix-revolutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/14/the-matrix-revolutions/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh the Matrix Revolutions. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/the-matrix-reloaded/">The Matrix Reloaded&lt;/a>: Part 2. We cut in right as that one ended, with Neo out for the count, robots descending on Zion, and Smith doing&amp;hellip; whatever Smith is doing. I particularly appreciate the idea of humans, programs, and machines perhaps finding common ground (which &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/the-matrix-resurrections/">The Matrix Resurrections&lt;/a> really got into).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Neo: I just have never&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rama-Kandra: &amp;hellip;heard a program speak of love?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neo: It&amp;rsquo;s a&amp;hellip; human emotion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rama-Kandra: No, it is a word. What matters is the connection the word implies. I see that you are in love. Can you tell me what you would give to hold on to that connection?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neo: Anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rama-Kandra: Then perhaps the reason you&amp;rsquo;re here is not so different from the reason I&amp;rsquo;m here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Matrix Reloaded</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/the-matrix-reloaded/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/the-matrix-reloaded/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Morpheus: [Morpheus addresses the people of Zion] Zion, hear me! It is true, what many of you have heard. The machines have gathered an army and as I speak, that army is drawing nearer to our home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[the Zion crowd becomes louder]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morpheus: Believe me when I say we have a difficult time ahead of us. But if we are to be prepared for it, we must first shed our fear of it. I stand here, before you now, truthfully unafraid. Why? Because I believe something you do not? No, I stand here without fear because I remember. I remember that I am here not because of the path that lies before me but because of the path that lies behind me. I remember that for 100 years we have fought these machines. I remember that for 100 years they have sent their armies to destroy us, and after a century of war I remember that which matters most&amp;hellip; We are still here! Today, let us send a message to that army. Tonight, let us shake this cave. Tonight, let us tremble these halls of earth, steel, and stone, let us be heard from red core to black sky. Tonight, let us make them remember, THIS IS ZION AND WE ARE NOT AFRAID!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>More Matrix! I love it!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Toy Story 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/toy-story-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/toy-story-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>For me, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/02/toy-story/">Toy Story&lt;/a> falls at just the right time for a blast of nostalgia. It came out when I was a kid and I watched it over and over again. Somehow, Toy Story 2, despite only coming out 4 years later, just doesn&amp;rsquo;t hit the same mark. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s still a good fun movie and worth watching, but&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s just not quite as good.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Buzz Lightyear: Woody, stop this nonsense and let&amp;rsquo;s go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Woody: Nah, Buzz.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sigh]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Woody: I can&amp;rsquo;t go. I can&amp;rsquo;t abandon these guys. They &lt;em>need&lt;/em> me to get into this museum. Without me, they&amp;rsquo;ll go back into storage. Maybe forever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buzz Lightyear: Woody, you&amp;rsquo;re not a collector&amp;rsquo;s item, you&amp;rsquo;re a child&amp;rsquo;s plaything. You - are - a &lt;em>toy&lt;/em>!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Locke &amp; Key: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/locke-key-season-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/locke-key-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Daaang things escalated. We&amp;rsquo;ve got more history, more direct interactions with the demons (and slight humanization to them, which is an interesting choice), and more character building with both the family and those around it. Man, I just want to give them all a big hug.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I so very look forward to Season 3! (see the end)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Matrix</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/the-matrix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/the-matrix/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh the Matrix. This movie came out at just the perfect time for me&amp;ndash;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t into the counter culture as much, but even then I was messing around with computers and hacking&amp;ndash;and I absolutely love every minute of it. It stands up even today, with a retrofuturistic sort of vibe that really still works even though it&amp;rsquo;s been twenty years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Men Tell No Tales</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/07/pirates-of-the-caribbean-dead-men-tell-no-tales/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/07/pirates-of-the-caribbean-dead-men-tell-no-tales/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the smash hit of the first three and the downer that was &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/03/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides/">On Stranger Tides&lt;/a>, I was cautiously hopeful that they could pull something off with Dead Men Tell No Tales. And&amp;hellip; they did? Sort of?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fugitive Telemetry</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/06/fugitive-telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/06/fugitive-telemetry/</guid><description>&lt;p>An odd book. It&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be #6 in the series, but really, it&amp;rsquo;s a prequel to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/network-effect/">Network Effect&lt;/a>. There&amp;rsquo;s not much you need to know between the two, so you can read them in either order and if it were up to me, I&amp;rsquo;d probably swap them (mostly because I want to know what happens next!), but it still works.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ratatouille</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/04/ratatouille/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/04/ratatouille/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s just a delightful movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Start with &amp;ldquo;Anyone can cook&amp;rdquo;, turn that up to 11 by making &amp;lsquo;anyone&amp;rsquo; a rat (because rats don&amp;rsquo;t belong in kitchens, get it?) and end up with a surprisingly touching movie about believing in yourself, doing whatever you set your mind to, and not having to necessarily do what it is that others expect of you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Caribbean: On Stranger Tides</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/03/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/03/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pirates of the Caribbean&amp;hellip; without Bloom or Knightly? At least they still have Johnny Depp I suppose. And Barbossa&amp;ndash;ish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Easily the weakest of the series. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; fine, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the absolutely bonkers charm of the earlier movies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mysterious Benedict Society</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/02/the-mysterious-benedict-society/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/02/the-mysterious-benedict-society/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that took a while to read. I read it outloud, part of a chapter a night many nights, and it still took a few months. Glad I did it though, it&amp;rsquo;s a great book, especially for kids, but even more so to read aloud with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a story about a group of children, each lost and/or alone in different ways, each brilliant (as the first section and a series of tests shows both to them and to us) and thus necessary for a &lt;em>SECRET MISSION&lt;/em>. I won&amp;rsquo;t go much more into that, but once they get out on the mission and have to prove that they are more than up to the task&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Blade Itself</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/31/the-blade-itself/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/31/the-blade-itself/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Every man has his excuses, and the more vile the man becomes, the more touching the story has to be. What is my story now, I wonder?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Joe Abercrombie / The Blade Itself have long held a highly recommended spot on my to read lis, so when I caught the audiobook on Libby/the Indiana Digital Library&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> I figured it was about time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quick version: it&amp;rsquo;s wonderful, but also &lt;em>very&lt;/em> dark. One of the main characters is a barbarian who&amp;rsquo;s family was recently killed, another is a soldier crippled in war turned torturer. And somehow, Abercrombie actually really makes you feel for the both of them, but man it takes a bit&amp;hellip; On top of that, there&amp;rsquo;s some fascinating hints of magic&amp;ndash;plus some more overt examples, no less terrible, when we meet Bayaz&amp;ndash;the First of the Magi&amp;hellip; or is he?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Altered Carbon: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/altered-carbon-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/altered-carbon-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s a huge bummer. They swapped out most of the cast, kept one that&amp;hellip; is a weird choice, and mostly changed the entire style of the show. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating choice and I wanted to like it&amp;hellip; but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Made it two episodes in. So it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Network Effect</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/network-effect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/network-effect/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>So that was what had happened before the survey. Now we’re here, ready for the next major disaster. (Spoiler warning.)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a full length Murderbot novel! Yay! And it gets far deeper and weirder into corners of the worldbuilding we&amp;rsquo;ve only had hints of before. I love seeing the hints of tension with the corporations and how much control they hvaqe, the weirdness that is alien remnants, and the knowledge that there are super weird problems out there that aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily directly related to Murderbot.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Caribbean: At World's End</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/pirates-of-the-caribbean-at-worlds-end/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/pirates-of-the-caribbean-at-worlds-end/</guid><description>&lt;p>There is so much to love about this movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, I love the opening!&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lNRjt4rCymM" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Spelunky</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/spelunky/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/spelunky/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The games reminded me of something the author Haruki Murakami says in the intro to the English edition of Blind Willow, Sleeping Woman: “I find writing novels a challenge, writing short stories a joy. If writing novels is like planting a forest, then writing short stories is more like planting a garden. The two processes complement each other, creating a complete landscape that I treasure.” In video games, we don’t have corresponding terms for novels and short stories—we simply have large games and small games. These Game Maker games were Murakami’s gardens: vibrant, intimate, and full of charm. Having just planted a large forest with Alec, I was eager to find my own little patch of fertile soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I absolutely love Spelunky. I remember playing the (now) Classic version when that&amp;rsquo;s all there was (even going so far as to decompile and mess with the source code, yay GameMaker Studio), spending hours on the HD remake (beat Olmec, made it to Hell, never did beat Yama)&amp;ndash;mostly on Steam, and more recently put just as many hours into Spelunky 2. It&amp;rsquo;s a great game and what little I knew of the story was already inspirational. So when I saw this book, written by Derek Yu himself, of course I had to give it a try.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Man's Chest</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/14/pirates-of-the-caribbean-dead-mans-chest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/14/pirates-of-the-caribbean-dead-mans-chest/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/pirates-of-the-caribbean-the-curse-of-the-black-pearl/">Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl&lt;/a> was surprisingly good. So of course they&amp;rsquo;re going to make a sequel and turn everything up to 11. More Johnny Depp (yay)! More love triangles (boo)! More supernatural beasties (awesome)! More mythology (sweet)!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like. As mentioned Depp is still great. That&amp;rsquo;s probably the number one reasons these movies are as awesome as they are. He just nails the roll.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exit Strategy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/exit-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/exit-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Murderbot has really stirred up some trouble. Now Dr. Mesnah&amp;rsquo;s caught up in it and it&amp;rsquo;s time to come back and perhaps fix some things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like the rest, it&amp;rsquo;s a quick read with a wonderful sense of all too familiar alienness, wonderful hacking and action scenes, and a fascinating look at what it means to be a person&amp;ndash;or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth the read, but at this point, I expect you&amp;rsquo;ll already be blowing through these.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Redwall: The Graphic Novel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/redwall-the-graphic-novel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/redwall-the-graphic-novel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s a great story. I read it long ago and &lt;a href="&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/19/redwall/">Redwall&lt;/a>">listened to it a couple years ago&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s a great story of animals basically doing the human thing in and around an abbey run by mice. It&amp;rsquo;s great fun so long as you don&amp;rsquo;t think too long and hard about which animals are sentient and which aren&amp;rsquo;t and how the vast differences in scale and lack of opposable thumbs could possibly work&amp;hellip; but other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s great fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Formatwise, I&amp;rsquo;ve read a few graphic novel adaptations of novels and usually they feel a little lackluster (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/white-sand/">White Sand&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/08/storm-front-graphic-novel/">Storm Front (Graphic Novel&lt;/a>) as two examples), but if anything was going to work, this was it. It&amp;rsquo;s already a lighter fantasy world with lots of light riddles and actions and over the top characters that fit just fine with graphic novels. And it pays off. As an introduction to this world, it&amp;rsquo;s a great alternative. It&amp;rsquo;s just so fun to see pictures of how someone else saw all of the characters from this world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>V for Vendetta</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/v-for-vendetta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/v-for-vendetta/</guid><description>&lt;p>That’s quite a story; quite a world. I only vaguely remember the film, but I still hear Hugo Weaving’s voice as V and Natalie Portman as Evey. The bones of what I remember match though. A story of a world gone well over the edge and a man determined to bring it back—but at what cost?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A fascinating read and worth the time. I need to watch the movie now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pocahontas</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/07/pocahontas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/07/pocahontas/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my favorites of the Disney animated classics. It&amp;rsquo;s a straight forward enough story that at least takes some pains to show the terrible way that European settlers treated Native Americans and shows that people are people and will often try to do the right thing, given a chance. The music is wonderful and the animation is really quite something that up even today.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moon Knight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/moon-knight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/moon-knight/</guid><description>&lt;p>That &amp;hellip; was truly bizarre. A main character with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/dissociative%20identity%20disorder">dissociative identity disorder&lt;/a> where their powers deal with but &lt;em>are not&lt;/em> caused by their disorder is fascinating (and truly weird to be watching at the same time as &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/01/altered-carbon-season-1/">Altered Carbon: Season 1&lt;/a>&amp;hellip;), the Egyptian background and characters are great, and there&amp;rsquo;s are some pretty awesome scenes, fight and otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Castingwise, Oscar Isaac is awesome. I&amp;rsquo;m amazed at how he brings both Marc and Steven to life. Ethan Hawke is a great maybe-baddie-but-maybe-just-a-different-point-of-view. And May Calamawy as Layla El-Faouly is a real stand out in just about everyway. I hope that we get to see more of them in the greater MCU, although I have no idea how that&amp;rsquo;s going to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of which, this was so different from other MCU properties. It&amp;rsquo;s got Egyptian gods and powers more or less walking around, which fits, but I do really wander how/if we&amp;rsquo;d see them or their avatars square off against normal MCU level heroes. Tonally, it&amp;rsquo;s rather different too. There&amp;rsquo;s still an end of the world threat, but a lot of it&amp;rsquo;s dealing with the internal struggles of Steven/Marc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s probably my favorite of the MCU TV shows so far&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll have to rewatch it and see if it holds up. It&amp;rsquo;s really quite good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/pirates-of-the-caribbean-the-curse-of-the-black-pearl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/pirates-of-the-caribbean-the-curse-of-the-black-pearl/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it began.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is just such a fun movie. Johnny Depp is absolutely the star of the show:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Mullroy: What&amp;rsquo;s your purpose in Port Royal, Mr. Smith?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Murtogg: Yeah, and no lies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jack Sparrow: Well, then, I confess, it is my intention to commandeer one of these ships, pick up a crew in Tortuga, raid, pillage, plunder and otherwise pilfer my weasely black guts out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Murtogg: I said no lies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mullroy: I think he&amp;rsquo;s telling the truth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Murtogg: If he were telling the truth, he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have told us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jack Sparrow: Unless, of course, he knew you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t believe the truth even if he told it to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The sheer number of wonderfully quoteable lines he has:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Norrington: No additional shot nor powder, a compass that doesn&amp;rsquo;t point north,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[looks at Jack&amp;rsquo;s sword]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Norrington: And I half expected it to be made of wood. You are without doubt the worst pirate I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jack Sparrow: But you have heard of me.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s on top of crazy pirate action (with a heart of gold buried somewhere deep in there), Geoffrey Rush&amp;rsquo;s spectacular portrayal of Barbossa, Bloom&amp;rsquo;s &amp;rsquo;everyman with a mysterious history&amp;rsquo;, and Keira Knightley&amp;rsquo;s beginning to work against the sexism inherent in the age and region (although that gets better in the sequels).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stiff: The Curious Lives of Human Cadavers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/stiff-the-curious-lives-of-human-cadavers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/stiff-the-curious-lives-of-human-cadavers/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Death. It doesn’t have to be boring.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a book. I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to try out one of Mary Roach&amp;rsquo;s books for a while and this one came up on the (digital) library, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a try. In a nutshell, it goes into the process of what happens right up to and after you die (including brain death and organ donation) along with the various things that might be done with your body afterwards (such as medical training and testing various products along with alternatives to burial).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“What I do is, I think of them as wax.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Theresa is practicing a time-honored coping method: objectification. For those who must deal with human corpses regularly, it is easier (and, I suppose, more accurate) to think of them as objects, not people.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating look into things you just don&amp;rsquo;t often think of. I quite enjoyed it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>