<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Derek Yu on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/derek-yu/</link><description>Recent content in Derek Yu on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/derek-yu/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spelunky</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/spelunky/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/spelunky/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The games reminded me of something the author Haruki Murakami says in the intro to the English edition of Blind Willow, Sleeping Woman: “I find writing novels a challenge, writing short stories a joy. If writing novels is like planting a forest, then writing short stories is more like planting a garden. The two processes complement each other, creating a complete landscape that I treasure.” In video games, we don’t have corresponding terms for novels and short stories—we simply have large games and small games. These Game Maker games were Murakami’s gardens: vibrant, intimate, and full of charm. Having just planted a large forest with Alec, I was eager to find my own little patch of fertile soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I absolutely love Spelunky. I remember playing the (now) Classic version when that&amp;rsquo;s all there was (even going so far as to decompile and mess with the source code, yay GameMaker Studio), spending hours on the HD remake (beat Olmec, made it to Hell, never did beat Yama)&amp;ndash;mostly on Steam, and more recently put just as many hours into Spelunky 2. It&amp;rsquo;s a great game and what little I knew of the story was already inspirational. So when I saw this book, written by Derek Yu himself, of course I had to give it a try.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>