<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Web Browsers on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/19/web-browsers/</link><description>Recent content in Web Browsers on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/19/web-browsers/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A quick mitmproxy setup</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/19/a-quick-mitmproxy-setup/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/19/a-quick-mitmproxy-setup/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another quick thing that I set up for the first time in a &lt;em>long&lt;/em> time. It&amp;rsquo;s honestly as much a note for myself as anything, but perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ll find it useful too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The problem: We were having intermittent issues with a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/content%20security%20policy">content security policy&lt;/a>. One of the warnings that cropped up was the inclusion of &lt;code>'inline-speculation-rules'&lt;/code> in the policy. This is currently only supported in Chrome and the issue was only appearing in Firefox. I could of course go through the effort of removing the header locally and testing&amp;ndash;but what if I could lie to the browser and change the header on the fly?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, for that, you have a number of options. &lt;a href="https://portswigger.net/burp" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Burp Suite&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.zaproxy.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">ZAP&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.charlesproxy.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Charles Proxy&lt;/a>. Many more, I&amp;rsquo;m sure. Any of these can modify traffic on the fly like that, but they&amp;rsquo;ll all designed for &lt;em>so much more&lt;/em> than that, making them a bit unwieldy. What I really wanted was something that was a whole lot smaller and did only this one thing (or could be at least configured as such)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter &lt;a href="https://mitmproxy.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;code>mitmproxy&lt;/code>&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve used it before, but never quite like this. As the name suggests, &lt;code>mitmproxy&lt;/code> is designed to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/man-in-the-middle">man-in-the-middle&lt;/a> yourself as a proxy&amp;ndash;feed all web requests through it and it can read requests, modify and forward (or block them), read responses, modify or replace them entirely, and all so much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Exactly what I needed!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>