<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kim Harrison on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/kim-harrison/</link><description>Recent content in Kim Harrison on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/kim-harrison/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Outlaw Demon Wails</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/03/the-outlaw-demon-wails/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/03/the-outlaw-demon-wails/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, enough side stories (and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/19/the-turn-the-hollows-begins-with-death/">prequels&lt;/a>!). Back to the main story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, Rachel can do demon things. And in doing so, she&amp;rsquo;s managed to really piss off one demon: Algaliarept (Al). Now he&amp;rsquo;s out every night on a technicality and coming for Rachel.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You can’t forget anything,” I said, watching the words vanish into nothing. “And even if you do, it always comes back to bitch-slap you in the morning.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So how in the world is she going to solve this one? Well&amp;hellip; perhaps not in &lt;em>the world&lt;/em> after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Rache?” Jenks said warily, hovering as I hid my hands so he couldn’t see them shake. “What did you do?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, more elf shenanigans with Trent and Ceri (although not the two of them together :whew:).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relationship drama, both with Ivy and perhaps with Marshal (from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/a-fistful-of-charms/">A Fistful of Charms&lt;/a>). It&amp;rsquo;s not quite Kistin, but it will be interesting to see. And uniting auras. What&amp;rsquo;s up with that? A mystery for another book I suppose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and historical drama with Rachel&amp;rsquo;s mom (now that was a bombshell&amp;hellip;). I figured something was up with that, but man that was still a hit. It will be interesting to see where that goes&amp;ndash;and if her mom will become a larger player going forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and suddenly Ryn Cormel. Who I just met in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/19/the-turn-the-hollows-begins-with-death/">The Turn&lt;/a>. Interesting that. If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read the prequel, would I have missed out on anything? Probably not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and a Gargoyle. I expected more from that. But perhaps next book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I &lt;em>really&lt;/em> enjoyed this one. This series has turned out to be primarily about demons, but&amp;hellip; perhaps that makes sense given, well, everything. I&amp;rsquo;m here for it though!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Side note: I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to these on audiobok. Why&amp;hellip; does this one have a different narrator? It&amp;rsquo;s a bit jarring. Piss-ker-ee. Lee line. Jenks&amp;rsquo; new voice. I think it&amp;rsquo;d be perfectly fine (although lee line would probably still bother me), but I&amp;rsquo;d just gotten so used to the other!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/topic/show/21045927-a-change-in-narrator-for-this-book" target="_blank" rel="noopener">there is a discussion about this&lt;/a> on Goodreads.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ms. Gavin and I are both working to get her to read AMERICAN DEMON. Should happen!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; Kim Harrison&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Not a why, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s known? And apparently we&amp;rsquo;ll go back to Marguerite Gavin after this one!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Second side note: The fact that they said &amp;lsquo;Al went into human resources&amp;rsquo; is certainly a choice. And they just skate &lt;em>right on&lt;/em> by that one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Into the Woods: Tales from the Hollows and Beyond</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/into-the-woods-tales-from-the-hollows-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/into-the-woods-tales-from-the-hollows-and-beyond/</guid><description>&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/1mGnIAxWGb2DBnlqwCqOuO?utm_source=generator&amp;theme=0"
 width="100%" height="80"
 frameBorder="0" allowfullscreen=""
 allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture">
&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>Now that that is out of the way &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Into the Woods is a collection of Hollows Shorts. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve liked the series enough to go ahead and want todo everything about it, I decided to pick up all the shorts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because I track my reading, I have to draw the line somewhere, so here it is: all of the short stories will be collected here (updating as I read them). Novellas (and novelettes?) will get their own posts.&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-bespelled-todo">The Bespelled (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#two-ghosts-for-sister-rachel">Two Ghosts for Sister Rachel&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#undead-in-the-garden-of-good-and-evil">Undead in the Garden of Good and Evil&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dirty-magic">Dirty Magic&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-bridges-of-eden-park">The Bridges of Eden Park&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ley-line-driver-todo">Ley Line Driver (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#million-dollar-baby-todo">Million Dollar Baby (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pet-shop-boys-todo">Pet Shop Boys (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#temson-estates-todo">Temson Estates (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#spider-silk-todo">Spider Silk (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#grace-todo">Grace (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav></description></item><item><title>Two Ghosts for Sister Rachel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/two-ghosts-for-sister-rachel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/two-ghosts-for-sister-rachel/</guid><description>&lt;p>So that&amp;rsquo;s a story. Young Rachel (finishing school, desperately wanting to go to the IS), still living at home with her mother, when her brother comes to visit! Given that we&amp;rsquo;ve barely seen them on page (&lt;em>have&lt;/em> we see her brother?), it&amp;rsquo;s some fun bit of backstory&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then the entire story revolves around trying to contact Rachel&amp;rsquo;s dead father to win a bet (and to join the IS in his footsteps), well, of course things are going to get complicated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun story with just the right amount of gut punches and backstory. I do wonder what we&amp;rsquo;ll see &amp;lsquo;in between&amp;rsquo;. How does Rachel end up strong enough to go on runs? She certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t doing that well here. And will see see her time at that camp?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, worth the read!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: red eye flights being renamed to &amp;lsquo;vamp flights&amp;rsquo; is a fun detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also: &amp;lsquo;Spell checker&amp;rsquo;. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also also: Man Rachel really will fall for anyone, won&amp;rsquo;t she&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Undead in the Garden of Good and Evil</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/20/undead-in-the-garden-of-good-and-evil/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/20/undead-in-the-garden-of-good-and-evil/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Life was more than waiting for it to end so she could started living.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Man Ivy is a mess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is the/a story of how Ivy came to be, how screwy (heh) vampires can be, how she got to be working as a runner, and how she came to meet Rachel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a pretty fun way to set it up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and much like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/into-the-woods-tales-from-the-hollows-and-beyond/#the-bridges-of-eden-park">The Bridges of Eden Park&lt;/a> this (especially the Kisten parts) back to back with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/11/for-a-few-demons-more/">For a Few Demons More&lt;/a> is certainly a touch of whiplash.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Turn: The Hollows Begins with Death</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/19/the-turn-the-hollows-begins-with-death/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/19/the-turn-the-hollows-begins-with-death/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The only thing worse than starting a plague on purpose was being stupid enough to start it by accident.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Okay, I&amp;rsquo;ve read (and quite enjoyed) enough of the Hollows that I want to go back and pick up the short stories and other supplementary stories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter: The Turn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story of science, betrayal, tomatoes, and a whole bunch of deaths that changed the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun story. While I really do appreciate that the Hollows is a world with without a &amp;lsquo;masquerade&amp;rsquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see the world before (and &lt;em>as&lt;/em>) all of the various Interlanders came out into the open. Especially seeing who was involved&amp;ndash;and wondering just what they&amp;rsquo;re all up to in the more modern time I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“A person is okay,” he said, peering into the darkness and the open street. “But when you put a bunch of us together, something is switched on, something ugly.” He glanced at her apologetically. “All of us, humans and nonhumans alike, are genetically primed to attack what’s different from the collective.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, a fun story to set up. As far as I&amp;rsquo;ve read, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to read for the main series, but I&amp;rsquo;ms till glad to have read it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For a Few Demons More</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/11/for-a-few-demons-more/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/11/for-a-few-demons-more/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There were no more choices, no more options, no more clever ways out of a tough situation. And the rush, I realized in a brutal wash of despair, is a false god I’ve chased my entire life. One that cost me everything in the blind search for sensation. My entire existence amounted to nothing.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That title is not a lie&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not just Algaliarept (Al &amp;#x1f604;) this time around. We also are introduced to Newt&amp;ndash;just sort of pops in and shows off some serious magical chops&amp;hellip; and then reveals that she&amp;rsquo;s not entirely sane any more. Mildly terrifying that. Plus Minias, her minder, who actually seems decent&amp;ndash;for a demon. Rachel is getting in pretty hard with all of these different favors owed (both ways). Makes for quite the story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that Trent&amp;rsquo;s getting married. And Rachel&amp;rsquo;s not only invited&amp;hellip; but in the wedding party? Well, actually it&amp;rsquo;s to provide security (hint: demons). But of course any time you put Trent and Rachel together there&amp;rsquo;s going to be trouble.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if &lt;em>that&lt;/em> wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough&amp;hellip; we have even more vampire trouble. Rachel and Ivy are such a mess&amp;ndash;and that one really can&amp;rsquo;t last too many more books. One step forward&amp;ndash;and another two back. And Kisten. Oh Kisten. Still not a good person, but perhaps good for Rachel? &lt;span class="spoiler">Oh Harrison, *that* was a low blow.&lt;/span>
&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I’ve got your back. Nothing alive will ever hurt you if I have breath in me. And nothing dead will hurt you if I don’t.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a story. Probably the most intense so far. I fully expect (and hope) that this really shakes up the world of the Hollows and I&amp;rsquo;m curious where in the &lt;em>world&lt;/em> we can go from here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Fistful of Charms</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/a-fistful-of-charms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/a-fistful-of-charms/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, enough vampire/demon nonsense for a moment, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about weres.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>As the joke goes, you don’t have to be faster than the wolf chasing you, just faster than everyone else running away.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Turns out that trying to get letter-of-the-law against multiple packs of werewolves has consequences. For everyone involved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick&amp;hellip; is a real piece of work. I will grant him the one small saving grace that he (along with most of the world) thought Rachel dead as part of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/14/every-which-way-but-dead/">Every Which Way But Dead&lt;/a>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&amp;hellip; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make him any better a person. At least Rachel eventually realizes it? Sort of. Mostly. Ish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel and Ivy&amp;hellip; come to a serious head in this book. Which went about as badly as I expected. I do wish the best for Ivy, but she certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t make that easy at times and Rachel is &lt;em>not&lt;/em> helping matters here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It (among a number of other plotlines in these books) are yet a bit more of Rachel being so sure she&amp;rsquo;s right and never quite taking responsibility for when that goes sidewise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jenks? I am &lt;em>so&lt;/em> glad to see him back again. The whole running off because of not being trusted last book, I get that. But Jenks is just so fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Plan B?&amp;rdquo; Ivy said. &amp;ldquo;What is plan B?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
Jenks reddened. &amp;ldquo;Grab the fish and run like hell,&amp;rdquo; he muttered, and I almost giggled.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And now there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em>whole lot more&lt;/em> Jenks. Which &amp;hellip; kind of weird and I don&amp;rsquo;t really get it. I do wonder if that&amp;rsquo;s going to be a recurring theme or was a one off. Half-related, the entire premise that Pixies only live ~20 years and Jenks is just about there? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to deal with this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a fun read and I appreciated a new set of problems. Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: Trent&amp;rsquo;s near complete absense was a bit strange. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s not his flavor of nonsense going on this time around, so it makes sense. But on the other hand, we have crime and rare artifacts, I fully expected that to bring him in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every Which Way But Dead</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/14/every-which-way-but-dead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/14/every-which-way-but-dead/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And oh, that climax. This is most certainly going to come back and bite Rachel. But honestly, what other choice did she even have?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; me, re: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/08/the-good-the-bad-and-the-undead/">The Good, the Bad, and the Undead&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that vampire/demon business of the previous book? Causing all sorts of chaos this time around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel, remaining entirely &lt;em>absolutely sure she is right about everything to the detriment of everyone around her&lt;/em>? Also chaos-causing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick-trauma and Rachel not realizing that &amp;rsquo;thing never done before&amp;rsquo; was causing some serious issues? Chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick is out of town, so totally platonic date with Kristen&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Who apparently has murdered people, because&amp;hellip; duh? Vampire?&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, but he promised not to do it anymore. Chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do appreciate seeing Demon Al as an actual &lt;em>demon&lt;/em>. Holding a prisoner for a thousand years. I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting for an attempted redemption arc there, but as it is it &lt;em>feels good&lt;/em> when Rachel gets one over on him. And Ceri has some interesting potential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh these books. Onwards!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Good, the Bad, and the Undead</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/08/the-good-the-bad-and-the-undead/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/08/the-good-the-bad-and-the-undead/</guid><description>&lt;p>And away we go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/">Dead Witch Walking&lt;/a> set up the world, it&amp;rsquo;s here where we really start setting up Rachel Morgan and go as investigators in their own right. And of course, they&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled right into a serial killer targeting leyline witches. Good times that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is quite the cast of characters this time around. Trent Kamalack is back and as morally &amp;rsquo;totally morally gray, but maybe for good reasons&amp;rsquo; kind of person&amp;ndash;and we do get to learn the what/why he is, which is neat.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Come work for me, and I’ll tell you.”&lt;br>
My eyes went to his. “You are a thief, a cheat, a murderer, and a not-nice man,” I said calmly. “I don’t like you.”&lt;br>
He shrugged, the motion making him look utterly harmless. “I’m not a thief,” he said. “And I don’t mind manipulating you into working for me when I need it.” He smiled, showing me perfect teeth. “I enjoy it, actually.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Head local vamp Piscary is scary and understated. Rachel&amp;rsquo;s mother is wacky. Her father&amp;hellip; had secrets. And Nick&amp;hellip; well, I&amp;rsquo;m happy if Rachel is happy, but that is so not going to go well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, getting more into what exactly layline magic is, how demons work in this world (parallel reality that&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em>really&lt;/em> Hell go!), how these vampires are different, and more &amp;lsquo;humans are terrified of tomatoes&amp;rsquo; than you can shake a stick at. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun world and I always like seeing how many different ways you can turn common tropes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On another hand&amp;hellip; man Rachel is kind of an idiot sometimes. She&amp;rsquo;s so absolutely sure shre&amp;rsquo;s right even when &lt;em>everyone&lt;/em> around her is trying to get her see the truth. Oy that was frustrating. One would htink that trying to set out on her own would make her a little more risk averse&amp;ndash;but I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s not in the cards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And oh, that climax. This is most certainly going to come back and bite Rachel. But honestly, what other choice did she even have?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun series and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to keep going. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dead Witch Walking</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Making a spell is easy. It&amp;rsquo;s trusting you did it right that&amp;rsquo;s hard.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another new (to me) urban fantasy in a &amp;rsquo;the supernatural world has been made public&amp;rsquo; world? Yes please!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, we have Rachel a witch and, as of the start of the story, bounty hunter. Frustrated with her job, she decides to quit.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I sighed. I hated the maze of bureaucracy with a passion, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found the best way to deal with it is to smile and act stupid. That way, no one gets confused.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And in this world, you just &lt;em>don&amp;rsquo;t do that&lt;/em>. So now she&amp;rsquo;s gone from bounty hunter to having a price oh &lt;em>her&lt;/em> head, backed only by her friend(ish) and former co-worker, living Vamp Ivy and Jenks&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, a four-inch tall pixie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, she&amp;rsquo;s also stumbling into a super natural drug trade, a whole rat fighting ring (from impressively up close and personal), and summoned demons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel is a lot of fun. Perfectly competent and willing to fight for it, even if things don&amp;rsquo;t always go right. I enjoy Ivy, even if she&amp;rsquo;s still mostly closed off through this book. Room to grow. And Jenks is hilarious. &amp;ldquo;You think my kids just popped out of the ground?&amp;rdquo; and all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worldbuilding is a lot of fun. I always like trying to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s diffrerent about this particular urban fntasty world and there is plenty of that here. Born vampires&amp;ndash;&lt;em>living&lt;/em> and only turning more traditional after death. Pixies and fairies, running their own smaller scale wars over garden space. Genetic engineering run amuck&amp;ndash;leading to a perfectly reasonable fear of tomatoes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite a a world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it&amp;rsquo;s fun to have the main character be a witch. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely certain how much of a witch&amp;rsquo;s magic is natural versus learned just yet, but mostly human magic user is always a fun point of view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far I&amp;rsquo;m cautiously optimistic. I do love a good urban fantasy. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun world (with openly acknowledged supernatural characters!) with fun characters and a lot of room to grow. And grow it did&amp;ndash;with 18 out as of now&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>