<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kim Harrison on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/kim-harrison/</link><description>Recent content in Kim Harrison on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/kim-harrison/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dead Witch Walking</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Making a spell is easy. It&amp;rsquo;s trusting you did it right that&amp;rsquo;s hard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another new (to me) urban fantasy in a &amp;rsquo;the supernatural world has been made public&amp;rsquo; world? Yes please!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, we have Rachel a witch and, as of the start of the story, bounty hunter. Frustrated with her job, she decides to quit.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I sighed. I hated the maze of bureaucracy with a passion, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found the best way to deal with it is to smile and act stupid. That way, no one gets confused.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And in this world, you just &lt;em>don&amp;rsquo;t do that&lt;/em>. So now she&amp;rsquo;s gone from bounty hunter to having a price oh &lt;em>her&lt;/em> head, backed only by her friend(ish) and former co-worker, living Vamp Ivy and Jenks&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, a four-inch tall pixie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, she&amp;rsquo;s also stumbling into a super natural drug trade, a whole rat fighting ring (from impressively up close and personal), and summoned demons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel is a lot of fun. Perfectly competent and willing to fight for it, even if things don&amp;rsquo;t always go right. I enjoy Ivy, even if she&amp;rsquo;s still mostly closed off through this book. Room to grow. And Jenks is hilarious. &amp;ldquo;You think my kids just popped out of the ground?&amp;rdquo; and all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worldbuilding is a lot of fun. I always like trying to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s diffrerent about this particular urban fntasty world and there is plenty of that here. Born vampires&amp;ndash;&lt;em>living&lt;/em> and only turning more traditional after death. Pixies and fairies, running their own smaller scale wars over garden space. Genetic engineering run amuck&amp;ndash;leading to a perfectly reasonable fear of tomatoes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite a a world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it&amp;rsquo;s fun to have the main character be a witch. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely certain how much of a witch&amp;rsquo;s magic is natural versus learned just yet, but mostly human magic user is always a fun point of view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far I&amp;rsquo;m cautiously optimistic. I do love a good urban fantasy. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun world (with openly acknowledged supernatural characters!) with fun characters and a lot of room to grow. And grow it did&amp;ndash;with 18 out as of now&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>