<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Patricia Briggs on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/patricia-briggs/</link><description>Recent content in Patricia Briggs on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/patricia-briggs/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Soul Taken</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/05/soul-taken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/05/soul-taken/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This frail cloth, a gift to the person he had once been, was his touchstone, a reminder that once he had been whole. Once there had been joy.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a crazy book for backstory. We get more backstory of Wulfe and Sherwood (big answers there), a bit more about Zee (he&amp;rsquo;s terrifying, but still a good guy), and even more escalations / variations on what it means that Mercy&amp;rsquo;s Coyote-magic is based around boundaries and death. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting variation, a complicated book, and well worth reading.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shorts - Shifting Shadows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/13/shorts-shifting-shadows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/13/shorts-shifting-shadows/</guid><description>&lt;p>With book #13 of the Mercy Thompson series (&lt;em>Soul Taken&lt;/em>) coming out later this month, I&amp;rsquo;ve been relistening to the rest of the series (and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably hit the &lt;em>Alpha &amp;amp; Omega&lt;/em> series on my way). Between the two, they&amp;rsquo;re either my top or second favorite urban fantasy series out there (the other being the Dresden Files) and I&amp;rsquo;ve reread each a number of times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around though, I decided to hit all of the short stories and novellas as well, primarily collected in &lt;em>Shifting Shadows&lt;/em>. Rather than one post per book, I&amp;rsquo;m just going to put them all in this one post, ordered chronologically within the Mercyverse. Any I haven&amp;rsquo;t read yet, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave as placeholders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good stories all and none seem critical for enjoying the main series if you skip over them. A bit more backstory, particularly for more minor characters though, which is appreciated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll try for minor spoilers at most, but I&amp;rsquo;m not always the most caring about that. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smoke Bitten</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/03/smoke-bitten/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/03/smoke-bitten/</guid><description>&lt;p>Two in a row! It&amp;rsquo;s like Christmas! If Christmas was chuck full of creepy uberpowerful fae&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the major plot threads is dealing with the fallout of . Mercy and co may have won the day, but in doing so they managed to tick off a great number of very powerful beings, lost a strong ally, and may have caused some permanent harm to Adam and Mercy&amp;rsquo;s relationship. I really hated this at first&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve loved how solid the relationships of the main characters are in these books, letting them deal with huge problems together&amp;ndash;but by the end I&amp;rsquo;m at least willing to see where this goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storm Cursed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/31/storm-cursed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/31/storm-cursed/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last re-read/listen through the Mercy Thompson books. I had forgotten just host much things had been changing on a larger world building scale in the last few books: since Mercy put herself and her pack on the line defending the people and territory of the Columbia Basin, things have gotten complicated. And dark. And did I mention complicated?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating world building.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wild Sign</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/13/wild-sign/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/13/wild-sign/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Mercyverse books (both Mercy Thompason and Alpha &amp;amp; Omega) are one of the few series of books I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to every few years for a complete reread, or in this case, a re-listen. Something that&amp;rsquo;s made all the better when you get to the end and there are new books to add to the old favorites!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the upside, it&amp;rsquo;s a crazy ride with a whole heap of more backstory for and reason to like Leah (some reviewers say it changed her backstory, but I think it fits), more information about witches, both white and black, and a few new crazy magical beings on the block (Bigfoot! Bigfeet? And that&amp;rsquo;s not even the crazy one&amp;hellip;). It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy world and a crazy plot and it manages to keep going all the way through.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Burn Bright</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/09/burn-bright/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/09/burn-bright/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It’s bad to have an enemy with the kinds of resources these people apparently have—but it is infinitely worse to have crazy people as enemies.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Taking place right on the heels of , &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="35839437" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35839437.burn-bright"> Burn Bright &lt;/a> sees Anna and Charles are back in Aspen Creek, only this time around Bran is still out of the picture just when things start going a little bit sideways. There&amp;rsquo;s conflict both within the pack and from outside, in particular focussed on the Wildlings&amp;ndash;a second pack of old wolves too dangerous to even be in Bran&amp;rsquo;s pack already of the most dangerous.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Silence Fallen</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/03/20/silence-fallen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/03/20/silence-fallen/</guid><description>&lt;p>I last read (/ listened to) the Mercy Thompson books back in 2016, so I thought it was about time to go through the series (plus the Alpha and Omega books) again. Imagine my delight when I saw both series had a new entry!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I&amp;rsquo;m a mechanic; I fix things that are broken. I turn into a thirty-five pound coyote. I have powerful friends. But when it comes right down to it, my real superpower is chaos.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Dead Heat</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/01/dead-heat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/01/dead-heat/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hope you like horses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, Dead Heat has two themes that are really interesting and worth exploring within the universe that Briggs is building. First is Charles&amp;rsquo; relationship with an old, non-werewolf friend. They&amp;rsquo;ve touched some on what happens when everyone you know ages and dies, but it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see it in first person. Especially knowing that they don&amp;rsquo;t have to die&amp;ndash;they could be changed instead&amp;ndash;but refuse to do so.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fair Game</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/26/fair-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/26/fair-game/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People as old and powerful as he should never be given someone to love. For Anna he would destroy the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Fair Game continues the story of Anna and Charles, this time to Boston, getting themselves involved in the investigation of a supernatural-hunter serial killer who&amp;rsquo;s been killing people (including Fae and werewolves) for decades.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hunting Ground</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/23/hunting-ground/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/23/hunting-ground/</guid><description>&lt;p>This time around, we leave the icy mountains to instead to head to Seattle. Long story short, the werewolves are coming out as the Fae did back in the 80s (in this universe). In order to make the transition a bit smoother, Charles and Anna are traveling to Seattle as representatives of the Marrok in order to meet with various delegations of the European wolves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After so many books (if you read the Mercy Thompson books first), it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the first real look at the European wolves , or really European characters in general. We have one wolf who rules most of mainland Europe as an unofficial, cruel mirror of the Marrok, another who believes himself to be King Arthur reborn, and another Omega whereby Anna can learn more about her powers. On top of that, there&amp;rsquo;s a Fae apparently powerful enough to hold the negotiations in check and a white which who gets her power from a rather interesting sacrifice. After only half a dozen characters in the first Alpha and Omega, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see so many more here. It brings Hunting Ground much closer to the Mercy Thompson books in style.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cry Wolf</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/20/cry-wolf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/20/cry-wolf/</guid><description>&lt;p>First off: no, you didn&amp;rsquo;t miss anything. This book really does start a few days after Anna&amp;rsquo;s and Charles&amp;rsquo; are mated, skipping to the end of what essentially makes up the Alpha and Omega short story. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a rough start, especially since so much of Anna&amp;rsquo;s character comes from those events that we never actually see, but I think it works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That leads into the next interesting part / potential problem with these books. Anna was tortured and raped by her first pack. Even though you never actually directly read the scenes in question, they&amp;rsquo;re an unrelenting part of Anna&amp;rsquo;s characters through not only this book but the entire series. On top of that, the paranormal romance parts (read: sex scenes) of Alpha and Omega are far more direct than they ever were in Mercy Thompson. Putting the two together leads to some rather strange and questionable scenes, in particular between Anna and Charles that, at least in my opinion, feel like they were never dealt with as they should/could have been.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fire Touched</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/15/fire-touched/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/15/fire-touched/</guid><description>&lt;p>In some ways, Fire Touched manages to back down from the scale of the previous two books. We&amp;rsquo;re no longer fighting primordial spirits or gods, but rather &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo; the Fae. Of course, as we see through the course of the book, there are some Fae who might as well be gods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, this book as many as any that came before will really change the shape of the future of the universe that Briggs is building. In a nutshell, the wolves are going politically toe to toe with the Fae. Anything more than that would be even more a spoiler, but it&amp;rsquo;s still another interesting bit of worldbuilding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Night Broken</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/06/night-broken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/06/night-broken/</guid><description>&lt;p>Interesting thing about tight first person point of view: when the main character feels strongly about another character, it comes through really strongly. Take for example Christy, Adam&amp;rsquo;s ex-wife. On one hand, I&amp;rsquo;m sure she&amp;rsquo;s not quite as bad as she appears, given that all we see is from Mercy&amp;rsquo;s point of view. On the other hand, she&amp;rsquo;s really a fairly troubled person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the supernatural scale, we actually manage to step up another level from the River Devil and Coyote and friends. This time around we get an ancient big bad from the Canary Islands who&amp;rsquo;s just as hard to kill as the River Devil but has even more firepower (heh) on their side. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating bit of mythology I&amp;rsquo;ve never come across anywhere else and manages to fit well enough into the current world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frost Burned</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/03/frost-burned/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/03/frost-burned/</guid><description>&lt;p>Frost Burned feels almost like two novels sort of smooshed together. In starts out with something of a bang with the entire pack getting kidnapped by people apparently mad enough to take on an entire pack of werewolves at once. By the second half though, that&amp;rsquo;s shifted into a little bit of Fae and a lotta bit of vampire trouble which&amp;ndash;don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong&amp;ndash;is related, but feels like a different sort of book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It actually works surprisingly well though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>River Marked</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/29/river-marked/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/29/river-marked/</guid><description>&lt;p>River Marked takes what we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in the previous 5 Mercy Thompson books and turns it somewhat on its head. Previously, we&amp;rsquo;ve had interesting but not entirely unbelievable versions of werewolves, vampires, ghosts, and fae&amp;ndash;all with a distinctly Old World influence on them. This time around though, we finally dig a bit into Mercy&amp;rsquo;s father&amp;rsquo;s family and get a big nasty beastie from the Americas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to get a bigger world to interact with. I&amp;rsquo;ve read fewer books than I&amp;rsquo;d like dealing with non-European myths and legends, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing to scratch that particular itch. On the other hand, the way it&amp;rsquo;s introduced in this story makes for a rather abrupt &amp;lsquo;power level&amp;rsquo; jump. We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen centuries (millennia?) old vampires and (possibly) wolves and the Gray Lords are nothing to sneeze at, but this is perhaps the first time that &lt;span class="spoiler">literal gods takes the stage&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Silver Borne</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/11/silver-borne/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/11/silver-borne/</guid><description>&lt;p>No more vampires, which is a plus for me at least. Your milage may vary. Instead we get a mix of wolves and Fae, which in my opinion are the best parts of the Mercyverse worldbuilding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The subplot with Samuel is interesting. One thing that many urban fantasies tend to sweep under the rug is exactly how hard it could be to live for century after century. Many will pay lip service to it, mentioning it from time to time, but the characters often still feel relatively young. Samuel has some of that as well, but there are at least hints of of it here that he is really an old wolf.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone Crossed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/08/bone-crossed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/08/bone-crossed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Back to vampires for a little while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember back when Mercy pissed off the local vampire leadership? Well now she&amp;rsquo;s run out of town&amp;hellip; and of course bumps into more vampires. One thing leads to another&amp;hellip; vampires die&amp;hellip; and Mercy saves the day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iron Kissed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/02/iron-kissed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/02/iron-kissed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Iron Kissed gets into one of the most interesting parts of the Mercy Thompson universe: the Fae. They may have come out to the public a few decades ago, but only the least of the Fae. When a small pile of the greater Fae are brutally murdered, Mercy gets involved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We get to learn a fair bit more about the Fae in general and Uncle Mike and Zee in particular, which is nice. They&amp;rsquo;re fascinating and just alien enough to be believable. On top of that, Mercy finally manages to choose between Sam and Adam, although if it will stick, who can say&amp;hellip; We start getting into a bit more of the romance aspects that some readers of the series are expecting&amp;ndash;and then the final section of the book happens (see spoiler section below).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blood Bound</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/23/blood-bound/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/23/blood-bound/</guid><description>&lt;p>Blood Bound follows Mercy Thompson as Stefan the vampire calls in a favor owed from the events of the first book. What follows is a violent, blood soaked look into the darker parts of the world Patricia Briggs has built.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While there was a decent amount of violence in Moon Called, Blood Bound out does it easily. Given that the big bad is a demon possessed vampire (as if one or the other wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be enough), it&amp;rsquo;s not surprising, but there are a few fairly intense scenes in here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moon Called</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/18/moon-called/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/18/moon-called/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take a kitchen sink urban fantasy world (vampires and werewolves and Fae, oh my), toss in a few interesting twists and head it with a woman mechanic protagonist with a flair of Native American magic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuilding-wise, there are a lot of urban fantasy tropes in here, but on the other hand tropes are tropes for a reason. The werewolves are extremely hierarchical (despite the fact that real world wolves aren&amp;rsquo;t actually, but it makes for a more interesting story) and there are some interesting aspects to pack magic that I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen elsewhere. Vampires are fairly typical thus far, although having one that drives around in a Mystery Machine van is kind of hilarious. (Plus I know we get more of him later). Walkers I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in other books and we really know little about them thus far (although to be fair, neither does Mercy), but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a bit of non-European flavor.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>