<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Skyward on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/skyward/</link><description>Recent content in Skyward on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/skyward/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Evershore</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/25/evershore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/25/evershore/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Like the Saint says, if you don’t have anything to say, you might scare your flightleader into thinking you’re dead.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The one with Jerkface and the Kitsen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like all of the Starsight novellas, we have a focus on what else has been going on while Spena has been doing her &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/cytonic/">Cytonic&lt;/a> things. This time&amp;ndash;as you might guess&amp;ndash;with Jerkface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s actually really great to see his point of view and especially to see just how much he&amp;rsquo;s grown throughout the books. He was always a leader, but he&amp;rsquo;s really coming into it now&amp;ndash;and really realizing that sometimes, just maybe, the books might be &lt;em>wrong&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do also love seeing more of the Kitsen. They&amp;rsquo;re really building up a regular anti-Superiority alliance there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the biggest bummer now is having to wait for Defiant to come out this November&amp;hellip; Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cytonic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/cytonic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/cytonic/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Stories say something. About us, and about where we came from. They’re a reminder that we have a past, a history. And a future.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was certainly a thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/skyward/">Skyward&lt;/a> introduced us to some far future humans trapped on a planet by terrifying aliens. Spensa learns how to fight, teachers her friends and allies how to be awesome, and saves the day from the aliens!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/">Starsight&lt;/a>, we get off world. We&amp;rsquo;re introduced us to some of those same aliens. Turns out they&amp;rsquo;re people, more or less just like us. So Spensa learns how to spy, teachers her new friends and allies how to be awesome, and saves the day from the Eldrich Horrors From Beyond Space!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So of course in Cytonic&amp;hellip; Spensa goes Beyond Space. She adventures through all manners of weird environments, meets a bunch of Pirates From Beyond Space&amp;hellip; And learns to fight, teachers her friends and allies how to be awesome, and saves the universe?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m starting to sense a pattern here.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>All people must accept that we have the potential to do terrible things. It is part of seeing our place in the universe, our heritage, and our natures. But in that acceptance we gain strength, for potential can be refused. Any hero who could have been a monster is more heroic for the choices he or she made to walk another road.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>ReDawn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/redawn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/redawn/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A prisoner could be convinced that they lived in a paradise, if the prison was pretty enough.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>ReDawn is a lot like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/">Sunreach&lt;/a> in that it&amp;rsquo;s a cousin to the main Skyward books, really expanding the universe and letting us know what the rest of Skyward flight (and others) were getting up to while Spensa was&amp;hellip; otherwise occupied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around&amp;hellip; the point of view is Alanik, the near human alien that crashed into Detritus right at the beginning of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/">Starsight&lt;/a>, enabling the events of that book.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I didn’t know enough about human politics to know who was correct, but I did know enough about politics in general to guess that everyone would interpret the law in the way that best suited themselves.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s facinating to have a point of view from someone who grew up in this universe on an alien world (bubbles of air around giant trees!) with an alien culture&amp;ndash;that in this case is actually tied to humanity throughout the past. It gives us a way to dig more into the relationships (especially the &amp;lsquo;relationships&amp;rsquo;) between the humans all the more, which I enjoyed a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;hellip; learning more about the Taynix / slugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty fun story, well worth it&amp;rsquo;s place as a Skyward sidestory novella!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunreach</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s cute. Part teenage romance, part &amp;lsquo;how in the world do we take care of these random alien slugs anyways&amp;rsquo;. Well worth a piece of the Skyward universe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Starsight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“A hero does not choose her trials. She steps into the darkness, then she faces what comes next.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If you are the sort to want absolutely zero spoilers going into a book &lt;em>stop reading now&lt;/em>. Go read the book (it&amp;rsquo;s really good, that&amp;rsquo;s not a spoiler :spoiler:) and then come back. You have been warned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, now that that&amp;rsquo;s out of the way. It&amp;rsquo;s been &amp;hellip; three years since I first read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/skyward/">Skyward&lt;/a>. WheN I read it, the sequels weren&amp;rsquo;t even out yet&amp;hellip; when Starsight first came out, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t get around to it. I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat lamenting that lack now. &amp;#x1f604; But as they say, the second best time to plant a tree is today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, Starsight takes place where Skyward left off. Spensa has some crazy new powers she doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand, M-Bot is out in the open&amp;ndash;and really the star of the book&amp;ndash;, and humanity is ready to take back the stars&amp;hellip; More or less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Spoilers. For real, albeit minor.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Defending Elysium</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/07/defending-elysium/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/07/defending-elysium/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You must understand that he knew the risks of living in an undeveloped civilization. Creatures of lesser intelligence cannot be held responsible for their acts of barbarity. You have not yet learned a better way.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve only read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/skyward/">Skyward&lt;/a> before of that series, so on re-reading, I noticed that Defending Elysium is sort of a prequel? It&amp;rsquo;s unclear to me exactly how much. It feels like the same world, but set well before and with none of the same characters? Especially since I haven&amp;rsquo;t read past Skyward before&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a bit more worldbuilding and background than I&amp;rsquo;d otherwise be aware of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short, but worth a read in my opinion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skyward</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/28/skyward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/28/skyward/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I imagined those broken rocks as the broken bodies of my enemies, their bones shattered, their trembling arms reaching upward in a useless gesture of total and complete defeat. I was a very odd little girl.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Spensa (Spin) is an odd girl in an odd world. Humanity is trapped on an alien planet for reasons (initially) unknown. The sky is filled with rubble and debris that occasionally rains down on them and from time to time aliens come down and try to kill them. Spin&amp;rsquo;s father is a pilot, trying to protect them, but he dies early in the book (before a timeskip), called a coward&amp;ndash;seemingly one of the worst things you can call someone in this world.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>