<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>S.M. Stirling on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/s.m.-stirling/</link><description>Recent content in S.M. Stirling on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/s.m.-stirling/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Island in the Sea of Time</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/24/island-in-the-sea-of-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/24/island-in-the-sea-of-time/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;What if the modern day island of Nantucket was transplanted whole and complete 3000 or so years into the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the entire basis of the setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, you get a book ranging from &amp;lsquo;how do we survive&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;we can&amp;rsquo;t change anything?!&amp;rsquo; to &amp;lsquo;how do we stop one of our own from building his own empire and taking over the world&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As one does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The historical basis is pretty interesting. It&amp;rsquo;s not a period I know &lt;em&gt;terribly&lt;/em&gt; much about&amp;ndash;although to be fair, there are a few cultures here that had to be invented mostly whole cloth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the builders of Stonehenge&amp;ndash;they never wrote anything, so we have only scant records of what they might have been like&amp;ndash;or the writers of Linear A and B (the former only deciphered in the 50s and the latter having not done yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then you have fascinating bits&amp;ndash;like you can&amp;rsquo;t very well trade with the local Native Americans for corn&amp;ndash;it won&amp;rsquo;t spread to this part of the world for thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The linguistics alone&amp;ndash;learning to speak various languages to various people was particularly interesting to me. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot to go from the idea that modern Lithuanian may be the closest to proto-Indo-European to being able to speak it, but for the sake of the story, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The survival aspects are a combination of &amp;lsquo;go humanity&amp;rsquo; and a bit much at times. The idea that they just so happen to have all the experts they could possibly need&amp;ndash;ancient fishing and farming, blacksmithing, metalurgy, chemistry. Nantucket is not &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; big. And lucky they just so happened to bring back the Coast Guard&amp;rsquo;s one large sailing ship with them. But again, it&amp;rsquo;s a story. Everyone trying and then&amp;hellip; just dying out wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be nearly as interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting aspect of the story was that we &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; really learn (at least in this first book) &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; the island was sent back in time. Are they actually in their own past? Or in some alternate reality? But &amp;hellip; does it really matter? Again, it&amp;rsquo;s a story. The survival and exploring the world as it was is the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually kind of like that we don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to know why any of this happened. Just enjoy the ride. I would like to see how things change over a much longer time period&amp;ndash;but I imagine that&amp;rsquo;s a much harder bit of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall an interesting book. Quite long. I&amp;rsquo;ll prob ably read the sequels at some point but not at the moment. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>