<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bash on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/programming/topics/bash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bash on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/programming/topics/bash/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Helper Scripts for Command Line MySQL</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/27/tiny-helper-scripts-for-command-line-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/27/tiny-helper-scripts-for-command-line-mysql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quite often, I&amp;rsquo;ll find myself wanting to query and manipulate MySQL data entirely on the command line. I could be building up a pipeline or working on a task that I&amp;rsquo;m going to eventually automate but haven&amp;rsquo;t quite gotten to yet. Whenver I have to do something like that, I have a small pile of scripts I&amp;rsquo;ve written over time that help out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;skiphead&lt;/code&gt;: Skip the first line of output, used to skip over headers in a query response&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;skipuntil&lt;/code&gt;: Skip all lines until we see one matching a pattern, used to resume partial tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;commaify&lt;/code&gt;: Take a list of single values on the command line and turn them into a comma separated list (for use in &lt;code&gt;IN&lt;/code&gt; clauses)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;csv2json&lt;/code&gt;: a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/11/csv-to-json/&#34;&gt;previously posted&lt;/a&gt; script for converting csv/tab delimited output to json&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt;: not my script, but used to take the output of csv2json and query it further in ways that would be complicated to do with SQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admitedly, the first two of those are one liners and I could easily remember them, but the advantage of a single command that does it is tab completion. &lt;code&gt;sk&amp;lt;tab&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, arrow to select which one I want, and off we go. I could put them as an alias, but I don&amp;rsquo;t always use the same shell (mostly &lt;a href=&#34;https://fishshell.com/&#34;&gt;fish&lt;/a&gt;, but sometimes Bash or Zsh).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>