<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ted Chiang on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ted-chiang/</link><description>Recent content in Ted Chiang on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ted-chiang/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exhalation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/22/exhalation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/22/exhalation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Two years, two bingos, two &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/30/stories-of-your-life-and-others/"&gt;Five SFF Shorts&lt;/a&gt;, both by Ted Chiang.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man I love his shorts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one goes more scifi and deals more with time travel and parallel realities than the other (which had more scifi interacting with religion), but I love them both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, I &lt;em&gt;The Merchant and the Alchemist&amp;rsquo;s Gate&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Anxiety is the Dizziness of Freedom&lt;/em&gt; were my favorites. The eponymous &lt;em&gt;Exhalation&lt;/em&gt; was an interesting look at entropy. And &lt;em&gt;The Lifestyle of Software Objects&lt;/em&gt;, by far the longest, had the time to go even more through the development of the idea over years (in universe).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting, I think that especially from this book, I find that I enjoy scifi more in shorts&amp;ndash;you have time to explore many more &lt;em&gt;ideas&lt;/em&gt; there&amp;ndash;and longer form in fantasy&amp;ndash;really digging into the worlds and characters more than the ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stories of Your Life and Others</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/30/stories-of-your-life-and-others/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/30/stories-of-your-life-and-others/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that was a delightful collection of shorts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t often read anthologies, but perhaps I should read more. I do love me some epic fantasy (I&amp;rsquo;ve read the entire &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-wheel-of-time/"&gt;The Wheel of Time&lt;/a&gt; half a dozen times now&amp;hellip;), but there&amp;rsquo;s just something about a story that builds up quickly, gets to the point, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t stick around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think of the 8, I only bounced off 1 (which was actually a fine story, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t suspend disbelief enough for the premise) and 1 was a bit meh, just for how short it was. 6 of 8 I absolutely loved though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>