<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Robert Jackson Bennett on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/robert-jackson-bennett/</link><description>Recent content in Robert Jackson Bennett on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/robert-jackson-bennett/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Locklands</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/01/locklands/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/01/locklands/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We’re all the result of countless actions and choices made throughout the centuries, and the odds of those actions and choices going the exact same way again are basically nil.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s certainly a finale! After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/06/foundryside/">Foundryside&lt;/a> started out as a nice bit of worldbuilding wrapped around a heist and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/28/shorefall/">Shorefall&lt;/a> turned things up to 11 with the return of the old, almost alien magic&amp;hellip; Now we have Locklands with hive minds, epic immortal duals, and finally&amp;hellip; a few answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a crazy (awesome) book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shorefall</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/28/shorefall/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/28/shorefall/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Learn what your city has forgotten. What men of power have forgotten time and time again, throughout history—that there is always, always something mightier.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/06/foundryside/">Foundryside&lt;/a> was quite a ride, with an awesome magic system, great characters, and some nice not entirely too dark bits of revolution going on&amp;ndash;and hints of something more. Shorefall takes all that&amp;hellip; and turns it way the heck up to 11.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foundryside</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/06/foundryside/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/06/foundryside/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Every innovation—technological, sociological, or otherwise—begins as a crusade, organizes itself into a practical business, and then, over time, degrades into common exploitation. This is simply the life cycle of how human ingenuity manifests in the material world. What goes forgotten, though, is that those who partake in this system undergo a similar transformation: people begin as comrades and fellow citizens, then become labor resources and assets, and then, as their utility shifts or degrades, transmute into liabilities, and thus must be appropriately managed.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was delightful. It&amp;rsquo;s been on my list for a while, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d give it a chance and I&amp;rsquo;m so very glad I did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I highly recommend the book, with the disclaimer that there are some dark scenes, bits (sorry) of body horror, and quite a lot of (made up fantasy) swearing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>City of Miracles</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/05/city-of-miracles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/05/city-of-miracles/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/05/city-of-miracles/">City of Miracles&lt;/a> is a bizarre, fantastic end to a bizarre, fantastic series. Once again with another point of view, this time we follow Sigrud, with Shara and Mulaghesh both taking minor background roles, what with Shara dying in the first few pages&amp;hellip; Hey. It&amp;rsquo;s not a spoiler, if it happens that early in the book&amp;hellip; &lt;span class="spoiler">Plus, you know she always has another trick up her sleeve!&lt;/span>
 ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sigrud is a fascinating character seeing him deal with yet another loss and on yet another mission to track down and kill those responsible in a way that only he can do is well worth reading on it&amp;rsquo;s own. Combine that with the inevitable-in-hindsite fallout of killing or driving off all the godly beings in a land&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>City of Blades</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/27/city-of-blades/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/27/city-of-blades/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Welcome to old Voortyashtan,” the captain says with false cheer, waving at the mouth of the Solda. “Though you can’t see much of it these days. It’s moved, y’see, about three hundred feet. Vertically, straight down.” He grins and laughs wickedly.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/27/city-of-blades/">City of Blades&lt;/a> surprised me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>City of Stairs</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/16/city-of-stairs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/16/city-of-stairs/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The city knows. It remembers. Its past is written in its bones, though the past now speaks in silences.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/16/city-of-stairs/">City of Stairs&lt;/a> is a wonderful book. The start is remarkably dense, dropping you into the deep end of a complicated world with flavors I at least wasn&amp;rsquo;t as familiar with where Proper Nouns abound and the rules are uncertain&amp;ndash;even to those living therein.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>