<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>James S.A. Corey on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/james-s.a.-corey/</link><description>Recent content in James S.A. Corey on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/james-s.a.-corey/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Babylon's Ashes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/11/19/babylons-ashes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/11/19/babylons-ashes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Babylon&amp;rsquo;s Ashes doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have much new to say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One one hand, the interplanetary and interpersonal conflicts we say growing through the last book or two come to a head here, with space battles large and small, culminating in a lot of destruction and a fascinating yet completely mysterious final battle.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nemesis Games</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/10/30/nemesis-games/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/10/30/nemesis-games/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You can tell you’ve found a really interesting question when nobody wants you to answer it.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, while the first novels in the Expanse series asked a whole pile of interesting questions about the Protomolecule and the gate builders&amp;hellip; both seem almost entirely absent in Nemesis Games.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Abaddon's Gate</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/09/09/abaddons-gate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/09/09/abaddons-gate/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Holden was starting to feel like they were all monkeys playing with a microwave. Push a button, a light comes on inside, so it’s a light. Push a different button and stick your hand inside, it burns you, so it’s a weapon. Learn to open and close the door, it’s a place to hide things. Never grasping what it actually did, and maybe not even having the framework necessary to figure it out. No monkey ever reheated a frozen burrito.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In the first book, the protomolecule made zombies. In the second, it made a Venuscomputer and super soldiers. This time around? A wormhole gate to transit hub in what looks to be a pocket universe where the laws of physics are&amp;hellip; flexible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Caliban's War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/22/calibans-war/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/22/calibans-war/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It’s not healthy having God sleeping right there where we can all watch him dream.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>After the events of Leviathan Wakes, the protomolecule is just hanging on doing strange things on Venus&amp;hellip; or is it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leviathan Wakes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/05/leviathan-wakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/05/leviathan-wakes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Structurally, Leviathan Wakes is an interesting novel. It&amp;rsquo;s science fiction / space opera but also has fairly strong threads of crime novel / horror / military scifi threading through it as well. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting mix and done well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, we follow Holden and Miller. Holden is initially second in command on an ice trawler who cares about people to a fault. He wants people to know the truth, even if doing so might cause even more problems than it solves. Miller on the other hand is an older cop on a space station. He&amp;rsquo;s had a hard life among the more criminal elements of society which leaves him with a somewhat less rosy opinion on humanity. The contrast between the two of them drives the story, especially as things really start going wrong.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>