<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shelagh Stephenson on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/shelagh-stephenson/</link><description>Recent content in Shelagh Stephenson on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/shelagh-stephenson/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/09/downton-abbey-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/09/downton-abbey-season-3/</guid><description>Oh, now that&amp;rsquo;s a season. It starts with a marriage, imprisonment, and money problems and only gets crazier from there.
Death is a theme as well, not once but twice. I get that sometimes actors move on , but they really did Matthew dirty with that one&amp;hellip;
Overall another solid season and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to what happens now!
Per episode reviews. Potential spoilers for the season as a whole.</description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/07/downton-abbey-season-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/07/downton-abbey-season-2/</guid><description>The season with World War I. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of changes, from war wounds to deaths to Downton becoming a temporary hospital.
It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating getting to know all these stories. Oh I wish the best for them all.
Such is life.
Onward!
Per episode reviews. Potential spoilers for the season as a whole.
Episode 2.1 And so&amp;hellip; war. Brutal away and at home for those that go, those that don&amp;rsquo;t, and those that can&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/downton-abbey-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/downton-abbey-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Somehow I&amp;rsquo;m always surprised when a highly rated show is actually good. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From a modern, American, middle-class point of view, the idea of the early 1900s British Aristocracy is just so strange. They do next nothing (useful) and have an entire staff to support it. The entire estate could go to a cousin they&amp;rsquo;d never met and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing they can do about it &amp;hellip; is so strange.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s oddly charming?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Grantham&amp;rsquo;s are fascinating. Sybil seems good people, Edith is certainly going to figure out how to come into her own, Mary is spoiled and needlessly cruel&amp;ndash;but may be learning. Lord and Lady Grantham are fun, if somewhat alien&amp;ndash;and I do love watching Lord Grantham try and completely fail to wrangle three young adult daughters. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The shining jewel of the family Dame Maggie Smith&amp;rsquo;s Dowager Countess of Grantham. Oh she&amp;rsquo;s just wonderful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among the staff, you have a whole &amp;rsquo;nother level of politics. They&amp;rsquo;re all great and terrible (as they should be) and there are every bit as many problems and politics as there are among the &amp;lsquo;family&amp;rsquo;. Turns out people are people no matter how much money they have or do not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a crazy amount to fit into seven episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward&amp;hellip; to war!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>