<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Discworld - Moist von Lipwig on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/discworld-moist-von-lipwig/</link><description>Recent content in Discworld - Moist von Lipwig on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/discworld-moist-von-lipwig/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Raising Steam</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/02/raising-steam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/02/raising-steam/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64222" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64222.going-postal">Going Postal&lt;/a>, Moist von Lipwig rebuilt the post office. In &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="116296" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/116296.making-money">Making Money&lt;/a>, he took on the banks. Now? Steam engines are coming to the Discworld!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see more and more technology come to the Discworld, especially watching it blend with the magic that&amp;rsquo;s already there. You have goblins running the clacks (telegraphs) and now the trains and a engine that might just be alive. On top of that, we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with some of the fall out of the recent (bookwise) war between the Trolls and the Dwarves.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making Money</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/18/making-money/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/18/making-money/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It was sad, like those businessmen who came to work in serious clothes but wore colorful ties in a mad, desperate attempt to show there was a free spirit in there somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64222" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64222.going-postal">Going Postal&lt;/a>, &amp;lsquo;former&amp;rsquo; conman Moist von Lipwig rebuilt Ankh-Morpork post from the ground up&amp;hellip; but now he&amp;rsquo;s bored. Everything is running as it should; there&amp;rsquo;s nothing left to fix. So when Vetinari offers him the chance to do the same to the bank&amp;hellip; of course he runs the other way. One thing leads to another though and eventually the Moist ends up with a new dog who just so happens to own the majority share in the bank. Good times.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Going Postal</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/12/going-postal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/12/going-postal/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the time of writing this, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64222" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64222.going-postal">Going Postal&lt;/a> is tied for the second highest rated Discworld book on Goodreads (tied with &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="400354" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/400354.men-at-arms">Men at Arms&lt;/a> at 4.37, behind &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="47989" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/47989.night-watch">Night Watch&lt;/a> at 4.48). There&amp;rsquo;s a reason for this&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Essentially, Going Postal takes a small pile of topics&amp;ndash;technical innovation and traditional technology versus the new hotness; conmen and businessmen; the postal service itself&amp;ndash;and squishes them together with the wonderful latter book Discworld flair Pratchett is so known for.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>