<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Seth MacFarlane on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/seth-macfarlane/</link><description>Recent content in Seth MacFarlane on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/seth-macfarlane/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Orville: New Horizons (Season 3)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/the-orville-new-horizons-season-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/the-orville-new-horizons-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>3 year time jump!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, there&amp;rsquo;s so much going on in this season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both large (Kaylon! Moclan! Krill! new friends and foes alike!) and small (so many relationships! new crew and old!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see how much this show has grown and changed. I just about bounced off the first few episodes, back when it was leaning hard into the humor and less into the sci-fi. But now&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see both the funny and the serious takes on all sorts of issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A delightful third season. If/when we get a Season 4, I&amp;rsquo;ll most certainly have to check it out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Orville: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/22/the-orville-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/22/the-orville-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>And another season! Got away from it for a while, but it&amp;rsquo;s finally done. I&amp;rsquo;m glad they&amp;rsquo;ve managed to stay away from pure comedy and stick to a scifi show that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>also&lt;/em> funny. It&amp;rsquo;s much better that way in my opinion&amp;ndash;even if we do get some &lt;em>pretty ridiculous&lt;/em> bits. &lt;em>The Great Release&lt;/em>. I rest my case.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, we get a lot more to shake up the status quo. The Moclans and their all male* society take a front seat, but we also have quite the story line for Isaac and his people, more Krill, digging into how real simulations can feel, and so much more. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the third (and final?) season!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Orville: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/30/the-orville-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/30/the-orville-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a Star Trek parody that&amp;rsquo;s more Star Trek than most (new) Star Trek. It&amp;rsquo;s got a really rough start while it&amp;rsquo;s still trying to lean into the humor, but as the show goes on and it gets more serious, it&amp;rsquo;s so much better. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to what they can do in season 2!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="reviews-by-episode">Reviews by Episode&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="1-old-wounds">1. &lt;em>Old Wounds&lt;/em>&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The truth is, you’re nobody’s first choice for this job. We have 3000 ships to staff and we need captains.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Wow. That was an awkward meet and greet. Supposed to be funny and an introduction to the characters I suppose, but… who would possibly think that’s okay?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arts and crafts meets tardigrade redwood. Hilarious.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>