<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bill Mantlo on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/bill-mantlo/</link><description>Recent content in Bill Mantlo on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/bill-mantlo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-3/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Rocket: Someday I&amp;rsquo;m gonna make great machines that fly. And me and my friends are gonna go flying together, into the forever and beautiful sky.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was fun. If you liked the previous two Guardians of the Galaxy entries (or especially the Holiday Special), I expect you&amp;rsquo;ll love this. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t care for them, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Guardians of the Galaxy Holiday Special</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/the-guardians-of-the-galaxy-holiday-special/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/the-guardians-of-the-galaxy-holiday-special/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that was delightful. How did I not watch this sooner?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell: it&amp;rsquo;s a standard &amp;ldquo;save Christmas&amp;rdquo; plotline gone so &lt;em>very &lt;strong>very&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> alien. With Mantis and Drax having the main plotline to bring Peter Quill that one perfect gift is so fun. They&amp;rsquo;re just alien enough to bring more than a touch of chaos with them to Earth while at the same time human enough to relate to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, don&amp;rsquo;t expect anything deeper than the above. There really isn&amp;rsquo;t anything here you&amp;rsquo;d miss by not watching&amp;ndash;but on the other other hand it&amp;rsquo;s a quick watch and fun enough to be worth it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Endgame</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s one heck of a climax.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/">Avengers: Infinity War&lt;/a>, Thanos won. He snapped and half of the universe died&amp;ndash;let&amp;rsquo;s ignore the logistics of that. In Endgame, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance&amp;ndash;a very small chance&amp;ndash;that they can fix it all. All they need is a little &amp;ndash;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tony Stark: [discussing the &amp;ldquo;Time Heist&amp;rdquo;] I believe the most likely outcome will be our collective demise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scott Lang: Not if we strictly follow the rules of time travel. That means no talking to our past selves, no betting on sporting events&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Infinity War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>All that. Ten years. 18 movies. Dozens of huge name actors and crossovers, all leading to this. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/">The Avengers&lt;/a> gave us a team up, but Infinity War turned it all up to 11. The battle scenes are insane (especially that final battle in Wakanda, especially especially the return of Thor), the villain&amp;ndash;Josh Brolin as Thanos&amp;ndash;is powerful and &lt;span class="spoiler">ACTUALLY GETS A CHANCE TO WIN&lt;/span>
, and I absolutely love seeing the interplay between all of the characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the surprisingly awesome &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/">Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/a>, it was really a question of: could they do it again? The answer, a resounding&amp;hellip; sort of?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 has some pretty awesome moments. The opening battle in particular is spectacular (I love the contrast of dancing Baby Groot against a big smack down in the background). And we get all piles of additional humor based around Drax&amp;rsquo;s literalness, Rocket being a racoon, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had forgotten just how &lt;em>fun&lt;/em> Guardians of the Galaxy is. Back when I &lt;a href="#original-2014-review">first reviewed it in 2014&lt;/a>, it surprised me with how different it was and just how much it opened up the Marvel Universe. Well, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen some pretty crazy things since then (Thor Ragnarok springs to mind), but it&amp;rsquo;s still a pretty crazy movie. I mean, come on. It&amp;rsquo;s a man obsessed with classic rock, a badass green woman assassin, an overly literal shirtless wrestler, a cybernetically enhanced racoon, and a speaking tree &lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> &lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Add in the first real hints of the Infinity Stones, Thanos as the continuing &amp;lsquo;bigger bad&amp;rsquo;, and you have a pretty impactful movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then on top of that, you get an absolutely hilarious movie, some wonderful action scenes (the meet up / fight in the square at the beginning is particularly wonderful, but there are several), and a whole range of colorful new characters. When you don&amp;rsquo;t have to even try to stick to what works on Earth&amp;hellip; things get pretty silly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a wonderful movie. I think this time around, I actually rate it higher than the Avengers, although still below Iron Man and Captain America 1 and 2. Well worth a watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the record: the ending scene is still kind of dumb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Random side note: the idea of a whole fleet of starships linking up (somehow) and literally trying to push a very slow moving enemy spaceship back into space is just bonkers. Among a movie full of crazy scenes, that one came the closest to really pulling me out of the film. But so it goes.&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="original-2014-review">Original 2014 review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Can Marvel do no wrong?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>