<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Stormlight Archive on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-stormlight-archive/</link><description>Recent content in The Stormlight Archive on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-stormlight-archive/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rhythm of War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/21/rhythm-of-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/21/rhythm-of-war/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Heroism is a myth you tell idealistic young people—specifically when you &amp;gt; want them to go bleed for you. It got one of my sons killed and another &amp;gt; taken from me. You can keep your heroism and return to me the lives of those &amp;gt; wasted on foolish conflicts.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well dang. After the absolutely bonkersiosity of the first three Stormlight Archive books, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t the slightest idea how Sanderson was going to pull off yet another (and another and another coming down the pipeline). And yet here we are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dawnshard</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/28/dawnshard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/28/dawnshard/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was unexpectedly wonderful. I was all set to dive into the behemoth that is &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="17250966" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17250966.rhythm-of-war">Rhythm of War&lt;/a> and then I noticed that there&amp;rsquo;s a 50k word &amp;lsquo;short&amp;rsquo; to read before it. I loved &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="34703445" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34703445.edgedancer">Edgedancer&lt;/a>, so let&amp;rsquo;s give this a try!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end, this I do not regret at all. &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="34703445" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34703445.edgedancer">Edgedancer&lt;/a> is a story that could was too long to be an interlude and too different to be in the main storyline, but having read it is a story that every much needed to be told.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Edgedancer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/11/25/edgedancer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/11/25/edgedancer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edgedancer is a short story set in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s Cosmere, specifically on Roshar of the Stormlight Archive. It features Lift, a young girl who was first featured in one of the interludes of &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="17332218" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17332218.words-of-radiance">Words of Radiance&lt;/a> interludes and now has a story all to her own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In short, Lift is a lot of fun. She&amp;rsquo;s a surgebinder who can make herself &amp;lsquo;awesome&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;her term for it&amp;ndash;and basically ignore friction. She seems an overall good person with a somewhat odd sense of morals and has a way of talking and acting that will just leave you smiling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oathbringer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/02/oathbringer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/02/oathbringer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hooooly crap. The first three quarters of Oathbringer are fairly slow. They&amp;rsquo;re still fascinating, building up more and more of the world of The Stormlight Archive, answering some questions while raising even more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then crap really hits the fan. I read the final several hundred pages in one session and wow a lot of things happen. Epic. Just epic. Read the book just for that and don&amp;rsquo;t put it down early.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Words of Radiance</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/15/words-of-radiance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/15/words-of-radiance/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I am offend!” Shallan yelled. “You have offended Her Highness again!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Very offend!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“You’d better apologize.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“No apologize!” Shallan declared. “Boots!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kal leaned back, looking between the two of them, trying to parse what had just been said. “Boots?” he asked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Yes,” Shallan said. “I am liking your boots. You will apology with boots.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“You . . . want my boots?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Did you not hear Her Highness?” Tyn asked, arms folded. “Are soldiers of this Dalinar Kholin’s army so disrespectful?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I’m not disrespectful,” Kal said. “But I’m not giving her my boots.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“You insult!” Shallan declared, stepping forward, pointing at him. Stormfather, those horses were enormous! “I will tell all who are to listen! When arriving, I will say, ‘Kholin is stealer of boots and taker of women’s virtue!’”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kal sputtered. “Virtue!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Yes,” Shallan said; then she glanced over to Tyn. “Virtue? No, wrong word. Virture . . . No . . . Vesture. Vesture! Taker of woman’s vesture! That is word I wanted.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The soldier glanced to his companions, looking confused. Drat, Shallan thought. Good puns are lost on men with poor vocabulary.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Way of Kings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/02/06/the-way-of-kings/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/02/06/the-way-of-kings/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tell … tell my brother … he must find the most important words a man can say.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>First, the &lt;em>worldbuilding&lt;/em> and &lt;em>magic systems&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>