<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Olivia Atwater on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/olivia-atwater/</link><description>Recent content in Olivia Atwater on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/olivia-atwater/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Small Miracles</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/11/small-miracles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/11/small-miracles/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Chocolate shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a sin at all. Everyone deserves a bit of chocolate.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Gadriel, a former (now fallen) Guardian Angel owes her angelic bookie&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. And all she has to do to come clear is to tempt one sinless mortal&amp;ndash;Holly Harker. Should be easy, it&amp;rsquo;s what she does now&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So of course wacky hijinks ensue, things go wrong, people get hurt (not badly, it&amp;rsquo;s not that sort of book), and just perhaps&amp;ndash;everyone comes out of it a bit better than they went in.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Believe me, plenty of people claim they love someone because they get the warm fuzzies around them - but love is something you do. Quite often, it&amp;rsquo;s something you choose.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s such a fun reading, reminding me fairly strongly of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/good-omens-the-nice-and-accurate-prophecies-of-agnes-nutter-witch/">Good Omens&lt;/a>&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Both in theme, but also in style. It&amp;rsquo;s a little bit irreverent, a little bit touching, and a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Structurally, the near constant footnotes detailing what is/isn&amp;rsquo;t a sin (points, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-good-place/">The Good Place&lt;/a> style) and the running score for Holly and her niece are a lot of fun. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect that to work as well in an audiobook as it did, but each time I heard that little chime, I got a little smile.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, another good read (on a bit of a run of those!). Well worth a try.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>