<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>jverkamp.com</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com" /><link rel="self" href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/feed/" /><updated>2015-10-27T00:00:00Z</updated><author><name>JP Verkamp</name></author><id>urn:uuid:78096ecf-1a9e-cb5b-4bec-1fe64bc50e98</id><entry><title>Oven sheet omelette</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/27/oven-sheet-omelette" /><id>urn:uuid:36c66318-9491-65aa-3cab-e1762b4bcf49</id><updated>2015-10-27T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cooked something worth blogging about, if only because it's so easy.</p>
<p><strong>Ingredients</strong></p>
<ul>
        <li>Ground beef (cooked and seasoned)</li>
    <li>3 small potatoes</li>
        <li>A dozen eggs</li>
        <li>An onion</li>
        <li>Cheese</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Recipe</strong></p>
<ol>
    <li>Preheat oven to 425℉</li>
        <li>Slice the potatoes thinly (I used a food processor)</li>
        <li>Pre-cook the potatoes for 5 minutes in the microwave</li>
    <li>Spray a deep oven sheet</li>
    <li>Put down a layer of potatoes and onions, then the beef</li>
    <li>Pour eggs over the whole thing</li>
    <li>Bake for 10 minutes</li>
    <li>Slice and server</li>
</ol>
<p>In progress, we have everything ready to go in the oven:</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/27/oven-sheet-omelette/1-ready-to-cook.jpg" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/27/oven-sheet-omelette/1-ready-to-cook.jpg" /></a></p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cooked something worth blogging about, if only because it's so easy.</p>
<p><strong>Ingredients</strong></p>
<ul>
        <li>Ground beef (cooked and seasoned)</li>
    <li>3 small potatoes</li>
        <li>A dozen eggs</li>
        <li>An onion</li>
        <li>Cheese</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Recipe</strong></p>
<ol>
    <li>Preheat oven to 425℉</li>
        <li>Slice the potatoes thinly (I used a food processor)</li>
        <li>Pre-cook the potatoes for 5 minutes in the microwave</li>
    <li>Spray a deep oven sheet</li>
    <li>Put down a layer of potatoes and onions, then the beef</li>
    <li>Pour eggs over the whole thing</li>
    <li>Bake for 10 minutes</li>
    <li>Slice and server</li>
</ol>
<p>In progress, we have everything ready to go in the oven:</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/27/oven-sheet-omelette/1-ready-to-cook.jpg" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/27/oven-sheet-omelette/1-ready-to-cook.jpg" /></a></p>
<!--more-->
<p>(Keen-eyed observers will note I may have forgotten the onions...)</p>
<p>And done / partially eaten:</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/27/oven-sheet-omelette/2-finished-dig-in.jpg" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/27/oven-sheet-omelette/2-finished-dig-in.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>It's really easy with only a couple minutes of prep and 15 minutes of waiting time. Nice for when you have only limited supplies and want a breakfasty dish.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>The Kane Chronicles</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-kane-chronicles" /><id>urn:uuid:5fcdb108-3d88-2e8f-19e3-9454cdebeb7a</id><updated>2015-10-23T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7090447-the-red-pyramid"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-kane-chronicles/1-the-red-pyramid.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9067850-the-throne-of-fire"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-kane-chronicles/2-the-throne-of-fire.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12893742-the-serpent-s-shadow"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-kane-chronicles/3-the-serpents-shadow.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Three more down on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/49971-kane-chronicles">The Kane Chronicles</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/15872.Rick_Riordan">Rick Riordan</a>. This is the same author (and based on a few hints, the same universe) as <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/18/the-heroes-of-olympus">The Heroes of Olympus</a> and before that the Percy Jackson series. Basically, it's the same rough idea, except instead of Greek/Roman mythology, we have Egyptian.</p>
<p>On one hand: Egyptian myths are awesome (and weird). There is a lot to mine from that. On the other: Riordan has told essentially the same core story a dozen times now. It's starting to show.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7090447-the-red-pyramid"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-kane-chronicles/1-the-red-pyramid.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9067850-the-throne-of-fire"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-kane-chronicles/2-the-throne-of-fire.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12893742-the-serpent-s-shadow"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-kane-chronicles/3-the-serpents-shadow.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Three more down on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/49971-kane-chronicles">The Kane Chronicles</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/15872.Rick_Riordan">Rick Riordan</a>. This is the same author (and based on a few hints, the same universe) as <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/18/the-heroes-of-olympus">The Heroes of Olympus</a> and before that the Percy Jackson series. Basically, it's the same rough idea, except instead of Greek/Roman mythology, we have Egyptian.</p>
<p>On one hand: Egyptian myths are awesome (and weird). There is a lot to mine from that. On the other: Riordan has told essentially the same core story a dozen times now. It's starting to show.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Overall, I liked them. I thought they were weaker than either Percy Jackson or <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/18/the-heroes-of-olympus">The Heroes of Olympus</a> but still strong enough on their own merits.</p>
<p>Individual reviews:</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7090447-the-red-pyramid"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-kane-chronicles/1-the-red-pyramid.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Red Pyramid would be a lot strong if I hadn't read Percy Jackson.</p>
<p>Don't get me wrong. Red Pyramid is still a fine book, although it feels like it's written for an even younger audience than Percy Jackson.</p>
<p>A few of the downsides:</p>
<ul>
        <li>Red Pyramid is told 'interview style', as if it were a transcribed copy of an audio recording. It would be fine as a framing device, except there are random interjections between the two narrators that each time pulled me out of the story. They're supposed to be 'witty', but I could have done without them.</li>

        <li>The humor feels younger than Percy Jackson. The five elements: Earth, Air, Fire, Water, and ... Cheese. I guess I'm getting old.</li>

        <li>Despite having two narrators, it was hard to tell who's chapter I was reading at times. Riordan did this much better in the Heroes of Olympus.</li>

        <li>The BAD GUYS were BAD just for the sake of BEING BAD. Even from a kid's book, I would like a little more depth. Although I guess there's something to be said for gods playing a role.</li>
</ul>
<p>On a more positive note:</p>
<ul>
        <li>Egyptian mythology is weird! The flavor does play through several points of the story. Where the Greek and Roman gods felt 'human', the Egyptian gods feel weird. That's a good thing. The hieroglyphics in particular were a neat touch.</li>

        <li>There are hints at a shared universe (the western bank belongs to ... others) without it being overbearing. I don't think I would ever like to see a crossover with the Greek/Roman books, but the possibility is neat in and of itself.</li>

        <li>SUMMON BIGGER BAD. The ending was fairly obvious from early on (and once again strongly echoes Percy Jackson), but it did leave me wanting more.</li>
</ul>
<p>Still. A fun read. Relatively quick. I'll finish the series.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9067850-the-throne-of-fire"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-kane-chronicles/2-the-throne-of-fire.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I don't really have particularly much to add for Throne of Fire that I didn't already say for The Red Pyramid.</p>
<p>Basically, more of the same. The Kanes have five days to save the world (it's impressive how even something like that can start to get old after a dozen novels...). They proceed to do so.</p>
<p>One particularly weird part this time: Sadie takes the time in the second day of the novel to go to Londor for her birthday. The fate of the world hangs in the balance... And you can teleport around the world. You can go to London later.</p>
<p>Another slight downside is that this very much feels like the middle book of a trilogy (which of course it is). It works more to set up the third and final book rather than being able to stand by itself. That doesn't necessarily make it bad, but it's not great when it's that obvious.</p>
<p>On the up side, the cast of characters has expanded a bit with a few new trainee godlings brought into the fold, apparently from that audio recording from the first novel.</p>
<p>Still, it was an entertaining enough read and kept me going enough that I still want to finish the trilogy.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12893742-the-serpent-s-shadow"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-kane-chronicles/3-the-serpents-shadow.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>A solid ending to the series. Once again the world will end in <i>n</i> days and it's up to Sadie and Carter to save that day.</p>
<p>Really, it feels like the second half of The Throne of Fire. We have the same support characters, the same big bad, the same magic, and it doesn't feel like that terribly much time has passed. Honestly, it's not a bad thing; it's just a little bit weird.</p>
<p>One thing I did like is that the climactic battle did actually feel big. It was a bit rushed, but it was nice to see everything coming together in a bunch of ways. The afterwards with the gods withdrawing was odd, but made sense. There there was a paragraph or two dedicated to setting the stage for a potential Percy Jackson crossover. I mentioned in a previous review: it's neat to think about, but I'm not sure how well it could be done.</p>
<p>So far as downsides, really the same as the previous two books. The meta story of being a transcription of an audio recording is weird. I sometimes couldn't tell which sibling I was reading. But it felt a little less bad this time around. Perhaps I just got used to it?</p>
<p>As I've said before: the series isn't quite as good as either the Greek or Roman series, but stand alone it's still certainly enjoyable. I'm glad I read them.</p>
<hr />
<p>Next up, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2429135.The_Girl_with_the_Dragon_Tattoo">The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/706255.Stieg_Larsson">Stieg Larsson</a>. Based on the reviews--everyone seems to either love it or hate it--and the genre--I tend not to like stories set in (or that could be set in) the modern real world... I have no idea if I'm going to like it.</p>
<p>We'll find out!</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Throne of the Crescent Moon</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/04/throne-of-the-crescent-moon" /><id>urn:uuid:e6d8363e-1056-6e43-dd61-f350164b74f0</id><updated>2015-10-04T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11487807-throne-of-the-crescent-moon"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/04/throne-of-the-crescent-moon/throne-of-the-crescent-moon.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I really liked this book.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11487807-throne-of-the-crescent-moon">Throne of the Crescent Moon</a> (by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/4025591.Saladin_Ahmed">Saladin Ahmed</a>) follows a band of somewhat unlikely heroes as they're off to save the day. You have an old ghul hunter (one of the last of his kind), a whirling dervish (I'd never before looked up what that actually meant), an alchemist and her mage of a husband, and a shape shifter who can take the form of a golden lion.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11487807-throne-of-the-crescent-moon"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/04/throne-of-the-crescent-moon/throne-of-the-crescent-moon.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I really liked this book.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11487807-throne-of-the-crescent-moon">Throne of the Crescent Moon</a> (by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/4025591.Saladin_Ahmed">Saladin Ahmed</a>) follows a band of somewhat unlikely heroes as they're off to save the day. You have an old ghul hunter (one of the last of his kind), a whirling dervish (I'd never before looked up what that actually meant), an alchemist and her mage of a husband, and a shape shifter who can take the form of a golden lion.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Arrayed against them; a beastie from the time of the dead gods raising a whole bunch of ghuls. Also a corrupt all powerful ruler and the Robin Hood esqe figure who may or may not be any better in the end.</p>
<p>One thing that I really loved about this book: the world. It's based on Arabic influences rather than the pseudo-European that I've seen in most of the fantasy I've read. Better yet, the Arabic influence is woven throughout the story in a way that just makes it come alive. You have sights and sounds and history and magic, all with (to me) a very new feel to it. If you've read a similar selection to me, this is worth reading just for that.</p>
<p>On top of that, I liked the relatively large ensemble cast. Even though we had five main characters and a whole pile of supporting cast (see above), I really thought that each had their own voice and I was greatly amused and intrigued with how each of them interacted with one another.</p>
<p>All together, it's a neat book. Especially after everything shakes out in the end, I wish the sequel were out already (planned release in 2016). What I think I really need is to do is to go find other fantasy novels from non-European authors...</p>
<p>Excellent.</p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>, I'm going to re-read / finish the <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/49971-kane-chronicles">The Kane Chronicles</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/15872.Rick_Riordan">Rick Riordan</a>. A combination of Percy Jackson / <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/18/the-heroes-of-olympus">The Heroes of Olympus</a> and Egyptian mythology? Count me in!</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Newsflesh Trilogy</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy" /><id>urn:uuid:54f77424-fa72-6fad-8d52-4a98f4391fe1</id><updated>2015-09-30T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7094569-feed"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/1-feed.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8429687-deadline"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/2-deadline.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11806716-blackout"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/3-blackout.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Onwards and brainwards!</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3153776.Mira_Grant">Mira Grant</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>.</p>
<p>Brains...</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7094569-feed"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/1-feed.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8429687-deadline"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/2-deadline.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11806716-blackout"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/3-blackout.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Onwards and brainwards!</p>
<p>The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3153776.Mira_Grant">Mira Grant</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>.</p>
<p>Brains...</p>
<!--more-->
<p>I find it vaguely amusing how relatively many zombie series I've read this year. <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/03/27/white-trash-zombie">White Trash Zombie</a> (with the next October 6th!). <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/03/31/precinct-13">Precinct 13</a>. <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris">Elantris</a> (Yeah--that doesn't really count.) Still, the more the merrier when you're hungry for flesh.</p>
<p>Overall, Newsflesh is an excellent series. Basically, in the future, zombies are here and bloggers have taken over the world. Where these stories really shine is their world building. The zombie plague is an infectious disease and society has changed as a result. It actually feels like something that could just happen, which really helped to draw me into the books.</p>
<p>Also positive, there are a goodly number of plot twists throughout the series. Some are obvious in hindsight, some even in foresight. And some... Ow. Some hit right where it hurts.</p>
<p>Here are my individual reviews. Warning: <strong>spoilers</strong>. Each book's review should be relatively spoiler-free, but it's hard to talk about Deadline and Blackout without spoilers for Feed.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7094569-feed"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/1-feed.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Feed follows the story of George (yup), Shaun (also yup), and Buffy (not even kidding), three bloggers covering the story of a lifetime: a Republican Presidential candidate. Then, as it always goes in a zombie story, things go wrong.</p>
<p>I liked the characters. The bloggers are divided into a newsie (tells it like it is), an Irwin (basically the action stars of the blogging world) (yup), and a fictional (writes poetry); missing only a Stewart (satire in the news) (also yup). I really felt for all of them, even if at time they tended a bit towards caricatures of their roles. Also: evil bad guy is evil and obvious, but sometimes that's not a bad thing.</p>
<p>This is also one of the best treatments of a 'realistic' zombie outbreak that I think I've read. Society has mostly adapted to everyone being a carrier with a system of restrictions (no one can go to Yosemite) and near constant blood tests. The CDC is far more powerful and people have adapted to the idea that any mammal over 40 pounds could be your death.</p>
<p>Therein lies the first oddity with this book: Feed doesn't actually feel like a zombie novel. More than anything it feels like a novel about journalism, politics, and freedom of speech... which just so happens to happen during after the zombie apocalypse. It took me a while to realize this, but I think it makes the novel stronger as a result.</p>
<p>And then there's the twists, oh the twists. I get it, it's a zombie story. People are going to die. Just... I didn't see that coming... Wow. That's certainly one way to get me to read the sequel.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8429687-deadline"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/2-deadline.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I was curious to see where Grant would take this, after killing off a small pile of main characters in the first book. It turns out: somewhere right between what I expected and what I didn't expect at all.</p>
<p>On one hand, Shaun is crazy now. He hears George's voice in his head and answers her out loud. Everyone around him of course thinks he's crazy, but they mostly seem to give him space. I'm not sure what I think about that. Shaun is still probably my least favorite of the main characters from the first book, which is certainly suboptimal, given that he's the only one to survive... (Also, the Coke fixation is weird.) But why does everyone else keep him around?</p>
<p>On the other hand, the world building continues to be excellent. We get a few neat twists (like what the reservoir conditions might actually mean) and dig a little deeper into the conspiracy behind it all. Given that there's still one more book, we don't get quite as much of that as I'd like, but so it goes. Still though, it feels like Grant really did her homework. The zombie threat feels real. That's saying something.</p>
<p>And then... The ending. One thing I don't care about in second books of trilogies is when they don't have an ending of their own. If Deadline had ended around 80%, it would have been fine. Instead, we get the ALL NEW BIGGER AND BETTER THREAT in the last 20% or so. Don't get me wrong, I really want to know how it all shakes out, but it's still annoying.</p>
<p>And then and then... That last sentence. Say <b>what!?</b></p>
<p>Needless to say, onwards to Blackout.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11806716-blackout"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/newsflesh-trilogy/3-blackout.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>A solid ending to a solid series. I think that I liked it more than Deadline, but less than Feed, owing entirely to one thing: George.</p>
<p>Yup, she's back. Literally the last thing that happens in Deadline gets fleshed out (heh) in Blackout as we alternate once again between Shaun's and Georgia's viewpoints. It's fairly obvious what's happened (and a neat extension of what we already know about the zombie virus), but that doesn't mean I was still rooting for her nevertheless.</p>
<p>That being said, her being back complicates Shaun's situation somewhat. He's not any less crazy and as odd as it sounds, his underlings are still just dealing with it. <spoiler>What's more, it's made explicit here that Georgia and Shaun have been sleeping together. I get it, and they're adopted rather than blood siblings, but it still feels a little off.</spoiler></p>
<p>Other than that, it's a solid conclusion to the series. We finally learn who the big bads are--although it's not a huge twist. We get a few more complications with the zombie virus with several nice showdowns across the country. The ending is less 'they all lived happily ever after' and more 'we may just survive this', but given the events of the stories, that's good enough for me. At least it's not a cliffhanger like Deadline...</p>
<p>Overall, great book, great series. Not quite on my list of favorites ever, but I'm glad I read it.</p>
<hr />
<p>Next up, we get a nice fantasy adventure based on Arabic history, rather than the European fantasy I've read piles of: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11487807-throne-of-the-crescent-moon">Throne of the Crescent Moon</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/4025591.Saladin_Ahmed">Saladin Ahmed</a></p>
<p>I'm looking forward to it.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Elantris</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris" /><id>urn:uuid:82dbdf77-b085-bb90-6691-c7f4377e417f</id><updated>2015-09-18T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68427.Elantris"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/elantris.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13578175-the-emperor-s-soul"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/the-emperors-soul.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I know I said last post that my next series would be The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a>, and that's still the case, but in the mean time, I have a <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a> review for <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68427.Elantris">Elantris</a> (and <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13578175-the-emperor-s-soul">The Emperor's Soul</a>) by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson">Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68427.Elantris"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/elantris.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13578175-the-emperor-s-soul"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/the-emperors-soul.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I know I said last post that my next series would be The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a>, and that's still the case, but in the mean time, I have a <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a> review for <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68427.Elantris">Elantris</a> (and <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13578175-the-emperor-s-soul">The Emperor's Soul</a>) by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson">Brandon Sanderson</a>.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Since there are only two and they're not particularly directly related to one another, here are the individual reviews:</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68427.Elantris"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/elantris.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I have yet to find a Sanderson novel that I don't particularly like and Elantris is no exception.</p>
<p>Basically, Elantris focuses around the titular city; once a place of wonder and magic which. Ten years ago, all that ended and now it's populated by essentially zombies: those without heartbeats who cannot die and cannot heal. We follow a few different story lines--a princess from another land engaged to the prince who gets Elantrisified in the very beginning of the story; an attempted religious coup from multiple fronts; and the politics of a kingdom/city trying to heal after massive upheaval.</p>
<p>This is his earliest work and in some ways it shows. He actually commented recently on the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast that he co-hosts that he's learned a lot about pacing since writing Elantris. Towards the end, I definitely noticed it. In the last 10% or so of the novel, everything comes to a head all at once. I think it could have been even strong had some of the storylines come to fruition earlier.</p>
<p>I did like a lot of the characters. Sarene reminds me strongly of Shallan from The Way of Kings (perhaps because it's the most recent other Sanderson novel I've read), but I think I actually like her more. Raoden seems almost too good to be true, but keeps just enough human trivialities (especially when interacting with Sarene), that I still like him. I particularly grew to like Hrathen. It's always interesting to see how fantasy novels interact with religion.</p>
<p>More than anything, I wish this novel had a sequel. Well, it sort of does in [book: The Emperor's Soul|13578175], although that it in a completely different part of the world. It looks like there is a true sequel in the works though (<a href="http://brandonsanderson.com/faq-will-there-be-a-sequel-to-elantris/">FAQ</a>). Awesome.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13578175-the-emperor-s-soul"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/18/elantris/the-emperors-soul.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>If I hadn't been told, at first I wouldn't realize that The Emperor's Soul takes place in a far away corner of the same world as Elantris. But as the story wears on, and the details of the magic system are revealed, it becomes more obvious that the worlds are one and the same. I really do love how Sanderson does magic systems. I've never seen anything quite like it, especially not at the same scale. Every system seems new, yet there's a shared core to all of them. I love it.</p>
<p>Other than that, I did like the character of Shai. There's something about an artist who works entirely to know that she did it, rather than for public acclaim that I enjoy. Sneaky and subtle. Excellent. I could see a few of the twists coming (that she wouldn't escape until the last moment; the changes she made), but that didn't make it any less enjoyable.</p>
<p>One thing I'd love to see if/when that Elantris sequel comes out? A meeting between the worlds. How would a Forger interact with an Elantrian? What about a Bloodsealer? I want to know more about them.</p>
<p>"You can't always write what you know--not exactly what you know. You can, however, write what you see." -- Brandon Sanderson</p>
<hr />
<p>With that, I have only <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1268479.Warbreaker">Warbreaker</a> left among Sanderson's <a href="http://coppermind.net/wiki/Cosmere">Cosmere</a> novels<span class="footnote"><sup><a href="#footnote-1">[1]</a></sup></span> and a few of the non-Cosmere ones.  Dang, he's prolific.</p>
<p>Next up (for real this time): the <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a>.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Partials Sequence</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence" /><id>urn:uuid:4fe7f178-a6d6-ecbf-e428-078b89728673</id><updated>2015-09-16T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12476820-partials"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/1-partials.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13645264-isolation"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/0.5-isolation.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13170596-fragments"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/2-fragments.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17607716-ruins"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/3-ruins.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/70323-partials-sequence">Partials Sequence</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/2740668.Dan_Wells">Dan Wells</a>.</p>
<p>I actually found Dan Wells through the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast (co-host <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson?from_search=true&search_version=service">Brandon Sanderson</a> is another author I love) and I'm glad I did. Basically, Partials is the young adult post-apocalyptic trilogy that I'd been looking for without even realizing it.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12476820-partials"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/1-partials.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13645264-isolation"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/0.5-isolation.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13170596-fragments"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/2-fragments.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17607716-ruins"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/3-ruins.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/70323-partials-sequence">Partials Sequence</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/2740668.Dan_Wells">Dan Wells</a>.</p>
<p>I actually found Dan Wells through the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast (co-host <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson?from_search=true&search_version=service">Brandon Sanderson</a> is another author I love) and I'm glad I did. Basically, Partials is the young adult post-apocalyptic trilogy that I'd been looking for without even realizing it.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>I've always had a problem with worlds like that in <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13335037-divergent">Divergent</a> and <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2767052-the-hunger-games">The Hunger Games</a>. There's always something (the strict divisions between classes and the titular Games for two examples) that just doesn't make sense. In my opinion, Partials doesn't really have that.</p>
<p>You have a war (which ended years before the series takes place) that genetically engineered super soldiers were created to fight on behalf of humanity. After that, you have a bio-weapon / virus that wipes out 99.96% of humanity and, in this case, renders the remaining tens of thousands sterile. I would like to think it unlikely, but all of that--and the story that develops from there--seems believable for the not too distant future. All together, I enjoyed Partials even more than I expected. It's even better having listened to several seasons now of Writing Excuses--I know about Wells and the writing process he goes through than I do many authors. As mentioned in my individual review for the third book: If Divergent / The Hunger Games left you wanting more, this is it. If you haven't read either, read these instead.</p>
<p>Here are my individual reviews as I went:</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12476820-partials"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/1-partials.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>The story of Partials takes place 11 years after humanity lost a terrible war. Basically, we created super soldiers (Partials) to fight for us. Of course, after they won the war they turned on us... Worse yet, right at the same time, there was a virus which killed 99.96% of humanity--including any new pregnancies.</p>
<p>So that's where we start. Humanity is stuck on Long Island while the Partials are <i>out there</i>™. Because no babies can survive the virus, the youngest living people are 14. The main characters are roughly 16. Even stranger, in an effort to figure out how to cure the virus, the Hope Act has been enacted. All women 18 or older must get pregnant as often as possible.</p>
<p>It's an odd premise, but each part at least follows through. It's a little strange that the main characters are so good at what they do (always a problem with YA fiction), but at least the idea that they had to grow up quickly helps offset that.</p>
<p>Other than that, it's an interesting world. The action keeps things moving, especially towards the latter end of the book, and I actually feel for the characters as things keep going sideways on them. There were a few twists that followed the standard YA post-apocalyptic tropes (is that a thing now) but a few that I missed, which is nice.</p>
<p>Overall, it's perhaps not as strong as some of the other books I've read this year (although it's the best post-apocalyptic YA :)), but it's more than good enough to finish the series.</p>
<p>Onward!</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13645264-isolation"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/0.5-isolation.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Quick and to the point, Isolation tells the story of Heron (who we met briefly in Partials) during the Isolation War. It gives a better picture into the Partials: how they are made, how they are trained, and why they might not only want to, but even been the right to, kill us.</p>
<p>It's a good story and I hope to see more of Heron in the second and third books of the Partials Sequence. It'll be interesting to see how she's grown and changed in the intervening years and how she interacts with the other human (and not) protagonists.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13170596-fragments"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/2-fragments.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>A good continuation to Partials. In this book, we see Kira start to come to terms with who she is as she sets off with Samm and Heron across what's left of the United States in search of answers--only to find more than she was looking for. Meanwhile, Marcus is back home, stuck between two warring Partial factions, trying desperately to broker a piece.</p>
<p>It's a neat continuation. I like watching the world expand, exploring more of what happened in the decade and change since everything fell apart. We're starting to get some answers, which of course lead to more questions. I look forward to Ruins, cautiously hoping that Wells can pull everything together for the finale.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17607716-ruins"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/partials-sequence/3-ruins.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>A solid ending to a solid series.</p>
<p>I think Ruins actually managed to pull things together in a way without feeling (too) rushed that none of the other YA series recently have managed to pull off. The previous plotlines (Kira's conflicted nature, the rest of the Trust, the cure(s)) all come to a head in a way that's still driving enough to finish the series but don't feel like the author was just phoning it in.</p>
<p>There were a few things that I felt were just glanced over.</p>
<p>Kira manages to succeed where a decade of scientists (including those who caused the problem in the first place) have failed. That seems strange. But it's at least lamp shaded in that they were too blind to see a solution.</p>
<p>The two new Trust members come out of nowhere and never really make much sense. Plus, they're just sort of resolved. They're interesting, but I feel like they could have done more.</p>
<p>The love triangle just vanishes. Perhaps more real world accurate and I cannot believe I'm saying this: but it was weird.</p>
<p>All together though, a solid read and a solid series. If Divergent / The Hunger Games left you wanting more, this is it. If you haven't read either, read these instead.</p>
<hr />
<p>So far, GoodReads says that I've read 71 books this year, with a total of 25,513 pages. Given that today is the 258th day of the year, that averages out to 100 pages per day and I'm right on target. Let's see if I can keep that up for the last third of the year... Especially with <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/category/writing/nanowrimo">NaNoWriMo</a> looming just over the horizon.</p>
<p>Up next, another apocalypse. Zombies this time, in The <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/47749-newsflesh">Newsflesh Trilogy</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3153776.Mira_Grant">Mira Grant</a>.</p>
<p>Brains...</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>The Iron Wyrm Affair</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/01/the-iron-wyrm-affair" /><id>urn:uuid:d1140414-f3b3-8ae2-b3cf-4c60713d0392</id><updated>2015-09-01T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12899734-the-iron-wyrm-affair"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/01/the-iron-wyrm-affair/the-iron-wyrm-affair.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12899734-the-iron-wyrm-affair">The Iron Wyrm Affair </a> (Bannon &amp; Clare #1) by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/131208.Lilith_Saintcrow">Lilith Saintcrow</a>.</p>
<p>Disclaimer: I didn't actually finish the story. I stopped at about 80%, although I was skimming before then. The cover looks good and the summary is intriguing, but the book itself I didn't particularly care for.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12899734-the-iron-wyrm-affair"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/01/the-iron-wyrm-affair/the-iron-wyrm-affair.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12899734-the-iron-wyrm-affair">The Iron Wyrm Affair </a> (Bannon &amp; Clare #1) by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/131208.Lilith_Saintcrow">Lilith Saintcrow</a>.</p>
<p>Disclaimer: I didn't actually finish the story. I stopped at about 80%, although I was skimming before then. The cover looks good and the summary is intriguing, but the book itself I didn't particularly care for.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Main problems:</p>
<ul>
    <li>There are <em>Proper Nouns</em> all over the place, but they're only rarely explained until much later (if at all). Some books can get away with this. This one did not.
    <li>The POV jumps from character to character and in some cases it can take a while to figure out who in the world is talking.</li>
    <li>Bannon (main character) is crazy powerful. Again, sometimes you can have a story start with a very powerful protagonist and go from there, but more often than not it doesn't work out.</li>
    <li>Clare (apparently supposed to be a main character) never really feels like a main character. He's badly overshadowed by Bannon and one of her Shields, to the point where I'm not sure why the series isn't titled Bannon and Mikal.</li>
    <li>Holy purple prose Batman. The wording feels accurate for the period (so far as I know, which I don't), but the fact that I noticed enough to comment on it isn't great. Also Bannon mentions over and over again how unladylike she's being. We get it.</li>
</ul>
<p>Upsides:</p>
<ul>
    <li>Some of the descriptions were very cool. Counter to the last point above, I really could see what was going on in some of the scenes. Not necessarily why it was happening and I'm sure I got some of the <em>Proper Nouns</em> wrong, but it was still solid.</li>
    <li>There is a lot of neat worldbuilding just beneath the surface. I wish it was more obvious, but it's always interesting to read alternate history at this level. I want to know how things changed! I want to know how things work! Usually that wanting will drive me kicking and screaming through a story (in the best way possible). It almost did this time.</li>
</ul>
<p>Similar to the point I made a little while back for Whitechapel Gods and <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/25/his-majestys-dragon">His Majesty's Dragon</a>. I'm sure there are loads of people who love this kind of story. I'm not one of them.</p>
<p>So it goes.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>The Academy</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy" /><id>urn:uuid:0b7731fd-746d-7733-9bc9-804c0233355e</id><updated>2015-08-27T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/337048.The_Engines_of_God"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/1-the-engines-of-god.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/352780.Deepsix"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/2-deepsix.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/382161.Chindi"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/3-chindi.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/352781.Omega"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/4-omega.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/352775.Odyssey"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/5-odyssey.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/535318.Cauldron"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/6-cauldron.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/42777-the-academy">The Academy</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/73812.Jack_McDevitt">Jack McDevitt</a>.</p>
<p>The Academy (it feels weird to call it that) takes place in a few century distant future where humanity has been to the stars and found them next to empty. There are hints at civilizations that have come before (a monument on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iapetus_(moon)">Iapetus</a> for example) and others still around, albeit not at our same technological level. There are terrible threats: truly giant clouds of gas that seem to have a thing for destroying cities in several of the novels and a planet about to fall into a gas giant in another.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/337048.The_Engines_of_God"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/1-the-engines-of-god.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/352780.Deepsix"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/2-deepsix.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/382161.Chindi"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/3-chindi.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/352781.Omega"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/4-omega.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/352775.Odyssey"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/5-odyssey.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/535318.Cauldron"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/6-cauldron.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/42777-the-academy">The Academy</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/73812.Jack_McDevitt">Jack McDevitt</a>.</p>
<p>The Academy (it feels weird to call it that) takes place in a few century distant future where humanity has been to the stars and found them next to empty. There are hints at civilizations that have come before (a monument on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iapetus_(moon)">Iapetus</a> for example) and others still around, albeit not at our same technological level. There are terrible threats: truly giant clouds of gas that seem to have a thing for destroying cities in several of the novels and a planet about to fall into a gas giant in another.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Overall, it's pretty solid science fiction. It's a little weird reading them all in sequence, since they only roughly seem to relate to one another. Sometimes characters are shared (superluminal pilot Priscilla "Hutch" Hutchins is one; reporter/editor Gregory MacAllister is another) and it's definitely a shared universe, but there are some events which come up in one book and not again for several sequels (if at all). It's not <em>bad</em> per say, just odd.</p>
<p>I do really like the world (galaxy?) that McDevitt has built here. I want to believe that life is far more common than he paints it--as a wise man once said, 'life finds a way'--but if that's not the case, I can imagine things working out exactly like this.</p>
<p>One particularly interesting point is that faster than light travel in this universe is possible, but limited. It still takes weeks / months / longer to get to other stars--which can be something of a problem if you happen to need rescuing. It's a perfect example though of just how <em>big</em> space is.</p>
<p>Also interesting (although I don't think I mention it in the individual reviews below) is the use of AI throughout the series. Each superluminal has an AI (although the Academy's seem to all be copies of a single AI named Bill) with a personality all its own. Yet they're just part of the world; for the most part people just interact with them as people. It's a neat idea and I like how it fits so seamlessly into the world.</p>
<p>That being said, here are my individual reviews:</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/337048.The_Engines_of_God"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/1-the-engines-of-god.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>The Engines of God fits into the same rough style of science fiction as Rama, where the story is drive more by events and discovery than particularly by plot or character. In my opinion, this can be a perfectly enjoyable form of story, just so long as you know that's what you're getting.</p>
<p>The basic idea of this story is that in the future, humanity has developed faster than light travel and expanded to other solar systems. We've found one other current civilization (roughly WWI era; they haven't noticed us) and hints of others stretching back tens of thousands of years. Yet there's something strange: every one of them has sharp discontinuities where the clock of technology is reset.</p>
<p>One downside to this style and for this story in particular is that we only find out roughly what happened to those civilizations in the last 10% or so of the book. As an effect, the climax of the story felt rushed, with no earl impact. I know this is the first of a series and I can only hope they explore the impact of what they found a little more.</p>
<p>So far as characters, this was another weaker part of the story. I honestly don't think I could tell you anything about any of the characters I just read about (except maybe Hutch). Part of that is me--I'm not great with remembering details about people--and part is the same type-of-story thing mentioned above. Still, it's a little weird.</p>
<p>Overall, it's a neat story and in a style I enjoy reading (once I figured out that was what was going on). It was more than good enough to start in on the rest of the series. I really do want to figure out what is going on there.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/352780.Deepsix"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/2-deepsix.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Similar to the Engines of God a large chunk of the book is spent on the technology / archaeological aspects and how they interact with the story, but in this case there's also a strong thriller aspect. Things just keep going wrong (although, given that it's a novel, you can almost guess how each thing is going to go) over and over up until the climax.</p>
<p>The last section in particular was intense; I read the entire thing in one sitting--a literal page turner.</p>
<p>I liked the main characters well enough, at least as they were written. This time around, I could actually start to tell them apart, which is an upside. There are at least two who are curiously misogynistic for no reason that I could tell...</p>
<p>On a downside, we really didn't learn anything more about the Omega Waves from the previous book. And now we have some mysterious aliens who were about with advanced technology on a few thousand years ago... Perhaps we'll run into them in one of the sequels? One can hope.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/382161.Chindi"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/3-chindi.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Chindi continues the trend of the previous two books in only vaguely being a sequel. It takes place after the previous two with one of the same characters (Hutch) and there are a few references to previous events... But that's about it. That's not a bad thing though.</p>
<p>This book starts with the discovery of an alien satellites around a neutron star. Hijinks ensue and people die (I'll come back to that in a second). It turns out that the satellites are part of a communication network. The next large chunk of the book follows our characters from world to world chasing after this network. (More people die). They finally end up finding a truly massive alien starship and exploring that (more people die). Then there's the climax where--just like Deepsix--our heroes have to attempt a daring / insane rescue mission so as not to leave a man behind.</p>
<p>On the plus side: I love the science aspects of the book. It's really starting to come together as a world and I like how there is some thought put into consequences. FTL travel and communication are possible, but it still takes time. Artificial gravity interacts oddly with inertia. Traveling at relativistic speeds does strange things to time. I keep turning pages, wanting to know more.</p>
<p>On the down side: It's getting increasingly hard to have sympathy for the characters. Over three books, there has been a fairly impressive body count. And almost all of them were avoidable. Over and over in this book, the author hangs a lampshade on the fact that what the characters are doing is dangerous. Off they go, and off someone dies. And yet other than a few token comments, no one seems to care. It's starting to get a bit weird.</p>
<p>Overall (and you can see by my rating), I'm still really enjoying this series. There's a definite sense of something building and the world growing and changing behind the scenes. And better, the epilogue of this book and the title of the next hint that we might just learn a bit more about the Omega Clouds from book 1! Looking forward to it.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/352781.Omega"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/4-omega.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Omega continues on in much the same vein as the previous Academy books. Science fiction in a universe where life is remarkably rare and civilization even more so. This time though... we've found someone.</p>
<p>The Omegas (clouds coming in 8000 year waves from the center of the galaxy which have a tendency to seek out and destroy right angles) return in the book, pointing directly to a new civilization. It's thousands of light years away, so there are only a limited number of ships that can possibly get there in time.</p>
<p>Hutch takes more of a backseat role this time, opening the stage to a few new characters. And just when I was finally getting to know her too. I like the new characters well enough and the death toll is at least lower this time. We'll see if they stick around in the next two books.</p>
<p>Overall, despite an entire civilization at stake, this book someone doesn't quite get as intense as those before it. Perhaps just because I've now read five of these in a row, but I can see from the outset which solutions are going to fail, which will partially succeed, and how they're finally going to save the day. It's not a problem per say, but it's getting there.</p>
<p>Final oddity (and this might have had some impact on the previous paragraph): I've actually read this book before. I'm fairly impressed that I managed to pick up and read the fourth in a series without realizing it (even if this is one series where that's not necessarily a problem) and that I didn't notice I was rereading until about 20% of the way into the book. It must have been pre-GoodReads that I last read it. Amusing.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/352775.Odyssey"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/5-odyssey.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Summary: The Academy is running out of money. In the meantime, MacAllister, a senator's daughter, a pilot, and a PR guy from the Academy are on a tour looking for UFOs because reasons. Eventually the find some (ish), the daughter gets contacted by aliens (maybe, no one believes her at first and it's never really explained), and a bunch of people die.</p>
<p>As with a few other books in this series, it takes half the book to get to what feels like the main plot point, with a massive acceleration in the last 15% and a final climax in the last 5%. It's not necessarily a bad thing, it just felt a lot more obvious in this book.</p>
<p>Especially when half the book it feels like is spent talking about how the Academy isn't getting funded any more (mirroring NASA and other modern day space programs) and an oddly large amount of the second half on a trial about a guy who went to a religious school, grew up, and punched a priest. I still haven't figured out where that came from.</p>
<p>That being said, I still enjoy the universe that McDevitt has built here. The universe actually feels big and the technology feels right. I want to believe that life will be more common than he paints it, but if it's not, this feels like how the universe might just be.</p>
<p>Once again, I hope the next book has a few more answers (we still don't know what the Omegas are and now there's a real current alien race?), but given the previous four and that #6 is the last book currently out... We'll see.</p>
<p>Edited to add: The book opens with a ship 'lost' in space because it didn't go nearly as far as it should have, despite the physicists saying that shouldn't be possible. Yet that particular weirdness is dropped and never mentioned again in favor of the 'retire the old ships because funding plot'. Weird.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/535318.Cauldron"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/the-academy/6-cauldron.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Following from Omega, the Academy is basically dead (lack of funding / interest) and humanity is withdrawing from the stars. Then there's a breakthrough in new FTL drive technology orders of magnitude faster than the previous incarnations. Hutch returns as one of the two pilots sent out on a high speed mission to the origin of the Chindi, a world SETI received a transmission came from, a black hole, and the possible origin of the Omegas (finally).</p>
<p>On the upside: we finally got something in the way of answers for both where the Chindi and the Omegas came from. It's by no means a complete answer, but more than we've had thus far. I'll take it. The addition of the new drive technology promises to really shake things up. I hope this isn't the last book in the series--I want to see where this universe goes, now that you can fly to the galactic core in about four months... (As an aside, space is *huge*).</p>
<p>On a slight downside, some of the stops really felt undeveloped. What could have been an entire book earlier in the series was only a chapter or two. Even so, I think this book had the best flow of the six; I finished it in a day.</p>
<hr />
<p>Overall, solid science fiction. Compared to the two previous such series I've read this year, I'd put it well above <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama">Rama</a> (when taken as a whole) and just about even with <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/10/enders-game">Ender's Game</a>. That should give you a hint at how much I liked these books. <img alt="smile" class="emoji" src="/emoji/smile.svg" /></p>
<p>Next up: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12899734-the-iron-wyrm-affair?from_search=true&search_version=service">The Iron Wyrm Affair</a>. It's got an intriguing cover and premise, but I'm a little worried that the reviews are all over the place. We'll see how it goes.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Laundry Files</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files" /><id>urn:uuid:be3e3e1e-8aa3-4d98-27ca-8ac00ecce18d</id><updated>2015-07-28T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/101869.The_Atrocity_Archives"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/1-the-atrocity-archives.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/14150.The_Jennifer_Morgue"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/2-the-jennifer-morgue.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7149287-the-fuller-memorandum"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/3-the-fuller-memorandum.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12393566-the-apocalypse-codex"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/4-the-apocalypse-codex.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18211295-the-rhesus-chart"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/5-the-rhesus-chart.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23154785-the-annihilation-score"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/6-the-annihilation-score.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/50764-laundry-files">The Laundry Files</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/8794.Charles_Stross">Charles Stross</a>. Even though this wasn't originally on my list, I ended up just reading this rather than reading two series at once. So it goes.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/101869.The_Atrocity_Archives"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/1-the-atrocity-archives.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/14150.The_Jennifer_Morgue"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/2-the-jennifer-morgue.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7149287-the-fuller-memorandum"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/3-the-fuller-memorandum.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12393566-the-apocalypse-codex"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/4-the-apocalypse-codex.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18211295-the-rhesus-chart"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/5-the-rhesus-chart.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23154785-the-annihilation-score"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/6-the-annihilation-score.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Next up on my <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/50764-laundry-files">The Laundry Files</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/8794.Charles_Stross">Charles Stross</a>. Even though this wasn't originally on my list, I ended up just reading this rather than reading two series at once. So it goes.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Basic premise: Cthulhian beasties live at the bottom of fractals. Higher mathematics is roughly equivalent to magic. Computers make math/magic far easier to perform.</p>
<p>It's a really cool premise and I'm glad that the series was recommended to me. I've greatly enjoyed following the exploits of Bob, computer programmer turned computational demonologist turned necromancer and his wife Mo: combat violinist.</p>
<p>Fair warning though: Stross takes tropes (such as computer programming, spy stuff, or the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_(software development)">scrum method</a>) and turns them up to 11. From time to time, the terminology gets a bit annoying (especially if you're not as familiar with the various fields he's writing about), but personally, I love it.</p>
<p>Now, the same as <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama">Rama</a>, my individual reviews as I read each book:</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/101869.The_Atrocity_Archives"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/1-the-atrocity-archives.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>That... was intense.</p>
<p>To really get the most out of this book, I think you'd have to have a certain combination of things in your head: a knowledge of a lot of the more esoteric bits of computer science theory, physics, pop culture, and cosmic horrors. Pretty much right up my alley. Even then, I will admit to having no idea exactly where he was going with a few of those.</p>
<p>It's entirely possible that you'll still like it, even without the same base knowledge. It's still a quick enough read, with enough action to keep you turning the page, even if some of the technical info dumps are probably going to get skipped.</p>
<p>The last bit spent in the other world was fascinating. From a purely academic / world building standpoint, I would love to be able to see how such an alternate universe would deal with the sun going out and the air seeping away. How long would people survive? How would they deal with the beastie making it all happen?</p>
<p>After this, I am definitely going to read the rest of the Laundry Files.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/14150.The_Jennifer_Morgue"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/2-the-jennifer-morgue.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>This is an excellent follow up to The Atrocity Archives.</p>
<p>On the plus side, Stross managed to tone down the technobabble from ridiculous to only mildly over the top. There's still more than enough references to enjoy and enough neat world building on the (non Euclidean) edges between technology and demonology, but it's not quite hitting you over the head like the first one did.</p>
<p>On the other hand, what he gave up in technobabble, he replaced with spybabble. There are are strong hints of spy novel trappings all over the book. Let's just say though, they are there for a good reason.</p>
<p>One neat addition to this book (although I don't know if she'll be back) is the character of Ramona Random. (view spoiler) (which leads to some more distinctly R rated scenes than the first book had), but I thought she was a really interesting character. Despite--or perhaps because of--her rather problematic backstory, I really started to root for her throughout the book.</p>
<p>Also Mo. She's something of a badass now, taking on the bigwigs both in the Laundry and in the real world. Her violin is an especially interesting bit of world building. I especially love her part towards the end even if I'll admit that I didn't see the twist coming as soon as I could have. I do hope they do more with her in the latter books.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7149287-the-fuller-memorandum"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/3-the-fuller-memorandum.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>(Take 2, the internet ate my first review)</p>
<p>This is another solid entry in the Laundry Files and perhaps my favorite yet. We're really starting to get into some of the more horrific corners of the world. In particular, we learn a bit more about Mo's violin; we get another glimpse into a far flung world (view spoiler); and more about Angleton than I bet Bob ever wanted to know (and I really is explored more in the next books).</p>
<p>On the down side, Bob and Mo continue to have to do some fairly terrible things. There's some fallout from that in this book, but I feel like they just sort of skate by it without really dealing with what's going on. That's either going to come up in a later book or it's going to continue to get weirder when it doesn't.</p>
<p>The writing still pulls you along kicking and screaming. From the halfway point on, and in particular the ending, I couldn't put it down. There are more odd first/third person switches (Bob speaks in first person, everyone else is third person) and in particular a few chapters where I assume the intention is to hide exactly who is speaking. All together, it requires a bit more mental bandwidth to read than the previous two, but it's still worth it.</p>
<p>Looking forward, there are still two novels with Bob as the main character. There are a few things that I really want to see. Fingers crossed.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12393566-the-apocalypse-codex"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/4-the-apocalypse-codex.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>The first chunk of this book was a little bit weak, in particularly the introduction of the new character Ms. Hazard. She represents a different style to the magic in this universe, which is interesting, but she just seems too good at her job. In the same manner as Superman, the more powerful someone becomes, the harder it is to make them interesting.</p>
<p>That does get better in the later half of the book, especially in the climax. I'm still not sure what to think about the mixed first/third person writing style, but it is interesting to see some of the scenes from two very different points of view. I miss Mo though.</p>
<p>So far as world building goes, Stross continues to build out the more interesting parts of the world, building towards an eventual apocalypse (or at least rather bad day). The visuals of the Sleeper and the Pyramid are still some of my favorite parts of these books, especially the idea that the wall from the previous books is designed to keep people out, not in. I hadn't gotten that impression before.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18211295-the-rhesus-chart"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/5-the-rhesus-chart.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Vampires don't exist.</p>
<p>Or at least that's what everyone in the Laundry believes. Turns out... there's a good reason for that.</p>
<p>From the perspective of someone in software development, the maddening extent at which the Scrum operates is amusing and all too close to home. After twisting first computer science and spy stuff into this world, it was neat to see the new topic.</p>
<p>My one real complaint with this book is that I think it's out of order. It's significantly smaller in scope than the previous two books where I was hoping for even more escalation towards CASE NIGHTMARE GREEN, rather than something somewhat more down to home. Although on the other hand, a few of the events in this book need the previous books to make sense. Still it's weird.</p>
<p>Now, sadly, I've finished the Bob focused Laundry Files novels released to date. So it goes. I look forward to the next.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23154785-the-annihilation-score"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/laundry-files/6-the-annihilation-score.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>The Annihilation Score takes a bit of a different take from the previous five books, shifting the viewpoint from the previous hero* Bob to his wife Mo.</p>
<p>Previously, Mo had been one of my favorite characters in the series. She's just mysterious enough that she's interesting, coming in to save the day with a truly terrifying violin. Unfortunately, the more I know about her, the less I care.</p>
<p>The basic idea is interesting enough. Basically, as the world careens towards madness, magic is becoming more prevalent. But people don't believe in magic anymore, they believe in superheroes. One thing leads to another and Mo ends up leading a mostly publicly known super-hero task force. Much as The Rhesus Chart, despite the incoming danger, this feels like a de-escalation from the first four books.</p>
<p>One problem that annoyed me throughout the book was the relationship between Bob and Mo. I get it, they've been through Hell (literally) and they're each dealing with their own demons (again, literally), but I don't really understand their reactions to it. It feels more like Stross needed to get Bob out of the picture. So it goes.</p>
<p>Overall, I miss Bob. I miss Mo as a secondary character. I still enjoyed this more than enough to continue the series when the next comes out.</p>
<p>* For some definitions of hero.</p>
<hr />
<p>Amusingly, I haven't actually read that many ongoing series this year. If/when the next book comes out, I'll probably update this post.</p>
<p>Up next (for real this time): <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/337048.The_Engines_of_God">The Engines of God</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/73812.Jack_McDevitt">Jack McDevitt</a>. Onwards!</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Rama</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama" /><id>urn:uuid:c1c3658d-eaa4-7e51-eefd-9ef913d82666</id><updated>2015-06-21T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112537.Rendezvous_with_Rama"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/1-rendezvous-with-rama.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112520.Rama_II"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/2-rama-ii.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112518.The_Garden_of_Rama"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/3-the-garden-of-rama.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112517.Rama_Revealed"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/4-rama-revealed.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/49121-rama">Rama</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/7779.Arthur_C_Clarke">Arthur C. Clarke</a> and <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/65129.Gentry_Lee">Gentry Lee</a>.</p>
<p>I'm going to try something a little different this time. On previous series, I found it hard to write a blog post after reading several books back to back, I've been reviewing each book individual <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/8261480-jp">on Goodreads</a> as I've read it. I have a short summary for the entire series, followed by the individual books. We'll see how it goes.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112537.Rendezvous_with_Rama"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/1-rendezvous-with-rama.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112520.Rama_II"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/2-rama-ii.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112518.The_Garden_of_Rama"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/3-the-garden-of-rama.jpg" /></a> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112517.Rama_Revealed"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/4-rama-revealed.jpg" /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/49121-rama">Rama</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/7779.Arthur_C_Clarke">Arthur C. Clarke</a> and <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/65129.Gentry_Lee">Gentry Lee</a>.</p>
<p>I'm going to try something a little different this time. On previous series, I found it hard to write a blog post after reading several books back to back, I've been reviewing each book individual <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/8261480-jp">on Goodreads</a> as I've read it. I have a short summary for the entire series, followed by the individual books. We'll see how it goes.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Overall, I like the first book (the only by only <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/7779.Arthur_C_Clarke">Arthur C. Clarke</a>, the rest were all co-authored by<span class="footnote"><sup><a href="#footnote-1">[1]</a></sup></span> <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/65129.Gentry_Lee">Gentry Lee</a>). It's the kind of science fiction driven not particularly by plot or character, but rather by discovery and exploration. It's not always done well, but in this case I particularly enjoyed it. Conversely though, the other three in the series have much more focus on character conflict and to a lesser extent (but more than Rama) a central plot.</p>
<p>That change in style really turned me off the second book in the series, to the extent that I almost didn't finish the series. I'm glad I did though. Each of the sequels (in particularly the first part of #2 and most of #4) has some interesting ideas and solid extensions of Clarke's original world.</p>
<p>If you're into more interested in the science part of science fiction, you could do far worse than Rama. If, on the other hand, you want a story with more depth to the characters and plots, give Rama II a chance (although just keep in mind that Rama and Rama II are fairly different). If you are a completionist, the last book is actually pretty good and does a reasonably good job of tying up a lot of loose ends from the previous books.</p>
<p>Now, the individual reviews. Warning, there will be (usually minor) spoilers!</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112537.Rendezvous_with_Rama"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/1-rendezvous-with-rama.jpg" /></a></p>
<h3>Rama</h3>
<p>It's been a little while since I've read much science fiction, particularly any of the sort that Clarke is known for. Forget strong plot or characters and focus entirely around the big idea: In this case, the starship Rama is plenty large.</p>
<p>It starts off quickly, only a few chapters before you're on the ship. From there, you have situation after situation, describing how interesting the world that Clarke has built is and how the explorers react to it. The lack of a more specific antagonist becomes more of a problem towards then end, in that the book just sort of ends. There are various problems throughout the book, but no sense of building. I'm still not entirely sure how much I like this style.</p>
<p>Overall though, I think it's a cool world and I want to know more. Given that the sequels were written many years later and co-written by an author with a somewhat different style (based on the forward in Rama II), it will be interesting to see how different they are.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112520.Rama_II"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/2-rama-ii.jpg" /></a></p>
<h3>Rama II</h3>
<p>This book feels rather different from Rendezvous with Rama.</p>
<p>For the first half, I wasn't sure that I actually liked the difference. Rather than the almost sterile science fiction that Clarke is better known for, the sequel deals a lot more with characters, drama, and to some extent matters of faith. It's especially interesting in how long it takes them to even get to Rama, especially compared to the first book.</p>
<p>Through the next quarter though, it really started picking up. I started to actually care about the characters and couldn't put it down. The feel of the ship, especially with some of the new findings, is just different enough that I wanted to know more.</p>
<p>At first, I wasn't sure that I was going to read the other two sequels. After this, I'm not sure how I couldn't.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112518.The_Garden_of_Rama"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/3-the-garden-of-rama.jpg" /></a></p>
<h3>The Garden of Rama</h3>
<p>Like Rama #2, I went back and forth while reading this one on if I was actually enjoying it or if I would finish it at all. In the end, I did finish it and I think I'll even start the last one mostly out of a sense of completionism.</p>
<p>Essentially, there are five sections:</p>
<p>In the first, the three explorers from Rama II are leaving the solar system at high speeds. The parts where they are exploring the ship and learning how to live with the local 3D printer and interacting with other alien species is neat. The part where they decide that two men and a woman are enough to start a colony... That's just a little weird. I missed the first book, where the science and sense of exploration was the core of the story.</p>
<p>In the second, they get to a sort of routing section and finally meet an alien intelligence (even if it's still a robot). They (and by extension, we) get some neat answers. I liked this section for precisely the same reason I didn't like the first section: it's about exploring the world of Rama.</p>
<p>In the third, they go back to Earth, both in the context of the story and for a few scenes. They are all new characters and I cannot figure out why I care about any of them. Then they're sent off to a colony on Mars, except... surprise, they're actually going to make a new colony on the rebuilt Rama II. This is fine, but I feel like it could have been shortened.</p>
<p>In the fourth, the colony grows and thrives. Or not. Turns out people are people and people are terrible. Really, this whole section was depressing and not really what I was hoping to see in this book. I liked the smaller scales of the first 2.5 books. This not so much. Especially since it all ends up with exactly the sort of power struggle and corruption that I both see as entirely too plausible and hope isn't actually inevitable in such situations.</p>
<p>Finally, there's a big jump in the last ten percent or so where Robert goes to meet with the avian colony from the previous books. Suffice it to say, they have a strange lifecycle that we'd previously , which would have been much more interesting had Orson Scott Card not done it ~4 years earlier in Speaker for the Dead. It is exactly the sort of thing I wanted though, I just wish it had more relation to the rest of the story and had more than 10% of the pages. This is why I'm reading the 4th book, hoping there will be more of this.</p>
<hr />
<p><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/112517.Rama_Revealed"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama/4-rama-revealed.jpg" /></a></p>
<h3>Rama Revealed</h3>
<p>In my opinion, this was by far the best of the sequels.</p>
<p>They start by doing exactly what I wanted out of the middle two books: getting away from the human settlement and into a situation where they are learning and experiencing something strange. In this case, they go to live among the octospiders, an intelligent civilization highly skilled in genetics and biological science who are completely deaf and only speak in color. It's a fascinating and nicely thought out situation and I did like it.</p>
<p>Even when, halfway through the book, the focus shifts back partially to the rest of the human colony in Rama, it still maintains a tight focus, with the bigger scale events going on behind the scenes. There was still a particular feel of exploring how different societies deal with issues (such as war: the octospiders view all war as terrible, not just certain kinds).</p>
<p>The final section, when the return to another Node felt a little strange. Either because it was rushed or because it felt sort of artificial. I didn't particularly mind though, since it still was working out echoes of events from all of the previous books and acted as a sufficient capstone to the series. I did think it was nice that Michael and Simone make another appearance, even if the latter replied her mother's odd fixation with a two person continuation of the species.</p>
<p>At the very end, the book veers somewhat towards a philosophical / religions tangent, which felt a little odd (the Ramas are essentially God) but still thought provoking.</p>
<p>Overall, I was pleasantly surprised by this book. If you made it through the middle two books, you should probably read this one as well.</p>
<hr />
<p>Side note: I didn't finish Whitechapel Gods (which was actually next on my original <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/01/2015-reading-list">2015 Reading List</a>) since, after 20%, I just really wasn't getting into it. There are some really interesting ideas (a steampunkification disease for example), but it was hard to get a grasp on exactly what was going on. So it goes.</p>
<p>Overall, that 47 of 100 books for the year, exactly on schedule. Next up: <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/337048.The_Engines_of_God">The Engines of God</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/73812.Jack_McDevitt">Jack McDevitt</a>. At the same time, I'm also reading <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/101869.The_Atrocity_Archives">The Laundry Files</a> by <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/8794.Charles_Stross">Charles Stross</a> on a one chapter a day email list.</p>]]></content></entry></feed>