<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MCU Phase 2 on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-phase-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MCU Phase 2 on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-phase-2/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Avengers: Age of Ultron</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</guid>
      <description>Hawkeye: The city is flying and we&amp;rsquo;re fighting an army of robots. And I have a bow and arrow. Nothing makes sense.
 Age of Ultron is an odd movie. From the perspective of a summer blockbuster/action movie, it&amp;rsquo;s solid. The opening action scene is wonderfully avengerful, there are all manner of awesome fights (the Hulk versus Iron Man fight and the final battle come to mind), and we get a few new characters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guardians of the Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>I had forgotten just how fun Guardians of the Galaxy is. Back when I first reviewed it in 2014, it surprised me with how different it was and just how much it opened up the Marvel Universe. Well, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen some pretty crazy things since then (Thor Ragnarok springs to mind), but it&amp;rsquo;s still a pretty crazy movie. I mean, come on. It&amp;rsquo;s a man obsessed with classic rock, a badass green woman assassin, an overly literal shirtless wrestler, a cybernetically enhanced racoon, and a speaking tree 1 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Captain America: The Winter Soldier</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/27/captain-america-the-winter-soldier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/27/captain-america-the-winter-soldier/</guid>
      <description>From one of the weakest MCU movies to one of the strongest. I loved the first solo entry of Captain American and the second is even better. Much like last time, I very much enjoyed this movie.
It&amp;rsquo;s a solid contrast against the first Captain America (blind optimistic patriotism versus a darker world, where even your friends&amp;hellip; might not be). It&amp;rsquo;s made all the better having already seen the future of Sam and Bucky/The Winter Soldier now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thor: The Dark World</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/</guid>
      <description>One problem that comic book universes in general and the MCU in specific have always had is that of scale. How in the world do you have a man in a suit, a literal &amp;lsquo;god&amp;rsquo;, a rage monster, a super soldier, and a couple &amp;hellip; regular people ever interact on the same scale? For the most part, it&amp;rsquo;s hand waved away. Everyone is paired up with an opponent of roughly the same power level and we move on with our lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iron Man 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/iron-man-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/iron-man-3/</guid>
      <description>For some reason, I Iron Man 3 as a fairly week entry, but looking back to when I last watched it in theaters&amp;hellip; I actually liked it about as much then I do now.
On one hand, I really do still think they absolutely nailed Robert Downey Jr. as Iron man. He can do both funny and broken pretty well and has more than a few chances for each this time around.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
