<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Daevabad Trilogy on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-daevabad-trilogy/</link><description>Recent content in The Daevabad Trilogy on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-daevabad-trilogy/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The City of Brass</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/07/05/the-city-of-brass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/07/05/the-city-of-brass/</guid><description>&lt;p>18th Century Cairo. Street living, mixed with all manner of quasi magical cons (palm readings, faking healings). And then &amp;hellip; one accidental summoning later and you&amp;rsquo;re off swept into the magical world of childhood stories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world building is really interesting. You get a touch of the Arabic world mixed with a straight up Arabic inspired fantasy world full of djinn in all manner of shapes and sizes&amp;hellip; even at the end of the story, I&amp;rsquo;m not actually 100% sure what all the differences are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I ever quite got around to liking Nahri. I was rooting for her before she took off, but I&amp;rsquo;m not thrilled where she ended up.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You&amp;rsquo;re some kind of thief, then?&amp;quot;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;That a very narrow-minded way of looking at it. I prefer to think of myself as a merchant of delicate tasks.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Ali and Dara though, I quite like the both of them&amp;ndash;surprisingly for roughly the same reasons. They are trying to do the &amp;lsquo;right thing&amp;rsquo;, just with rather opposing ways of going about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“To keep walking a path between loyalty to your family and loyalty to what you know is right. One of these days, you’re going to have to make a choice.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the second book. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>