<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mark Millar on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/mark-millar/</link><description>Recent content in Mark Millar on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/mark-millar/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ultimate Comics Avengers Vs. New Ultimates: Death of Spider-man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/13/ultimate-comics-avengers-vs.-new-ultimates-death-of-spider-man/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/13/ultimate-comics-avengers-vs.-new-ultimates-death-of-spider-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Danvers and the Ultimates vs Fury and the Avengers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-avengers-v-ultimates-textbundle-ac3741.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man that’s a mess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth the read. They’re finally hitting their stride on more Ultimate Universe titles than Spider-Man. Which I suppose they had better be…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Avengers, Vol. 3: Blade vs. The Avengers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/08/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-3-blade-vs.-the-avengers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/08/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-3-blade-vs.-the-avengers/</guid><description>&lt;p>You’ve heard of Marvel Zombies? Well if that wasn’t terrifying enough… what about Marvel Vampires!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s actually a really neat story. Blade shows up, so vampires are real. Only this time around, they’ve figured out that turning Super Vampires might just be their big shot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neat idea. Solid execution. A few more deaths. Marvel Ultimate yo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By far my favorite Ultimate Avengers so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Avengers, Vol. 2: Crime and Punishment</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/28/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-2-crime-and-punishment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/28/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-2-crime-and-punishment/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the Ultimates universe, the Avengers are the team that takes the dirty jobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like, apparently, teaming up with the Punisher (temporarily) and a proto Hulk gang boss (not sure why) against Ghost Rider?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s certainly a thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s the kind of story where no one wins and I’m not really sure the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Avengers, Vol. 1: Next Generation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/27/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-1-next-generation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/27/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-1-next-generation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Captain American’s back. With a bit of unexpected past come to haunt him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we need a new team to bring him in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introducing: the Avengers! This time around the BlackOps version of the Ultimates. And &lt;strong>oh&lt;/strong> that’s a team. Hawkeye, a new drugged up bug girl, a new Widow, War Machine (transformers style), Nerd-Hulk (seriously), and another Stark—with issues all his own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can’t possibly go well…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimates 2, Volume 2: Grand Theft America</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/26/the-ultimates-2-volume-2-grand-theft-america/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/26/the-ultimates-2-volume-2-grand-theft-america/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oy. An awful lot happens in this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a traitor in the Ultimates. Relationship issues abound (both Cap/Wasp and Iron Man/Black Widow). Death. Destruction. Mayhem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, otherworldly invsions!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s way too much for a single volume, but man does it hit hard. The only real question(s) I have are&amp;hellip; where in the world do you go after something like this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth a read, especially after the build up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Annuals, Volume 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/ultimate-annuals-volume-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/ultimate-annuals-volume-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>One issue from each of the current main series. A combination of cute and not great, all on the too short end. Spider-Man was by far the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not sure what the point was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimates 2, Volume 1: Gods and Monsters</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/the-ultimates-2-volume-1-gods-and-monsters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/the-ultimates-2-volume-1-gods-and-monsters/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that’s good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, it comes out that Hulk is still around. After murdering hundreds. And now Thor is off the team (by choice) and it’s less clear than ever if he’s Thor—or a meta human with some serious psychiatric issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love seeing the relationships in the series. Cap and Janet are great—I’m enjoying the slightly more unhinged / human Cap. Pym and Banner as science Bros with issues. Iron Man and Black Widow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of it great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More of this please.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Fantastic Four, Volume 6: Frightful</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/13/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-6-frightful/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/13/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-6-frightful/</guid><description>&lt;p>Time travel! That never goes well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Zombies! Also not great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lovecraftian chest busters! Now you’re just making things up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot to put in one volume one again, but perhaps my favorite Fantastic Four thus far. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Fantastic Four, Volume 5: Crossover</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/10/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-5-crossover/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/10/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-5-crossover/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the mess of the last volume, it’s time to… turn up the wacky even more?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time travel, parallel universes, super zombies, and Atlantis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is so much to fit into a single volume. No idea what will stick, but any one of those could carry a dozen volumes if not a series of their own… and they just keep doing it. Issue after issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Slow down!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The zombie plague was pretty neat, not going to lie. I wonder if we’ll see more of that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 6: Return of the King</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/ultimate-x-men-vol.-6-return-of-the-king/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/ultimate-x-men-vol.-6-return-of-the-king/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wherein we get this universe’s history. How the a Professor and Magneto started out to build a mutant utopia, how some minor* differences in option came between them, and how Xavier ended up in a wheelchair.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a nice longer story and I really do dig the conflict between the Professor and Magneto. There are also some really interesting ideas buried within the action. Ends justifying the means. The cost(s) of rehabilitation or even imprisonment of a super powered prisoner. What it means to be human.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A solid story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 5: Ultimate War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/25/ultimate-x-men-vol.-5-ultimate-war/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/25/ultimate-x-men-vol.-5-ultimate-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>Magneto is back and &lt;strong>mad&lt;/strong>. The Brotherhood vs the Ultimates! The X-Men are nowhere to be found. At least not ent S.H.I.E.L.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Probably for the best, given the various infighting and differences of opinion in each and every one of these groups. They really do their best to constantly shake up teams in comics, don’t they.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I never really had reason to consider before… you know what Captain America’s shield, Thor’s hammer, and Iron Man’s armor have in common?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They’re all made of metal…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately for all the promises, surprisingly little actually happens. It will be interesting to see what’s next… but something more now would have been nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 4: Hellfire and Brimstone</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/22/ultimate-x-men-vol.-4-hellfire-and-brimstone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/22/ultimate-x-men-vol.-4-hellfire-and-brimstone/</guid><description>&lt;p>All the fallout and barely time to process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now Jean is having hallucinations and Beast’s new flame is digging for secrets…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quite a ride, setting up all sorts of what’s next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, sudden art shifts yo. I like the new one. Don&amp;rsquo;t think that will ever stop being surprising.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimates, Volume 2: Homeland Security</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/16/the-ultimates-volume-2-homeland-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/16/the-ultimates-volume-2-homeland-security/</guid><description>&lt;p>The one where we process the fallout from the first volume. Hulk on a murderous rampage. Hank Pym’s domestic abuse. Hard topics and certainly worthy of discussion…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just kidding. Invasion of the shape shifting Nazi aliens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As one does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s another intense story line and maybe actually shaking up a few things. I really am curious how they’ll continue to deal with Banner and Pym. Slowly I expect. But that works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also: The fact that in this continuity, Thor is thought crazy is thoroughly amusing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimates, Volume 1: Super-Human</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/15/the-ultimates-volume-1-super-human/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/15/the-ultimates-volume-1-super-human/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let’s get the team together! Iron Man! Bruce Banner! Thor? Nah. The Pyms!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/the-ultimates-v1-ef3bba.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Captain America!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now… we just need someone to fight…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s a solid opener. Enough with the meet and greet to know who is who (even if it does rely somewhat on previous superhero knowledge) and then let them fight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m looking forward to seeing where else they go from here!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Side note: holy crap that last issue they threw in there—that’s really setting us up for some interesting story lines…)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 3: World Tour</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-3-world-tour/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-3-world-tour/</guid><description>&lt;p>First off, Gambit. Hard to understand with a heart of gold. Then a quick look at what’s the Professor actually did to Magneto. Here’s a hint: actually killing him might have been kinder in the long run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then finally, we’re on to the World Tour! It’s all about proving that mutants do good for the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What could possibly go wrong…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really do fall on the ‘Professor is being an overly pacifist idiot’ side of times things. It’ll be interesting to see what’s next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, these plots really could use some more time to breath. In the span of a single volume, we&amp;rsquo;re introduced to the idea of &lt;span class="spoiler">Professor X having a wife and child&lt;/span>
to said &lt;span class="spoiler">child trying to kill everything&lt;/span>
to &lt;span class="spoiler">their eventual defeat (for now? it's unclear)&lt;/span>
. Such is comics life?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 2: Return to Weapon X</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-2-return-to-weapon-x/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-2-return-to-weapon-x/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rogue. Juggernaut. Sabertooth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-x-men-v2-f2525e.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s another crazy action packed volume. I’m amazed at how much they’re fitting into these. Almost as amazed at how any of them are supposed to fit into those outfits…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, Weapon X, S.H.I.E.L.D., what’s left of the Brotherhood, and a few new friends all together. Learning just what lines they’ll each be willing to cross…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 1: The Tomorrow People</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-x-men-vol.-1-the-tomorrow-people/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-x-men-vol.-1-the-tomorrow-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting the team together, sleeper agent Wolverine, love triangles, betrayal, mass murder, and the bluening of Beast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is an awful lot to fit into a single volume…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The philosophical differences between Professor X and his X-Men versus Magneto and his Brotherhood is quite often at the core of these stories, so it’s no surprise to see it here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only question is… what comes next?!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>