<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rosaria Munda on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/31/rosaria-munda/</link><description>Recent content in Rosaria Munda on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/31/rosaria-munda/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Furysong</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/31/furysong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/31/furysong/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When a government ceases to protect its people, it becomes necessary to overthrow it.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s how you end a trilogy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Revolution on revolution, coup on coup. Love and hate, betrayal and double/triple/who even knows crossing. And death. Oh the deaths.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, we get a conclusion (for now) of the revolution we were first introduced to in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/30/fireborne/">Fireborne&lt;/a>. And the government in exile of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/flamefall/">Flamefall&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characters are still a large driving factor here, especially (but not only!) Annie and Lee. We finally get an answer to the whole &amp;lsquo;will they / won&amp;rsquo;t they&amp;rsquo; which I expect we all saw coming, but it&amp;rsquo;s all in &lt;em>how&lt;/em> it happened&amp;hellip; and what came next. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of sweet here&amp;ndash;and more than a helpful of bittersweet as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that Griff is a fascinating point here. He got everything he wanted in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/flamefall/">Flamefall&lt;/a> and a few things that he couldn&amp;rsquo;t bear. So for half the book, he&amp;rsquo;s the hero&amp;ndash;and drowning himself in his sorrows. But add in Delo as an actual point of view this time around? A plot well worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the antagonists side, we have Ixion. Oh we love to hate them. Being the last book, they have to fall, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a long painful trip to get there. The (re)introduction of the Bassileans, their princess, and their gargantuan dragon. I think that&amp;rsquo;s a sort of difference in dragon breeds and hints at a larger world that I could do with more of. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to realize that for all the chaos we&amp;rsquo;ve been through with these books, they&amp;rsquo;re only a tiny part of the larger world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then there&amp;rsquo;s Power. He is very much the most complicated character in these books, thoroughly in the morally gray category. Oh Power.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I loved these books. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to see what else &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/31/rosaria-munda/">Rosaria Munda&lt;/a> has done! Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I just wanted it to be in writing, somewhere. I wanted it to be in writing that it was you. For me. It&amp;rsquo;s always been you.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Flamefall</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/flamefall/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/flamefall/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Revenge doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to begin with a knife. It can begin with a well-delivered speech.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The cracks were already showing in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/30/fireborne/">Fireborne&lt;/a>. There may have been a Revolution, dealing away with the Dragonlords of old&amp;hellip; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean that whatever comes next is going to be any better. So much so that you start to see those with the feeling that &amp;lsquo;maybe things weren&amp;rsquo;t so bad under the Dragonlords after all&amp;rsquo;. And it just so happens that there&amp;rsquo;s more than one cousin in exile&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really enjoy seeing Annie come into her own in this book, taking her place in charge of the dragon riders after Lee stepped down. And then dealing with all that comes from having to make all those hard decisions at the top. Dealing with Lee and the government and the other riders and her own past. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Lee, actually coming out into the open&amp;ndash;while dealing with the trauma at the end of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/30/fireborne/">Fireborne&lt;/a>. Complicated that. I kept expecting him to snap&amp;ndash;and hoping that he won&amp;rsquo;t, that he &lt;em>will actually be better&lt;/em>. I&amp;rsquo;m rooting for you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then we have newcomer Griff. Another peasant dragon rider from a &lt;em>very&lt;/em> different set of circumstances. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to introduce a new main character in the second book, but I really do think it was done well. Man, the New Pythians are &lt;em>twisted&lt;/em>, almost comically evil. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make them any less dangerous to those in teh story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy there&amp;rsquo;s just so much in this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tonight I&amp;rsquo;m full of confidence, like a dragon riding a gale. I am done letting these tendrils of shame tie me to the ground. No shadow is so great that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t shrink when viewed from the air.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see how it ends from here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fireborne</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/30/fireborne/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/30/fireborne/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dragons!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;are actually probably the weakest part of the book. We&amp;rsquo;ll get back to that.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>They watch us kneel, they see the back of our heads, and they think we&amp;rsquo;ve given in. They don&amp;rsquo;t realize you can think from your knees just as well as from your feet.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What we have here is an epic fantasy world, full of the aforementioned dragons and strife and war&amp;hellip; but for a change, this world is set in the near aftermath of the collapse of the old regime and the rise of the good guys. In theory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everyone gets a chance at education. Even commoners&amp;ndash;even orphans of the revolution&amp;ndash;can apply to be trained as dragon riders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From there, we get the first half of the book&amp;ndash;a straight up magic school style training montage. It feels awfully YA, in the genre of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/01/the-hunger-games/">The Hunger Games&lt;/a> / &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/03/29/divergent/">Divergent&lt;/a> / &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/20/harry-potter/">Harry Potter&lt;/a>, up to and including a school tournament to decide the &amp;lsquo;best dragonrider&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What really makes the book shine to me is that initial setting&amp;ndash;the idea that we&amp;rsquo;re shortly after a revolution, building something new. And the entirely too real chance that the anything new&amp;hellip; might be just as bad as what came before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now&amp;hellip; the dragons. Despite the fact that all of our main characters have a dragon and they&amp;rsquo;re present throughout the series&amp;ndash;they never seem to really have any personality or presence of their own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even now, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could honestly tell you more than the subspecies of each dragon, and even then only barely. I like intelligent dragons (a la &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/31/temeraire/">Temeraire&lt;/a>) and &lt;em>love&lt;/em> books with more &lt;em>alien&lt;/em> dragons (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/the-rage-of-dragons/">The Rage of Dragons&lt;/a> shines here). These are almost more like cars or fighter jets than anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s really a bummer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I enjoyed the series. And the way things go towards the latter part of the book + the ending really make me curious where in the world it&amp;rsquo;s going from here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>