<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>T.J. Klune on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.j.-klune/</link><description>Recent content in T.J. Klune on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.j.-klune/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Under the Whispering Door</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/03/under-the-whispering-door/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/03/under-the-whispering-door/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first time you share tea, you are a stranger.&lt;br&gt;
The second time you share tea, you are an honored guest.&lt;br&gt;
The third time you share tea, you become family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So&amp;hellip; what do you call a slice of life story when the protagonist dies at the end of the first chapter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you do, &lt;em&gt;Under the Whispering Door&lt;/em&gt; is a delightful example thereof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wallace starts out a kind of terrible person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The machine had broken down, and though no one was infallible, Wallace needed to switch out the part for a new one. He’d worked too hard to let it fail now. Last year had been the most profitable in the firm’s history. This year was shaping up to be even better. No matter what condition the world was in, someone always needed to be sued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then he dies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The House in the Cerulean Sea</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/18/the-house-in-the-cerulean-sea/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/18/the-house-in-the-cerulean-sea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A gnome, a sprite, a wyvern, a green blob, a were-Pomeranian, and the Antichrist get sent to live in an orphanage on an island&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds like the setup for a rather strange joke, but instead the punchline is a delightful, amusing, and surprisingly touching story about actually taking the time to notice and perhaps care for someone a little bit different.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>