<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lightbringer on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/lightbringer/</link><description>Recent content in Lightbringer on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/lightbringer/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Blood Mirror</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/02/the-blood-mirror/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/02/the-blood-mirror/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Look at your mistakes long enough to learn from them, then put them behind you.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On one hand, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/02/the-blood-mirror/">The Blood Mirror&lt;/a> takes the storyline of the previous books and turns it up even more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Broken Eye</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/19/the-broken-eye/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/19/the-broken-eye/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Magic was useful for everything. It just killed you. You should always think of it first. Then you should decide if a little dram of death was worth it.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Just whoa. This book got big. We see a lot more about the world and more about the powers that exist beneath the surface. The world is weird and complicated and everything we thought we knew&amp;hellip; well, i9t&amp;rsquo;s mostly right. Just incomplete.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Blinding Knife</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/29/the-blinding-knife/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/29/the-blinding-knife/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Blinding Knife is what a sequel should be. It takes the action and magic that made &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/28/the-black-prism/">The Black Prism&lt;/a> good and made it better while toning down a lot of the exposition and over-characterization that made it a bit of a drag at times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, the magic system has a lot more depth than it did in the first book while at the same time not spending quite as much time hitting us over the head with terms we don&amp;rsquo;t quite understand yet. Even if I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily like some of the choices (like why you can&amp;rsquo;t draft green from white light by default), it&amp;rsquo;s still a well done system. Otherwise, the worldbuilding has gotten bigger. Magical trading cards. Seers. Old Gods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Black Prism</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/28/the-black-prism/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/28/the-black-prism/</guid><description>&lt;p>I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know that &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/28/the-black-prism/">The Black Prism&lt;/a> was a series until I&amp;rsquo;d finished &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brent-weeks/">Brent Weeks&lt;/a> other series ( &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/05/18/the-way-of-shadows/">The Way of Shadows&lt;/a> et al) and it came up in &amp;lsquo;related works&amp;rsquo;. Reading the summary, I almost wish I&amp;rsquo;d read them the other way around. Lightbringer seems like more of a traditional epic fantasy (albeit with an interesting magic system, see below) rather than the unrelenting grimdarkness that was The Night Angel books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that I&amp;rsquo;ve really been liking about this series thus far is the world building. In particular the magic system. The basic idea is that drafters (magic users) can take light of certain colors&amp;ndash;each person has different ranges&amp;ndash;and use those colors to do various things. Like you can make a napalm like substance out of red or a solid, smooth surface out of blue. On the down side, drafting too much of a color will eventually drive you mad&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. If I knew more about the actual physics of light, I imagine I&amp;rsquo;d be more annoyed at the technical details, but as it stands, I know just enough to think it&amp;rsquo;s a really cool idea.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>