<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ultimate X-Men on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/ultimate-x-men/</link><description>Recent content in Ultimate X-Men on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/ultimate-x-men/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 10: Cry Wolf</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/10/ultimate-x-men-vol.-10-cry-wolf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/10/ultimate-x-men-vol.-10-cry-wolf/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gambit’s back! With some new big bad backers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Always my factor X-Man growing up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good times, I hope they all stick around for a while. New and interesting stories!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 9: The Tempest</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/05/ultimate-x-men-vol.-9-the-tempest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/05/ultimate-x-men-vol.-9-the-tempest/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hank is gone. Time to mourn? Not nearly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A quick introduction to Mister Sinister… and perhaps someone even more sinister behind the curtains?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A decent story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 8: New Mutants</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/ultimate-x-men-vol.-8-new-mutants/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/ultimate-x-men-vol.-8-new-mutants/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-x-men-v8-fb5799.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things have been rough for the X-Men, what with the whole Magneto thing (again) and anti-Mutant feelings running high. So of course what do we need? More mutants!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Angel. Emma Frost. Dazzler. Alex Summers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s cool to see so many new (old) faces and shake up the status quo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll just have to see what’s next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nothing particularly special about this volume but also not terrible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 7: Blockbuster</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/28/ultimate-x-men-vol.-7-blockbuster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/28/ultimate-x-men-vol.-7-blockbuster/</guid><description>&lt;p>The one that starts digging into Logan’s issues. And oh does he have issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Best part:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-x-men-v7-c53993.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good part of the story is Spider-Man and Wolverine teaming up. That’s just wonderful. I really enjoy the contrast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-x-men-v7-fcbbf8.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Daredevil! Even if not much. Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like the longer stories that, while having some self contained parts, are really part of a larger story. In this case: who was Logan and where (when?) did he come from?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 6: Return of the King</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/ultimate-x-men-vol.-6-return-of-the-king/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/ultimate-x-men-vol.-6-return-of-the-king/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wherein we get this universe’s history. How the a Professor and Magneto started out to build a mutant utopia, how some minor* differences in option came between them, and how Xavier ended up in a wheelchair.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a nice longer story and I really do dig the conflict between the Professor and Magneto. There are also some really interesting ideas buried within the action. Ends justifying the means. The cost(s) of rehabilitation or even imprisonment of a super powered prisoner. What it means to be human.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A solid story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 5: Ultimate War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/25/ultimate-x-men-vol.-5-ultimate-war/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/25/ultimate-x-men-vol.-5-ultimate-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>Magneto is back and &lt;strong>mad&lt;/strong>. The Brotherhood vs the Ultimates! The X-Men are nowhere to be found. At least not ent S.H.I.E.L.D.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Probably for the best, given the various infighting and differences of opinion in each and every one of these groups. They really do their best to constantly shake up teams in comics, don’t they.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I never really had reason to consider before… you know what Captain America’s shield, Thor’s hammer, and Iron Man’s armor have in common?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They’re all made of metal…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately for all the promises, surprisingly little actually happens. It will be interesting to see what’s next… but something more now would have been nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 4: Hellfire and Brimstone</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/22/ultimate-x-men-vol.-4-hellfire-and-brimstone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/22/ultimate-x-men-vol.-4-hellfire-and-brimstone/</guid><description>&lt;p>All the fallout and barely time to process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now Jean is having hallucinations and Beast’s new flame is digging for secrets…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quite a ride, setting up all sorts of what’s next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, sudden art shifts yo. I like the new one. Don&amp;rsquo;t think that will ever stop being surprising.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimates, Volume 2: Homeland Security</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/16/the-ultimates-volume-2-homeland-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/16/the-ultimates-volume-2-homeland-security/</guid><description>&lt;p>The one where we process the fallout from the first volume. Hulk on a murderous rampage. Hank Pym’s domestic abuse. Hard topics and certainly worthy of discussion…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just kidding. Invasion of the shape shifting Nazi aliens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As one does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s another intense story line and maybe actually shaking up a few things. I really am curious how they’ll continue to deal with Banner and Pym. Slowly I expect. But that works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also: The fact that in this continuity, Thor is thought crazy is thoroughly amusing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 3: World Tour</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-3-world-tour/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-3-world-tour/</guid><description>&lt;p>First off, Gambit. Hard to understand with a heart of gold. Then a quick look at what’s the Professor actually did to Magneto. Here’s a hint: actually killing him might have been kinder in the long run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then finally, we’re on to the World Tour! It’s all about proving that mutants do good for the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What could possibly go wrong…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really do fall on the ‘Professor is being an overly pacifist idiot’ side of times things. It’ll be interesting to see what’s next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, these plots really could use some more time to breath. In the span of a single volume, we&amp;rsquo;re introduced to the idea of &lt;span class="spoiler">Professor X having a wife and child&lt;/span>
to said &lt;span class="spoiler">child trying to kill everything&lt;/span>
to &lt;span class="spoiler">their eventual defeat (for now? it's unclear)&lt;/span>
. Such is comics life?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 2: Return to Weapon X</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-2-return-to-weapon-x/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-2-return-to-weapon-x/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rogue. Juggernaut. Sabertooth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-x-men-v2-f2525e.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s another crazy action packed volume. I’m amazed at how much they’re fitting into these. Almost as amazed at how any of them are supposed to fit into those outfits…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, Weapon X, S.H.I.E.L.D., what’s left of the Brotherhood, and a few new friends all together. Learning just what lines they’ll each be willing to cross…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 1: The Tomorrow People</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-x-men-vol.-1-the-tomorrow-people/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-x-men-vol.-1-the-tomorrow-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting the team together, sleeper agent Wolverine, love triangles, betrayal, mass murder, and the bluening of Beast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is an awful lot to fit into a single volume…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The philosophical differences between Professor X and his X-Men versus Magneto and his Brotherhood is quite often at the core of these stories, so it’s no surprise to see it here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only question is… what comes next?!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>