<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Marvel 1602 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-1602/</link><description>Recent content in Marvel 1602 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-1602/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Marvel 1602: Witch Hunter Angela</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/20/marvel-1602-witch-hunter-angela/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/20/marvel-1602-witch-hunter-angela/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The last of the 1602 stories, so far as I know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A truly odd story of two women hunting. I … don’t actually know so they are in the original continuity. So I’m not sure what changes here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various panels making our clear that the characters are aware of our time and that they aren’t in it… is an odd choice. Related to the above perhaps?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The art changes style from part to part and some of it absolutely gorgeous in a haunting sort of way, other parts oddly surreal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I enjoyed it, if perhaps the least of this run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602: Spider-Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/20/marvel-1602-spider-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/20/marvel-1602-spider-man/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s straight up Spider-Man, 400 years ago. Octavius, Lizard, Goblin, Fisk. All the villains you’d expect in about to the ways you’d expect them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s enjoyable, but not exactly groundbreaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My one (strong dislike) is replacing Virginia Dare with Mary Jane Watsonne. So not necessary… a problem with comics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602: Fantastick Four</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/marvel-1602-fantastick-four/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/marvel-1602-fantastick-four/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Four of the Fantastick. A story I’m more or less familiar with, only from various movies rather than the comics. Here, they’re in the world created by time travel to 1602. Doom wants to travel beyond the edge of the world to heal his face and takes Shakespeare along for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting enough story. Weird to involve Shakespeare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602: New World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/18/marvel-1602-new-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/18/marvel-1602-new-world/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-1602/"&gt;Marvel 1602&lt;/a&gt; established a world where time travel managed to accidentally cause various heroes to be born around the year 1602, now in New World we see more fallout if that story. The 1602 Master Spider of course, but also Lord Iron, Master Jameson and his broadsheet, and, of course, the Hulk—who needs no puny time periodic appropriate name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like somewhat smaller a story than the original 1602 and more like we’re reading something that we’ve seen before, just with a new coat of paint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still fun though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/17/marvel-1602/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/17/marvel-1602/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sir Nicholas Fury, with his servant Peter Parquagh. Stephen Strange, master of medicines. A blind man jumping around in the night. Sister Wanda, with her red habit. Witchbreed. So many new takes on old friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh. And dinosaurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/marvel-1602-8f5230.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As things escalate, it turns out there may very well be a reason everything is out of time… as there always had to be in a comic book. It’s neat when you get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worth a read. It’s certainly an interesting ride.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>