<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2010 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/2010/</link><description>Recent content in 2010 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 23:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/2010/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/downton-abbey-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/downton-abbey-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Somehow I&amp;rsquo;m always surprised when a highly rated show is actually good. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From a modern, American, middle-class point of view, the idea of the early 1900s British Aristocracy is just so strange. They do next nothing (useful) and have an entire staff to support it. The entire estate could go to a cousin they&amp;rsquo;d never met and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing they can do about it &amp;hellip; is so strange.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s oddly charming?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Grantham&amp;rsquo;s are fascinating. Sybil seems good people, Edith is certainly going to figure out how to come into her own, Mary is spoiled and needlessly cruel&amp;ndash;but may be learning. Lord and Lady Grantham are fun, if somewhat alien&amp;ndash;and I do love watching Lord Grantham try and completely fail to wrangle three young adult daughters. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The shining jewel of the family Dame Maggie Smith&amp;rsquo;s Dowager Countess of Grantham. Oh she&amp;rsquo;s just wonderful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among the staff, you have a whole &amp;rsquo;nother level of politics. They&amp;rsquo;re all great and terrible (as they should be) and there are every bit as many problems and politics as there are among the &amp;lsquo;family&amp;rsquo;. Turns out people are people no matter how much money they have or do not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a crazy amount to fit into seven episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward&amp;hellip; to war!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iron Man 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/23/iron-man-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/23/iron-man-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I vaguely remember Iron Man 2 being a much weaker movie than the first Iron Man, but you know, it&amp;rsquo;s actually really good. The action is great, especially the fight scenes with the electro whips and between Iron Man and (not yet named) War Machine. Good stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, Don Cheadle is a great replacement as Rhodes; you can feel Robert Downey Jr. as Iron Man at the top of his game (with nothing to lose &lt;spoiler>because he&amp;rsquo;s dying&lt;/spoiler>); and I still think Paltrow makes a great Potts.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>