<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andi C. Buchanan on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/15/andi-c.-buchanan/</link><description>Recent content in Andi C. Buchanan on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/15/andi-c.-buchanan/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Weddings and Witchcraft</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/15/weddings-and-witchcraft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/15/weddings-and-witchcraft/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>gasp&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We actually get to cycle back to a previous main character?! And not one, but two of them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, Laurel and Marigold are getting married! Yay for them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Most of the story deals with the stress that comes with planning and dealing with an upcoming wedding&amp;ndash;totally get that&amp;ndash;along with a mysterious and magical saboteur&amp;ndash;that was a fun twist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re my favorites of this series&amp;rsquo; characters and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see some closure for them. I really feel books 1, 2, and 5 could have been made into a single novel, with an emphasis on the cozy on account of no &amp;lsquo;huge&amp;rsquo; big bads throughout the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, an enjoyable read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On to something bigger!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data and Divination</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/14/data-and-divination/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/14/data-and-divination/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another book, another point of view. This time a bit more distant in Jasmina (and Larch), witches who&amp;rsquo;ve managed to escape a cult-like witchy family (one a long time ago and the other just now, being the main point of the story).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see a bit more of the world that Buchanan is building and the idea of Divination applying to technology / computer searches is pretty fun. But like all of the books here, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>far&lt;/em> too short to actually get into anything. I want to see more of the family they escaped from. I want to see more of the fae (introduced and problem solved in &lt;em>literally&lt;/em> a paragraph this time).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps such a short form is not for me after all. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still a decent book and it was interesting to see it tie into the Laurel&amp;rsquo;s world&amp;ndash;and how different the two are&amp;ndash;eventually. Onward to the lastward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alpaca and Apparitions</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/05/alpaca-and-apparitions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/05/alpaca-and-apparitions/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pretty much the same vein as &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/03/succulents-and-spells/">Succulents and Spells&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/31/microscopes-and-magic/">Microscopes and Magic&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s quick, cute, and light on the action.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mostly, we get another point of view (Laurel&amp;rsquo;s cousin Mildred, the &amp;lsquo;fibre witch&amp;rsquo;). It was a bit jarring at first, I&amp;rsquo;m not always the best at similar names and really thought it was Marigold and I&amp;rsquo;d missed something big&amp;hellip; but no, it&amp;rsquo;s just a different character each time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characterization and plot remains cozy, with fun little experiments each time. This time, we have a much more rural life with &lt;em>alpacas&lt;/em>! And of course a new neighbor to date (&lt;span class="spoiler">gay and trans this time&lt;/span>
). And a mystery to solve&amp;hellip; that doesn&amp;rsquo;t end up mattering overmuch?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, they&amp;rsquo;re nice quick reads as a palette cleanser. I miss Laurel and Marigold (they show up for a bit, but it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t count). But we&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes from here!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Microscopes and Magic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/31/microscopes-and-magic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/31/microscopes-and-magic/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much more of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/03/succulents-and-spells/">Succulents and Spells&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s quick, doesn&amp;rsquo;t really go anywhere (huge), and is a fun little read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, I like seeing more of Marigold as the primary point of view. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird to swap, but I think I like her more than Laurel. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s because she&amp;rsquo;s just coming into the magical world?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the downside&amp;hellip; the (a?) big bad is maginanotech bugs. And there&amp;rsquo;s really no justification for nanotech just &lt;em>existing&lt;/em> in this world. I generally only like one real &amp;lsquo;give&amp;rsquo; to a story and this is a bit much. Especially when it could totally just be magical and that would be fine. Even magical bioengineering would be better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such is life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s cute and if you liked the first, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably like this. I&amp;rsquo;m curious what in the world is next&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Succulents and Spells</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/03/succulents-and-spells/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/03/succulents-and-spells/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Marigold took a deep breath. &amp;ldquo;My name is Marigold Ann Nightfield. I use she/her pronouns. I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD
candidate in biomedical science.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laurel offered her hand across the table, and Marigold took it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Laurel Windflower. She/her as well.&amp;rdquo; She didn’t mention the incomplete MA she&amp;rsquo;d been postponing, for one reason or another, for the past two years. &amp;ldquo;So, is your PhD in monster biology or something?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That was delightful. It&amp;rsquo;s a cozy urban fantasy, light and cute with just enough touches of something bigger and more dangerous out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth a read. And at a novella length 100 pages, it&amp;rsquo;s worth trying just to see if you like it. And if you do, there are a handful more to dig deeper! (I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>