<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jules Verne on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/jules-verne/</link><description>Recent content in Jules Verne on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/jules-verne/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Journey to the Center of the Earth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/11/journey-to-the-center-of-the-earth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/11/journey-to-the-center-of-the-earth/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We are of opinion that instead of letting books grow moldy behind an iron grating, far from the vulgar gaze, it is better to let them wear out by being read.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This year &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2024-book-bingo/">book bingo&lt;/a> has a &amp;lsquo;Underground&amp;rsquo; category&amp;ndash;and I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to actually go back and read more Verne. Seemed like a great chance to check out Journey to the Center of the Earth!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a quintessential Jules Verne adventure. A student and professor find an old manuscript purporting to describe a path to the very center of the Earth&amp;hellip; and off they go to Snæfellsjökull (Icelandic is such a lovely language) and down into the Earth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From that, it&amp;rsquo;s one adventure after another. Down caves, running out of food and water, nearly dying&amp;ndash;and all manner of completely scientifically improbable findings along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Science, my boy, is made up of mistakes, but they are mistakes which it is useful to make, because they lead little by little to the truth.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I think the biggest difficulty in this book is probably entirely tied up with the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s 160 years old. It&amp;rsquo;s just written in a very different style. People just &amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t talk like that. But it does make it feel amusingly old-timey, which I actually like. (I wonder how much of that is the translation?)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read. Going to have to read a few more of these!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>