<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My Father's Dragon on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/my-fathers-dragon/</link><description>Recent content in My Father's Dragon on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 02:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/my-fathers-dragon/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Dragons of Blueland</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/16/the-dragons-of-blueland/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/16/the-dragons-of-blueland/</guid><description>&lt;p>Elmer is finally home! And now Boris can go home as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only to immediately run into trouble (his family has been trapped!) and fly all the way back to pick up the one friend he has (Elmer. Duh. &amp;#x1f604;) and get the help he needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a weird premise, but a fun enough book. The mathematical problem solving (and oh so prescient packing) comes to a head here, but it&amp;rsquo;s just as fun as ever to read in the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the weakest of the bunch, but a decent end to the series.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Elmer and the Dragon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/16/elmer-and-the-dragon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/16/elmer-and-the-dragon/</guid><description>&lt;p>The somewhat sillier (who&amp;rsquo;d have thought it possible) sequel to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/my-fathers-dragon/">My Father’s Dragon&lt;/a>, wherein Elmer and Boris take an entire book to return home (and all sorts of strange things happen along the way).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s really the second half of the book (and if you read it as part of &lt;em>Three Tales of My Father&amp;rsquo;s Dragon&lt;/em> it fits better)&amp;ndash;and slightly weaker, especially without the first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing to love about both the first and this book is the weird obsession with &amp;lsquo;inventory tracking&amp;rsquo;. He picks 38 tangerines. Then eats 15. Then 11 more. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun way for kids who&amp;rsquo;s minds work that way to track things, do math, all the while looking for that &lt;em>mistake&lt;/em> they know must be there!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also a nice touch that we stick around with the new characters we meet a lot better this time. The entire book is about Elmer, Boris, and the canaries, rather than a new animal puzzle each chapter. I like it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Father's Dragon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/16/my-fathers-dragon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/16/my-fathers-dragon/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a cute story, good for children.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A story about the narrator&amp;rsquo;s father&amp;rsquo;s adventures, gone fantastic. There are talking animals and a dragon and it&amp;rsquo;s never really clear how much if any of this might have happened&amp;hellip; but in the end, does it matter?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s cute and teaches kids how to solve problems, make new friends, and rescue dragons. All lessons worth learning.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>