<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Christopher Nolan on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/christopher-nolan/</link><description>Recent content in Christopher Nolan on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/christopher-nolan/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Oppenheimer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/">Barbenheimer&lt;/a>!&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Oppenheimer: Albert? When I came to you with those calculations, we thought we might start a chain reaction that would destroy the entire world&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
Einstein: I remember it well. What of it?&lt;br>
Oppenheimer: I believe we did.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That is a long, dense film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s complicated and there are &lt;em>long&lt;/em> stretches with little going on by talking and setting. But&amp;hellip; man, is it thematic talking and setting?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s all about the story of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J.%20Robert%20Oppenheimer">J. Robert Oppenheimer&lt;/a>, the so called &amp;lsquo;father of the atomic bomb&amp;rsquo; and&amp;hellip; well, how he earned that title. I knew bits and pieces of the story, but having watched this, bits and pieces were apparently all I knew. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of amazing how many of the names I recognize from physics classes were involved in either the project or Oppenheimer&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was at times difficult to follow, there are a ton of jumps (mostly stylistically) and it makes me wander just how much of that was actually problems in Oppenheimer&amp;rsquo;s mind and how much was style. That&amp;rsquo;s not really clear, even by the end of the movie. I certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised though if he was having issues like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Einstein: When they&amp;rsquo;ve punished you enough, they&amp;rsquo;ll serve you salmon and potato salad, make speeches, give you a medal, and pat you in the back telling all is forgiven. Just remember, it won&amp;rsquo;t be for you&amp;hellip; it would be for them.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I think the cast was another impressive part of this film. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t speak to just how perfectly accurate it was, but I think Cillian Murphy was an excellent casting for Oppenheimer. He&amp;rsquo;s got just the right amount of strange charisma to really pull you into the film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matt Damon and Robert Downey Jr. were solid roles, enough to actually remind me why they&amp;rsquo;re considered solid actors&amp;ndash;and not just playing themselves as some do. Alden Ehrenreich I thought looked familiar, but had to look up where I&amp;rsquo;d seen him recently (Solo and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/17/beautiful-creatures/">Beautiful Creatures&lt;/a> (that&amp;rsquo;s been a while)). There are just a bunch of people I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in other things before&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, quite the solid movie. I think I learned something and enjoyed the process of doing something, which is something always worth saying. It&amp;rsquo;s long, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth a watch!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Personally, I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s any reason to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/">Barbenheimer&lt;/a> it though, although it is amusing.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last note:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Oppenheimer: Now I am become Death, the destroyer of worlds.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The first time he says it&amp;hellip; was surprising and kind of weird. I expect they were going with &amp;rsquo;everyone is waiting for him to say the line&amp;hellip; psyche!&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave it at that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tenet</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/06/tenet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/06/tenet/</guid><description>&lt;p>That &amp;hellip; is a summer blockbuster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an absolutely bonkers plot. In a nutshell, the future is at war with the present (somehow) and there is technology that can &amp;lsquo;invert&amp;rsquo; people and things so that they experience time backwards. How exactly that works and what exactly happens when you mess with the past/future is&amp;hellip; never entirely clear. But it certainly does make for some absolutely crazy action scenes where some things are going forward, some backward, people are in the same scene more than once and&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Man of Steel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/07/17/man-of-steel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2013 04:55:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/07/17/man-of-steel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dang.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I went to see Man of Steel mostly because I knew it&amp;rsquo;s on the way out of theaters. What I really want to see is Pacific Rim, but I feel like I have a few weeks for that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did. Man of Steel is well worth the price of admission and one of the few movies that is definitely worth seeing on a big screen. Just the sheer viseral impact of watching the Kryptonians toss each other into (and through) building after building, throwing about train engines as if they weighed nothing&amp;hellip; It felt a little surreal at times&amp;ndash;like that&amp;rsquo;s just *not *how momentum is supposed to work&amp;ndash;but I think that actually helped the illusion. Even more than with the Hulk or with Thor; these &lt;em>felt&lt;/em> like gods among men.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Dark Knight Rises</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/07/31/the-dark-knight-rises/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 04:55:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/07/31/the-dark-knight-rises/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is another movie right up there with the Avengers in terms of anticipation and I have to say that it delivered. There&amp;rsquo;s just something about super hero movies that&amp;rsquo;s going particularly well right now. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how long this is going to last, but I&amp;rsquo;m more than happy to ride it while it does.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>