<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Marvel Cinematic Universe on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-cinematic-universe/</link><description>Recent content in Marvel Cinematic Universe on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-cinematic-universe/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Agatha All Along</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/21/agatha-all-along/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/21/agatha-all-along/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that was a delight. Take Agatha (and the general fallout of her created world) from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/">WandaVision&lt;/a>, turn up the witchiness, and go on a magical mystical, somewhat terrifying adventure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating story and, honestly, if you would have left out a few scenes it would have worked perfectly well completely outside of the Marvel Cinematic Universe as well. And at this point, that&amp;rsquo;s a strong point in its favor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man Kathryn Hawn does great in this. I loved the supporting witch cast, especially Aubrey Plaza. She does unsettling and off kilter so well. And Teen&amp;ndash;he was an interesting counterpoint. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about the worldbuilding around either Rio (Plaza) or Teen (Locke), those parts felt weird, but the actors were awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;hellip; &lt;strong>the song&lt;/strong> (I don&amp;rsquo;t see this version as spoilers, but some might).&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VnjYeJ5blxo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Man that song has been stuck in my head for weeks now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I personally would have dropped the last half of the last episode, the penultimate really works better as a conclusion. This really doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a sequel (although apparently there will be a third show as a &amp;lsquo;TV trilogy&amp;rsquo; sort of thing?), but so it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/02/deadpool-wolverine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/02/deadpool-wolverine/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so here it is, (almost) the entire reason I rewatched &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/deadpool/">Deadpool&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/28/deadpool-2/">Deadpool 2&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much exactly what you get if you took the (crass) humor of Deadpool, jammed in as many cameos as you could, and shoved it into the modern &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-cinematic-universe/">MCU&lt;/a>, multiverse, TVA, and all&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Deadpool: Welcome to the MCU. You&amp;rsquo;re joining at a bit of a low point.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m still not &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> sure if that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loki: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/12/loki-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/12/loki-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year, another Loki. I really enjoyed &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/">Season 1&lt;/a>. No idea if they could top it. And I&amp;rsquo;m still not 100% sure if they made it better, but they most certainly made it weirder. And I&amp;rsquo;m here for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cast is great of course, with Tom Hiddleston&amp;rsquo;s Loki carrying the show. I really did quite enjoy Jonathan Majors&amp;rsquo; new double role as He Who Remains but also now as Victor Timely. That&amp;rsquo;s most certainly something&amp;ndash;and makes me wonder if they can/could have actually pulled it all off, depending on if Majors sticks around in the MCU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I mentioned in &lt;a href="#6-glorious-purpose">the last episode review below&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s a crazy show, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like about it. It could really change everything&amp;hellip; but I have the unfortunate feeling they&amp;rsquo;re not going to let it. We shall have to see!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Secret Invasion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/secret-invasion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/secret-invasion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s fine. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see some spy stories in the MCU, even if they&amp;rsquo;re light on the spy stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have Fury again, even if (in hindsight) I was perfectly fine without knowing more about Fury&amp;rsquo;s backstory. And the introduction of Super Skrulls? Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really need that in the MCU. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fan of it in either of the previous story lines I&amp;rsquo;ve read them in (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/13/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-6-frightful/">Ultimate Fantastic Four&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/04/runaways-vol.-8-dead-end-kids/">Runaways&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you know what I really think bothers me about the Skrull? All through the Infinity Saga, we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to believe they&amp;rsquo;ve been here, working with Fury. And we never heard even a hint about them. I get it. They’re shapeshifters. The perfect secret agents. Still weird to add something like this after 15 years&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If it had been something tied into each movie and show, leading up to an event (like the Infinity Saga), it could have worked. As it is, it really feels like the concept of an MCU is working against them here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-3/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Rocket: Someday I&amp;rsquo;m gonna make great machines that fly. And me and my friends are gonna go flying together, into the forever and beautiful sky.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was fun. If you liked the previous two Guardians of the Galaxy entries (or especially the Holiday Special), I expect you&amp;rsquo;ll love this. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t care for them, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Guardians of the Galaxy Holiday Special</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/the-guardians-of-the-galaxy-holiday-special/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/the-guardians-of-the-galaxy-holiday-special/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that was delightful. How did I not watch this sooner?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell: it&amp;rsquo;s a standard &amp;ldquo;save Christmas&amp;rdquo; plotline gone so &lt;em>very &lt;strong>very&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> alien. With Mantis and Drax having the main plotline to bring Peter Quill that one perfect gift is so fun. They&amp;rsquo;re just alien enough to bring more than a touch of chaos with them to Earth while at the same time human enough to relate to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, don&amp;rsquo;t expect anything deeper than the above. There really isn&amp;rsquo;t anything here you&amp;rsquo;d miss by not watching&amp;ndash;but on the other other hand it&amp;rsquo;s a quick watch and fun enough to be worth it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/21/ant-man-and-the-wasp-quantumania/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/21/ant-man-and-the-wasp-quantumania/</guid><description>&lt;p>Upside: It&amp;rsquo;s visually super colorful and weird and it&amp;rsquo;s got a lot of potential for the new MCU Phase 5!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Downside: It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; weird and chaotic and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really fit with anything else we particularly know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; fine? I enjoyed watching it, but it&amp;rsquo;s in the category of MCU films that I doubt I&amp;rsquo;d watch again unless I&amp;rsquo;m doing a full rewatch (which is getting to be quite the endeavor).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Werewolf by Night</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/05/werewolf-by-night/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/05/werewolf-by-night/</guid><description>&lt;p>I managed to skip by this last fall, much to my now dismay. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;ndash;only sort of an MCU special; focused on the monster/&amp;lsquo;horror&amp;rsquo; side of Marvel comics rather than the super-hero business. They do open with a sillouette of the heroes we know and love&amp;hellip; before all color drains out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What comes next? An introduction to a monster hunting family/society and a competition to win the mysterious &amp;lsquo;Bloodstone&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;which gives you a sort of power over/against monsters. And then&amp;ndash;the HUNT/BATTLE ROYALE!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wakanda Forever</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/01/wakanda-forever/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/01/wakanda-forever/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>How?&lt;br>
How is never as important as why.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So. How do you fill the giant Chadwick Boseman shaped hole in the MCU?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently&amp;hellip; with funeral services, Atlantis (but not), mer-Hermes (the first self described mutant in the MCU), and&amp;ndash;eventually&amp;ndash;someone new to take up the mantle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; fine?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were certainly some pretty spectacular action scenes. The under water scenes are pretty&amp;ndash;even if they only sort of make sense. The character and costume design continues to impress. And there are giant piles of funeral services and mourning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, the sudden introduction of an entire (large) underwater civilization feels&amp;hellip; weird. And as we&amp;rsquo;ve had before with the Marvel movies, some of the big battle set pieces don&amp;rsquo;t make that much sense. They&amp;rsquo;re going out on a boat to fight water people. All to&amp;hellip; limit how many fighters they have to film? And then all but like ten people die and we&amp;rsquo;re just okay with that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s about the middle of the road so far as Marvel movies go for me. Pretty good, decent action, but there have been better entries. Pretty high up for 2023, but that&amp;rsquo;s probably more because I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen that many movies this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>She-Hulk: Attorney at Law</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/14/she-hulk-attorney-at-law/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/14/she-hulk-attorney-at-law/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not easy being green.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a strange one. She&amp;rsquo;s the Hulk&amp;rsquo;s cousin. One things lead to another, and she gets all Hulked out&amp;hellip; but without any of the downsides?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The contrast between being a Hulk and being a lawyer (and being a big green lawyer) is pretty cool, Tatiana Maslany does a wonderful job in the titular role, and it was great fun to see Tim Roth&amp;rsquo;s Abomination again, not to mention Charlie Cox&amp;rsquo;s Daredevil. Fun casting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a really weird show. And they&amp;rsquo;re rather solidly into the whoe 4th wall breaking thing, which is kind of amusing. Weird. But amusing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I enjoyed the show. Not my favorite of the MCU TV shows, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have watched it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Am Groot</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/28/i-am-groot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/28/i-am-groot/</guid><description>&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re ~3 minute shorts (with 3+ minutes of credits each) about a young reincarnation of a tree-person who can&amp;rsquo;t talk, other than to say &amp;lsquo;I Am Groot&amp;rsquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I was expecting, but for what they are&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;re cute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth the 15 minutes to watch them all. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor: Love and Thunder</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/31/thor-love-and-thunder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/31/thor-love-and-thunder/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/">Thor&lt;/a> was probably the most underwhelming of Phase 1, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/">Thor: The Dark World&lt;/a> tried to go more fantasy and was mostly forgettable, and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/">Thor: Ragnarok&lt;/a> was a blast. Getting better all the time, so &amp;hellip; what about &lt;em>Thor: Love and Thunder&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good question. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to love about the movie: Hemsworth&amp;rsquo;s sense of humor, Portman back and then some, Thompson&amp;rsquo;s awesome and slightly awkward Valkyrie. And of course Bale plays a solidly terrifying baddy in Gorr.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, there is a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of movie to get through here, probably more than a bit too much. A cancer plot, succession jealousy, a threat spanning across the Galaxy (or at least the gods thereof)&amp;ndash;heck, the idea that gods are just &lt;em>a thing&lt;/em> now, Thor unpacking even more trauma. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot to put into a single movie and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>quite&lt;/em> work. It&amp;rsquo;s still a solid enough flick, but not nearly up to what &lt;em>Ragnarok&lt;/em> did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, pretty impressive for the first 4th solo outing in the MCU. Because that&amp;rsquo;s a thing we can say now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/29/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/29/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. That&amp;rsquo;s what what you get if you take a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/directors/sam-raimi">director best known for his horror movies&lt;/a>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and let them loose in the MCU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like it. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eternals</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/25/eternals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/25/eternals/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ancient aliens sent to Earth thousands of years ago to protect&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> humanity&amp;hellip; but only from very specific threats. Loki and the Chitauri? Nah. Hydra? Nope. Thanos? Of course not. A whole cast of superheroes&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and we&amp;rsquo;ve never seen them before&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&amp;ndash;and I doubt that any of the should-be-worldwide-news events in this film will make it into any of the others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you ignore all that though, it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting enough idea, especially once you start digging into the greater cosmic plot. There&amp;rsquo;s even more to unpack than we even get a chance to look at in that movie. I really do want to know where it goes next&amp;ndash;and if there will be any impact at all on the greater MCU.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ms. Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ms. Marvel is not particularly earth-shattering. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t deal with the end of the world and only barely with the greater MCU (although there is a decent bit of &amp;lsquo;how the world changes with superheroes in it, like Ant-Man&amp;rsquo;s podcast and Avengercon).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What it is though? A awful lot of fun. Iman Vellani as Kamala Khan is just an absolute delight and really looks like she had a great time in the role. The whole supporting cast is great as well, especially Kamala&amp;rsquo;s family and friends Bruno and Nakia.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Kamala Khan: [whispers] I&amp;rsquo;m a super hero.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[She runs off gleefully]&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed this. Especially when it leaned into the Muslim + Pakistani culture and the family dynamics of the whole thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: I don’t need anyone on my side. I’m not even concerned if God is on my side as long as I am on His side. God is always right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Agent Deever: I don’t have time for Quranic quotes. Excuse me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: Actually, that was Abraham Lincoln.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The big fights and greater threats were kind of cheesey and didn&amp;rsquo;t mesh as well (especially the big showpiece in the final episode), but the down to earth human parts of being a teenager superhero? Awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so hard to rank these any more, since there&amp;rsquo;s just so much to love in the MCU. I think Ms. Marvel ends up pretty squarely in the middle of the pack&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;d still say it&amp;rsquo;s worth a watch. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moon Knight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/moon-knight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/moon-knight/</guid><description>&lt;p>That &amp;hellip; was truly bizarre. A main character with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/dissociative%20identity%20disorder">dissociative identity disorder&lt;/a> where their powers deal with but &lt;em>are not&lt;/em> caused by their disorder is fascinating (and truly weird to be watching at the same time as &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/01/altered-carbon-season-1/">Altered Carbon: Season 1&lt;/a>&amp;hellip;), the Egyptian background and characters are great, and there&amp;rsquo;s are some pretty awesome scenes, fight and otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Castingwise, Oscar Isaac is awesome. I&amp;rsquo;m amazed at how he brings both Marc and Steven to life. Ethan Hawke is a great maybe-baddie-but-maybe-just-a-different-point-of-view. And May Calamawy as Layla El-Faouly is a real stand out in just about everyway. I hope that we get to see more of them in the greater MCU, although I have no idea how that&amp;rsquo;s going to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of which, this was so different from other MCU properties. It&amp;rsquo;s got Egyptian gods and powers more or less walking around, which fits, but I do really wander how/if we&amp;rsquo;d see them or their avatars square off against normal MCU level heroes. Tonally, it&amp;rsquo;s rather different too. There&amp;rsquo;s still an end of the world threat, but a lot of it&amp;rsquo;s dealing with the internal struggles of Steven/Marc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s probably my favorite of the MCU TV shows so far&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll have to rewatch it and see if it holds up. It&amp;rsquo;s really quite good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: No Way Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finally got around to watching this. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did, it&amp;rsquo;s hilarious and an aboslute blast of nostalgia. Similar to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/">Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a>, I don&amp;rsquo;t know know if this would possibly hold up without the weight of all of the movies that came before it (I doubt it), but with that weight&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s really really good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s funny, it&amp;rsquo;s touching, and there are some really crazy action scenes. But the greatest strength of course comes from &lt;span class="spoiler">bringing back a half dozen villains and all three modern live action Spider-Men into one film&lt;/span>
. Would anyone have believed something that crazy possible, especially before Infinity War/Endgame? I doubt it. But it&amp;rsquo;s quite satisfying.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>As much as I loved &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/">Spider-Man: Homecoming&lt;/a>, Spider-Man: Far From Home takes what made it great and turns it up a few levels &lt;em>even further&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One one level, you have Spider-Man being Spider-Man. He&amp;rsquo;s a good kid, trying to make his way in life, trying to deal with the dual life of being a highschooler and being a superhero&amp;ndash;of saving the world and perhaps getting the girl.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then you layer all the weight of the greater MCU on top of it. This takes place just after &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/">Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a>. So you have the fallout of Iron Man (Spider-Man&amp;rsquo;s mentor/Uncle Ben figure) being gone and Spider-Man having to step into &lt;em>those&lt;/em> shoes, the first big mention of The Blip&amp;ndash;and how you deal with coming back and the world has changed, and all sorts of dealing with a Nick Fury who&amp;rsquo;s lost several of his heaviest hitters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Homecoming</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>That&lt;/em> is a truly delightful Spider-Man movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird seeing him introduced &lt;em>after&lt;/em> the events of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/">Captain America: Civil War&lt;/a>) and completely skipping how he became Spider-Man in the first place&amp;hellip; but it works. I really like the entire plot, dealing with the fallout of the Avengers / super-hero activity and how normal people try to live their lives around it&amp;ndash;and what happens when the powers that be step in and take that away from them. Excellent villain fuel. It&amp;rsquo;s a little silly that &lt;span class="spoiler">the Vulture ends up being Spider-Man's crush's father...&lt;/span>
, but I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s the sort of thing you expect from superhero films. Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid, fun action film.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hawkeye</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/22/hawkeye/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/22/hawkeye/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really enjoyed Hawkeye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s just &lt;em>fun&lt;/em>, which compared to &lt;em>Wandvision&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Loki&lt;/em> and really even &lt;em>What If&amp;hellip;&lt;/em> is a worthwhile goal and really does a lot to show off the more human scale of superheroes. It&amp;rsquo;s never really made much sense that Hawkeye and Black Widow were Avengers&amp;hellip; and it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But they do it anyways. Because what Heroes do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see them building up the new &amp;lsquo;Young Avengers&amp;rsquo; and branching out as much as they are. I think Hailee Steinfeld did a great job, especially when acting against &lt;span class="spoiler">Florence Pugh's Yelena&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was a surprisingly delightful movie. It takes a character I&amp;rsquo;ve at least barely heard of&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> with a cast pretty much unknown to the western world&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and turns it into a wonderful combination of human drama, Lovecraftian baddies, and awesome action scenes. It&amp;rsquo;s well among my favorite MCU movies to date (only Captain America beats it out among introductions and a few others overall) and well worth the watch. After how big the MCU has gotten recently, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of nice to see a movie that almost completely stands on it&amp;rsquo;s own&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. It&amp;rsquo;s a big world, with parallel/pocket universes and gates to worlds chock full of truly alien baddies, but at the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s a story about family, about legacy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What If...?</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</guid><description>&lt;p>What if…?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a wacky title, but it sums up the series pretty well. Take what the MCU has spent a decade building on top of half a century of comics before that&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. The comics have done all manner of continuity resets and what-ifs, so it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual to see the stories as they could have been&amp;ndash;if only one thing changed. But this is a first for the MCU. I fully expect with the coming Phase 4, we&amp;rsquo;ll see a bit more of this though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Widow</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been to theaters since&amp;hellip; &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/">Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a>. Man it&amp;rsquo;s been a weird few years. Which actually wraps up Black Widow pretty well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly solid action/spy movie. There are a number of spectacular action scenes, a deep dive into Black Widow&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s akin to an origin story, but filling in a character we already knew a decent amount of back rather than introducing someone new, which was nice&amp;ndash;and the introduction of a few new characters I expect we&amp;rsquo;ll see more of. After the absolutely draining intensity of Infinity War/Endgame plus just how dark the followup shows have been, it was nice to have something relatively &amp;rsquo;lighter&amp;rsquo; and smaller in scope.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Endgame</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s one heck of a climax.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/">Avengers: Infinity War&lt;/a>, Thanos won. He snapped and half of the universe died&amp;ndash;let&amp;rsquo;s ignore the logistics of that. In Endgame, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance&amp;ndash;a very small chance&amp;ndash;that they can fix it all. All they need is a little &amp;ndash;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tony Stark: [discussing the &amp;ldquo;Time Heist&amp;rdquo;] I believe the most likely outcome will be our collective demise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scott Lang: Not if we strictly follow the rules of time travel. That means no talking to our past selves, no betting on sporting events&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Captain Marvel is a bit of an odd movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a straight up superhero origin story with a bit more of a cosmic twist than many we&amp;rsquo;ve seen (other than Guardians of the Galaxy&amp;hellip; and Thor&amp;hellip;) It&amp;rsquo;s something of a prequel&amp;ndash;in that it&amp;rsquo;s chronologically set before any of the other Marvel movies other than the beginning of Captain America. It&amp;rsquo;s got a hero in Captain Marvel with a grab bag of vaguely defined glowy energy powers with memory issues who has to go on a journey and power up to her final form.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ant-Man and the Wasp</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ant-Man and his daughter are adorable. Especially with Luis&amp;rsquo; help. Luis is wonderful. Everyone playing Luis as he describes everyone. And Paul Rudd playing Janet van Dyne. Add to that the interactions with/introduction of Jimmy Woo.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Scott Lang: Come on, Woo. I&amp;rsquo;ve got three days left. Why would I try to escape?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jimmy Woo: Sorry, Scott, but rules are rules. You trip the perimeter alarm, we search the place. Keel to stern, soup to nuts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Infinity War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>All that. Ten years. 18 movies. Dozens of huge name actors and crossovers, all leading to this. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/">The Avengers&lt;/a> gave us a team up, but Infinity War turned it all up to 11. The battle scenes are insane (especially that final battle in Wakanda, especially especially the return of Thor), the villain&amp;ndash;Josh Brolin as Thanos&amp;ndash;is powerful and &lt;span class="spoiler">ACTUALLY GETS A CHANCE TO WIN&lt;/span>
, and I absolutely love seeing the interplay between all of the characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Panther</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a very solid movie. The casting is top notch, the style is wonderfully afrofuturistic, and the plot/motivation is interesting enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting with the plot/motivation, I think that the choice to have Wakanda separated from the rest of the world, all through centuries of slavery and inequality is certainly an interesting one. And I&amp;rsquo;m not at all alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nakia: I came to support you, and to honor your father. But I can&amp;rsquo;t stay. It&amp;rsquo;s just &amp;hellip; ! found my calling out there. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen too many in need just to turn a blind eye. I can&amp;rsquo;t be happy here knowing that there&amp;rsquo;s people out there who have nothing .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor: Ragnarok</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ooh, that poster. &lt;em>le kiss&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/">Thor&lt;/a> was &amp;hellip; fine, a weirdly downscale introduction to a kind of strange character early in the MCU. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/">Thor: The Dark World&lt;/a> went the other way, being too bigt and ambitious and suffering somewhat for it. So going into Thor: Ragnarok, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what we were going to get.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An absolute gem of an 80s sci fi/fantasy action superhero comedy that just works. Right from the very intro, you know it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a different sort of movie. They lean hard into the Norse/Asgardian mythos, with Thor in the underworld, chained up (but not concerned) by a giant flaming skeleton who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to signify the end of days. One spectacular Thor&amp;rsquo;ful action scene later and we&amp;rsquo;re back on Asgard, dealing with the missing Odin. Then we&amp;rsquo;re off to Earth, only to bump into Doctor Strange, now fully into his powers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the surprisingly awesome &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/">Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/a>, it was really a question of: could they do it again? The answer, a resounding&amp;hellip; sort of?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 has some pretty awesome moments. The opening battle in particular is spectacular (I love the contrast of dancing Baby Groot against a big smack down in the background). And we get all piles of additional humor based around Drax&amp;rsquo;s literalness, Rocket being a racoon, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doctor Strange</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/10/doctor-strange/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/10/doctor-strange/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Wong: While heroes like the Avengers protect the world from physical dangers, we sorcerers safeguard it against more mystical threats.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Man, that is a visually stunning movie. The first battle with building magically twisting all over (a la Inception), the glowing magic rings, the magical doodads. I am ever thankful that superhero movies have gotten popular enough that studios will spend the big bucks on special effects. They really do look great.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain America: Civil War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>Captain America: Civil War isn&amp;rsquo;t really a Captain America movie. While it deals with the Winter Solder to some extent, as much as that it&amp;rsquo;s an Iron Man movie since &lt;span class="spoiler">he killed Stark's parents...&lt;/span>
. But really, it&amp;rsquo;s an Avengers movie. Everyone shows up, takes sides, and eventually ends up a great big superhero fight. And It&amp;hellip; Is&amp;hellip; Spectacular. In my opinion, it&amp;rsquo;s the best MCU movie to this point, beating out any of the solo outings and even the first two Avengers movies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ant-Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/02/ant-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/02/ant-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Continuing in the set of Marvel movies that came out after I stopped going to theaters quite so much / reviewing movies in 2014, we have Ant-Man!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a heist movie/comedy with superheroes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful movie, with a lighter, funnier theme than a lot of the movies. The cast is wonderful. Paul Rudd is hilarious and well cast as Ant-Man, Michael Douglas is a wonderful cranky old man scientist that&amp;rsquo;s been burned as Hank Pym, Corey Stoll is a wonderful crazy (spoilers) bad guy, and Evangeline Lilly is criminally underused. Eventually that will/should get better. But the real standout has to be Michael Peña as Luis. He&amp;rsquo;s hilarious. The &amp;lsquo;he said/she said&amp;rsquo; stories told with all manner of different actors but his voice are a joy to watch. He&amp;rsquo;s just that funny.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Age of Ultron</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Hawkeye: The city is flying and we&amp;rsquo;re fighting an army of robots. And I have a bow and arrow. Nothing makes sense.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Age of Ultron is an odd movie. From the perspective of a summer blockbuster/action movie, it&amp;rsquo;s solid. The opening action scene is wonderfully avengerful, there are all manner of awesome fights (the Hulk versus Iron Man fight and the final battle come to mind), and we get a few new characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loki</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another MCU made for Disney+ TV outing. After the amazing &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/">WandaVision&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/">The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/a>, Loki had a high bar to clear. In my nutshell: they nailed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I am Loki of Asgard, and I am burdened with glorious purpose.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Loki (the character) is fascinating. He started out a well cast mostly villain of his own in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/">Thor&lt;/a> and became the first recurring villain in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/">The Avengers&lt;/a>. And after that, he&amp;rsquo;s back again and again in each of the Thor and Avengers movies. In a universe where every other villain (even Thanos) is basically a one and done, it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating way to do it. On top of that, he&amp;rsquo;s interesting. Over the years, he&amp;rsquo;s grown to be rather likeable (if you ignore the fact that he&amp;rsquo;s killed how many people?) and even a hero. So of course when you set him up as the protagonist of his own show&amp;hellip; expect great things.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had forgotten just how &lt;em>fun&lt;/em> Guardians of the Galaxy is. Back when I &lt;a href="#original-2014-review">first reviewed it in 2014&lt;/a>, it surprised me with how different it was and just how much it opened up the Marvel Universe. Well, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen some pretty crazy things since then (Thor Ragnarok springs to mind), but it&amp;rsquo;s still a pretty crazy movie. I mean, come on. It&amp;rsquo;s a man obsessed with classic rock, a badass green woman assassin, an overly literal shirtless wrestler, a cybernetically enhanced racoon, and a speaking tree &lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> &lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Add in the first real hints of the Infinity Stones, Thanos as the continuing &amp;lsquo;bigger bad&amp;rsquo;, and you have a pretty impactful movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then on top of that, you get an absolutely hilarious movie, some wonderful action scenes (the meet up / fight in the square at the beginning is particularly wonderful, but there are several), and a whole range of colorful new characters. When you don&amp;rsquo;t have to even try to stick to what works on Earth&amp;hellip; things get pretty silly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a wonderful movie. I think this time around, I actually rate it higher than the Avengers, although still below Iron Man and Captain America 1 and 2. Well worth a watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the record: the ending scene is still kind of dumb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Random side note: the idea of a whole fleet of starships linking up (somehow) and literally trying to push a very slow moving enemy spaceship back into space is just bonkers. Among a movie full of crazy scenes, that one came the closest to really pulling me out of the film. But so it goes.&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="original-2014-review">Original 2014 review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Can Marvel do no wrong?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain America: The Winter Soldier</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/27/captain-america-the-winter-soldier/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/27/captain-america-the-winter-soldier/</guid><description>&lt;p>From &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/">one of the weakest&lt;/a> MCU movies to one of the strongest. I loved the first solo entry of Captain American and the second is even better. Much like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/27/captain-america-the-winter-soldier/">last time&lt;/a>, I very much enjoyed this movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a solid contrast against the first Captain America (blind optimistic patriotism versus a darker world, where even your friends&amp;hellip; might not be). It&amp;rsquo;s made all the better having already seen the future of Sam and Bucky/The Winter Soldier now. Last time through, I was hoping they could pull off all the new characters and now&amp;hellip; I think they did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around (and so far), the top of my list for the year. An excellent movie.&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="original-2014-review">Original 2014 review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Out of all the pre-Avengers / &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Marvel_Cinematic_Universe_films#Phase_One:_Avengers_Assembled">Phase One&lt;/a> Marvel Cinematic Universe movies, it&amp;rsquo;s really a toss up whether Iron Man or Captain American was my favorite. In &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Marvel_Cinematic_Universe_films#Phase_Two">Phase Two&lt;/a>? It&amp;rsquo;s not even a question&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Captain America: The Winter Soldier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor: The Dark World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>One problem that comic book universes in general and the MCU in specific have always had is that of scale. How in the world do you have a man in a suit, a literal &amp;lsquo;god&amp;rsquo;, a rage monster, a super soldier, and a couple &amp;hellip; regular people ever interact on the same scale? For the most part, it&amp;rsquo;s hand waved away. Everyone is paired up with an opponent of roughly the same power level and we move on with our lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No where those is this contrast more apparent than in the Universe of Thor. The people of Asgard are supposed to be gods. They live thousands of years. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen them shrug off some pretty crazy weapons. And yet here they are, dying to spears and falling rocks. It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean, there are any number of brilliant CGI shots of the weird world of Asgard, and it at least has a much bigger scope than the first Thor, but it still feels &amp;hellip; hollow. It&amp;rsquo;s a pity, because I enjoy Thor&amp;rsquo;s super powerful fish out of water story well enough in the combined movies, but this is not my favorite of the combined films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s always interesting to re-read my older reviews: &lt;a href="#original-2013-review">see below&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="original-2013-review">Original 2013 review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The first Thor was a bit disappointing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There, I said it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It could certainly have been worse, but it really felt like the entire movie served solely to set up Thor&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> for the Avengers. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t terrible, it just &amp;hellip; was.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iron Man 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/iron-man-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/iron-man-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>For some reason, I Iron Man 3 as a fairly week entry, but looking back to when I last watched it in theaters (&lt;a href="#original-2013-review">see below&lt;/a>)&amp;hellip; I actually liked it about as much then I do now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, I really do still think they absolutely nailed Robert Downey Jr. as Iron man. He can do both funny and broken pretty well and has more than a few chances for each this time around. I know now (and didn&amp;rsquo;t then) that there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an Iron Man 4, but he still did an amazing job in this last solo outing and in the teams ups yet to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise, I actually really liked Gwyneth Paltrow&amp;rsquo;s as Pepper Potts. It&amp;rsquo;s good seeing her as both a foil for Iron Man and actually being a badass in her own right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ben Kingsley still steal the show, although this time around I&amp;rsquo;m coming to see just how much range there was in Guy Pearce&amp;rsquo;s Aldrich Killian. He pulled down on his luck geek up through brilliant and crazy mirror to Tony Stark all the way to &lt;span class="spoiler">fire breathing baddie&lt;/span>
 pretty darn well so far as action movies go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One that I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention last time around, but made all the more apparent I think having just seen in her in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/godzilla-vs-kong/">Godzilla vs Kong&lt;/a>) was Rebecca Hall&amp;rsquo;s performance as Maya Hansen. She does smart conflicted scientist very well in both films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it was a fascinating way to deal with PTSD, even if does feel a bit sudden (although PTSD can do that) and could really have used a bit deeper dive (not really room for that in a summer blockbuster).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, feel free to give my &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/iron-man-3/">previous review&lt;/a> a look. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really changed my opinion much, but it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the two 8 years apart. A lot can change in 8 years&amp;hellip; Both so far as the MCU and in my own life. Some things change, some things stand the tests of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this time around, I&amp;rsquo;ll slot it in just below the Avengers on both lists. I think Iron Man 3 might actually be the better movie in a lot of ways, but the Avengers I think wins just on sheer spectacle. Feel free to disagree. :) It&amp;rsquo;s all made up numbers anyways.&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="original-2013-review">Original 2013 review:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Go see Iron Man 3. I&amp;rsquo;ll wait.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier basically takes place where Avengers: Endgame left off. Steve Rogers as Captain America has stepped down, leaving his shield to Sam Wilson/The Falcon/the (rumored) future Captain America. And on a superficial level, that&amp;rsquo;s about where it ends: Sam Wilson has the shield and is expected to take up the mantle of Captain America.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, oh the story it tells along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, you have the dynamic between titular Falcon and Winter Soldier. Brought together by their respective friendships with Captain America, it&amp;rsquo;s quite often hilarious listening to them bicker. They really do respect and care about one another, and that makes the bickering all the better.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Avengers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hooo boy. When I &lt;a href="#original-2012-review">first saw this movie&lt;/a> (in theaters, in the before times), I was pretty much blown away. It was a big budget, box office smasher of a movie, bringing together an entire series of super hero movies in one giant box office smash. It was something that had never really been done before&amp;hellip; and they managed to actually pull it off. And not only that (knowing what I do now), it was the start of something &lt;strong>even bigger&lt;/strong>. Absolutely bonkers to believe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, with the benefit of hindsight, it does have a few issues for it&amp;rsquo;s size: you don&amp;rsquo;t get as much time with all the characters as you need. The jokes are very Whedon-esqe and over the top&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s one thing to have Tony Stark quip, but things like Thor&amp;rsquo;s immediate &amp;ldquo;he&amp;rsquo;s adopted&amp;rdquo; quip just don&amp;rsquo;t feel right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But for what it is&amp;ndash;a giant summer blockbuster and a fantastic action movie&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much top of the line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It actually topped my list back in during my &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2012-movie-reviews/">2012 Movie Revies&lt;/a>, but this time around&amp;hellip; I just really like the other individual films more. So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Still well well worth the watch).&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="original-2012-review">Original 2012 review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s really not much to say about this that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been said / won&amp;rsquo;t be said a thousand times over. Long story short, it&amp;rsquo;s a great movie and a hit out of the park for everyone involved. I liked it enough that I&amp;rsquo;m sure to see it again and I strongly suggest that you go to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain America: The First Avenger</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/31/captain-america-the-first-avenger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/31/captain-america-the-first-avenger/</guid><description>&lt;p>Now that is how you do a super hero movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For anyone that&amp;rsquo;s somehow missed it, Captain America is the story about how a little guy from Brooklyn with a heart of gold and a steadfast determination to serve his country in World War II gets just that chance: taking a super soldier serum to get buff, becomes a showgirl for a while (because of course), fights Nazis, and gets frozen in the ice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thor is an odd sort of movie for the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marvel%20Cinematic%20Universe">Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/a>. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s our first foray into the more &amp;lsquo;magical&amp;rsquo; side of the universe, with ancient Gods and the like. Although in this universe, we&amp;rsquo;re led to believe that it&amp;rsquo;s really just highly advanced science. On the other hand, despite a worlds spanning plot (literally, 3 of them), it still feels oddly &amp;hellip; small.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s weird. We&amp;rsquo;re supposed to believe that Odin is over a thousand years old and Thor is&amp;hellip; just now coming into his kingship now? How long does it take for them to grow up? And Asgardians at some level can die in battle, but in others handle getting thrown around and hit by cars just fine? It&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip; a little weird. The idea of Thor being a spoiled young man and having to show his worthiness is a solid enough plot (and a common enough Thor origin story); although it all comes together a mite quickly for him. And then the final battle&amp;ndash;while it looks cool enough I guess, it&amp;rsquo;s all feels like they could have used a bit more time and money to fill things in a bit more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iron Man 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/23/iron-man-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/23/iron-man-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I vaguely remember Iron Man 2 being a much weaker movie than the first Iron Man, but you know, it&amp;rsquo;s actually really good. The action is great, especially the fight scenes with the electro whips and between Iron Man and (not yet named) War Machine. Good stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, Don Cheadle is a great replacement as Rhodes; you can feel Robert Downey Jr. as Iron Man at the top of his game (with nothing to lose &lt;spoiler>because he&amp;rsquo;s dying&lt;/spoiler>); and I still think Paltrow makes a great Potts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Incredible Hulk</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/20/the-incredible-hulk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/20/the-incredible-hulk/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Bruce Banner: [in a poor Portuguese] Don&amp;rsquo;t make me hungry. You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like me when I&amp;rsquo;m hungry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tough Guy Leader: [in Portuguese] What the hell he is talking about?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of bummer that The Incredible Hulk is stuck in sort of a legal loophole and isn&amp;rsquo;t available with all the rest of the MCU on Disney+ (A̸̜̓L̶̬̽L̷̗̋ ̵̦̂Ĥ̴̖A̵͓͋I̴̝̓L̵̺̓ ̶͖̄T̶̿͜H̶̬̊È̷̡ ̸̜̋M̸̮̔O̷̜͒U̶͇̓S̵̺̏Ë̵̝́). On top of that, it&amp;rsquo;s the only main MCU superhero that they&amp;rsquo;ve recast (so far). Conversely though, it&amp;rsquo;s actually (surprisingly) a good movie.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WandaVision</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Wanda Maximoff: We are an unusual couple, you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vision: Oh, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that was ever in question.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well. That was most certainly a thing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iron Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/iron-man/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/iron-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Way back in 2008, I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone had the slightest idea how far the Marvel Cinematic Universe would go. Taking a less well known superhero (face it, before this few knew who Iron Man was), attaching him to a talented but troubled actor (Robert Downy Jr was an amazing cast) and make a fairly stock standard action movie and&amp;hellip; build a media empire that would span more than 12 years and 20 films (so far&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>