<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>John Elder Robison on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/john-elder-robison/</link><description>Recent content in John Elder Robison on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/john-elder-robison/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Look Me in the Eye: My Life with Asperger's</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/18/look-me-in-the-eye-my-life-with-aspergers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/18/look-me-in-the-eye-my-life-with-aspergers/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am fond of the quote “When you’ve met one Aspergian, you’ve met one Aspergian. We are all unique.” That may be true, but now that I’m meeting other Aspergians, I am finding that some traits I thought were unique to me are actually characteristic of Aspergians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Robison&amp;ndash;John Elder&amp;ndash;grew up with autism (or what would once have been diagnosed as Aspergers before DSM-5). He was always an odd kid and had to grow up quick and come up with all manner of interesting coping mechanisms to survive in a world that wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely sure how to deal with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that he had an&amp;hellip; interesting home life, also described by his brother in the memoir &lt;em&gt;Running with Scissors&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ndash;and later planted the seed that grew into &lt;em&gt;Look Me in the Eye&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should write a memoir. About Asperger’s, about growing up not knowing what you had. A memoir where you tell all your stories. Tell everything.” About five minutes later, he e-mailed me a sample chapter. “Like this?” was the subject line of the e-mail. Yes. Like that. Once again, my brilliant brother had found a way to channel his unstoppable Asperger energy and talent. When he decided to research our family history and create a family tree, the document ended up being more than two thousand pages long. So once the idea of writing a memoir was in his head, he dove in with an intensity that would send most people straight into a psychiatric hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although found that although people didn&amp;rsquo;t always do what he expected, electronics most certainly did. This lead to &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; the career, building, repairing, and upgrading sound systems, including building a lot of the custom hardware used by the band KISS&amp;ndash;and then later also getting into designing the electronics in toys and eventually repairing expensive cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly not where I expected his story to go, I&amp;rsquo;ll say that much, but the way he describes the story, each step just makes so much sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fascinating half of the book (to me) is hearing John Elder describe the world he lives in. I&amp;rsquo;ll go into more specifics &lt;a href="#aspergian-traits"&gt;in a later section&lt;/a&gt;, but this was really the part of the book that stood out to me. Like the quote says/implies, every is different&amp;ndash;and those with autism are no exception&amp;hellip; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that people who&amp;rsquo;s brains tend the same way might just see the world the same way. Some of these things I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen put into words before. Worth the read just for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I quite enjoyed this book. If you have autism (diagnosed or not)&amp;ndash;or if you know someone with autism (and I expect you do, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t know it), I recommend giving it a read. Perhaps you&amp;rsquo;ll see something of yourself in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>