<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amy Garvey on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/amy-garvey/</link><description>Recent content in Amy Garvey on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/amy-garvey/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Experiment</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/17/the-experiment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/17/the-experiment/</guid><description>&lt;p>The one where Ax watches entirely too much TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Look, Tobias! Victor and Nikki are doing that thing again!&amp;gt; I pointed at the screen. &lt;They do this very often.>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Uh-huh.&amp;gt; His hawk eyes were trained on the little screen as Victor tightened his arms around Nikki. &amp;lt;It&amp;rsquo;s called kissing, Ax-man. Just like yesterday. And the day before. Kissing. Everyone does it. Of course, you need lips.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;I know what it is called. And the role of lips is self-evident. I simply do not know why it is performed.>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Ah. Well . . .&amp;gt; Tobias rearranged his wings noisily. &amp;lt;It&amp;rsquo;s definitely got a purpose. By the way, Marco&amp;rsquo;s heading this way.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Way too much.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Marco sighed. &amp;ldquo;Whatever you call it, it basically reeks, you know. I think it&amp;rsquo;s time I introduced you to some better programming, Ax. Buffy. Party of Five, maybe. Cops. South Park. Something, anything better than this. Although she is hot.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Yes, she is hot. This is why she often wears less artificial skin.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Yeah, well, I think you may have your cause and effect turned around there. Hey, you know what you need? A TV Guide.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Entirely&lt;/em> too much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Nothing but lame sitcom reruns this week,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re not missing anything.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;There are always These Messages,&amp;gt; I pointed out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;These what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;The shorter shows that are displayed between longer shows. These Messages. They are often my favorites. &amp;ldquo;Zestfully clean! Zestfully clean! You&amp;rsquo;re not fully clean unless you&amp;rsquo;re Zestfully clean!&amp;rdquo; So much information condensed into so brief a format. So much emotional intensity.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re starting to scare me, Ax.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes. The entire book is like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, there&amp;rsquo;s also something about a machine to remove free will, which seems to fall into the &amp;lsquo;duh, that&amp;rsquo;s not possible category&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I wanted to tell him. I wanted to say, Look, it can&amp;rsquo;t be done. You don&amp;rsquo;t understand! There&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as a human being without a free will. It&amp;rsquo;s . . . it&amp;rsquo;s . . . idiotic! But he&amp;rsquo;s no scientist, much less a philosopher. You can&amp;rsquo;t separate a sentient creature from free will. They are free will. Yeerk, Hork-Bajir, human, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. A sentient species has free will like an object has mass. You can&amp;rsquo;t separate them! But Visser Three doesn&amp;rsquo;t listen.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Which&amp;hellip; annoyed me more than it probably should have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We don&amp;rsquo;t know what free will is. But you &lt;em>very much&lt;/em> can seemingly take away people&amp;rsquo;s free will. That&amp;rsquo;s what whole classes of drugs are designed to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>