<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stargate on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/stargate/</link><description>Recent content in Stargate on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/stargate/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stargate Universe: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/stargate-universe-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/stargate-universe-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Each time I rewatch Stargate (and with 17 seasons and a handful of movies, that&amp;rsquo;s something of a time commitment), I forgot just how much better Stargate Universe season 2 is than season 1. And I &lt;em>already&lt;/em> liked Season 1. But 2 is where things really get on their own. The crew trapped on Destiny is really learning how to use the ship and making it their own, finding new (huge) mysteries, and actually getting a few big bads on a scale with the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld/Ori/Wraith. And with how things end up&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s such a bummer it has to end. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to check out the follow up graphic novel this time around, official canon or not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate Universe: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/30/stargate-universe-season-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/30/stargate-universe-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onward to another universe!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stargate SG-1 started it all, focusing mostly on adventure and exploring a brand new universe. Stargate Atlantis took that feeling and went hard into the sci-fi nature of the show, giving us an entirely different galaxy and people, dealing with (in some ways) much larger and more complicated threats.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stargate Universe&amp;hellip; in some ways takes us even father, across tens or hundreds of galaxies to an Ancient (both in manufactory and age) ship&amp;ndash;the Destiny. And there&amp;rsquo;s a fair bit of the sci-fi thriller feel of trying to survive in difficult times, learning about the ship and galaxy you&amp;rsquo;ve found yourself in. But really, at it&amp;rsquo;s heart, Stargate Universe is about people. And man are they some messed up and drama-filled people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/23/stargate-atlantis-season-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/23/stargate-atlantis-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do sorely wish that Atlantis could have gotten another season. There are some &lt;em>very&lt;/em> strong episodes in this seaon. As much as I liked Weir and Carter, Woolsey is another huge case of character improvement (almost as much as McKay).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mini-reviews (potential spoilers):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Search and Rescue&lt;/em>: Half a closed room, buried deep in a collapsed building, half Teyla. Neither quite what I was hoping for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/10/stargate-atlantis-season-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/10/stargate-atlantis-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy season in how it begins (lost in space!) and ends (lost in time!). More replicators, more wraith, more variations thereof. A handful of smaller episodes with only small combinations of main cast really shine. We lose a few of the big leads and gain a few more old names. It&amp;rsquo;s also always interesting how shows deal with the pregnancy of a main cast member.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onwards and Season 5-wards! To the end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/stargate-atlantis-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/stargate-atlantis-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like in this series. We get new, complicate Wraith threats (Michael and Todd!), Replicators, lost Ancients, and some of the best McKay episodes in the show (McKay and Mrs. Miller and Tao of Rodney). Not to mention Lucius Lavin. No really. :) And then there&amp;rsquo;s Sunday&amp;hellip; Man it sucks to kill off major characters just to raise the stakes, but it still works as an episode.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/09/stargate-atlantis-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/09/stargate-atlantis-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a beginning and ending, with a whole lot in between. One of the biggest changes is the introduction of Ronan Dex. Replacement for Lt. Ford who has a tendency to shoot first and ask questions&amp;ndash;well, never. He&amp;rsquo;s quite the character and a good addition to the team. Interesting that the main team is half from Pegasus now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mini-reviews (potential spoilers):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Siege, Part 3: Man this is a fun three parter. I don’t care as much for the repeated theme of military taking over, but it is still a great episode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intruder: Computer virus running the show. we’ve done this before.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Runner: Ford’s passing of the torch to Ronon Dex. Ford never quite works and I really end up liking Dex.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Duet: Two minds stuck in McKay’s body. A story we’ve seen before, but I really like in particular how it humanizes him.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Condemned: Penal colony/execution and overzealous laws. Again, we’ve done it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Trinity: McKay discovers a super weapon research station and he believes he can fix it better than the Ancients. The hubris of McKay is a great contrast to Duet and I b really enjoy the relationship between Sheppard and McKay.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Instinct: The first hints that it may be possible to &amp;lsquo;cure&amp;rsquo; the Wraith. Also Jewel Staite, which is amusing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conversion: Fallout from Instinct leads to a return of Iratus bugs (Sheppard is thrilled).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aurora: Ancients! Virtual reality! a fascinating episode and a poignant ending.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lost Boys: Highs to lows. Ford is back and still… questionable at best.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Hive: Teyla is Wraith-psychic. Sheppard falls for any pretty face. Cool action scenes though.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Epiphany: Time dilation! The way to fit a lifetime in an episode. A lot like Brief Candle from SG-1.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Critical Mass: Crossover, chock full of mostly minor characters from SG-1! It&amp;rsquo;s interesting watching them out of order, since the Ori aren&amp;rsquo;t about yet. The Twilight Bark analogy falling flat to a room full of SGC is hilarious. Cadman back is great. Wish she has a bigger roll over all.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Grace Under Pressure: McKay stuck in a jumper deep in the ocean, hallucinating. One of the best McKay episodes in the show.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Tower: Of course the Ancients had more cities. And of course Sheppard&amp;rsquo;s, &amp;ldquo;I never see this coming&amp;rdquo;. An interesting exploration of what the ancients left behind.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Michael: I remember watching this the first time and feeling something was vaguely wrong from the beginning. Knowing just what that is just means that I can be on the look out for it the whole way through.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Inferno: The Ancients were really good at finding creative ways to harness huge amounts of power. It&amp;rsquo;s amusing how often they tend to explode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allies: The enemy of my enemy&amp;hellip; Should damn will still be my enemy.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>On to Season 3! Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m glad to be watching these now and not having to wait a year or more for the &amp;lsquo;To Be Continued&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/29/stargate-atlantis-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/29/stargate-atlantis-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it begins again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While Stargate SG-1 really has a solid place in my heart, in a way I like Atlantis even better. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it could have been what it is without SG-1, but with it, it&amp;rsquo;s made even better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have a generally optimistic can do attitude, backed up by McKay quite often saving the day (which is crazy coming off SG-1, I forgot how annoying he is and just &lt;em>how much&lt;/em> he grows throughout the seasons of Atlantis). On top of that, the second weird (Torri Higginson) is back as the woman in charge and plays that well. I think perhaps my favorite character though (if not McKay, I know right?) is Joe Flanigan as Lt. Colonel John Sheppard. He&amp;rsquo;s a military leader that cares more for his people than for the rules (seen that before), but he&amp;rsquo;s smart (although he keeps it low key) and snarky rather than cynical as Jack could be. It&amp;rsquo;s a good mix. Teyla&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve never quite cared for, but she&amp;rsquo;s portrayed well enough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate: Continuum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-continuum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-continuum/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was a far better movie (in my opinion) than &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/">Stargate: The Ark of Truth&lt;/a>. It basically felt like a slightly higher budget two part episode (although those already tended to be good) of the series and actually gave a chance to say goodbye to a few more people: In particularly Ba&amp;rsquo;al (RIP) and O&amp;rsquo;Neill, who really needed it. Not to mention a callback to the real villains of the show: The Goa&amp;rsquo;uld.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate: The Ark of Truth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stargate: The Ark of Truth is the first of two direct-to-video sequels to SG-1. This one picks up after the SG-1 series finale and concludes the Ori arc and throws in a number of other callbacks along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
Lt. Colonel Cameron Mitchell: It's kind of weird not having a big bad guy to fight anymore.
&lt;p>Lt. Colonel Samantha Carter: Yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s how we felt when we defeated the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld. And The Replicators. The first time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 10</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/19/stargate-sg-1-season-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/19/stargate-sg-1-season-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whoo boy. And so it ends. It&amp;rsquo;s a different sort of excellent from the peak of early SG-1, but the new team is really gelling, the Ori are a decent new threat, and it&amp;rsquo;s quite a ride to go out on. Not all shows end so well. I&amp;rsquo;m happy with this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excellent episodes: &lt;b>The Pegasus Project&lt;/b>, crossover with Atlantis! &lt;b>200&lt;/b>, the best parody episode ever. &lt;b>The Quest: Part 1/2&lt;/b>, a big team up with SG-1, Ba&amp;rsquo;al, and even eventually Adria, off to find a magic doodad&amp;ndash;plus, a dragon! &lt;b>The Road Not Taken&lt;/b>, more parallel world shenanigans! &lt;b>The Shroud&lt;/b>, Daniel as a prior!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 9</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/22/stargate-sg-1-season-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/22/stargate-sg-1-season-9/</guid><description>&lt;p>And now we&amp;rsquo;re really getting into the cast shake ups. Richard Dean Anderson has mostly moved on and the powers that be have finally realized the team needs a new lead: So we get Ben Browder as Lt. Colonel Cameron Mitchell. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have minded Carter keeping the reigns and Browder certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t Anderson, but unlike the whole Jonas mess, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to be. He&amp;rsquo;s still a fairly straight laced military leader, but he&amp;rsquo;s his own kind and I really like it. It works out pretty well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 8</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/01/stargate-sg-1-season-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/01/stargate-sg-1-season-8/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things are getting shaken up yet again. O&amp;rsquo;Neill is the big boss now and isn&amp;rsquo;t going on missions any more, leaving SG-1 down a member. Dr. Weir has a new face (Torri Higginson); who will continue the role in Atlantis is kind of weird, but knowing already how well she did there, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see it any other way. Anubis is gone for the moment and the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld are in disarray. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a weird season overall, but things really pick up in the second half with a number of old threats all gaining ground at the same time in one big what could have been series finale.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 7</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/stargate-sg-1-season-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/stargate-sg-1-season-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>Daniel Jackson is back! (they could have done rather a bit more with re-integrating him I think)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beginning of the search for Atlantis! (it&amp;rsquo;s amusing, if a bit annoying how long that takes)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stronger episodes: &lt;em>Lifeboat&lt;/em> (Michael Shanks can really act; the plot is weird and weak but the acting is pretty dang impressive), &lt;em>Heroes&lt;/em> (Oy. Just Oy. It&amp;rsquo;s a slow burn, but very very good), *Lost City( (woo the beginning of Atlantis! on man that battle scene!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/03/stargate-sg-1-season-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/03/stargate-sg-1-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first big shake up of the main SG-1 cast. For better or for worse (or for out of universe negotiating reasons), Daniel Jackson is no longer part of SG-1 (or, truly, this mortal plane), so instead we have Jonas: who&amp;rsquo;s basically a carbon copy of Daniel Jackson, but without all the history. I think he absolutely did a great job&amp;ndash;and props to Corin Nemec for pulling that off&amp;ndash;but I really wish that they could have done something a little more different since they were already shaking things up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/22/stargate-sg-1-season-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/22/stargate-sg-1-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>Great episodes: &lt;em>2001&lt;/em> (echoes of &lt;em>2010&lt;/em> from last season), &lt;em>Wormhole X-Treme!&lt;/em> (the parody episode to end all parody episodes), &lt;em>Summit&lt;/em>/&lt;em>Last Stand&lt;/em> (Goa&amp;rsquo;uld politics! A new bigger bad?!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Less great episodes: &lt;em>Threshold&lt;/em> (Jaffa weirdness and Teal&amp;rsquo;c defection didn&amp;rsquo;t last nearly long enough), &lt;em>Beast of Burden&lt;/em> (we did this already)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Towards the end, we do get one interesting bit of shake up with the &lt;span class="spoiler">death of Daniel Jackson. Of course it's not the first time&lt;/span>
, but I imagine that for anyone watching this in real time, that was quite the shake up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/07/stargate-sg-1-season-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/07/stargate-sg-1-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another great seasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good episodes: &lt;em>Small Victories&lt;/em> (Replicators!), &lt;em>Upgrades&lt;/em> (SG-1 on PCP!), &lt;em>Divide and Conquer&lt;/em> (oh O&amp;rsquo;Neill and Carter&amp;hellip;), and &lt;em>2010&lt;/em> (time travel!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not as great: &lt;em>Crossroads&lt;/em> (Jaffa episodes) and &lt;em>Entity&lt;/em> (we&amp;rsquo;ve done this before).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Best of the Best: &lt;em>Window of Opportunity&lt;/em>. Groundhog Day done Stargate style. It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely wonderful and the only episode I&amp;rsquo;ll just randomly watch out of order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly middling seasons. It&amp;rsquo;s still a great show, but (other than &lt;em>Window of Opportunity&lt;/em>), a general dearth of amazing. So it goes. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/28/stargate-sg-1-season-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/28/stargate-sg-1-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>The good/great:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Fair Game&lt;/em>: Negotiating with the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld with Asgard as mediators!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Legacy&lt;/em>: A typical &amp;lsquo;maybe you were crazy all along&amp;rsquo; episode!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Point of View&lt;/em>: More alternate realities!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Foothold&lt;/em>: Aliens in the SGC!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Urgo&lt;/em>: &amp;ldquo;Comtraya!&amp;rdquo; A wonderful episode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>A Hundred Days&lt;/em>: It&amp;rsquo;s kind of hilarious how often O&amp;rsquo;Neill gets stranded and finds love&amp;hellip; Still a touching story. I just want him to be happy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Crystal Skull&lt;/em>: I love this episode and Daniel&amp;rsquo;s grandfather is hilarious. Unfortunately this is also one of the weaknesses of Stargate: Sometimes we get cool plot points (the giant aliens) that just never come up again. So it goes. Perhaps in the novels?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/17/stargate-sg-1-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/17/stargate-sg-1-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onwards!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SG-1 has saved the world and now they&amp;rsquo;re back to do it again!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We get the introduction of the Tok&amp;rsquo;ra (&lt;em>In the Line of Duty&lt;/em>, etc; Selmac is one of my favorite minor characters of the show), moral questionable decisions (&lt;em>Prisoners&lt;/em>), more Asguard (&lt;em>Thor&amp;rsquo;s Chariot&lt;/em>/&lt;em>The Fifth Race)&lt;/em>, and the NID (&lt;em>Touchstone&lt;/em>), and &lt;em>1969&lt;/em> (time travel!). So many things keep happening and such great episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think one of my favorite episodes of the season is &lt;em>Message in a Bottle&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing what Anderson can act despite being stuck to a wall. &lt;em>The Fifth Race&lt;/em> I love for similar reasons. We get the real acting range of Anderson as he starts to lose himself to an alien device overwriting his brain. Not to mention the implications to the greater Stargate universe that we&amp;rsquo;ll be feeling for seasons to come.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/13/stargate-sg-1-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/13/stargate-sg-1-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man, I love this show.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aafGXNWHGaw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Stargate is one of those shows for me that every time I see a reference to it, every time I hear someone talking about it, it makes me want to watch it again. This will mark at least the 5th time. And that&amp;rsquo;s counting the movie, SG-1 (10 seasons), Atlantis (5 seasons), Universe (2 seasons, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t see them 5 times since I watched them as they came out), and the follow up films. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; a lot of media.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>