<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Eric Pearson on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/eric-pearson/</link><description>Recent content in Eric Pearson on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/eric-pearson/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black Widow</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been to theaters since&amp;hellip; &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/">Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a>. Man it&amp;rsquo;s been a weird few years. Which actually wraps up Black Widow pretty well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly solid action/spy movie. There are a number of spectacular action scenes, a deep dive into Black Widow&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s akin to an origin story, but filling in a character we already knew a decent amount of back rather than introducing someone new, which was nice&amp;ndash;and the introduction of a few new characters I expect we&amp;rsquo;ll see more of. After the absolutely draining intensity of Infinity War/Endgame plus just how dark the followup shows have been, it was nice to have something relatively &amp;rsquo;lighter&amp;rsquo; and smaller in scope.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor: Ragnarok</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ooh, that poster. &lt;em>le kiss&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/">Thor&lt;/a> was &amp;hellip; fine, a weirdly downscale introduction to a kind of strange character early in the MCU. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/">Thor: The Dark World&lt;/a> went the other way, being too bigt and ambitious and suffering somewhat for it. So going into Thor: Ragnarok, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what we were going to get.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An absolute gem of an 80s sci fi/fantasy action superhero comedy that just works. Right from the very intro, you know it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a different sort of movie. They lean hard into the Norse/Asgardian mythos, with Thor in the underworld, chained up (but not concerned) by a giant flaming skeleton who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to signify the end of days. One spectacular Thor&amp;rsquo;ful action scene later and we&amp;rsquo;re back on Asgard, dealing with the missing Odin. Then we&amp;rsquo;re off to Earth, only to bump into Doctor Strange, now fully into his powers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Godzilla vs Kong</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/godzilla-vs-kong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/godzilla-vs-kong/</guid><description>&lt;p>You know, that was more enjoyable than I think it had any right to be. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of movie that would have been far more spectacular on a big screen, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to the theaters in a while, so I&amp;rsquo;ll take smaller.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All around, it&amp;rsquo;s a visual delight. Transporting Kong is hilarious looking. The Hollow Earth is an insane idea, but it&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful world and all of those big beasties to fight are a lot of fun to see. &lt;spoiler>Mechagodzilla&lt;/spoiler> makes even less sense than a lot of the movie / other human ways to fight the monsters. But once again, it makes for a wonderful visual.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>