<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Greg Pak on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/greg-pak/</link><description>Recent content in Greg Pak on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/greg-pak/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Darth Vader, Vol. 1: Dark Heart of the Sith</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/05/darth-vader-vol.-1-dark-heart-of-the-sith/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/05/darth-vader-vol.-1-dark-heart-of-the-sith/</guid><description>&lt;p>Darth Vader, shortly after Luke escapes him in The Empire Strikes Back. Realizing that perhaps he doesn’t actually &lt;em>know&lt;/em> what happened to Padme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Off to trawl through the past. With… quite the droid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/darth-vader-2020-v1-textbundle-108da3.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a fascinating look into Vader forced to dig into Anakin’s past. On Tattoine. On—and under—Naboo. Work the Handmaidens and other from Padme’s life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A fascinating mix. I’m curious where it goes next!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: I can’t imagine reading these issue by issue… dang that’s a cliffhanger in issue 1…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602: New World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/18/marvel-1602-new-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/18/marvel-1602-new-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/17/marvel-1602/">Marvel 1602&lt;/a> established a world where time travel managed to accidentally cause various heroes to be born around the year 1602, now in New World we see more fallout if that story. The 1602 Master Spider of course, but also Lord Iron, Master Jameson and his broadsheet, and, of course, the Hulk—who needs no puny time periodic appropriate name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It feels like somewhat smaller a story than the original 1602 and more like we’re reading something that we’ve seen before, just with a new coat of paint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still fun though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>