<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mrs. Piggle Wiggle on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mrs.-piggle-wiggle/</link><description>Recent content in Mrs. Piggle Wiggle on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mrs.-piggle-wiggle/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Happy Birthday, Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/happy-birthday-mrs.-piggle-wiggle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/happy-birthday-mrs.-piggle-wiggle/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends&amp;hellip; 50 years later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is an interesting one. Apparently, it was largely written by the original author&amp;rsquo;s daughter with the first story an unpublished original and the rest based on &amp;rsquo;notes among her mother&amp;rsquo;s possessions&amp;rsquo;. For the most part, it fits. And ending it all with a party celebrating the titular Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello, Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/hello-mrs.-piggle-wiggle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/hello-mrs.-piggle-wiggle/</guid><description>&lt;p>Somehow, Mrs. Piggle-Returned. And the complete lack of any mention of her farm is just about as weird as when Star Wars did it. Add to that another complete reliance on random magical pills and powders&amp;hellip; this one is also not my favorite, although I prefer it slightly to [[Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle&amp;rsquo;s Magic]].&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/mrs.-piggle-wiggle/">Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle&lt;/a> for my thoughts for the series as a whole.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle's Farm</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/mrs.-piggle-wiggles-farm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/mrs.-piggle-wiggles-farm/</guid><description>&lt;p>My thoughts for the series as a whole are on the review for &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/mrs.-piggle-wiggle/">Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For &amp;hellip; reasons, Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle has moved out of town to a farm. Here, she takes the problem children and uses (farm style) household chores in order to help them be better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It actually really works&amp;ndash;and is so much less likely than [[Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle&amp;rsquo;s Magic]]. I think this might actually be my favorite. It&amp;rsquo;s weird, writing this out, to realize how relatively few stories this one had though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle's Magic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/mrs.-piggle-wiggles-magic/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/mrs.-piggle-wiggles-magic/</guid><description>&lt;p>My thoughts for the series as a whole are on the review for &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/mrs.-piggle-wiggle/">Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle&lt;/a>. Really, if I&amp;rsquo;d only read that book and this one, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I would have continued the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first, we have fairly mundane and reasonable solutions to realistic childhood issues. In this one&amp;ndash;straight out magic. I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge fan, especially with the tonal shift. But I do really like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/mrs.-piggle-wiggles-farm/">Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle’s Farm&lt;/a> and (perhaps surprisingly) &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/happy-birthday-mrs.-piggle-wiggle/">Happy Birthday, Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle&lt;/a>, so I&amp;rsquo;m glad I continued.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, this one does have some fun moments (the Tattletales, Lester the pig with his table manners), so it&amp;rsquo;s not all bad!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/mrs.-piggle-wiggle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/18/mrs.-piggle-wiggle/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle books are an interesting sort of children&amp;rsquo;s tales. Throughout the books, we&amp;rsquo;re introduced to familys with strange names, where always and without fail, the children are in some way, shape, or form misbehaving. One thing leads to another, their mother&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> is at her wit&amp;rsquo;s end, and&amp;hellip; they call Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle and she saves the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Originally published 1947-1957, the first four books are very much a product of their times. The family dynamics, the problems the children have, and even some of the (less magical) solutions. Yet a lot of the problems ring true, even today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to the 4 of the 5 books we&amp;rsquo;ve found audiobooks for in a somewhat random order. Mostly, the order doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. Each story is fairly self contained&amp;ndash;with the exception of book 3: Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle&amp;rsquo;s farm, in which she&amp;rsquo;s moved out of town. Except in book 4, she&amp;rsquo;s back and no mention is made ever again. Anyways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last, published in book 5, actually fits fairly well with the first 4, despite the fact that it was published 50 years later by MacDonald&amp;rsquo;s daughter. Honestly, on just listening to them, it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel all that different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the main decider on if I&amp;rsquo;d like a particular story or not depended entirely on how magical the solution was. While they&amp;rsquo;re all somewhat unbelievable (a day or two staying up late curing a TV addiction? sure), I like the ones with a practical solution. In particular, Mrs. Piggle-Wiggle (1), her Farm (3), and Happy Birthday (5) are my favorites. Conversely, her Magic (2) and Hello (4) are much more about magical pills and tonics that miraculously solve problems&amp;ndash;not particularly applicable that, even if they are fun to read about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, they&amp;rsquo;re a lot of fun to read/listen to and I don&amp;rsquo;t expect they&amp;rsquo;ll go away any time soon.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>