<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>V.E. Schwab on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/05/v.e.-schwab/</link><description>Recent content in V.E. Schwab on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/05/v.e.-schwab/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Invisible Life of Addie LaRue</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/05/the-invisible-life-of-addie-larue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/05/the-invisible-life-of-addie-larue/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Seven freckles. One for every love she’d have, that’s what Estele had said, when the girl was still young. One for every life she’d lead. One for every god watching over her. Now, they mock her, those seven marks. Promises. Lies. She’s had no loves, she’s lived no lives, she’s met no gods, and now she is out of time.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Addie LaRue is a story about making deals with the devil. A story about living forever. A story about living a life where no one seems to see you for you or to pay you any mind.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Conjuring of Light</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/29/a-conjuring-of-light/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/29/a-conjuring-of-light/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends. Where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/21/a-gathering-of-shadows/">A Gathering of Shadows&lt;/a> was the bright(ish) interlude, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/29/a-conjuring-of-light/">A Conjuring of Light&lt;/a> goes dark quick. The magic that killed Black London is free in Red London and trying it&amp;rsquo;s damnedest to &amp;hellip; take over the world? It&amp;rsquo;s a little unclear. I guess a piece of sentient magic gets a pass on the &amp;rsquo;evil for the sake of being evil&amp;rsquo; card.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, we don&amp;rsquo;t really have anyone know, although we get a lot more of Rhy who actually gets to explore being given a literal second chance at life and what it means to be king. Speaking of which, King Maxim and Queen Emira had a lot going for them. I &amp;hellip; just wish they were developed a bit more. Rhy&amp;rsquo;s relationship with Alucard gets a fair bit more time. It&amp;rsquo;s complicated (in a good way) and well done. I wish them the best.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Gathering of Shadows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/21/a-gathering-of-shadows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/21/a-gathering-of-shadows/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Oh yes, your relationship with Miss Bard is positively ordinary.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Be quiet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Crossing worlds, killing royals, saving cities. The marks of every good courtship.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>A Darker Shade of Magic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/11/a-darker-shade-of-magic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/11/a-darker-shade-of-magic/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/11/a-darker-shade-of-magic/">A Darker Shade of Magic&lt;/a> is a surprisingly fantastic book&amp;ndash;and I mean that in the true sense of the word &lt;em>fantastic&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The core worldbuilding conceit of the book is that of four parallel worlds, specifically four Londons. Gray London (our London?), a dull world with little to no magic left; Red London, with magic full of life; White London, with a more sharp and controlling feel; and lost Black London. The feel and description of each London really makes the book, with Schwab evoking each London with colors and scents and even feelings. It&amp;rsquo;s a really interesting take and done rather well.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>