<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cherie Dimaline on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/cherie-dimaline/</link><description>Recent content in Cherie Dimaline on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/cherie-dimaline/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Never Whistle at Night: An Indigenous Dark Fiction Anthology</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/03/never-whistle-at-night-an-indigenous-dark-fiction-anthology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/03/never-whistle-at-night-an-indigenous-dark-fiction-anthology/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Indigenous people believe that one should never whistle at night. This belief takes many forms: for instance, Native Hawaiians believe it summons the Hukai’po, the spirits of ancient warriors, and Native Mexicans say it calls Lechuza, a witch that can transform into an owl. But what all these legends hold in common is the certainty that whistling at night can cause evil spirits to appear—and even follow you home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A collection of two dozen horror (and otherwise dark fiction) stories by a wide variety of indigenous authors. Three of which I&amp;rsquo;d read before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/rebecca-roanhorse/"&gt;Rebecca Roanhorse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/darcie-little-badger/"&gt;Darcie Little Badger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/cherie-dimaline/"&gt;Cherie Dimaline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like any anthology there are some stories in here that I didn&amp;rsquo;t care much for&amp;ndash;and some that really hit hard. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating new look (for me) into all sorts of new and interesting creepy things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And all too often, you might just find that people are people. And people are scarier than any monster out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for these next pages, let these writers take you by the hand, lead you into the darkness at the heart of—let me put some quotation marks around it—“America.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>VenCo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/29/venco/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/29/venco/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hold on a minute,” Lucky said. So far, the stories weren’t making things any clearer. “I don’t get it. Did someone give us the spoons?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, yes, in a manner of speaking,” Meena said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But I found mine. You both found yours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In a secret tunnel off your basement?” Lettie replied. “Really? Hanging from a spider web in a graveyard on a specific day?
At the bottom of a box of donated books? Statistically improbable.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Never mind probability, what about the laws of nature? The world cannot be just a series of randoms,” Freya chimed in. “Might as well believe in some beardo in the sky.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a book about spoons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And witches, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, I know there are Wiccans, right? Like a religion?” No one gave her any indication she was on the right path, so she kept talking. “And there are Halloween witches—like vampires and demons and all that. And I know about the bullshit witch trials. Thousands of women burned at the stake for being smart or queer or loud. I guess that’s about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But really about spoons.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>