<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Rings of Power on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/14/the-rings-of-power/</link><description>Recent content in The Rings of Power on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 23:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/14/the-rings-of-power/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Rings of Power: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/14/the-rings-of-power-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/14/the-rings-of-power-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are &lt;em>way&lt;/em> too many storylines in this show. For episodes at a time, we may not see elves. Or dwarves. Or Gandalf-but-still-not-Gandalf. I keep getting to the start of an episode and thinking &amp;lsquo;oh hey, we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen them in a while&amp;rsquo;. But the interesting thing is that I got to the end of the episodes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s what we saw in the first season, but even more so. There are so many different threads and events&amp;ndash;things separated by decades if not centuries in the original works all crammed together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But on the other hand, we get more rings! (Up from zero &amp;#x1f604;) We get bigger battles! (Not quite Helm&amp;rsquo;s Deep, but close) More Tom Bombadil! (You&amp;rsquo;ll just have to watch to see if you think I&amp;rsquo;m making that one up) And we get more &amp;hellip; humanized orcs with families and children? I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;hellip; not entirely sure what to think about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall&amp;hellip; it mostly reminds me just &lt;em>good&lt;/em> the Peter Jackson movies were. But it&amp;rsquo;s certainly watchable and I&amp;rsquo;ll catch whatever season(s) come next. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Rings of Power: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/the-rings-of-power-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/the-rings-of-power-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that’s quite the thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They couldn’t/didn’t get the rights to the third age, so instead we get much older stories. Stories after the fall of Morgoth but still during the end of the era of Elves and Númenor. Before the rise of the kingdoms of Men.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s a lot crammed into eight episodes. One might argue too much. Leaves some stories a bit thin. But really, having seen them, I don’t know what I’d cut.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a watch. Looking forward to season two!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>