<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stargate Atlantis on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/stargate-atlantis/</link><description>Recent content in Stargate Atlantis on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/stargate-atlantis/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/23/stargate-atlantis-season-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/23/stargate-atlantis-season-5/</guid><description>And so it ends.
I do sorely wish that Atlantis could have gotten another season. There are some very strong episodes in this seaon. As much as I liked Weir and Carter, Woolsey is another huge case of character improvement (almost as much as McKay).
Mini-reviews (potential spoilers):
Search and Rescue: Half a closed room, buried deep in a collapsed building, half Teyla. Neither quite what I was hoping for.</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/10/stargate-atlantis-season-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/10/stargate-atlantis-season-4/</guid><description>Onward!
It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy season in how it begins (lost in space!) and ends (lost in time!). More replicators, more wraith, more variations thereof. A handful of smaller episodes with only small combinations of main cast really shine. We lose a few of the big leads and gain a few more old names. It&amp;rsquo;s also always interesting how shows deal with the pregnancy of a main cast member.
Onwards and Season 5-wards!</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/stargate-atlantis-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/stargate-atlantis-season-3/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like in this series. We get new, complicate Wraith threats (Michael and Todd!), Replicators, lost Ancients, and some of the best McKay episodes in the show (McKay and Mrs. Miller and Tao of Rodney). Not to mention Lucius Lavin. No really. :) And then there&amp;rsquo;s Sunday&amp;hellip; Man it sucks to kill off major characters just to raise the stakes, but it still works as an episode.</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/09/stargate-atlantis-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/09/stargate-atlantis-season-2/</guid><description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a beginning and ending, with a whole lot in between. One of the biggest changes is the introduction of Ronan Dex. Replacement for Lt. Ford who has a tendency to shoot first and ask questions&amp;ndash;well, never. He&amp;rsquo;s quite the character and a good addition to the team. Interesting that the main team is half from Pegasus now.
Mini-reviews (potential spoilers):
Siege, Part 3: Man this is a fun three parter.</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/29/stargate-atlantis-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/29/stargate-atlantis-season-1/</guid><description>And so it begins again.
While Stargate SG-1 really has a solid place in my heart, in a way I like Atlantis even better. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it could have been what it is without SG-1, but with it, it&amp;rsquo;s made even better.
You have a generally optimistic can do attitude, backed up by McKay quite often saving the day (which is crazy coming off SG-1, I forgot how annoying he is and just how much he grows throughout the seasons of Atlantis).</description></item></channel></rss>