<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ben Sharpsteen on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/12/ben-sharpsteen/</link><description>Recent content in Ben Sharpsteen on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/12/ben-sharpsteen/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/12/snow-white-and-the-seven-dwarfs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/12/snow-white-and-the-seven-dwarfs/</guid><description>&lt;p>An almost 100 year old movie, based on a story likely at least a century older, combining aspects of stories who knows how old, animated for the modern (of the time) movie going audience. It&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of a truely delightful era&amp;ndash;that of the Disney animated classics. While they&amp;rsquo;ve certainly got their problems (the rather traditional gender roles and Disney&amp;rsquo;s ongoing copyright battles to name a pair), they&amp;rsquo;re still something elegant and innocent about them and Snow White is no exception.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/13/the-many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/13/the-many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh is just delightful&amp;ndash;and a blast of nostalgia on top of that. I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to actually watch all of the Disney classic growing up (still haven&amp;rsquo;t), but I definiately watched this one. And now, after reading many of the stories to my children, it&amp;rsquo;s a delight to be able to share the video form with them as well!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really like the style of these stories. It&amp;rsquo;s a mix of animated world with the real storybook characters (Pooh et al), but also obviously in a book, as they hob from page to page. It&amp;rsquo;s not the story of style you&amp;rsquo;d always expect to work, but it really works here.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>