<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>J. Michael Straczynski on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/j.-michael-straczynski/</link><description>Recent content in J. Michael Straczynski on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/j.-michael-straczynski/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Underworld: Awakening</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/16/underworld-awakening/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/16/underworld-awakening/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while. Both since watching {{crosslink &amp;ldquo;Underworld: Rise of the Lycans&amp;rdquo;}} and in universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like the idea of advancing the world. Bringing the Vampires and the Lycans out into the open. And the humans &lt;em&gt;winning&lt;/em&gt; as, with their numbers, makes enough sense in this universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selene: For 12 years, I was held captive by the humans. The world I once knew has changed. Vampires and Lycans are now the hunted.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Thor</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Thor is an odd sort of movie for the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marvel%20Cinematic%20Universe"&gt;Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/a&gt;. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s our first foray into the more &amp;lsquo;magical&amp;rsquo; side of the universe, with ancient Gods and the like. Although in this universe, we&amp;rsquo;re led to believe that it&amp;rsquo;s really just highly advanced science. On the other hand, despite a worlds spanning plot (literally, 3 of them), it still feels oddly &amp;hellip; small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plotwise&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s weird. We&amp;rsquo;re supposed to believe that Odin is over a thousand years old and Thor is&amp;hellip; just now coming into his kingship now? How long does it take for them to grow up? And Asgardians at some level can die in battle, but in others handle getting thrown around and hit by cars just fine? It&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip; a little weird. The idea of Thor being a spoiled young man and having to show his worthiness is a solid enough plot (and a common enough Thor origin story); although it all comes together a mite quickly for him. And then the final battle&amp;ndash;while it looks cool enough I guess, it&amp;rsquo;s all feels like they could have used a bit more time and money to fill things in a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>World War Z</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/06/28/world-war-z/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 04:55:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/06/28/world-war-z/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World War Z on amazon.com" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0770437400/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0770437400&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=jverkampcom-20"&gt;World War Z&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty awesome book, showing the aftermath of a decade long zombie war, accounting for the various changes (religious, political, and otherwise) that such an event would bring about. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it (and aren&amp;rsquo;t completely anti-zombie), I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it enough. It&amp;rsquo;s really a neat book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="World War Z on IMDb" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0816711/"&gt;World War Z&lt;/a&gt;, on the other hand, is a pretty good film and has next to nothing to do with the book&amp;ndash;other than the title and the semi-eponymous zombie threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read nothing else here, just know this: just forget about the book for a few hours. It will make the movie that much better.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>