<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stargate SG-1 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-sg-1/</link><description>Recent content in Stargate SG-1 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:00:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-sg-1/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stargate: Continuum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-continuum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-continuum/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was a far better movie (in my opinion) than &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/">Stargate: The Ark of Truth&lt;/a>. It basically felt like a slightly higher budget two part episode (although those already tended to be good) of the series and actually gave a chance to say goodbye to a few more people: In particularly Ba&amp;rsquo;al (RIP) and O&amp;rsquo;Neill, who really needed it. Not to mention a callback to the real villains of the show: The Goa&amp;rsquo;uld.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate: The Ark of Truth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stargate: The Ark of Truth is the first of two direct-to-video sequels to SG-1. This one picks up after the SG-1 series finale and concludes the Ori arc and throws in a number of other callbacks along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
Lt. Colonel Cameron Mitchell: It's kind of weird not having a big bad guy to fight anymore.
&lt;p>Lt. Colonel Samantha Carter: Yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s how we felt when we defeated the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld. And The Replicators. The first time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 10</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/19/stargate-sg-1-season-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/19/stargate-sg-1-season-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whoo boy. And so it ends. It&amp;rsquo;s a different sort of excellent from the peak of early SG-1, but the new team is really gelling, the Ori are a decent new threat, and it&amp;rsquo;s quite a ride to go out on. Not all shows end so well. I&amp;rsquo;m happy with this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Excellent episodes: &lt;b>The Pegasus Project&lt;/b>, crossover with Atlantis! &lt;b>200&lt;/b>, the best parody episode ever. &lt;b>The Quest: Part 1/2&lt;/b>, a big team up with SG-1, Ba&amp;rsquo;al, and even eventually Adria, off to find a magic doodad&amp;ndash;plus, a dragon! &lt;b>The Road Not Taken&lt;/b>, more parallel world shenanigans! &lt;b>The Shroud&lt;/b>, Daniel as a prior!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 9</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/22/stargate-sg-1-season-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/22/stargate-sg-1-season-9/</guid><description>&lt;p>And now we&amp;rsquo;re really getting into the cast shake ups. Richard Dean Anderson has mostly moved on and the powers that be have finally realized the team needs a new lead: So we get Ben Browder as Lt. Colonel Cameron Mitchell. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have minded Carter keeping the reigns and Browder certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t Anderson, but unlike the whole Jonas mess, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to be. He&amp;rsquo;s still a fairly straight laced military leader, but he&amp;rsquo;s his own kind and I really like it. It works out pretty well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 8</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/01/stargate-sg-1-season-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/01/stargate-sg-1-season-8/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things are getting shaken up yet again. O&amp;rsquo;Neill is the big boss now and isn&amp;rsquo;t going on missions any more, leaving SG-1 down a member. Dr. Weir has a new face (Torri Higginson); who will continue the role in Atlantis is kind of weird, but knowing already how well she did there, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see it any other way. Anubis is gone for the moment and the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld are in disarray. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a weird season overall, but things really pick up in the second half with a number of old threats all gaining ground at the same time in one big what could have been series finale.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 7</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/stargate-sg-1-season-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/stargate-sg-1-season-7/</guid><description>&lt;p>Daniel Jackson is back! (they could have done rather a bit more with re-integrating him I think)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beginning of the search for Atlantis! (it&amp;rsquo;s amusing, if a bit annoying how long that takes)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stronger episodes: &lt;em>Lifeboat&lt;/em> (Michael Shanks can really act; the plot is weird and weak but the acting is pretty dang impressive), &lt;em>Heroes&lt;/em> (Oy. Just Oy. It&amp;rsquo;s a slow burn, but very very good), *Lost City( (woo the beginning of Atlantis! on man that battle scene!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/03/stargate-sg-1-season-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/03/stargate-sg-1-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first big shake up of the main SG-1 cast. For better or for worse (or for out of universe negotiating reasons), Daniel Jackson is no longer part of SG-1 (or, truly, this mortal plane), so instead we have Jonas: who&amp;rsquo;s basically a carbon copy of Daniel Jackson, but without all the history. I think he absolutely did a great job&amp;ndash;and props to Corin Nemec for pulling that off&amp;ndash;but I really wish that they could have done something a little more different since they were already shaking things up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/22/stargate-sg-1-season-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/22/stargate-sg-1-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>Great episodes: &lt;em>2001&lt;/em> (echoes of &lt;em>2010&lt;/em> from last season), &lt;em>Wormhole X-Treme!&lt;/em> (the parody episode to end all parody episodes), &lt;em>Summit&lt;/em>/&lt;em>Last Stand&lt;/em> (Goa&amp;rsquo;uld politics! A new bigger bad?!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Less great episodes: &lt;em>Threshold&lt;/em> (Jaffa weirdness and Teal&amp;rsquo;c defection didn&amp;rsquo;t last nearly long enough), &lt;em>Beast of Burden&lt;/em> (we did this already)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Towards the end, we do get one interesting bit of shake up with the &lt;span class="spoiler">death of Daniel Jackson. Of course it's not the first time&lt;/span>
, but I imagine that for anyone watching this in real time, that was quite the shake up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/07/stargate-sg-1-season-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/07/stargate-sg-1-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another great seasons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good episodes: &lt;em>Small Victories&lt;/em> (Replicators!), &lt;em>Upgrades&lt;/em> (SG-1 on PCP!), &lt;em>Divide and Conquer&lt;/em> (oh O&amp;rsquo;Neill and Carter&amp;hellip;), and &lt;em>2010&lt;/em> (time travel!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not as great: &lt;em>Crossroads&lt;/em> (Jaffa episodes) and &lt;em>Entity&lt;/em> (we&amp;rsquo;ve done this before).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Best of the Best: &lt;em>Window of Opportunity&lt;/em>. Groundhog Day done Stargate style. It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely wonderful and the only episode I&amp;rsquo;ll just randomly watch out of order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly middling seasons. It&amp;rsquo;s still a great show, but (other than &lt;em>Window of Opportunity&lt;/em>), a general dearth of amazing. So it goes. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/28/stargate-sg-1-season-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/28/stargate-sg-1-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>The good/great:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Fair Game&lt;/em>: Negotiating with the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld with Asgard as mediators!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Legacy&lt;/em>: A typical &amp;lsquo;maybe you were crazy all along&amp;rsquo; episode!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Point of View&lt;/em>: More alternate realities!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Foothold&lt;/em>: Aliens in the SGC!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Urgo&lt;/em>: &amp;ldquo;Comtraya!&amp;rdquo; A wonderful episode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>A Hundred Days&lt;/em>: It&amp;rsquo;s kind of hilarious how often O&amp;rsquo;Neill gets stranded and finds love&amp;hellip; Still a touching story. I just want him to be happy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Crystal Skull&lt;/em>: I love this episode and Daniel&amp;rsquo;s grandfather is hilarious. Unfortunately this is also one of the weaknesses of Stargate: Sometimes we get cool plot points (the giant aliens) that just never come up again. So it goes. Perhaps in the novels?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/17/stargate-sg-1-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/17/stargate-sg-1-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onwards!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>SG-1 has saved the world and now they&amp;rsquo;re back to do it again!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We get the introduction of the Tok&amp;rsquo;ra (&lt;em>In the Line of Duty&lt;/em>, etc; Selmac is one of my favorite minor characters of the show), moral questionable decisions (&lt;em>Prisoners&lt;/em>), more Asguard (&lt;em>Thor&amp;rsquo;s Chariot&lt;/em>/&lt;em>The Fifth Race)&lt;/em>, and the NID (&lt;em>Touchstone&lt;/em>), and &lt;em>1969&lt;/em> (time travel!). So many things keep happening and such great episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think one of my favorite episodes of the season is &lt;em>Message in a Bottle&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing what Anderson can act despite being stuck to a wall. &lt;em>The Fifth Race&lt;/em> I love for similar reasons. We get the real acting range of Anderson as he starts to lose himself to an alien device overwriting his brain. Not to mention the implications to the greater Stargate universe that we&amp;rsquo;ll be feeling for seasons to come.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/13/stargate-sg-1-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/13/stargate-sg-1-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man, I love this show.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aafGXNWHGaw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Stargate is one of those shows for me that every time I see a reference to it, every time I hear someone talking about it, it makes me want to watch it again. This will mark at least the 5th time. And that&amp;rsquo;s counting the movie, SG-1 (10 seasons), Atlantis (5 seasons), Universe (2 seasons, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t see them 5 times since I watched them as they came out), and the follow up films. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; a lot of media.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>