<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Poppy War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/08/the-poppy-war/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/08/the-poppy-war/</guid><description>War doesn&amp;rsquo;t determine who&amp;rsquo;s right. War determines who remains.
That&amp;hellip; is quite a book.
Plotwise, for the first third or so, it&amp;rsquo;s a very solid &amp;lsquo;poor girl works very hard and gets into a prestigious (military) school&amp;rsquo;. Once there, she&amp;rsquo;s outcast and has to fight (literally) for her place. On top of that, she bumps into the mysterious &amp;lsquo;Lore&amp;rsquo; master who everyone thinks is nuts&amp;ndash;but just might know a bit about the magic no one believes in any more.</description></item><item><title>Daemon Voices</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="35478763" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35478763.daemon-voices">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/daemon-voices.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He is interested in the discoveries of science (“intellectual daring and imaginative brilliance without parallel”), the freedoms of democracy (in particular “the great democracy of reading and writing”), the evils of authoritarianism (“always reductive whether it’s in power or not”) and the pitfalls of education (“any education that neglects the experience of delight will be a dry and tasteless diet with no nourishment in it”). He is profoundly interested in religion, while remaining puzzled by aspects of it. “The first thing to say about the Bishop’s arguments in his book,” he writes in “God and Dust,” “is that I agree with every word of them, except the words I don’t understand; and that the words I don’t understand are those such as spirit, spiritual and God.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Philip Pullman is an interesting author, which makes Daemon Voices an interesting sort of book. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a selected collection of essays and presentation he&amp;rsquo;s given over the years on a wide range of topics. In particular, he talks a lot about Paradise Lost (makes me want to actually read it), his religious and philosophical views (and a dive into Gnosticism) and how those interact with his writing, and a bit on writing advice and his own particular style.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating look and there&amp;rsquo;s a little for everyone, so if you like what Pullman has written, you can certainly do worse than give it a chance!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below are a few interesting quotes that I highlighted for just about every essay. It&amp;rsquo;s not really the sort of book where one should worry about spoilers, but just in case that&amp;rsquo;s not a shared option, you have been warned. (Also: &lt;em>long&lt;/em>)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 16: The Wild Card</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/05/hellblazer-vol.-16-the-wild-card/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/05/hellblazer-vol.-16-the-wild-card/</guid><description>A crazy bloody mess with some old friends in the longer stories and a few neat bits in the short ones. But more of Angela and Gemma.
A rather solid volume.
Thoughts as I read (spoilers):
High on Life Constantine with brown hair?! (Might be red) What’s this?
Bit of an ass.
Using his blood to heal/as a pick me up is quite the trick.
That’s a neat trick…</description></item><item><title>The Last Uncharted Sky</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/28/the-last-uncharted-sky/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/28/the-last-uncharted-sky/</guid><description>Where An Alchemy of Masques and Mirrors was mystery and religious fiddling and A Labyrinth of Scions and Sorcery was a political story, culminating in a fall of power (or at least a shift), The Last Uncharted Sky shifts yet again. This time we have a (aero)nautical adventure with skyships, pirates, lost treasures, and found families. Really, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful exploration of just how wonderful and strange the world we&amp;rsquo;ve been allowed to inhabit for just a little while.</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 15: Highwater</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/13/hellblazer-vol.-15-highwater/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/13/hellblazer-vol.-15-highwater/</guid><description>It’s… fine? I enjoyed the first two longer stories well enough but the latter one was all kinds of weird. And not in a way I cared for?
Onward! Maybe to something new?
Individual thoughts (spoilers):
Lapdogs and Englishmen That’s what I was looking for. Great art style, interesting story. Bit of magic (ish), bits of fate.
Oh Constantine. It fits though. 5
And then suddenly young punk Constantine.</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 14: Good Intentions</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/11/hellblazer-vol.-14-good-intentions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/11/hellblazer-vol.-14-good-intentions/</guid><description>That’s a few hard hitting stories. Hard Times is about Constantine in prison. Weird art style and hard to read. Good Intentions is the aftermath… people are terrible. Freezes Over it’s a pretty good locked room mystery with just the possibility of something more.
Overall, good but not the best Constantine. Needs more out and out unambiguous supernatural IMO.
Onwards!
Thoughts/spoilers:
Hard Time (Parts 1-5) Been a while. Came back to…</description></item><item><title>Biological Bits: A brief guide to the ideas and artefacts of computational artificial life</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/10/biological-bits-a-brief-guide-to-the-ideas-and-artefacts-of-computational-artificial-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/10/biological-bits-a-brief-guide-to-the-ideas-and-artefacts-of-computational-artificial-life/</guid><description>Came across a reddit thread about this book. I&amp;rsquo;ve long been interested in alife, artificial evolution, simulated creatures, etc, and have been looking to add back in more non-fiction so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d go ahead and give it a whirl.
Overal though, it seems&amp;hellip; rather lackluster. I guess if you&amp;rsquo;re just getting into the field, it&amp;rsquo;s a good summary of what all is involved, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get more than a page into detail about absolutely anything.</description></item><item><title>A Labyrinth of Scions and Sorcery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/a-labyrinth-of-scions-and-sorcery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/a-labyrinth-of-scions-and-sorcery/</guid><description>An Alchemy of Masques and Mirrors was a delightful surprise of a book, with unique/excellent worldbuilding, fun characters, great wordsmithing, and a solid mystery of a plot. A Labyrinth of Scions and Sorcery has all three once again, although we mostly lose the mystery of the of first book and get a bunch of politics instead. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s still great, it just took me a bit to get into the tonal shift.</description></item><item><title>The Wyrmling Horde</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/the-wyrmling-horde/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/the-wyrmling-horde/</guid><description>I think that for the most part The Wyrmling Horde takes everything I mentioned in Worldbinder and does a bit more of that. There are some really fascinating worldbuilding ideas being explored here, although I miss the smaller scope of just the Endowments and possibly the wizards of the early books. The characters are cool&amp;ndash;and I do actually find the inversions of several of them fascinating&amp;ndash;but we&amp;rsquo;re also missing a few faces that I really wish we would see more of.</description></item><item><title>Brothers of War The Iron Brigade at Gettysburg</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/03/brothers-of-war-the-iron-brigade-at-gettysburg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/03/brothers-of-war-the-iron-brigade-at-gettysburg/</guid><description>“But at a great cost,” Williams continued, looking at the men and pointing in the direction where the Nineteenth suffered so horrendously. “The cost will be felt in hundreds of homes, factories, and farms back in Indiana…not only now, but for generations. Although we’ll be forever saddened by the price that the Nineteenth has paid on this field, we should always remember that those lives and limbs were not lost in vain.</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 13: Haunted</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/11/hellblazer-vol.-13-haunted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/11/hellblazer-vol.-13-haunted/</guid><description>One heck of a crazy longer story (Haunted, one of the best of that length) and a bunch of shorter ones, ranging from not much to really good.
Mini-reviews and pretty pictures (spoilers):
Haunted That’s a story. Enough time to breathe, a cast of new and interesting story, and all sorts of gross and creepy scenes.
Part One Oy. Although you can’t say she’s wrong.
Murder scene description: oy that’s graphic.</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 12: How to Play with Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/07/hellblazer-vol.-12-how-to-play-with-fire/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/07/hellblazer-vol.-12-how-to-play-with-fire/</guid><description>Three multiple parters? No single issues? Sweet. Up the Down Staircase want my favorite, but both How to Play with Fire and Son of Man were excellent.
Mini reviews, pretty (horrifying) pictures and spoilers:
Up the Down Staircase Memes? I feel like I missed something. Interesting character development, but no real pay off.
Part One You are dating the wrong man.
Other than that, we have a fairly standard meet the family type scene.</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 11: Last Man Standing</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/03/hellblazer-vol.-11-last-man-standing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/03/hellblazer-vol.-11-last-man-standing/</guid><description>A solid one. Big stories are interesting, little ones are touching_weird_sweet, and Constantine’s got some new people and problems to deal with. Nothing too surreal either, which I appreciate.
Mini-reviews (spoilers):
Days of Wine and Roses A little bit of Constantine, a little bit of regular human terror.
The Wild Hunt Oh my.
Also: Colts!
Last Man Standing Argue and his men as ancient immortals? Merlin as a dragon?</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 10: In the Line of Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/01/hellblazer-vol.-10-in-the-line-of-fire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/01/hellblazer-vol.-10-in-the-line-of-fire/</guid><description>Fortune telling, Constantine’s father, more evil demons and arguably worse angels, and of course dead soldiers who can’t find rest.
Not a standout volume, but still pretty good.
Mini reviews (spoilers):
The Nature of the Beast Sure…
Reading the future is a common enough trope in this genre, but I enjoyed it.
Walking the Dog Another ghost story&amp;hellip;
…ish.
Oops. A neat twist.
Punkin’ Up the Great Outdoors Going to be a weird one:</description></item></channel></rss>