<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 23: No Future</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/11/hellblazer-vol.-23-no-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/11/hellblazer-vol.-23-no-future/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="52476989" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/52476989.hellblazer-vol-23-no-future">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-23-no-future.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>An interesting collection. Constantine in India, looking for purity. Punk and the Conservatives. Nergal and Bast’s … cousin, maybe? And Papa Midnite backstory. A lot of leaning on the past, but neat stories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Closed and Common Orbit</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/10/a-closed-and-common-orbit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/10/a-closed-and-common-orbit/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="29475447" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29475447.a-closed-and-common-orbit">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-closed-and-common-orbit.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Life is terrifying. None of us have a rule book. None of us know what we&amp;rsquo;re doing here. So, the easiest way to stare reality in the face and not utterly lose your shit is to believe that you have control over it. If you believe you have control, then you believe you&amp;rsquo;re at the top. And if you&amp;rsquo;re at the top, then people who aren&amp;rsquo;t like you&amp;hellip; well, they&amp;rsquo;ve got to be somewhere lower, right? Every species does this. Does it again and again and again. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if they do it to themselves, or another species, or someone they created.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh. Wow. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/">The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet&lt;/a> felt like lightning in a bottle. Something amazing&amp;ndash;a look at the life in a long haul spaceship full of strange and wonderful characters&amp;ndash;that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how it could possibly be continued.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out&amp;hellip; just like this. This is a very very good sequel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, A Closed and Common Orbit was a bit of a surprise. We only barely get any of the characters we know and love from the first book. There are a few hints of and references to them, but for the most part, we instead focus on Lovey/Sidra* and Pepper, learning once again how two very strange and different sorts of people can grow into a family. The same general idea, approached a totally different way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All Systems Red</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="32758901" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32758901.all-systems-red">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/all-systems-red.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Okay, I get what all the hype is about. Take a heavily armed cyborg/clone, designed entirely as muscle to defend the more squishy &amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; humans, have it turn off the software constraining it from killing everyone, add in a wonderfully snarky sense of humor&amp;hellip; and see what happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I COULD HAVE BECOME a mass murderer after I hacked my governor module, but then I realized I could access the combined feed of entertainment channels carried on the company satellites. It had been well over 35,000 hours or so since then, with still not much murdering, but probably, I don’t know, a little under 35,000 hours of movies, serials, books, plays, and music consumed. As a heartless killing machine, I was a terrible failure.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 22: Regeneration</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/04/hellblazer-vol.-22-regeneration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/04/hellblazer-vol.-22-regeneration/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="45429584" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/45429584.hellblazer-vol-22-regeneration">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-22-regeneration.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Some holiday cheer (nothing deep but they’re neat enough), a new girl gone very very wrong, and Chas getting to be the hero. A good volume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Individual readalong reviews. Spoilers:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022 Book Bingo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/01/2022-book-bingo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/01/2022-book-bingo/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s do this again! I barely made it, but there were so many books that I absolutely ended up loving that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I otherwise would have read. So this year, better!
Rules:
Must be speculative fiction (SF, fantasy, horror with speculative elements) Limit the number of novellas (fewer than 40k words or defined by the author as such) or combine them A book of short stories counts Graphic novels/manga should be treated as novellas Web novels count (if they&amp;rsquo;re long enough) Audiobooks count Official thread</description></item><item><title>The Scorpio Races</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-scorpio-races/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-scorpio-races/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="10626594" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10626594.the-scorpio-races">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-scorpio-races.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There are moments that you&amp;rsquo;ll remember for the rest of your life and there are moments that you think you&amp;rsquo;ll remember for the rest of your life, and it&amp;rsquo;s not often they turn out to be the same moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s island life&amp;ndash;a small town, far out on the water that lives and dies by the one big event a year. Just in this case, that one event is a race involving murderous meat eating horses that come from the sea and would like eating the racers just as much as carrying them. It&amp;rsquo;s a magical combination of worldbuilding, with the quiet island life and violence of the sea horses complementing one another nicely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="22733729" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22733729.the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ashby eyed the readouts on his control screen. “I swear, our engines have never been running this smooth.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sissix spoke without looking up from her navigation controls. “That’s what happens when you take two easily-bored techs on a long haul.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Hmm. Maybe we should do this more often.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That made Sissix’s head turn. She gave him a look that could melt the hull. “Let’s not.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a great book. It&amp;rsquo;s a slice of life story, set on small starship travelling the galaxy chock full of some of the most fascinating and delightful characters I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a scifi novel in a long time. There&amp;rsquo;s not particularly a huge over-arching plot. Instead, our intrepid band of oddballs is off on a long mission (it&amp;rsquo;s a Long Way after all) to the edge (center?) of &amp;lsquo;known&amp;rsquo; space. Really, we&amp;rsquo;re just on a trip with them, through all the ups and downs, the drama and relationships. It&amp;rsquo;s exactly the sort of story I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know I was looking for. Well worth a read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cece Rios and the Desert of Souls</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/cece-rios-and-the-desert-of-souls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/cece-rios-and-the-desert-of-souls/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="49613673" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/49613673.cece-rios-and-the-desert-of-souls">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/cece-rios-and-the-desert-of-souls.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Since before I could remember, Mamá had taught me the legends of the criaturas. They were creatures unlike humans, children of the Desert goddess, who the Great Namer created from dust and words. Mama taught me the difference between animal criaturas, who were made to fill the desert, and dark criaturas, who were made to attack the descendants of the Sun god—us. But her advice for dealing with both types was the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a delightful book. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick read (middle grade) with lovely worldbuilding (albeit a bit of whiplash reading it back to back with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/black-sun/">Black Sun&lt;/a>). It&amp;rsquo;s got a touch of southwest US / Mexican mythology with Coyote myths, El Sombrerón//La Chupacabra/La Llorona and others, brujas, and touch of Pokemon/creature collection with whole loads of hearts and the power of one little girl trying to save her sister and instead&amp;ndash;perhaps&amp;ndash;accidentally changing the world along the way. It&amp;rsquo;s a great read and something that I&amp;rsquo;m definitely going to put onto the list to read to my children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 21: The Laughing Magician</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/hellblazer-vol.-21-the-laughing-magician/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/hellblazer-vol.-21-the-laughing-magician/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="43088693" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43088693.hellblazer-vol-21-the-laughing-magician">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-21-the-laughing-magician.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>More lore around the Constantine line, hints of destiny thwarted before birth, a magic stick, and a mage hunting shark man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good times. Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also: Tell me there’s a series about Johanna Constantine. That’s quite the story of hers at the end of the volume.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Sun</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/black-sun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/black-sun/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="50892360" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/50892360.black-sun">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/black-sun.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Your father thought he could forbid me to wear this,” she said calmly enough, but the boy could hear the thread of pain in her voice, the places where deprivation and sorrow had left their cracks. “But your father doesn’t understand that this is the way of my ancestors, and their ancestors before them. He cannot stop a Carrion Crow woman from dressing to honor the crow god, particularly on a day as sacred as today.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a magical book. It&amp;rsquo;s got dark and beautiful worldbuilding, some absolutely bizarre and still somehow eminently relatable characters, and quite the cliffhanger of an ending (spoilers I suppose). Well worth reading.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Changeling</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/26/the-changeling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/26/the-changeling/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="31147267" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/31147267.the-changeling">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-changeling.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>On one level, it&amp;rsquo;s about fatherhood. Apollo grew up without a dad and vows he&amp;rsquo;s going to do better by his own son. And right from the beginning&amp;ndash;a surprise delivery no one around was quite ready for&amp;ndash;he does everything he can. As a father, with my youngest about the age of Apollo&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; when things go sideways. But we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On another level, it&amp;rsquo;s about motherhood. Emma had all sorts of issues of her own, but she and Apollo seem absolutely delightful together. So when the first signs of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/postpartum%20depression">postpartum depression&lt;/a> start, it&amp;rsquo;s terrifying and entirely too relatable to many parents out there. New babies are hard, not going to lie, and everyone deals with that completely differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a third, it&amp;rsquo;s about fairy tales and other stories. The stories we read to our children and the stories we tell ourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on a last level, it&amp;rsquo;s about magic. There are hints right from the beginning that there&amp;rsquo;s something strange in this world. From Apollo&amp;rsquo;s dreams of his absent father, to the magic inheriant in old books and libraries, to finding a postcard from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aleister%20Crowley">Aleister Crowley&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s little in the way of obviously supernatural for most of the book&amp;hellip; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t last.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 20: Systems of Control</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/25/hellblazer-vol.-20-systems-of-control/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/25/hellblazer-vol.-20-systems-of-control/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="40003443" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40003443.hellblazer-vol-20-systems-of-control">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-20-systems-of-control.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Constantine gets his Mojo back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joyride is a pretty crazy story which may yet come back to haunt us. All His Engines is even better, getting some Aztec flair in line. A good volume.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 19: The Red Right Hand</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/21/hellblazer-vol.-19-the-red-right-hand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/21/hellblazer-vol.-19-the-red-right-hand/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="37489676" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/37489676.hellblazer-vol-19-the-red-right-hand">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-19-the-red-right-hand.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Well that’s an interesting saga. Heaven, Hell, and… a Third Place. Mythology certainly goes some interesting places in Hellblazer. I enjoyed it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Physics of the Impossible</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/21/physics-of-the-impossible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/21/physics-of-the-impossible/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="1168341" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1168341.physics-of-the-impossible">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/physics-of-the-impossible.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Physics of the Impossible is a really great book. It goes into a wide variety of primarily science fictional topics in decreasingly order of likelihood and gets into how each works (so far as they do work with what we know now) and what it would take to make them possible. There&amp;rsquo;s just enough scientific background that I understood most of it and could stretch for the rest, with pointers for what to search for to learn more, which is always a good way to go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read! One interesting point is how many of these seeded ideas for more stories in the future! Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 18: The Gift</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/15/hellblazer-vol.-18-the-gift/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/15/hellblazer-vol.-18-the-gift/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="35141041" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35141041.hellblazer-vol-18-the-gift">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-18-the-gift.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>All about that little issue of Constantine and one very very long day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s a lot of crazy things going on better my here. Quiet a story… where can it possibly go next?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nate the Great Stalks Stupidweed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/15/nate-the-great-stalks-stupidweed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/15/nate-the-great-stalks-stupidweed/</guid><description>My oldest started reading not that long ago and oh how they&amp;rsquo;ve taken it to heart. Immediately into just about everything they can get their hands on. One of which?
Nate the Great!
They vary a bit in quality, but &amp;lsquo;Stalks Stupidweed&amp;rsquo; is pretty high up there in my opinion. It&amp;rsquo;s cute and has a few laugh out loud moments. Worth a try (especially if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the first 8).</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 17: Out of Season</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/14/hellblazer-vol.-17-out-of-season/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/14/hellblazer-vol.-17-out-of-season/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="34690711" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34690711.hellblazer-vol-17-out-of-season">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-17-out-of-season.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Constantine lost and found and so very screwed. Literally. A lot happens in this one and there’s a lot of potential for what comes next. Looking forward to it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Rain and Paper Cranes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/10/black-rain-and-paper-cranes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/10/black-rain-and-paper-cranes/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="55833231" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/55833231.black-rain-and-paper-cranes">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/black-rain-and-paper-cranes.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a strange book. It&amp;rsquo;s one part historical novel&amp;ndash;detailing the development, usage, and aftermath of the nuclear weapons detonated over Hiroshima and Nagasaki at the end of World War II&amp;ndash;one part technical manual&amp;ndash;very roughly detailing the physics and engineering behind early nuclear weapons&amp;ndash;and one part children&amp;rsquo;s book&amp;ndash;many scenes involve Fritz, the talking (and super fast) dove. We&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Poppy War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/08/the-poppy-war/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/08/the-poppy-war/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="35068705" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35068705.the-poppy-war">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-poppy-war.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>War doesn&amp;rsquo;t determine who&amp;rsquo;s right. War determines who remains.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;hellip; is quite a book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Daemon Voices</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="35478763" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/35478763.daemon-voices">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/daemon-voices.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He is interested in the discoveries of science (“intellectual daring and imaginative brilliance without parallel”), the freedoms of democracy (in particular “the great democracy of reading and writing”), the evils of authoritarianism (“always reductive whether it’s in power or not”) and the pitfalls of education (“any education that neglects the experience of delight will be a dry and tasteless diet with no nourishment in it”). He is profoundly interested in religion, while remaining puzzled by aspects of it. “The first thing to say about the Bishop’s arguments in his book,” he writes in “God and Dust,” “is that I agree with every word of them, except the words I don’t understand; and that the words I don’t understand are those such as spirit, spiritual and God.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Philip Pullman is an interesting author, which makes Daemon Voices an interesting sort of book. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a selected collection of essays and presentation he&amp;rsquo;s given over the years on a wide range of topics. In particular, he talks a lot about Paradise Lost (makes me want to actually read it), his religious and philosophical views (and a dive into Gnosticism) and how those interact with his writing, and a bit on writing advice and his own particular style.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating look and there&amp;rsquo;s a little for everyone, so if you like what Pullman has written, you can certainly do worse than give it a chance!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below are a few interesting quotes that I highlighted for just about every essay. It&amp;rsquo;s not really the sort of book where one should worry about spoilers, but just in case that&amp;rsquo;s not a shared option, you have been warned. (Also: &lt;em>long&lt;/em>)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 16: The Wild Card</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/05/hellblazer-vol.-16-the-wild-card/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/05/hellblazer-vol.-16-the-wild-card/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="32018137" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32018137.hellblazer-vol-16-the-wild-card">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-16-the-wild-card.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>A crazy bloody mess with some old friends in the longer stories and a few neat bits in the short ones. But more of Angela and Gemma.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A rather solid volume.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Last Uncharted Sky</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/28/the-last-uncharted-sky/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/28/the-last-uncharted-sky/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="45046548" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/45046548.the-last-uncharted-sky">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-last-uncharted-sky.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/08/an-alchemy-of-masques-and-mirrors/">An Alchemy of Masques and Mirrors&lt;/a> was mystery and religious fiddling and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/a-labyrinth-of-scions-and-sorcery/">A Labyrinth of Scions and Sorcery&lt;/a> was a political story, culminating in a fall of power (or at least a shift), The Last Uncharted Sky shifts yet again. This time we have a (aero)nautical adventure with skyships, pirates, lost treasures, and found families. Really, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful exploration of just how wonderful and strange the world we&amp;rsquo;ve been allowed to inhabit for just a little while.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 15: Highwater</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/13/hellblazer-vol.-15-highwater/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/13/hellblazer-vol.-15-highwater/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="30082502" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/30082502.hellblazer-vol-15-highwater">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-15-highwater.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>It’s… fine? I enjoyed the first two longer stories well enough but the latter one was all kinds of weird. And not in a way I cared for?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward! Maybe to something new?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 14: Good Intentions</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/11/hellblazer-vol.-14-good-intentions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/11/hellblazer-vol.-14-good-intentions/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="28007964" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28007964.hellblazer-vol-14-good-intentions">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-14-good-intentions.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>That’s a few hard hitting stories. Hard Times is about Constantine in prison. Weird art style and hard to read. Good Intentions is the aftermath… people are terrible. Freezes Over it’s a pretty good locked room mystery with just the possibility of something more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, good but not the best Constantine. Needs more out and out unambiguous supernatural IMO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onwards!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Biological Bits: A brief guide to the ideas and artefacts of computational artificial life</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/10/biological-bits-a-brief-guide-to-the-ideas-and-artefacts-of-computational-artificial-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/10/biological-bits-a-brief-guide-to-the-ideas-and-artefacts-of-computational-artificial-life/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="44011307" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/44011307.biological-bits-a-brief-guide-to-the-ideas-and-artefacts-of-computational-artificial-life">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/biological-bits-a-brief-guide-to-the-ideas-and-artefacts-of-computational-artificial-life.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Came across a &lt;a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/alife/comments/sls0rt/biological_bits_by_alan_dorin_great_introduction/">reddit thread&lt;/a> about this book. I&amp;rsquo;ve long been interested in alife, artificial evolution, simulated creatures, etc, and have been looking to add back in more non-fiction so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d go ahead and give it a whirl.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overal though, it seems&amp;hellip; rather lackluster. I guess if you&amp;rsquo;re just getting into the field, it&amp;rsquo;s a good summary of what all is involved, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get more than a page into detail about absolutely anything. Probably I&amp;rsquo;m not the target audience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Labyrinth of Scions and Sorcery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/a-labyrinth-of-scions-and-sorcery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/a-labyrinth-of-scions-and-sorcery/</guid><description>An Alchemy of Masques and Mirrors was a delightful surprise of a book, with unique/excellent worldbuilding, fun characters, great wordsmithing, and a solid mystery of a plot. A Labyrinth of Scions and Sorcery has all three once again, although we mostly lose the mystery of the of first book and get a bunch of politics instead. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s still great, it just took me a bit to get into the tonal shift.</description></item><item><title>The Wyrmling Horde</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/the-wyrmling-horde/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/the-wyrmling-horde/</guid><description>I think that for the most part The Wyrmling Horde takes everything I mentioned in Worldbinder and does a bit more of that. There are some really fascinating worldbuilding ideas being explored here, although I miss the smaller scope of just the Endowments and possibly the wizards of the early books. The characters are cool&amp;ndash;and I do actually find the inversions of several of them fascinating&amp;ndash;but we&amp;rsquo;re also missing a few faces that I really wish we would see more of.</description></item><item><title>Brothers of War The Iron Brigade at Gettysburg</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/03/brothers-of-war-the-iron-brigade-at-gettysburg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/03/brothers-of-war-the-iron-brigade-at-gettysburg/</guid><description>“But at a great cost,” Williams continued, looking at the men and pointing in the direction where the Nineteenth suffered so horrendously. “The cost will be felt in hundreds of homes, factories, and farms back in Indiana…not only now, but for generations. Although we’ll be forever saddened by the price that the Nineteenth has paid on this field, we should always remember that those lives and limbs were not lost in vain.</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 13: Haunted</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/11/hellblazer-vol.-13-haunted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/11/hellblazer-vol.-13-haunted/</guid><description>One heck of a crazy longer story (Haunted, one of the best of that length) and a bunch of shorter ones, ranging from not much to really good.
Mini-reviews and pretty pictures (spoilers):
Haunted That’s a story. Enough time to breathe, a cast of new and interesting story, and all sorts of gross and creepy scenes.
Part One Oy. Although you can’t say she’s wrong.
Murder scene description: oy that’s graphic.</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 12: How to Play with Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/07/hellblazer-vol.-12-how-to-play-with-fire/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/07/hellblazer-vol.-12-how-to-play-with-fire/</guid><description>Three multiple parters? No single issues? Sweet. Up the Down Staircase want my favorite, but both How to Play with Fire and Son of Man were excellent.
Mini reviews, pretty (horrifying) pictures and spoilers:
Up the Down Staircase Memes? I feel like I missed something. Interesting character development, but no real pay off.
Part One You are dating the wrong man.
Other than that, we have a fairly standard meet the family type scene.</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 11: Last Man Standing</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/03/hellblazer-vol.-11-last-man-standing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/03/hellblazer-vol.-11-last-man-standing/</guid><description>A solid one. Big stories are interesting, little ones are touching_weird_sweet, and Constantine’s got some new people and problems to deal with. Nothing too surreal either, which I appreciate.
Mini-reviews (spoilers):
Days of Wine and Roses A little bit of Constantine, a little bit of regular human terror.
The Wild Hunt Oh my.
Also: Colts!
Last Man Standing Argue and his men as ancient immortals? Merlin as a dragon?</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 10: In the Line of Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/01/hellblazer-vol.-10-in-the-line-of-fire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/01/hellblazer-vol.-10-in-the-line-of-fire/</guid><description>Fortune telling, Constantine’s father, more evil demons and arguably worse angels, and of course dead soldiers who can’t find rest.
Not a standout volume, but still pretty good.
Mini reviews (spoilers):
The Nature of the Beast Sure…
Reading the future is a common enough trope in this genre, but I enjoyed it.
Walking the Dog Another ghost story&amp;hellip;
…ish.
Oops. A neat twist.
Punkin’ Up the Great Outdoors Going to be a weird one:</description></item></channel></rss>