<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Last Argument of Kings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/last-argument-of-kings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/last-argument-of-kings/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I have learned all kinds of things from my many mistakes. The one thing I never learn is to stop making them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And so it ends&amp;hellip; for now. Some of our old friends (more or less) are dead, some are broken, and some &amp;hellip; miraculously seem to have gotten everything they wanted in life. There are more surprises and political shifts than one knows how to deal with, a chunk more of world building around the First and Second Laws, and all manner of battles and death and destruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It remains fascinating what Abercrombie can do with characters. Glokta is a terrible person&amp;ndash;and he makes us root for him. Logen is a berserker in the truest sense&amp;ndash;and he makes us feel sorry for him. Jezal is excellent at failing upward&amp;ndash;and he makes us feel sorry for him. It&amp;rsquo;s all around amazing and the real strength of the series.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/14/the-first-fifteen-lives-of-harry-august/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/14/the-first-fifteen-lives-of-harry-august/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take the timeloop premise of Groundhog Day (et al), apply it to lifetimes, add a few neat worldbuilding twists, break things up with a cataclysm coming back through time&amp;hellip; and you have The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August. I love all of those things, so of course, I love this book as well. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unwritten, Vol. 3: Dead Man's Knock</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/10/the-unwritten-vol.-3-dead-mans-knock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/10/the-unwritten-vol.-3-dead-mans-knock/</guid><description>&lt;p>He&amp;rsquo;s on the run and&amp;ndash;eventually&amp;ndash;starting to accept his destiny. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to get further into who everyone is and how the world works. I&amp;rsquo;m curious where things will go next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Snake Falls to Earth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/06/a-snake-falls-to-earth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/06/a-snake-falls-to-earth/</guid><description>I do love stories that take mythology I don&amp;rsquo;t know as well and expands on it. In this case, the Lipan (Apache) people of what became the southwestern US down into Mexico. The idea of a world inhabited by animal people&amp;ndash;those that can shape shift between an animal and a human form&amp;ndash;that was once connected to Earth&amp;hellip; and now is not.
“And if they don’t?” I muttered. “Pfft. You’re a cottonmouth,” she snickered.</description></item><item><title>The Galaxy, and the Ground Within</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/22/the-galaxy-and-the-ground-within/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/22/the-galaxy-and-the-ground-within/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People – a group comprised of every sapient species, organic or otherwise – were chaos, but chaos was good. Chaos was the only sensible conclusion. There was no law that was just in every situation, no blanket rule that could apply to everyone, no explanation that accounted for every component. This did not mean that laws and rules were not helpful, or that explanations should not be sought, but rather that there should be no fear in changing them as needed, for nothing in the universe ever held still.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh, I do love these books. Especially on audio. There just such a delightful take on the sci-fi &amp;lsquo;slice of life&amp;rsquo; genre. Once again, it&amp;rsquo;s a new cast and new stories, with loose tiebacks to the previous characters (seeing Pei and hearing her talk about Ashby is a nice change of view). Chambers really shines at taking a bunch of weird and wonderful aliens, sticking them in a tight space (this time what&amp;rsquo;s essentially a &amp;lsquo;space truck stop&amp;rsquo;) for a few days, and seeing what happens. Nothing earthshaking&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> or deadly&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, but a lot of interpersonal drama. It&amp;rsquo;s great. Worth a read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unwritten, Vol. 2: Inside Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/22/the-unwritten-vol.-2-inside-man/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/22/the-unwritten-vol.-2-inside-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things are starting to move now! Prison, dedicated journalists, some real magic, and death. I’ll still trying to figure out the rules, but I’m enjoying it so far!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Outside</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/21/the-outside/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/21/the-outside/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Well, it did what Outside usually did in stories. Showed up. Violated all the known laws of physics. Killed some people and drove the rest mad.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s certainly an interesting book. It&amp;rsquo;s one part autism as &amp;lsquo;different, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay and sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s a superpower and sometimes it sucks&amp;rsquo;, one part cosmic horror, and one part fascinating worldbuilding with technoreligion writ large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it didn&amp;rsquo;t quite feel finished to me. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of setup, but the ending drew somewhere between a true horror ending and something much &amp;lsquo;better&amp;rsquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s potential for a sequel there, but without it, it could have been better. Still an enjoyable enough read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Before They Are Hanged</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/before-they-are-hanged/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/before-they-are-hanged/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We should forgive our enemies, but not before they are hanged.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Before They Are Hanged takes &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/31/the-blade-itself/">The Blade Itself&lt;/a> and takes everything up a notch. It&amp;rsquo;s still a dark and twisted world, there are still terrible people on all sides&amp;hellip; but now we have even more hints and worldbuilding on darker things coming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a worthwhile continuation to the first story and I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to see where it goes next. The narration in particular remains well worth it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unwritten, Vol. 1: Tommy Taylor and the Bogus Identity</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/the-unwritten-vol.-1-tommy-taylor-and-the-bogus-identity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/the-unwritten-vol.-1-tommy-taylor-and-the-bogus-identity/</guid><description>Well that’s a start. A world where Tommy Taylor is a modern hidden world fantasy even bigger than Harry Potter… until the author disappears, leaving behind disillusioned son Tom Taylor. There are more than hints of a darker truth behind the story, hidden worlds within hidden worlds. And a section at the end establishing how far back in time the truth goes.
So far, a fascinating sort of story. Well written and illustrated.</description></item><item><title>The Rage of Dragons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/the-rage-of-dragons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/the-rage-of-dragons/</guid><description>&lt;p>African-inspired Bronze-age fantasy with piles of caste based tensions, crazy sword battles, interesting magic, demons, dragons, and the distinct feeling that the &amp;lsquo;good guys&amp;rsquo; might not actually be that good after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m reminded a lot of Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game (which I love and need to re-read at some point) in that you have a surprisingly good soldier that manages to train harder and break the rules, breaking down society as he goes. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot darker though and Tau (said soldier) is motivated almost entirely by vengeance. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; a lot to read at times, but it fits. Man he&amp;rsquo;s stupid at times for it though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a great book and worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fugitive Telemetry</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/06/fugitive-telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/06/fugitive-telemetry/</guid><description>&lt;p>An odd book. It&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be #6 in the series, but really, it&amp;rsquo;s a prequel to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/network-effect/">Network Effect&lt;/a>. There&amp;rsquo;s not much you need to know between the two, so you can read them in either order and if it were up to me, I&amp;rsquo;d probably swap them (mostly because I want to know what happens next!), but it still works.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mysterious Benedict Society</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/02/the-mysterious-benedict-society/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/02/the-mysterious-benedict-society/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that took a while to read. I read it outloud, part of a chapter a night many nights, and it still took a few months. Glad I did it though, it&amp;rsquo;s a great book, especially for kids, but even more so to read aloud with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a story about a group of children, each lost and/or alone in different ways, each brilliant (as the first section and a series of tests shows both to them and to us) and thus necessary for a &lt;em>SECRET MISSION&lt;/em>. I won&amp;rsquo;t go much more into that, but once they get out on the mission and have to prove that they are more than up to the task&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Blade Itself</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/31/the-blade-itself/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/31/the-blade-itself/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Every man has his excuses, and the more vile the man becomes, the more touching the story has to be. What is my story now, I wonder?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Joe Abercrombie / The Blade Itself have long held a highly recommended spot on my to read lis, so when I caught the audiobook on Libby/the Indiana Digital Library&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> I figured it was about time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quick version: it&amp;rsquo;s wonderful, but also &lt;em>very&lt;/em> dark. One of the main characters is a barbarian who&amp;rsquo;s family was recently killed, another is a soldier crippled in war turned torturer. And somehow, Abercrombie actually really makes you feel for the both of them, but man it takes a bit&amp;hellip; On top of that, there&amp;rsquo;s some fascinating hints of magic&amp;ndash;plus some more overt examples, no less terrible, when we meet Bayaz&amp;ndash;the First of the Magi&amp;hellip; or is he?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Network Effect</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/network-effect/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/network-effect/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>So that was what had happened before the survey. Now we’re here, ready for the next major disaster. (Spoiler warning.)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a full length Murderbot novel! Yay! And it gets far deeper and weirder into corners of the worldbuilding we&amp;rsquo;ve only had hints of before. I love seeing the hints of tension with the corporations and how much control they hvaqe, the weirdness that is alien remnants, and the knowledge that there are super weird problems out there that aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily directly related to Murderbot.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spelunky</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/spelunky/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/spelunky/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The games reminded me of something the author Haruki Murakami says in the intro to the English edition of Blind Willow, Sleeping Woman: “I find writing novels a challenge, writing short stories a joy. If writing novels is like planting a forest, then writing short stories is more like planting a garden. The two processes complement each other, creating a complete landscape that I treasure.” In video games, we don’t have corresponding terms for novels and short stories—we simply have large games and small games. These Game Maker games were Murakami’s gardens: vibrant, intimate, and full of charm. Having just planted a large forest with Alec, I was eager to find my own little patch of fertile soil.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I absolutely love Spelunky. I remember playing the (now) Classic version when that&amp;rsquo;s all there was (even going so far as to decompile and mess with the source code, yay GameMaker Studio), spending hours on the HD remake (beat Olmec, made it to Hell, never did beat Yama)&amp;ndash;mostly on Steam, and more recently put just as many hours into Spelunky 2. It&amp;rsquo;s a great game and what little I knew of the story was already inspirational. So when I saw this book, written by Derek Yu himself, of course I had to give it a try.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exit Strategy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/exit-strategy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/exit-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Murderbot has really stirred up some trouble. Now Dr. Mesnah&amp;rsquo;s caught up in it and it&amp;rsquo;s time to come back and perhaps fix some things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like the rest, it&amp;rsquo;s a quick read with a wonderful sense of all too familiar alienness, wonderful hacking and action scenes, and a fascinating look at what it means to be a person&amp;ndash;or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth the read, but at this point, I expect you&amp;rsquo;ll already be blowing through these.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Redwall: The Graphic Novel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/redwall-the-graphic-novel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/redwall-the-graphic-novel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s a great story. I read it long ago and &lt;a href="&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/19/redwall/">Redwall&lt;/a>">listened to it a couple years ago&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s a great story of animals basically doing the human thing in and around an abbey run by mice. It&amp;rsquo;s great fun so long as you don&amp;rsquo;t think too long and hard about which animals are sentient and which aren&amp;rsquo;t and how the vast differences in scale and lack of opposable thumbs could possibly work&amp;hellip; but other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s great fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Formatwise, I&amp;rsquo;ve read a few graphic novel adaptations of novels and usually they feel a little lackluster (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/white-sand/">White Sand&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/08/storm-front-graphic-novel/">Storm Front (Graphic Novel&lt;/a>) as two examples), but if anything was going to work, this was it. It&amp;rsquo;s already a lighter fantasy world with lots of light riddles and actions and over the top characters that fit just fine with graphic novels. And it pays off. As an introduction to this world, it&amp;rsquo;s a great alternative. It&amp;rsquo;s just so fun to see pictures of how someone else saw all of the characters from this world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>V for Vendetta</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/v-for-vendetta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/09/v-for-vendetta/</guid><description>&lt;p>That’s quite a story; quite a world. I only vaguely remember the film, but I still hear Hugo Weaving’s voice as V and Natalie Portman as Evey. The bones of what I remember match though. A story of a world gone well over the edge and a man determined to bring it back—but at what cost?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A fascinating read and worth the time. I need to watch the movie now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stiff: The Curious Lives of Human Cadavers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/stiff-the-curious-lives-of-human-cadavers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/stiff-the-curious-lives-of-human-cadavers/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Death. It doesn’t have to be boring.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a book. I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to try out one of Mary Roach&amp;rsquo;s books for a while and this one came up on the (digital) library, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a try. In a nutshell, it goes into the process of what happens right up to and after you die (including brain death and organ donation) along with the various things that might be done with your body afterwards (such as medical training and testing various products along with alternatives to burial).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“What I do is, I think of them as wax.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Theresa is practicing a time-honored coping method: objectification. For those who must deal with human corpses regularly, it is easier (and, I suppose, more accurate) to think of them as objects, not people.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating look into things you just don&amp;rsquo;t often think of. I quite enjoyed it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eric Carle's Animals Animals</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/29/eric-carles-animals-animals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/29/eric-carles-animals-animals/</guid><description>That&amp;rsquo;s an adorable and longer than expected book of poetry about animals in various ways and forms in prime Eric Carle form. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve met a book of theirs yet I don&amp;rsquo;t like and this is no exception. Worth the read.</description></item><item><title>Record of a Spaceborn Few</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/24/record-of-a-spaceborn-few/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/24/record-of-a-spaceborn-few/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Amias Mitchell,’ Kip said. ‘Born aboard the Asteria. Forty Solar days of age as of GC standard day 211/310. He is now, and always, a member of our Fleet. By our laws, he is assured shelter and passage here. If we have food, he will eat. If we have air, he will breathe. If we have fuel, he will fly. He is son to all grown, brother to all still growing. We will care for him, protect him, guide him. We welcome you, Amias, to the decks of the Asteria, and to the journey we take together.’ He spoke the final words now, and the room joined him. ‘From the ground, we stand. From our ships, we live. By the stars, we hope.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely fascinating what Becky Chambers has done with The Wayfarers books. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/">In one&lt;/a>, we get a slice of life on a long haul spaceship with all sorts of aliens; &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/10/a-closed-and-common-orbit/">in two&lt;/a>), we get an embodied AI and a former cloned slave learning about being people, and now&amp;hellip; we get the most &amp;lsquo;human&amp;rsquo; centric of the stories thus far. It&amp;rsquo;s all about the Exodus Fleet&amp;ndash;a few dozen generation ships built from the ruins of Earth&amp;rsquo;s cities and launched into deep space what feels like a very long time ago&amp;ndash;certainly before humanity knew for sure there was anyone else out there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Edgeworld: A Little Chaos In Your Life</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/19/edgeworld-a-little-chaos-in-your-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/19/edgeworld-a-little-chaos-in-your-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a neat enough story and I really like the worldbuilding&amp;hellip; I just wish there was more of it. Even at a volume, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of space to explore.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Complete Maus</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/19/the-complete-maus/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/19/the-complete-maus/</guid><description>Maus. What&amp;rsquo;s there even to say? It&amp;rsquo;s a story about a son and a father. About growing up Jewish during the rise of the Nazi party and during the Holocaust. About the ways that dramatically changes the lives of even those survive.
All told in a comic book style with different style animals for different races.
It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating way to tell the story (a (Jewish) mouse wearing a (Polish) pig mask to hide from the Nazis&amp;hellip;) even if / perhaps because it raises questions of it&amp;rsquo;s own.</description></item><item><title>Rogue Protocol</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/17/rogue-protocol/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/17/rogue-protocol/</guid><description>(There needs to be an error code that means “I received your request but decided to ignore you.”)
I do love me some Murderbot.
First, we got the origin story and then the one where the mystery deepens). Now&amp;hellip; Murderbot is really digging into where it came from &amp;hellip; and what int eh world GrayCris is doing there. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun story and I really love seeing Murderbot learn and grow as a person*.</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 26: The Curse of the Constantines</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/17/hellblazer-vol.-26-the-curse-of-the-constantines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/17/hellblazer-vol.-26-the-curse-of-the-constantines/</guid><description>&lt;p>Suicide Bridge: a single, not bad. Curse of the Constantines: it’s about blood and family and the nephew never mentioned. I like the idea of sometimes blood matters—and sometimes it doesn’t. Death and Cigarettes—a send off, Constantine style. He never really dies. Seems weird to have Epiphany and Finn here. Bad Blood… what was that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, out in Constantine style, could have done without Bad Blood. So it goes. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate Universe Vol. 1: Back to Destiny</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/17/stargate-universe-vol.-1-back-to-destiny/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/17/stargate-universe-vol.-1-back-to-destiny/</guid><description>&lt;p>I miss Stargate&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>6 issues making what would have been a decent enough Season 3 opener… but I want so much more than that. What would it be like to have &lt;span class="spoiler">an Ancient &lt;/span>
on the crew?! So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it has potential as a contusion but I wouldn’t really consider it necessary or even necessarily canon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 25: Another Season</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/hellblazer-vol.-25-another-season/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/hellblazer-vol.-25-another-season/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man Constantine’s life is a mess. Father in law has some use for him—which goes badly. He’s down a thumb and needs to deal with that—which goes badly. His coat’s gone evil walkabout—which goes badly. Gemma has it out for him (or at least his demonic twin)—which goes badly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think you get the idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A solid enough issue, but certainly an odd one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Last Graduate</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/the-last-graduate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/the-last-graduate/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Mum spent a lot of time in my formative years gently reminding me that people don’t think about us nearly as much as we think they do, because they’re all busy worrying what people are thinking about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>El is a super dramatic senior&amp;ndash;and she&amp;rsquo;s got her reasons, with the whole potential Dark Goddess thing she has going on&amp;ndash;and life is only getting weirder. She&amp;rsquo;s determined to get &lt;em>everyone&lt;/em> out, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the least bit of sense and she&amp;rsquo;s absolutely going to do it in world ending style. Oh, and of course there&amp;rsquo;s Orion. What&amp;rsquo;s up with that relationship, am I right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, if you loved &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/">A Deadly Education&lt;/a> (as I did), you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to love The Last Graduate. It turns the whole Scholomance craziness up to 11, gives us a dark chosen one that actually kind of works within the world building, and I really do love and care for the characters. And if the cliff hanger at the end of book 1 wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough&amp;hellip; THERE&amp;rsquo;S AN EVEN WORSE ONE AND THE NEXT BOOK ISN&amp;rsquo;T EVEN OUT YET.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways. Read it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 24: Sectioned</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/hellblazer-vol.-24-sectioned/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/hellblazer-vol.-24-sectioned/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that’s unexpected. Epiphany is pretty cool… but she’s way too young for him. Still, demons, time travel, a succubus, demon blood transfusion slaves, a wedding or two? A good volume.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Artificial Condition</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/15/artificial-condition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/15/artificial-condition/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When constructs were first developed, they were originally supposed to have a pre-sentient level of intelligence, like the dumber variety of bot. But you can’t put something as dumb as a hauler bot in charge of security for anything without spending even more money for expensive company-employed human supervisors. So they made us smarter. The anxiety and depression were side effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Murderbot is out on their own! It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting change of pace from the previous story, where Muderbot was still in the role of SecUnit&amp;hellip; On the way, it runs into ART (a spaceship AI; not it&amp;rsquo;s real name, it stands for Asshole Research Transport; three guesses who that&amp;rsquo;s from&amp;hellip;) who turns out to be a great ally. Muderbot gets a few changes to act slightly less SecUnit and more Augmented Human, goes back to the planet where to some extend it all began, and ends up hiring out it&amp;rsquo;s services as private security&amp;ndash;hey, do what you know.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vehicles: Experiments in Synthetic Psychology</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/14/vehicles-experiments-in-synthetic-psychology/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/14/vehicles-experiments-in-synthetic-psychology/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is an exercise in fictional science, or science fiction, if you like that better. Not for amusement: science fiction in the service of science. Or just science, if you agree that fiction is part of it, always was, and always will be as long as our brains are only minuscule fragments of the universe, much too small to hold all the facts of the world but not too idle to speculate about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What am I in for…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it’s an interesting read. In a nutshell, it builds up a model for ‘vehicles’ that start with a single wheel and basic sensor and grows, adding better senses and in particular a more and more complicated brain. I would have liked something a bit more technical and/or practical but there are a lot of interesting ideas here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One downside, the wording is … a bit pretentious at times. Academic is probably a better word. Above is the first paragraph.. and that’s really how it stays.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, an interesting enough and surprisingly quick read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Deadly Education</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/</guid><description>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s a joy of a book. Saying which I suppose&amp;ndash;after you&amp;rsquo;ve read it&amp;ndash;feels a bit ironic.
It&amp;rsquo;s one part magic school, with your more or less typical teenage protagonists doing more or less typical teenage thing. In my opinion, Novik does this very well. Main character El (short for Galadriel) is so wonderfully snarky and done with it teenage girl that I could practically feel her angst coming off the page&amp;ndash;and it&amp;rsquo;s all the better, because she really does have a good reason for it.</description></item><item><title>Paradise Lost</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/12/paradise-lost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/12/paradise-lost/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s an odd sort of book. It&amp;rsquo;s basically the story of the Fall of Satan plus Genesis, wrapped up in some crazy flowery poetry, writ long. It&amp;rsquo;s been on my &amp;lsquo;why not&amp;rsquo; list for a long time and hearing more about it in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/">Daemon Voices&lt;/a> bumped it up a fair bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am I glad to have read it? Yes. Is it a good book? Maybe. The poetry is absolutely beautiful in some places, but the story is one you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard before, if you&amp;rsquo;ve any sort of judeo-christian upbringing, although it does embelish in spots. And oy does it get long. It thought there were 7 books for some reason, so when I finished number 7 and we&amp;rsquo;re barely into Genesis&amp;hellip;, well, I knew I was wrong about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, the first few books with the fall of Satan are very cool and I&amp;rsquo;d say worth reading. The rest, hit or miss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 23: No Future</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/11/hellblazer-vol.-23-no-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/11/hellblazer-vol.-23-no-future/</guid><description>&lt;p>An interesting collection. Constantine in India, looking for purity. Punk and the Conservatives. Nergal and Bast’s … cousin, maybe? And Papa Midnite backstory. A lot of leaning on the past, but neat stories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Closed and Common Orbit</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/10/a-closed-and-common-orbit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/10/a-closed-and-common-orbit/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Life is terrifying. None of us have a rule book. None of us know what we&amp;rsquo;re doing here. So, the easiest way to stare reality in the face and not utterly lose your shit is to believe that you have control over it. If you believe you have control, then you believe you&amp;rsquo;re at the top. And if you&amp;rsquo;re at the top, then people who aren&amp;rsquo;t like you&amp;hellip; well, they&amp;rsquo;ve got to be somewhere lower, right? Every species does this. Does it again and again and again. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if they do it to themselves, or another species, or someone they created.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh. Wow. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/">The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet&lt;/a> felt like lightning in a bottle. Something amazing&amp;ndash;a look at the life in a long haul spaceship full of strange and wonderful characters&amp;ndash;that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how it could possibly be continued.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out&amp;hellip; just like this. This is a very very good sequel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, A Closed and Common Orbit was a bit of a surprise. We only barely get any of the characters we know and love from the first book. There are a few hints of and references to them, but for the most part, we instead focus on Lovey/Sidra* and Pepper, learning once again how two very strange and different sorts of people can grow into a family. The same general idea, approached a totally different way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All Systems Red</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, I get what all the hype is about. Take a heavily armed cyborg/clone, designed entirely as muscle to defend the more squishy &amp;rsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; humans, have it turn off the software constraining it from killing everyone, add in a wonderfully snarky sense of humor&amp;hellip; and see what happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I COULD HAVE BECOME a mass murderer after I hacked my governor module, but then I realized I could access the combined feed of entertainment channels carried on the company satellites. It had been well over 35,000 hours or so since then, with still not much murdering, but probably, I don’t know, a little under 35,000 hours of movies, serials, books, plays, and music consumed. As a heartless killing machine, I was a terrible failure.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 22: Regeneration</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/04/hellblazer-vol.-22-regeneration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/04/hellblazer-vol.-22-regeneration/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some holiday cheer (nothing deep but they’re neat enough), a new girl gone very very wrong, and Chas getting to be the hero. A good volume.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Individual readalong reviews. Spoilers:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022 Book Bingo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/01/2022-book-bingo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/01/2022-book-bingo/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s do this again! I barely made it, but there were so many books that I absolutely ended up loving that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I otherwise would have read. So this year, better!
Rules:
Must be speculative fiction (SF, fantasy, horror with speculative elements) Limit the number of novellas (fewer than 40k words or defined by the author as such) or combine them A book of short stories counts Graphic novels/manga should be treated as novellas Web novels count (if they&amp;rsquo;re long enough) Audiobooks count Official thread</description></item><item><title>The Scorpio Races</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-scorpio-races/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-scorpio-races/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There are moments that you&amp;rsquo;ll remember for the rest of your life and there are moments that you think you&amp;rsquo;ll remember for the rest of your life, and it&amp;rsquo;s not often they turn out to be the same moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s island life&amp;ndash;a small town, far out on the water that lives and dies by the one big event a year. Just in this case, that one event is a race involving murderous meat eating horses that come from the sea and would like eating the racers just as much as carrying them. It&amp;rsquo;s a magical combination of worldbuilding, with the quiet island life and violence of the sea horses complementing one another nicely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ashby eyed the readouts on his control screen. “I swear, our engines have never been running this smooth.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sissix spoke without looking up from her navigation controls. “That’s what happens when you take two easily-bored techs on a long haul.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Hmm. Maybe we should do this more often.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That made Sissix’s head turn. She gave him a look that could melt the hull. “Let’s not.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a great book. It&amp;rsquo;s a slice of life story, set on small starship travelling the galaxy chock full of some of the most fascinating and delightful characters I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a scifi novel in a long time. There&amp;rsquo;s not particularly a huge over-arching plot. Instead, our intrepid band of oddballs is off on a long mission (it&amp;rsquo;s a Long Way after all) to the edge (center?) of &amp;lsquo;known&amp;rsquo; space. Really, we&amp;rsquo;re just on a trip with them, through all the ups and downs, the drama and relationships. It&amp;rsquo;s exactly the sort of story I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know I was looking for. Well worth a read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cece Rios and the Desert of Souls</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/cece-rios-and-the-desert-of-souls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/cece-rios-and-the-desert-of-souls/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Since before I could remember, Mamá had taught me the legends of the criaturas. They were creatures unlike humans, children of the Desert goddess, who the Great Namer created from dust and words. Mama taught me the difference between animal criaturas, who were made to fill the desert, and dark criaturas, who were made to attack the descendants of the Sun god—us. But her advice for dealing with both types was the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a delightful book. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick read (middle grade) with lovely worldbuilding (albeit a bit of whiplash reading it back to back with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/black-sun/">Black Sun&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s got a touch of southwest US / Mexican mythology with Coyote myths, El Sombrerón//La Chupacabra/La Llorona and others, brujas, and touch of Pokemon/creature collection with whole loads of hearts and the power of one little girl trying to save her sister and instead&amp;ndash;perhaps&amp;ndash;accidentally changing the world along the way. It&amp;rsquo;s a great read and something that I&amp;rsquo;m definitely going to put onto the list to read to my children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 21: The Laughing Magician</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/hellblazer-vol.-21-the-laughing-magician/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/hellblazer-vol.-21-the-laughing-magician/</guid><description>&lt;p>More lore around the Constantine line, hints of destiny thwarted before birth, a magic stick, and a mage hunting shark man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good times. Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also: Tell me there’s a series about Johanna Constantine. That’s quite the story of hers at the end of the volume.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Sun</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/black-sun/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/29/black-sun/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Your father thought he could forbid me to wear this,” she said calmly enough, but the boy could hear the thread of pain in her voice, the places where deprivation and sorrow had left their cracks. “But your father doesn’t understand that this is the way of my ancestors, and their ancestors before them. He cannot stop a Carrion Crow woman from dressing to honor the crow god, particularly on a day as sacred as today.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a magical book. It&amp;rsquo;s got dark and beautiful worldbuilding, some absolutely bizarre and still somehow eminently relatable characters, and quite the cliffhanger of an ending (spoilers I suppose). Well worth reading.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Changeling</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/26/the-changeling/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/26/the-changeling/</guid><description>&lt;p>On one level, it&amp;rsquo;s about fatherhood. Apollo grew up without a dad and vows he&amp;rsquo;s going to do better by his own son. And right from the beginning&amp;ndash;a surprise delivery no one around was quite ready for&amp;ndash;he does everything he can. As a father, with my youngest about the age of Apollo&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; when things go sideways. But we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On another level, it&amp;rsquo;s about motherhood. Emma had all sorts of issues of her own, but she and Apollo seem absolutely delightful together. So when the first signs of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/postpartum%20depression">postpartum depression&lt;/a> start, it&amp;rsquo;s terrifying and entirely too relatable to many parents out there. New babies are hard, not going to lie, and everyone deals with that completely differently.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a third, it&amp;rsquo;s about fairy tales and other stories. The stories we read to our children and the stories we tell ourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on a last level, it&amp;rsquo;s about magic. There are hints right from the beginning that there&amp;rsquo;s something strange in this world. From Apollo&amp;rsquo;s dreams of his absent father, to the magic inheriant in old books and libraries, to finding a postcard from &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aleister%20Crowley">Aleister Crowley&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s little in the way of obviously supernatural for most of the book&amp;hellip; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t last.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 20: Systems of Control</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/25/hellblazer-vol.-20-systems-of-control/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/25/hellblazer-vol.-20-systems-of-control/</guid><description>&lt;p>Constantine gets his Mojo back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Joyride is a pretty crazy story which may yet come back to haunt us. All His Engines is even better, getting some Aztec flair in line. A good volume.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 19: The Red Right Hand</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/21/hellblazer-vol.-19-the-red-right-hand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/21/hellblazer-vol.-19-the-red-right-hand/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that’s an interesting saga. Heaven, Hell, and… a Third Place. Mythology certainly goes some interesting places in Hellblazer. I enjoyed it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Physics of the Impossible</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/21/physics-of-the-impossible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/21/physics-of-the-impossible/</guid><description>&lt;p>Physics of the Impossible is a really great book. It goes into a wide variety of primarily science fictional topics in decreasingly order of likelihood and gets into how each works (so far as they do work with what we know now) and what it would take to make them possible. There&amp;rsquo;s just enough scientific background that I understood most of it and could stretch for the rest, with pointers for what to search for to learn more, which is always a good way to go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read! One interesting point is how many of these seeded ideas for more stories in the future! Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 18: The Gift</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/15/hellblazer-vol.-18-the-gift/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/15/hellblazer-vol.-18-the-gift/</guid><description>&lt;p>All about that little issue of Constantine and one very very long day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s a lot of crazy things going on better my here. Quiet a story… where can it possibly go next?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nate the Great Stalks Stupidweed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/15/nate-the-great-stalks-stupidweed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/15/nate-the-great-stalks-stupidweed/</guid><description>My oldest started reading not that long ago and oh how they&amp;rsquo;ve taken it to heart. Immediately into just about everything they can get their hands on. One of which?
Nate the Great!
They vary a bit in quality, but &amp;lsquo;Stalks Stupidweed&amp;rsquo; is pretty high up there in my opinion. It&amp;rsquo;s cute and has a few laugh out loud moments. Worth a try (especially if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the first 8). :D</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 17: Out of Season</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/14/hellblazer-vol.-17-out-of-season/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/14/hellblazer-vol.-17-out-of-season/</guid><description>&lt;p>Constantine lost and found and so very screwed. Literally. A lot happens in this one and there’s a lot of potential for what comes next. Looking forward to it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>