<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science Fiction on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/writing/genres/science-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science Fiction on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 14:00:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/writing/genres/science-fiction/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Observers on Cydonia</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/19/observers-on-cydonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/19/observers-on-cydonia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They came without warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After so many years of finding nothing, the scientists had given up hope of ever finding life on Mars. Despite all of the probes, all of the rovers, Mars seemed destined to remain a dead planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spirit had been silent for years and it seemed that Opportunity would so follow on in its sister&amp;rsquo;s wake. Curiosity soldiered onward, drilling and lasering its way across the dusty ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week it seemed, there was some new discovery; compounds from meteorites that revealed how the early solar system had come to be, ancient rocks that could only have been shaped by flowing water, deep in the red planet&amp;rsquo;s shadowed path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But never the Holy Grail, the one thing everyone wished for, even if they could no long admit to it in public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never signs of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never the slightest hint that Earth may not have been unique in the universe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 24 - Aftermath</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/16/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-24-aftermath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 14:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/16/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-24-aftermath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;              the
              only 
    real reward for a job well
       done is another job
          worse     than
         the         first

               the
              only
    escape is to never finish.
      but in the end, even
          that      is
         not        really

           an option
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lillian awoke and was immediately struck by a strong sense of déjà vu. She was lying on her back in a hospital bed, just like the one she had woken up in&amp;ndash;hours? days? years?&amp;ndash;ago. Once again, she was strapped down, but more loosely than before. There was a little give at the arms and legs, although the band around her middle was just as tight as before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no pain, which was curious. She wondered about that until she spied any IV with an innocent enough looking bag dispensing some sort of clear liquid into her arm. Must be some sort of pain killer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 23 - Trust</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/13/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-23-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/13/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-23-trust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    trust
              is a 
             double 
    edged sword; razor sharp and
      capable of harming both
        he who trusts and he
          who is   trusted     
         one and   the same

                    likewise
              it
             is he
    who is trusted who will
      cause the most harm
        when      every
       thing        goes

    wrong
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight back was uneventful. Lillian and Jacobs took some time to talk about Watkins. It had almost certainly been Adrian, but why Watkins? He had to have been close enough to take a shot at either Lillian or Jacobs, why hadn&amp;rsquo;t he taken it? And where was he? There was still no sign of him anywhere&amp;ndash;not a blip on either the shuttle&amp;rsquo;s sensors or on &lt;em&gt;Borealis&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;. Well before they reached the shuttle bay, their conversation started looping back on itself and gradually faded into silence. But it was the kind of silence between good friends&amp;ndash;the kind of silence that they&amp;rsquo;d used to share back before Lillian had gone off on the &lt;em&gt;Daedalus&lt;/em&gt;. It was nice to finally find it again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 22 - Reboot</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/09/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-22-reboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/09/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-22-reboot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                   the 
                 modern
        computer is nothing short
           short of a miracle
              with    billions
            of tiny    circuits

          and                role
        billions           to play
    of lines of code  and each important
      each  having        in     its
     their      own      own      way
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once back out into space, Lillian settled down to try to figure out how this was even going to work. They&amp;rsquo;d loaded dozens of metallic panels into the back of the shuttle, all carefully stacked. They were rather heavy now, but that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem when they got there&amp;ndash;Watkins could just shut the gravity plating off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She pulled out the tools she&amp;rsquo;d collected and arranged them neatly on the floor. Most of them she wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need and there was only limited options. Mostly it was soothing. Organizing things always helped to calm her nerves. It took up most of the time on the short flight back out to the damage and by the time she got there, she was completely calm. Ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except there was Adrian. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly calm-inducing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 21 - Triage</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/06/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-21-triage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 14:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/06/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-21-triage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;            all
            that
    you know and all that
     you are can be gone
        in an instant
       all         that
      you            can

           hope for

             is
            that
    your instant takes an
     entire lifetime to 
       find you and to
        claim     its
       final       due
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lillian, what is it?&amp;rdquo; She heard Jacobs&amp;rsquo; voice, but it felt far away, inconsequential. She floated on the ceiling, barely aware of time slipping by. Seconds, minutes, hours. Jacobs was talking, but she couldn&amp;rsquo;t even make out what he was saying. What did it matter anyways? Quinn was dead and it was all her fault.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 20 - Spacewalk</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/02/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-20-spacewalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 14:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/02/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-20-spacewalk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;         in
       space
    one can truly
      be   free
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Lillian shimmied into the suit, with Madeline&amp;rsquo;s help, she took a moment to think about what was before her. She was going to have to leave the relatively safe confines of the &lt;em&gt;Borealis&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ndash;safe at least while the shields weren&amp;rsquo;t disabled&amp;ndash;to voyage out into the interstellar void. Outside of the ship, there was nothing. Not the sort of nothing that you could feel when you were in the middle of a deserted road deep into the night, but the crushing nothingness that the human mind isn&amp;rsquo;t really equipped to handle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 19 - Traitor</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/30/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-19-traitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/30/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-19-traitor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;              is
            there
    anything more terrible
     than being betrayed
        by a       man
       that         you&#39;ve
      come            to call 

             friend
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; Adrian.&amp;rdquo; Lillian jerked straight up in her bed. For a second, she wavered between her dream of events years gone by and the disasters of the present day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starfall</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/28/starfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 14:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/28/starfall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lying on my back, looking up into the night sky, I could feel the most curious sensation of being pulled up into the night sky, being pulled away from they very Earth on which I lay. I reached out with arms and bare feet, grabbing onto the soil with fingers and toes, determined to remain firmly grounded, firmly of this Earth. The attraction grew, I could feel my body lifting away, pulling against my four firm points of contact, fighting against myself for what little hold I still had.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 18 - Daedalus</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/26/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-18-daedalus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/26/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-18-daedalus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;            the
            mind 
    is a miraculous tool
     for bringing order
        to      chaos
       and       truth      out
                           of the
                   darkness; but with this
                    ability comes the risk
                        of      seeing
             real,     what       isn&#39;t
            making
    phantoms of shadows and
     conspiracies of those
        that      mean
       no          harm
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time, Lillian had been trusted with a solo mission to repair a damaged gravity plate. She gotten up that morning to check her assignments for the day and there it was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LILLIAN SHAW - 0800 - REPAIR GRAV PLATE 1352 IN MESS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her mentor finally trusted her! Today, she was extra careful as she collected her tools from the small chest under the bed in her bunk and fastened them around her jumpsuit. Tanaka-sensei had given her the belts&amp;ndash;made with a mix of Velcro and elastic bags&amp;ndash;and she loved them. A place for everything and everything in its place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last check to make sure she had everything and off she went. Her first solo!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 17 - Darkness</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/23/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-17-darkness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 14:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/23/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-17-darkness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;         all
        those
    who are afraid
     of the dark
     are   afraid
    for       good reason

           in
          the
    cold dark of space
     there is no one
       there    to
      save      you
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second time she came to, it was to a sharp pain in her side. Although she was still floating in the near darkness, her light was in front of her this time, so there were no shadows to threaten her awakening. As she woke, one hand flew to her side where it met with Eve&amp;rsquo;s shell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do you mind?&amp;rdquo; Eve&amp;rsquo;s voice sounded in her head.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 16 - Collision</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/19/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-16-collision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 14:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/19/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-16-collision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;          the
          void
    between the stars
      is cold dark
     and        more
    lonely        than

           one
          could
    possibly hope to imagine
       but it is foolish
       to         see
      it           as

    completely
         empty
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They waited a heartbeat. Two. Half a dozen. The emergency power finally kicked in, bathing them all in a reddish glow that contrasted harshly with Eve&amp;rsquo;s blue. With a start, Lillian realized that she wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually sitting on her bed any longer, but rather floating a few centimeters above it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She looked over, Madeline was doing the same beside her. On her other side, Eve seemed unaware of the fact that they should be floating and was still sitting resolutely in Lillian&amp;rsquo;s chair. That puzzled her for a second longer than it probably should have until she put it all together. The power was out. And with it, the artificial gravity, apparently. It should have been on the emergency circuit, but apparently it wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 15 - Artifact</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/16/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-15-artifact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 14:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/16/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-15-artifact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;        we
        are
     not alone
      in  the 
     uni   verse
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started out in the Kuiper Belt. About 40 years ago, that&amp;rsquo;s when the first real effort to mine the Kuiper Belt objects came about. And Dark Sun was at the forefront. They&amp;rsquo;d claimed hundreds, if not thousands, of Kuiper Belt objects for themselves. Most of them were for mining, but they had a good number of scientific endeavors as well. One of particular interest was the Deep Deep Space Array of telescopes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 14 - Madeline</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/12/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-14-madeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/12/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-14-madeline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;        of
       all
    the species     
     on Earth
    only   one  
    has     not

            only

             the
           ability
      to destroy itself
        but also what
       seems     to be
      the          need
             to
            do
           so
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Missing something?&amp;rdquo; Lillian could feel her voice rising and tried to push it back down. &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for you for over an hour.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Looking for me?&amp;rdquo; Madeline looked truly confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I stopped by your room probably a little bit after midnight and you weren&amp;rsquo;t here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sure I was. I&amp;rsquo;ve been here since I left your room.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 13 - Missing</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/09/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-13-missing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/09/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-13-missing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;                  when
                 in the
             deepest darkest
    depths of space, there is nowhere
      to run, nowhere to hide and
          no one to turn to when 
         everything      suddenly
        takes a              turn to
       the                     strange
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Madeline?&amp;rdquo; Lillian choked out after a moment of stunned silence. &amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t be serious.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m completely serious,&amp;rdquo; Eve responded evenly. &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;s my best friend,&amp;rdquo; Lillian replied, but it sounded flat even to her own ears.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 12 - Eve</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/05/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-12-eve/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 14:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/05/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-12-eve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;           the
          human
    body and soul are
     sometimes known
      as the  ghost
     and         the

    shell    what
            no-one
      seems to ask is can
        you can have a 
       shell     without
      its           ghost

             or a ghost
                without a shell
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving Adrian&amp;rsquo;s office, it was too late to finish her shift and too early for dinner. Nothing else particularly drew her, so Lillian decided to go back to her room. She was going to have to have to deal with that briefcase sooner or later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 11 - Surprises</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/02/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-11-surprises/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/02/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-11-surprises/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;              there
            exists an
    old Chinese saying: may you
     live in interesting times
        but sometimes, things
       can get       just a 
      little           too 
                         interesting
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lillian awoke from her dream full of bittersweet memories. It had been a while since she&amp;rsquo;d dreamed of her mother. Since she&amp;rsquo;d felt the cool touch of her hands on her faces. Heard the soft voice, reading to her before bed. But the memories of after were terribly bitter. They had found some of the men directly responsible for the bombing, but never those in charge. And no reason was ever given. Truly, that was the worst-it being just a random act of violence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lost in translation</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/30/lost-in-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 14:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/30/lost-in-translation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;﻿A man and a woman stood side by side, overlooking a sight that had, until a few months ago, never before been seen to human eyes. They were in orbit around a planet, blue green like the Earth but with just enough difference to know they were nowhere near home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The land was different. Rather than half a dozen large land masses spread more or less evenly, this world had only a single huge continent, spanning perhaps half of an entire hemisphere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 10 - Memories</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/28/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-10-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 14:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/28/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-10-memories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;          at              
          our             
    core all that we       made
      know and all         from
       that   we    the places that we
      are      is       have seen
                       and     the
                     people     that
                we
          once
    knew
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The morning began just like any other. Lillian awoke to the sounds and smells of frying bacon and the delicious aroma of homemade pancakes. She jumped out of bed&amp;ndash;&lt;em&gt;Mom&amp;rsquo;s cooking!&lt;/em&gt; she thought to herself&amp;ndash;and threw herself out of her door. She was in such a rush that she nearly collided with her father just outside the door, jumping aside bare centimeters from impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 9 - Lies</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/25/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-9-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/25/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-9-lies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;            the
          absolute
    best of lies are those
      hidden between two
        two grains of
      what        could
     only            be
            truth
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adrian had a small office in the command section of the ship, just off of a central area shared by all of the security staff. He took all four of them there, leaving his partner to examine the wreckage of the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herman</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/23/herman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/23/herman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Herman was alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then again, Herman was always alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He had no family, no friends. No one to call and ask how his day was. No one to come over and borrow a cup of sugar or chat about the latest ball game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again there was no more sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were no more ball games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it would have been nice to have someone to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 8 - Counterpoint</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/21/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-8-counterpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 14:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/21/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-8-counterpoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;          the
         human                 land
    being is truly the        for no
     most dangerous      other would so be
    animal       in         so willingly
    all          the       to       lose
                          every     thing
               for
             naught
        but the slightest
         chance of some
        future        hope
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lillian woke with tears on her pillow. Even taking the strange nature of time dilation from her years on the gateships into account, Lillian had lived off Earth longer than she&amp;rsquo;d lived on it. But she still remembered that quiet house in a city by the beach and thought of it as home. But it was all long gone. Destroyed by what was believed by some to be both the single greatest proof of intelligent extra-solar life ever. And known by everyone to be the single greatest act of devastation in the history of the human race. And perhaps the worst part was that there had been next to no warning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 7 - Impact</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/18/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-7-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 14:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/18/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-7-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;             a
           moment
         is all it
    takes for the entire
      world to change
      for       better
     or             for
           worse
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once they were in orbit, a sort of quiet anticipation settled over the ship. For several moments, no one spoke. Finally, several of the more adventurous passengers started whispered conversations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 6 - Greetings</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/14/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-6-greetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 14:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/14/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-6-greetings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;           deep                 
         in your                special
       heart, you             someone and
    never truly forget     know that nothing
     that moment when          could ever 
        you first             be       the 
      meet     that          same       again
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lillian jumped and spun to the door. She didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize the voice and, as she finished her turn, realized she didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize the face either. Which meant that it had to be someone that had just arrived. With only a few dozen crew members it was hard not to know at least everyone&amp;rsquo;s face&amp;ndash;even if Lillian tended towers horrible with names.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 5 - Confession</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/11/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-5-confession/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 14:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/11/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-5-confession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;             the 
            deep
      dark secrets of the 
        human soul are
       nothing     when
      faced   the   with
            needs
          of
        a
      true
    friend
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lillian and Madeline reached the observation lounge with only a few minutes to spare before the gate was scheduled to be activated. They weren&amp;rsquo;t the only ones either. Hans and Jacobs had already claimed one of the tables on a raised platform in the center of the room. Jacobs was waving his arms wildly at the girls.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 4 - Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/07/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-4-troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 14:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/07/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-4-troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;          yet
         even
     when the stars
    high in the sky
        go dark
      it&#39;s   easy                 for
     to         see              deep
                           in your heart you
                             know that it&#39;s
                                not the 
            that             star    light
           shines
       brightest, but the
         light of your
        smile      and
      warmth      of your            
                                    heart
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 3 - Inspection</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/04/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-3-inspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/09/04/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-3-inspection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;          when
        you want
      nothing more
     than to go home
       and nothing
      else      will
     be           good      enough
            some
            times
       you just might
    find that you are already
       there      they 
      say           home
               is
              where
       the heart is but in
         reality home is
           where    your
         friends     are
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, they set out towards the damaged power conduit that had been reported earlier. The power conduits mainly fed the gate generators along the inner ring of the ship. Seeing as there&amp;rsquo;d be no reason for &lt;em&gt;Borealis&lt;/em&gt; to exist if it weren&amp;rsquo;t for the gate&amp;ndash;there were backups after all&amp;ndash;but they still needed an occasional look over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 2 - Borealis</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/08/31/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-2-borealis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 14:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/08/31/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-2-borealis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;            at
           the 
          speed
     of light even the 
      smallest grain
     of         sand
    has           the

          power

    to destroy the world
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dull metallic banging cut through the air, the sound of fists hitting metal. &amp;ldquo;Lillian, wake up! You&amp;rsquo;re going to be late.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lillian jerked awake and sat up far too quickly, banging her head on the top of her bunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That dream again,&amp;rdquo; she mumbled to herself. &amp;ldquo;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had that one in years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Sea of Stars - Ch. 1 - Liftoff</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/08/28/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-1-liftoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/08/28/a-sea-of-stars-ch.-1-liftoff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;           in
          every
        young life
    there comes a time
      when the whole
     world       seems
    to             shift

                      for
                     some
                   the change
               is small yet for
                   some this 
                 change   will
               drive        their

    future
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>