<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Umbrella Academy (TV) on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-umbrella-academy-tv/</link><description>Recent content in The Umbrella Academy (TV) on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-umbrella-academy-tv/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Umbrella Academy: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/28/the-umbrella-academy-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/28/the-umbrella-academy-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was quite a continuation. Out of one apocalypse and right into another. This time in the 1960s!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a neat concept and gives the characters a bit more time to grow&amp;ndash;while at the same time the viewers know there&amp;rsquo;s quite the timeline. And with time travel&amp;hellip; you can kill people off and still have to deal with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also instead of Hazel and Cha-Chat, you have three Swedish brothers (less amusing, far more terrifying).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I quite enjoyed it. And there&amp;rsquo;s still &lt;em>plenty&lt;/em> of room left for Season 3. A quick search shows February 2022&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m going to go with a probably not on that. But still soon!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Umbrella Academy: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/17/the-umbrella-academy-season-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/17/the-umbrella-academy-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>On the 12th hour of the first day of October 1989, 43 women around the world gave birth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was unusual only in the fact that none of these women had been pregnant when the day first began.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sir Reginald Hargreeves, eccentric billionaire and adventurer, resolved to locate and adopt as many of the children as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh that&amp;rsquo;s quite a show. After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/11/23/the-umbrella-academy-vol.-1-the-apocalypse-suite/">reading through the graphic novels&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s a rather different experience. The core is the same, even if details are a bit different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Colm Feore as Reginald Hargreeves is my favorite casting. He reminds me as Michael Douglas as Dr. Hank Pym in Ant-Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward to season 2!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>