<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bartimaeus on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/bartimaeus/</link><description>Recent content in Bartimaeus on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/bartimaeus/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ptolemy's Gate</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/ptolemys-gate/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/ptolemys-gate/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nathaniel is 17 now, the sweetheart of the government after saving everyone in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/23/the-golems-eye/">The Golem’s Eye&lt;/a> and even worse when it comes to believing the goverment&amp;rsquo;s line about the supremacy of magicians and mistreating Bartimaeus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you might guess, in much the same way as in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/23/the-golems-eye/">The Golem’s Eye&lt;/a>, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really care for Nathaniel. Bartimaeus is still pretty cool, but where this book really shines is seeing what Kitty has gotten up to over the past few years and actually digging into what Ptolemy was like.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Golem's Eye</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/23/the-golems-eye/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/23/the-golems-eye/</guid><description>&lt;p>To as large extent, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/08/23/the-golems-eye/">The Golem’s Eye&lt;/a> continues where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/22/the-amulet-of-samarkand/">The Amulet of Samarkand&lt;/a> left off. Nathaniel is a rising star, now climbing the ranks of government and Bartimaeus is just as snarky as ever. We get quite a bit more (including POV time) from Kitty and her friends, showing that it&amp;rsquo;s not all fun and games in this particular echo of London.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting that Nathaniel grew up so quickly and is in government now. To go with the inevitable comparisons to Harry Potter the first book raised, it&amp;rsquo;s as if we&amp;rsquo;d skipped right by books 2-7 and went straight to Harry&amp;rsquo;s training as an Auror. I actually really appreciate that; it&amp;rsquo;s something new. EVen if it does strain credulity somewhat. He&amp;rsquo;s 14 for crying out loud&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Amulet of Samarkand</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/22/the-amulet-of-samarkand/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/22/the-amulet-of-samarkand/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And then, as if written by the hand of a bad novelist, an incredible thing happened.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/22/the-amulet-of-samarkand/">The Amulet of Samarkand&lt;/a> is a fun book. It feels someone like a grittier Harry Potter, where instead of the bright and shiny flick of a wand, you summon demons. Instead of a fantastic hidden castle in the woods, you have Arthur Underwood&amp;ndash;imagine if Harry was tutored throughout his magical career by a slightly more competent Vernon Dursley. And instead of a dark wizard coming to kill you because of an accident of your birth&amp;hellip; well, Nathaniel does a pretty good job of bringing trouble down upon his own head.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>