<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Schitt's Creek on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/schitts-creek/</link><description>Recent content in Schitt's Creek on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/schitts-creek/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/17/schitts-creek-season-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/17/schitts-creek-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so it ends. As expected, David and Patrick&amp;rsquo;s wedding is a big storyline (and man David is neurotic when stressed), but we also have Alexis continuing to grow in relationships and work (which is such an amazing growth from Season 1), the whole hotel starting to grow (rapidly) and Moira doing Moira things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a good way to end the show. We have some ending up moving back to the lives they once had, hopefully a little more self aware (I doubt so in Moira&amp;rsquo;s case&amp;hellip;) from their time in Schitt&amp;rsquo;s Creek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a show I normally would have chosen, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have watched it. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/01/schitts-creek-season-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/01/schitts-creek-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Moira gets a chance to do what she loves&amp;ndash;and is as Moira about it the entire season as possible. So much David and Patrick, which is great. Alexis is really growing, which is awesome&amp;ndash;she has a ways to go yet though. Also Stevie gets a few moments to shine, she&amp;rsquo;s really the surprise soul of this series in a lot of ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only one more season!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/20/schitts-creek-season-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/20/schitts-creek-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Death and pregnancy; the Rose children growing up, Johnny finally has something to do, and Moira is&amp;hellip; Moira. Oy&amp;ndash;ra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit amused that we got the pregnancy storyline &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;without Jocelyn's actress even being pregnant IRL; I feel like that's the more common reason to work in something like this. It works though!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fun season. Onward we barrel towards the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/08/schitts-creek-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/08/schitts-creek-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really picking up now! I&amp;rsquo;m actually starting to really enjoy the relationships between the characters. David is still my favorite, but Alexis ia really growing on me. And I still don&amp;rsquo;t care much for Moira.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire idea of David not having a (valid) driver&amp;rsquo;s license or Alexis never having graduated High School because rich/reasons&amp;hellip; actually makes a lot of sense. But Alexis actually &lt;em&gt;going&lt;/em&gt; to High School? In what universe would that happen&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s what GEDs are for. Really pulled me out of the plotline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, an enjoyable enough season. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how quickly shows with shorter episodes go by&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/30/schitts-creek-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/30/schitts-creek-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Much better than season 1! It&amp;rsquo;s still cringe, but at least David is trying, Alexis is failing, and their parents are&amp;hellip; surviving?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I appreciate about this season is how the rest of the cast is getting slightly less caricaturish. Roland is still full on Roland, but Jocelyn is really growing into a good person who&amp;rsquo;s still perfectly fine at snarking at the Rose&amp;rsquo;s. Even Bob is starting to fire back. Makes the town council &amp;lsquo;main plot&amp;rsquo; amusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still a very quick watch. Onward to season 3.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/24/schitts-creek-season-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/24/schitts-creek-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tonally&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; different from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/18/mr.-robot-season-4/"&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/a&gt;. Bit of whiplash from that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, a rich family loses everything&amp;hellip; but the town they bought for a joke (see? rich). Now they have to go live there, with the overblown locals. A whole new way of life to learn and all the hilarious complications that come from that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not the kind of show that I usually like, since it&amp;rsquo;s just so &amp;hellip; cringey/awkward. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to watch people lose everything and just seem so &amp;hellip; bad at being human. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know anyone in that income bracket or especially anyone that&amp;rsquo;s lost so much. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any easier to believe. They&amp;rsquo;re each quick watches at around 20 minutes though. That&amp;rsquo;s something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there are a number of really funny moments in there. David is great, Stevie is great. Johnny&amp;ndash;I can&amp;rsquo;t get American Pie out of my head. Alexis and especially Moira aren&amp;rsquo;t great, but so it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worth giving a few episodes a try. It gets better throughout the season.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>