<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Schitt's Creek on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/schitts-creek/</link><description>Recent content in Schitt's Creek on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/schitts-creek/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/08/schitts-creek-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/08/schitts-creek-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/schitts-creek-season-2.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s really picking up now! I&amp;rsquo;m actually starting to really enjoy the relationships between the characters. David is still my favorite, but Alexis ia really growing on me. And I still don&amp;rsquo;t care much for Moira.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The entire idea of David not having a (valid) driver&amp;rsquo;s license or Alexis never having graduated High School because rich/reasons&amp;hellip; actually makes a lot of sense. But Alexis actually &lt;em>going&lt;/em> to High School? In what universe would that happen&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s what GEDs are for. Really pulled me out of the plotline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, an enjoyable enough season. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how quickly shows with shorter episodes go by&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/30/schitts-creek-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/30/schitts-creek-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/schitts-creek-season-2.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Much better than season 1! It&amp;rsquo;s still cringe, but at least David is trying, Alexis is failing, and their parents are&amp;hellip; surviving?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I appreciate about this season is how the rest of the cast is getting slightly less caricaturish. Roland is still full on Roland, but Jocelyn is really growing into a good person who&amp;rsquo;s still perfectly fine at snarking at the Rose&amp;rsquo;s. Even Bob is starting to fire back. Makes the town council &amp;lsquo;main plot&amp;rsquo; amusing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still a very quick watch. Onward to season 3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/24/schitts-creek-season-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/24/schitts-creek-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/schitts-creek-season-1.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Tonally&amp;hellip; &lt;em>very&lt;/em> different from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/18/mr.-robot-season-4/">Mr. Robot&lt;/a>. Bit of whiplash from that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, a rich family loses everything&amp;hellip; but the town they bought for a joke (see? rich). Now they have to go live there, with the overblown locals. A whole new way of life to learn and all the hilarious complications that come from that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not the kind of show that I usually like, since it&amp;rsquo;s just so &amp;hellip; cringey/awkward. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to watch people lose everything and just seem so &amp;hellip; bad at being human. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know anyone in that income bracket or especially anyone that&amp;rsquo;s lost so much. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any easier to believe. They&amp;rsquo;re each quick watches at around 20 minutes though. That&amp;rsquo;s something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, there are a number of really funny moments in there. David is great, Stevie is great. Johnny&amp;ndash;I can&amp;rsquo;t get American Pie out of my head. Alexis and especially Moira aren&amp;rsquo;t great, but so it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth giving a few episodes a try. It gets better throughout the season.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>