<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 Movie Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-movie-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 Movie Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-movie-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Encanto</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/13/encanto/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/13/encanto/</guid><description>Disney has really been doing quite well the last 12 years. Tangled, Wreck-It Ralph, Frozen, Big Hero 6, Moana, and now Encanto? (I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen Raya yet) All really solid films. Encanto specifically, I really enjoyed. It&amp;rsquo;s got great songs, fun characters, beautiful animation, and a lovely story. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to see a story based on yet another culture&amp;ndash;Columbia this time&amp;ndash;Disney is really doing that well. Overall, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t quite put it to the level of Moana, but it&amp;rsquo;s just about there.</description></item><item><title>Harry Potter 20th Anniversary: Return to Hogwarts</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/17/harry-potter-20th-anniversary-return-to-hogwarts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/17/harry-potter-20th-anniversary-return-to-hogwarts/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/movies/harry-potter-20th-anniversary-return-to-hogwarts.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>You know&amp;hellip; I should really re-watch those movies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I expect is the case for many in roughly my age bracket, Harry Potter was a huge part of my life growing up. I think I got into it with the release of the 3rd or 4th book (can&amp;rsquo;t quite remember) and absolutely devoured each book after that the night it came out. I watched all of the movies a number of times. It was absolutely fascinating watching the characters in this other world basically growing up with me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now&amp;hellip; 20 years later.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode IX - The Rise of Skywalker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/star-wars-episode-ix-the-rise-of-skywalker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/star-wars-episode-ix-the-rise-of-skywalker/</guid><description>Given the internet&amp;rsquo;s backlast, I exepcted a lot worse. At least to me, The Rise of Skywalker did a pretty decent job of closing the loop on the saga that began a long time ago with the rise of Palpatine and the fall of Anakin Skywalker. Really, that&amp;rsquo;s the entire story, and you get that here in spades.
There were definitely some weird choices made in pacing (in particular, right at the beginning, they sort of drop the whole &amp;lsquo;Emperor is back&amp;rsquo; thing on us&amp;hellip; apparently the reveal came in &amp;hellip; Fortnite?</description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VIII - The Last Jedi</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/05/star-wars-episode-viii-the-last-jedi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/05/star-wars-episode-viii-the-last-jedi/</guid><description>More Star Wars! I remember being&amp;hellip; somewhat disappointed. Tonally, they got away from the nostalgia of the Force Awakens. There are still some absolutely beautiful/powerful moments (the final battles over the salt flats or whatever those were were pretty cool), but not quite as strong as it was before. And there are all sorts of things that just feel &amp;rsquo;less magical&amp;rsquo; and more movie driven than anything.
This time around, I liked it a lot more.</description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VII - The Force Awakens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/04/star-wars-episode-vii-the-force-awakens/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/04/star-wars-episode-vii-the-force-awakens/</guid><description>Woo, new Star Wars! I remember the hype when The Force Awakens first came out. It was pretty crazy to see new Star Wars for the first time (second time?) in years. And it&amp;rsquo;s pretty dang cool. It&amp;rsquo;s shinier than the original trilogy, a bit less stuck in the weeds (trade blockades!) than the prequels, and it leans hard on nostalgia. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s Star Wars! Could they have done something newer and more unique?</description></item><item><title>The Star</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/03/the-star/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/03/the-star/</guid><description>Not really sure what to say about this one. It&amp;rsquo;s the Nativity story told from the point of view of various animals, voiced by a few famous people (Kris Kristofferson as &amp;lsquo;Old Donkey&amp;rsquo; was pretty awesome&amp;hellip; also Oprah apparently?).
It&amp;rsquo;s a cute enough story and the kids enjoy it. The songs are a nice touch.
I expect this will be fairly low on my list for the year, mostly since I&amp;rsquo;m&amp;hellip; not really the target audience.</description></item><item><title>The Grinch</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/02/the-grinch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/02/the-grinch/</guid><description>Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s nostalgia speaking, but I really miss the 1966 How the Grinch Stole Christmas! It was basically a reading of the book with a great narrator (Boris Karloff, who amusingly is best known for a bunch of 1930-40s horror films) and a few new songs that really fit the Seuss style. Given that the Grinch is probably in my top 5 Seuss books overall, of course I like it.</description></item></channel></rss>