<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Altered Carbon on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/altered-carbon/</link><description>Recent content in Altered Carbon on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/altered-carbon/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Altered Carbon: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/01/altered-carbon-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/01/altered-carbon-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/altered-carbon.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>That is a spectacular show. In a nutshell, it takes a cyberpunk future world where the technology exists to separate the &amp;lsquo;mind&amp;rsquo;/stack/DHF of a person from their body/sleeve. Really, it&amp;rsquo;s primarily a tool for the wealthy to accumulate even more wealth and a number of the characters mention that we aren&amp;rsquo;t meant to live forever&amp;hellip; And that actually made me think. It&amp;rsquo;s been something I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought would be neat: to be able to repair or move into another body if this is damaged, to send me mind to other worlds, etc. But how in the world would people react to that sort of power and change?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the very least, let&amp;rsquo;s hope it&amp;rsquo;s better than what we see in Altered Carbon. Hoo boy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s part detective show that segues into murder/revenge/revolution plots with more than a dash of questions around identity in a world where bodies are quite literally and easily (if not cheaply) replaceable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of rather graphic violence and nudity, but for the most part it makes sense within the context of the show. Certainly not one for the kids though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The casting, I loved. Joel Kinnaman as Takeshi Kovacs nails the &amp;lsquo;Envoy brought back&amp;rsquo;, Dichen Lachman as Reileen Kawahara is a wonderful &lt;span class="spoiler">example of long lives corrupting people&lt;/span>
. My surprise favorite? Chris Conner as &amp;lsquo;Poe&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the AI running an Edgar Allen Poe themed hotel that hasn&amp;rsquo;t seen a guest in years/decades. He&amp;rsquo;s such a surprisingly wonderful character.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s quite a spectacular show. Well worth the watch. Now the confusing it&amp;hellip; &lt;span class="spoiler">apparently almost the entire cast was replaced for S2?&lt;/span>
It&amp;rsquo;s something that the concept of the show certainly allows, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know how in the world they&amp;rsquo;re going to pull that one off. I guess we&amp;rsquo;ll see!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>