<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raymond St. Elmo on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/raymond-st.-elmo/</link><description>Recent content in Raymond St. Elmo on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/raymond-st.-elmo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Letters from a Shipwreck in the Sea of Suns and Moons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/letters-from-a-shipwreck-in-the-sea-of-suns-and-moons/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/letters-from-a-shipwreck-in-the-sea-of-suns-and-moons/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We are the interviewers. For a story.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And who am I?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You are the old sailor who remembers being a young sailor on Unicorn, a three masted schooner out of San Francisco plying the Pacific waters.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That sounds familiar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You are Clarence St. Elmo, for a name. You are a bad poet lost in the sea of time, a castaway on an island where the dead gods wander.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That sounds awful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>And beyond a name, on that side of things, past the mirror and the window and the words, you are the Keeper of Shipwreck Light in the Sea of Suns and Moons.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, I knew that.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That&amp;hellip; is a truly delightfully weird book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It jumps around in structure and time between letters from a sailor to the girl he left back home&amp;ndash;to said sailor being interviewed by &amp;hellip; someone&amp;ndash;to stories about a most mysterious shipwreck and the island he came to inhabit thereafter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Structurally, it&amp;rsquo;s very strange and at times hard to figure out what in the world is going on&amp;ndash;but that&amp;rsquo;s all intentional. It&amp;rsquo;s really quite worth it in the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s not much more I can say without spoiling the whole thing&amp;ndash;that is, if I really actually understood what and how, if anything, of the story actually happened. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth a read.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>