<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2019 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2019/</link><description>Recent content in 2019 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2019/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Star Wars: Episode IX - The Rise of Skywalker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/star-wars-episode-ix-the-rise-of-skywalker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/star-wars-episode-ix-the-rise-of-skywalker/</guid><description>Given the internet&amp;rsquo;s backlast, I exepcted a lot worse. At least to me, The Rise of Skywalker did a pretty decent job of closing the loop on the saga that began a long time ago with the rise of Palpatine and the fall of Anakin Skywalker. Really, that&amp;rsquo;s the entire story, and you get that here in spades.
There were definitely some weird choices made in pacing (in particular, right at the beginning, they sort of drop the whole &amp;lsquo;Emperor is back&amp;rsquo; thing on us&amp;hellip; apparently the reveal came in &amp;hellip; Fortnite?</description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</guid><description>As much as I loved Spider-Man: Homecoming, Spider-Man: Far From Home takes what made it great and turns it up a few levels even further.
One one level, you have Spider-Man being Spider-Man. He&amp;rsquo;s a good kid, trying to make his way in life, trying to deal with the dual life of being a highschooler and being a superhero&amp;ndash;of saving the world and perhaps getting the girl.
And then you layer all the weight of the greater MCU on top of it.</description></item><item><title>Knives Out</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/24/knives-out/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/24/knives-out/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lieutenant Elliott: I&amp;rsquo;m sorry this is an open and shut case of suicide and quite frankly Benny we are getting to the point where I have to ask you what we&amp;rsquo;re doing here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Benoit Blanc: The method? Throat slit? Typical for a suicide?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lieutenant Elliott: Yes, I mean, that&amp;rsquo;s dramatic, but look around. I mean, the guy practical lives in a Clue board.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was a surprising yet great fun movie. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a murder mystery. Heir of the family is found dead&amp;ndash;apparent suicide. But things quickly become more complicated, with a detective (Daniel Craig as Benoit Blanc with a hilarious southern drawl that still somehow works&amp;hellip;) anonymously hired to &amp;lsquo;get to the truth&amp;rsquo;. The family is a nightmare, everyone has a reason to have offed the old man&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shazam!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/shazam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/shazam/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was not really what I expected. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s got the heart of a super hero origin story, with Billy Batson gaining powers, learning to use them (and not lose himself or his friends/family while doing so), and fighting the big bad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Endgame</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</guid><description>Wow.
That&amp;rsquo;s one heck of a climax.
In Avengers: Infinity War, Thanos won. He snapped and half of the universe died&amp;ndash;let&amp;rsquo;s ignore the logistics of that. In Endgame, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance&amp;ndash;a very small chance&amp;ndash;that they can fix it all. All they need is a little &amp;ndash;
Tony Stark: [discussing the &amp;ldquo;Time Heist&amp;rdquo;] I believe the most likely outcome will be our collective demise.
Scott Lang: Not if we strictly follow the rules of time travel.</description></item><item><title>Captain Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/</guid><description>Captain Marvel is a bit of an odd movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a straight up superhero origin story with a bit more of a cosmic twist than many we&amp;rsquo;ve seen (other than Guardians of the Galaxy&amp;hellip; and Thor&amp;hellip;) It&amp;rsquo;s something of a prequel&amp;ndash;in that it&amp;rsquo;s chronologically set before any of the other Marvel movies other than the beginning of Captain America. It&amp;rsquo;s got a hero in Captain Marvel with a grab bag of vaguely defined glowy energy powers with memory issues who has to go on a journey and power up to her final form.</description></item></channel></rss>