<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2019 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2019/</link><description>Recent content in 2019 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2019/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black Mirror: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/07/black-mirror-season-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/07/black-mirror-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>A whole series in three episodes? Whee!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how the three episodes are at once similar and so different. There&amp;rsquo;s little enough radically different technology&amp;ndash;mostly extrapolations of what we have now or may expect to have soon&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s done well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And even with just three, we already have one that&amp;rsquo;s a straight forward exploration, one that&amp;rsquo;s more of a slow burn, and one that has a sudden sharp escalation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot to fit into a short season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For All Mankind: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/16/for-all-mankind-season-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/16/for-all-mankind-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Watched with someone that didn&amp;rsquo;t know what the show was about. A few minutes of &amp;ldquo;okay, so it&amp;rsquo;s about the moon landing.&amp;rdquo; And then the moment when he speaks&amp;hellip; Delightful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about &lt;strong>STOP READING NOW AND GO WATCH THIS SHOW&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m waiting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea of an alternate history where the Soviets made it to the moon is so fascinating. And it&amp;rsquo;s only made all the better by all the character moments and (surprisingly to me) other historical events &lt;em>not on the moon&lt;/em> we see along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s such a good show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to what they do with Season 2. What changes&amp;hellip; and what stays the same?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Boys: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/05/the-boys-season-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/05/the-boys-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things just keep getting more bonkers and bloody. Really, if you made it this far, you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to love Season 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Boys are (still) out to deal with Homelander&amp;hellip; and they may just have found the weapon to do it. Only this time the solution is perhaps eve more expensive than the cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Homelander is really the (wonderful terrible) heart of the show. Anthony Starr is amazing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a few new supes running around (in secret). And all sorts of ones we knew about doing even more terrible and deprived things in general.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And in the end, the more things change, the more things stay the same. But worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Season 4. It&amp;rsquo;s weird to be caught up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Boys: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/the-boys-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/the-boys-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Managed to get away for a bit since [[The Boys: Season 1|season 1]]; sometimes life happens (but not for everyone in the Boys&amp;hellip;). But I finally made it through season 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man this is a violent bloody show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still quite the exploration for &amp;lsquo;what if superheroes were real&amp;hellip; and terrible&amp;rsquo; that really draws you in, but now with more terrible corporations. And Nazis. Because of course we had to go there. It actually works really well, the conflict of benefiting from Nazi science is a &lt;em>big deal&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still really enjoy (in a twisted way) how terrifying Antony Starr plays Homelander. If he goes off the rails, what &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> are you going to do to stop him?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus show Hughie (really all of the &amp;rsquo;the Boys&amp;rsquo;) is far better than his comic counterpart. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see him well out of his comfort zone, both in relationships (especially with Starlight) and all the madcap shenanigans Butcher&amp;rsquo;s gang gets up to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, mostly Nazis, but Compound V not only getting revealed the the characters, but also going public? We haven&amp;rsquo;t nearly seen the ramifications of that. Hoping to see more of &lt;em>that&lt;/em> in Season 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, great show. Very much deserves the R rating. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/14/downton-abbey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/14/downton-abbey/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Royal Family comes to Downton Abbey.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Anna Bates: Is it always like this?&lt;br>
Richard Ellis: A royal visit is like a swan on a lake. Grace and serenity above, demented kicking down below.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s basically a film length episode of Downton Abbey. And that&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I would have preferred it stay on the small screen, but if that isn&amp;rsquo;t in the cards, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to at least have a chance to have one last* (grand) hurrah for the characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Boys: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/09/the-boys-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/09/the-boys-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve previously watched the first season and read the comics, but with season 3 out now (and I haven’t reviewed the show previously), let’s watch it again. Should be interesting seeing what’s different this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow that&amp;rsquo;s violent. Just as bad if not worse than the comics, since you get to see it all on screen. But in a way that actually has some solid visuals and crazy scenes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fruits Basket: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/27/fruits-basket-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/27/fruits-basket-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I started the second season&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, we do get a bit of backstory with parent issues (oh so many parent issues), the rest of the zodiac (more or less), and some answers about Akito.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, there are piles of weird age issues (I know this is apparently an anime staple; that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it better) and episode after episode dedicated to &amp;hellip; the student council of all things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We made it through 15 episodes of this season. Fin. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fruits Basket: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/26/fruits-basket-season-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/26/fruits-basket-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I expect there are those who really love it, but &amp;hellip; this is not a show for me. I don’t like most of the characters (and &lt;em>really&lt;/em> don’t like some of them), most of the plots are entirely too high school, and the magic of the world/zodiac is criminally underused/explored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode IX - The Rise of Skywalker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/star-wars-episode-ix-the-rise-of-skywalker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/star-wars-episode-ix-the-rise-of-skywalker/</guid><description>Given the internet&amp;rsquo;s backlast, I exepcted a lot worse. At least to me, The Rise of Skywalker did a pretty decent job of closing the loop on the saga that began a long time ago with the rise of Palpatine and the fall of Anakin Skywalker. Really, that&amp;rsquo;s the entire story, and you get that here in spades.
There were definitely some weird choices made in pacing (in particular, right at the beginning, they sort of drop the whole &amp;lsquo;Emperor is back&amp;rsquo; thing on us&amp;hellip; apparently the reveal came in &amp;hellip; Fortnite?</description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</guid><description>As much as I loved Spider-Man: Homecoming, Spider-Man: Far From Home takes what made it great and turns it up a few levels even further.
One one level, you have Spider-Man being Spider-Man. He&amp;rsquo;s a good kid, trying to make his way in life, trying to deal with the dual life of being a highschooler and being a superhero&amp;ndash;of saving the world and perhaps getting the girl.
And then you layer all the weight of the greater MCU on top of it.</description></item><item><title>Knives Out</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/24/knives-out/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/24/knives-out/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lieutenant Elliott: I&amp;rsquo;m sorry this is an open and shut case of suicide and quite frankly Benny we are getting to the point where I have to ask you what we&amp;rsquo;re doing here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Benoit Blanc: The method? Throat slit? Typical for a suicide?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lieutenant Elliott: Yes, I mean, that&amp;rsquo;s dramatic, but look around. I mean, the guy practical lives in a Clue board.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was a surprising yet great fun movie. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a murder mystery. Heir of the family is found dead&amp;ndash;apparent suicide. But things quickly become more complicated, with a detective (Daniel Craig as Benoit Blanc with a hilarious southern drawl that still somehow works&amp;hellip;) anonymously hired to &amp;lsquo;get to the truth&amp;rsquo;. The family is a nightmare, everyone has a reason to have offed the old man&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shazam!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/shazam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/shazam/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was not really what I expected. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s got the heart of a super hero origin story, with Billy Batson gaining powers, learning to use them (and not lose himself or his friends/family while doing so), and fighting the big bad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Endgame</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</guid><description>Wow.
That&amp;rsquo;s one heck of a climax.
In Avengers: Infinity War, Thanos won. He snapped and half of the universe died&amp;ndash;let&amp;rsquo;s ignore the logistics of that. In Endgame, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance&amp;ndash;a very small chance&amp;ndash;that they can fix it all. All they need is a little &amp;ndash;
Tony Stark: [discussing the &amp;ldquo;Time Heist&amp;rdquo;] I believe the most likely outcome will be our collective demise.
Scott Lang: Not if we strictly follow the rules of time travel.</description></item><item><title>Captain Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/</guid><description>Captain Marvel is a bit of an odd movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a straight up superhero origin story with a bit more of a cosmic twist than many we&amp;rsquo;ve seen (other than Guardians of the Galaxy&amp;hellip; and Thor&amp;hellip;) It&amp;rsquo;s something of a prequel&amp;ndash;in that it&amp;rsquo;s chronologically set before any of the other Marvel movies other than the beginning of Captain America. It&amp;rsquo;s got a hero in Captain Marvel with a grab bag of vaguely defined glowy energy powers with memory issues who has to go on a journey and power up to her final form.</description></item></channel></rss>