<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Moonbase Saga on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/30/moonbase-saga/</link><description>Recent content in Moonbase Saga on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/30/moonbase-saga/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moonwar</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/30/moonwar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/30/moonwar/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/30/moonwar/">Moonwar&lt;/a> finishes the story of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/23/moonrise/">Moonrise&lt;/a>, really establishing Moonbase as a power in the solar system in its own right and a refuge from the growing New Morality movements on Earth&amp;ndash;especially when it comes to developing nano-technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are certainly parts of the story that are hard to believe&amp;ndash;particularly just how much control the UN has over &amp;hellip; well, anything, but especially the media. It&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip; strange and feels like a manufactured threat. On the other hand, the idea of a religious far right growing to power and working to completely ban &amp;lsquo;unnatural&amp;rsquo; technology (like nanomachines) feels altogether too prescient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moonrise</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/23/moonrise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/23/moonrise/</guid><description>&lt;p>A bit of a jump in focus and topic from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/14/mars/">Mars&lt;/a> , &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/23/moonrise/">Moonrise&lt;/a> is more similar to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/26/privateers/">Privateers&lt;/a> et al (the Dan Randolph books), with more of a focus on corporate structure over science.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amusingly, despite the title/series, Moonrise is only tangentially about the Moonbase, despite a large chunk of the book taking place there. Really, it&amp;rsquo;s about the bizarre broken family and corporate dynamic of Masterson Aerospace and the rise of nanotechnology in Ben Bova&amp;rsquo;s universe. From what I remember of other books in the series (from more than a decade ago), the rise of technology and the idea of it being banned on Earth for religious reasons is a fairly major plot point from here on out, so it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how that all began.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>