<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2006 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2006/</link><description>Recent content in 2006 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2006/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lost: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/30/lost-season-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/30/lost-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Season 1 was all about surviving on the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 2 was all about mysteries. More survivors. The Hatch. A monster made of smoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we get Season 3: All about the Others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, what a season that was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learn how they live in several different guises, from the cages of &lt;em&gt;A Tale of Two Cities&lt;/em&gt; to the village/barracks of &lt;em&gt;Stranger in a Strange Land&lt;/em&gt;, to a sort of mass exodus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom: Hey, you got yourself a fish biscuit! How&amp;rsquo;d you do that?&lt;br&gt;
Sawyer: Figured out your complicated gizmos, thats how.&lt;br&gt;
Tom: It only took the bears two hours.&lt;br&gt;
[Sawyer contemplates briefly]&lt;br&gt;
Sawyer: How many of &amp;rsquo;em were there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All sorts of medical madness, in &lt;em&gt;Every Man for Himself&lt;/em&gt; and pretty much anything with Juliet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that all, one character who &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; goes through an arc this season is Locke. He&amp;rsquo;s lost his way&amp;hellip; only to find it again. And lose it. And find another. Oh Locke. You&amp;rsquo;re so very interesting, but also so hard to actually root for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sayid: Kate, if you were looking for help to find Jack, why didn&amp;rsquo;t you ask us?&lt;br&gt;
Kate: Two reasons: you don&amp;rsquo;t know where to look and you&amp;rsquo;re not motivated. And I don&amp;rsquo;t blame you. Why would you want to go on another trek across the island, risk more lives just to get Jack back?&lt;br&gt;
Locke: You&amp;rsquo;re wrong.&lt;br&gt;
Kate: Oh, really? They why didn&amp;rsquo;t you come after-&lt;br&gt;
Locke: Not about the motivation, just about knowing where to look. We got a compass bearing, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure if we follow it, it&amp;rsquo;ll lead us right to &amp;rsquo;em.&lt;br&gt;
Kate: How?&lt;br&gt;
Sayid: Because of the way the sunlight hit Mr. Eko&amp;rsquo;s stick&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my continued favorite though? Desmond. Wakes up naked. Wakes up in his flat. Wakes up and buys a ring. Oh, he&amp;rsquo;s got a complicated life, both on the island and off of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desmond Hume: See you in another life, brother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a less positive note, we have main-character-who-have-obviously-been-there-all-along Nikki and Paulo. I mean, it worked well enough for Desmond and seems to be working okay for Juliet. So why not someone else? But they come out of nowhere and get all &lt;em&gt;Expose&lt;/em&gt;d by the end. So it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that&amp;hellip; to go &lt;em&gt;Through the Looking Glass&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, this is a fun show.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Night at the Museum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/26/night-at-the-museum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/26/night-at-the-museum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Another on that list of movies I&amp;rsquo;m a little surprised I&amp;rsquo;d never seen before&amp;ndash;yet I&amp;rsquo;ve seen enough random clips on YouTube shorts at this point that I feel like I have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Side note: This also came back to mind since Ben Stiller wrote a good amount of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/severance/"&gt;Severance&lt;/a&gt; of all things.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s a ridiculous and fun movie. The whole premise&amp;ndash;that a magical artifact somehow animates all the exhibits at the museum every night&amp;ndash;yet somehow no one has ever noticed this? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the list bit of sense. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any less fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easter Island Head: HEY!&lt;br&gt;
[pauses]&lt;br&gt;
Easter Island Head: Dum-dum.&lt;br&gt;
Larry: Yes?&lt;br&gt;
Easter Island Head: You give me gum-gum!&lt;br&gt;
Larry: I give you gum-gum?&lt;br&gt;
Easter Island Head: You new Dum-dum. You give me gum-gum.&lt;br&gt;
Larry: Gee, okay, you know what? I have no gum-gum. Sorry. And my name isn&amp;rsquo;t Dum-dum. My name&amp;rsquo;s Larry.&lt;br&gt;
Easter Island Head: No, your name Dum-dum.&lt;br&gt;
[some people are running away]&lt;br&gt;
Easter Island Head: Oh, you in trouble, Dum-dum. You better run-run. From Attila the Hun-hun.&lt;br&gt;
[Attila yells and chases Larry]&lt;br&gt;
Easter Island Head: See you later, Dum-dum!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of fun action scenes in the movie. Just don&amp;rsquo;t think about it all too hard and enjoy the ride. I especially loved the chaos of the dioramas of thousands of tiny men come to life and fighting one another. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jedediah: No problemo, Gigantor.&lt;br&gt;
Larry: Um, my name&amp;rsquo;s Larry, first of all okay, Jed? See, I call you Jed, I don&amp;rsquo;t call you tiny, right?&lt;br&gt;
Jedediah: What&amp;rsquo;s that supposed to mean?&lt;br&gt;
Larry: Hey teeny, how does that sound?&lt;br&gt;
Jedediah: I&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t like it. It hurts my feelings.&lt;br&gt;
Larry: Okay, well Gigantor makes me feel like some sort of freak.&lt;br&gt;
Octavius: I don&amp;rsquo;t. I just call you Larry.&lt;br&gt;
Larry: Don&amp;rsquo;t be a kiss-ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The casting in this movie is a big strength! Dick Van Dyke was a lot of fun as old former night watchman Cecil. Robin Williams (RIP :sad:) is always a delight and his Teddy Roosevelt was no exception. Rami Malek is certainly no &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mr.-robot/"&gt;Mr. Robot&lt;/a&gt;, but he&amp;rsquo;s got a perfect presence as Ahkmenrah. And Steve Coogan as Octavius and Owen Wilson&amp;rsquo;s Jedediah were hilarious (especially since the latter was originally a minor cameo).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And you know? Apparently &amp;lsquo;The real-life American Museum of Natural History had 20% more visitors during the holiday season following this movie&amp;rsquo;s opening.&amp;rsquo; So good on them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the sequels? No idea where they go from here, but you know what? Worth a try!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/doctor-who-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/doctor-who-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m still re-watching Doctor Who in fits and starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, after all that was great with Eccleston/Nine in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/02/doctor-who-season-1/"&gt;season 1&lt;/a&gt;, how we get Tennant/Ten. Oh, I do enjoy his take on the doctor. It&amp;rsquo;s a perfect mix of a whimsical seeing what he can get away with&amp;ndash;with the absolute feel of sadness and age that a being like the Doctor really should be feeling&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And all with Rose along for the ride. Rose gets a lot of hate at times, but I really think she was a pretty good first nu-Who companion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this season, we a fair few two parters, a bunch of great episodes. &lt;a href="#4-the-girl-in-the-fireplace"&gt;The Girl in the Fireplace&lt;/a&gt; is a great take on &amp;rsquo;the Time Travelers wife&amp;rsquo; sort of thing. &lt;a href="#5-rise-of-the-cybermen"&gt;Rise of the Cybermen&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="#6-age-of-steel"&gt;Age of Steel&lt;/a&gt; introduces us to some old foes. &lt;a href="#8-the-impossible-planet"&gt;The Impossible Planet&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="#9-satan-pit"&gt;Satan Pit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; start getting into Doctor Who as sci-fi/horror (and I love it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="#10-love--monsters"&gt;Love &amp;amp; Monsters&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; actually not that bad? It&amp;rsquo;s definitely one of the &amp;lsquo;Doctor-lite&amp;rsquo; episodes, which are always something interesting to try. The ending is crass and kind of terrifying to really think about&amp;ndash;rather than the laughs you might think they were going for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, a solid season!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href="#special-the-runaway-bride"&gt;the special&lt;/a&gt; introduces Donna! Even if she won&amp;rsquo;t be back for a bit, she&amp;rsquo;s certainly a contender for my favorite companion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/02/doctor-who-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/02/doctor-who-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched through modern Doctor Who a few times, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a while. I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually caught the 13th Doctor yet, let alone 14 and 15&amp;hellip; Now, with the new &amp;lsquo;reboot&amp;rsquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s about time to give it another go. And a good time to review them this time around!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I love this show. It&amp;rsquo;s wacky and cheap looking at times. Tonally, we&amp;rsquo;re all over the place, from farting aliens right up to the borders (if not more so) of horror with The Empty Child. Callbacks to the old show (which I still haven&amp;rsquo;t watched, one day) and all new friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do wish we&amp;rsquo;d gotten more of Eccelston, I forgot how much I liked his Doctor. But still, it&amp;rsquo;s good to have what we have!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Underworld: Evolution</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/underworld-evolution/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/underworld-evolution/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Quite an interesting contrast compared to the first &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/underworld/"&gt;Underworld&lt;/a&gt;. Where the first was a straight forward vampire/werewolf urban fantasy action flick, Evolution tries to be more. We get deeper worldbuilding, more backstory&amp;ndash;especially for Selene&amp;ndash;and more hints that the entire world is changing. It works&amp;hellip; well enough?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Man's Chest</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/14/pirates-of-the-caribbean-dead-mans-chest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/14/pirates-of-the-caribbean-dead-mans-chest/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/pirates-of-the-caribbean-the-curse-of-the-black-pearl/"&gt;Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl&lt;/a&gt; was surprisingly good. So of course they&amp;rsquo;re going to make a sequel and turn everything up to 11. More Johnny Depp (yay)! More love triangles (boo)! More supernatural beasties (awesome)! More mythology (sweet)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the plus side, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like. As mentioned Depp is still great. That&amp;rsquo;s probably the number one reasons these movies are as awesome as they are. He just nails the roll.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>