<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2021 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2021-tv-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2021 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2021-tv-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2021 TV &amp; Movies Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-tv-movies-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-tv-movies-retrospective/</guid><description>I do a post each year on books, but this year I also started reviewing movies and TV shows! I have absolutely no idea how much value people get out of this (and I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you), but I enjoy doing it, so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to stop any time soon. :D
In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s been a good year for movies and TV!
Overall, I watched:
55 movies</description></item><item><title>The Wheel of Time: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/</guid><description>The Wheel of Time turns, and ages come and pass, leaving memories that become legend. Legend fades to myth, and even myth is long forgotten when the Age that gave it birth comes again. In one Age, called the Third Age by some, an Age yet to come, an Age long past, a wind rose in the Mountains of Mist. The wind was not the beginning. There are neither beginnings nor endings to the turning of the Wheel of time.</description></item><item><title>Hawkeye</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/22/hawkeye/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/22/hawkeye/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/hawkeye.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed Hawkeye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s just &lt;em>fun&lt;/em>, which compared to &lt;em>Wandvision&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Loki&lt;/em> and really even &lt;em>What If&amp;hellip;&lt;/em> is a worthwhile goal and really does a lot to show off the more human scale of superheroes. It&amp;rsquo;s never really made much sense that Hawkeye and Black Widow were Avengers&amp;hellip; and it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But they do it anyways. Because what Heroes do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see them building up the new &amp;lsquo;Young Avengers&amp;rsquo; and branching out as much as they are. I think Hailee Steinfeld did a great job, especially when acting against &lt;span class="spoiler">Florence Pugh's Yelena&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mr. Robot: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/20/mr.-robot-season-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/20/mr.-robot-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/mr.robot-season-3.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Oh boy. This one really dug into the darker parts of character growth. Elliot finds new ways to be even crazier, Angela is&amp;hellip; off the rails entirely, Moustache Guy (Bobby Cannavale/Irvin) is awesome, and the entire plot of Darlene, Dominque, and the FBI was fascinating to watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I keep being pleasantly surprised with where this show keeps going. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have expected them to make it past the first season plotwise&amp;hellip; yet here we are. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to where we can go from here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mr. Robot: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/mr.-robot-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/mr.-robot-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/mr.robot-season-2.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>After Season 1 wrapped up, where do you even go from there? They finished their big goal. Dealing with the fallout is the obvious answer&amp;hellip; or ramping things up even further. We get a bit of both in Season 2, mostly with even more big twists from Elliot&amp;rsquo;s entirely confusing mind but also a plot that is both deeper and more terrifying than I would have thought at first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not quite as solid as Season 1, in most part because it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as new and fresh. But it&amp;rsquo;s still very good and well worth the watch. Whatever shall we learn in Season 3?!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mr. Robot: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/mr.-robot-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/mr.-robot-season-1/</guid><description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a heck of a show. Given that I&amp;rsquo;m do computer security for a living (albeit with a bit less of the black hat revolutionary mindset) and have my own problems figuring out how brains&amp;ndash;mine and others&amp;ndash;work (albeit not nearly to that extent&amp;hellip;) I feel like the perfect audience for this show. I&amp;rsquo;m honestly impressed with how well they got the hacking in this show. It&amp;rsquo;s not 100%&amp;ndash;that would be boring&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s miles closer than two-hackers-typing-on-a-keyboard-is-faster.</description></item><item><title>Squid Game</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/squid-game/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/squid-game/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t actually do much social media (other than a relatively limited set of subreddits), so I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually notice what was apparently a fairly large storm of people watching Squid Game, but when it came up on Honest Trailers it seemed pretty interesting. 9 episodes and I just finished Stargate Universe, so I figured, let&amp;rsquo;s give it a spin!
Let&amp;rsquo;s say&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s at once exactly what I expected, but even then had a few interesting twists and turns.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos-season-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos-season-6/</guid><description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a lot. In order to finish all of the stories they wanted to tell&amp;ndash;but also not to have to negotiate another season&amp;rsquo;s worth of contracts with the actors, season 6 is really two seasons in one. The first is slightly shorter than the other seasons at 12 (instead of 13), while the second half is only 9. So one big season? Two small? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that much when you&amp;rsquo;re streaming them back to back.</description></item><item><title>Stargate Universe: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/stargate-universe-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/stargate-universe-season-2/</guid><description>Each time I rewatch Stargate (and with 17 seasons and a handful of movies, that&amp;rsquo;s something of a time commitment), I forgot just how much better Stargate Universe season 2 is than season 1. And I already liked Season 1. But 2 is where things really get on their own. The crew trapped on Destiny is really learning how to use the ship and making it their own, finding new (huge) mysteries, and actually getting a few big bads on a scale with the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld/Ori/Wraith.</description></item><item><title>What If...?</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</guid><description>What if…?
It&amp;rsquo;s a wacky title, but it sums up the series pretty well. Take what the MCU has spent a decade building on top of half a century of comics before that1. The comics have done all manner of continuity resets and what-ifs, so it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual to see the stories as they could have been&amp;ndash;if only one thing changed. But this is a first for the MCU. I fully expect with the coming Phase 4, we&amp;rsquo;ll see a bit more of this though.</description></item><item><title>Stargate Universe: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/30/stargate-universe-season-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/30/stargate-universe-season-1/</guid><description>Onward to another universe!
Stargate SG-1 started it all, focusing mostly on adventure and exploring a brand new universe. Stargate Atlantis took that feeling and went hard into the sci-fi nature of the show, giving us an entirely different galaxy and people, dealing with (in some ways) much larger and more complicated threats.
Stargate Universe&amp;hellip; in some ways takes us even father, across tens or hundreds of galaxies to an Ancient (both in manufactory and age) ship&amp;ndash;the Destiny.</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/23/stargate-atlantis-season-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/23/stargate-atlantis-season-5/</guid><description>And so it ends.
I do sorely wish that Atlantis could have gotten another season. There are some very strong episodes in this seaon. As much as I liked Weir and Carter, Woolsey is another huge case of character improvement (almost as much as McKay).
Mini-reviews (potential spoilers):
Search and Rescue: Half a closed room, buried deep in a collapsed building, half Teyla. Neither quite what I was hoping for.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/18/the-sopranos-season-5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/18/the-sopranos-season-5/</guid><description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a season. It&amp;rsquo;s great to see how Christopher has been growing over the series&amp;ndash;man that penultimate episode though. The introduction and arc of Tony B (Buscemi is wonderful) is quite a thing. It just keeps picking up. Crazy to think there&amp;rsquo;s only one more season, even if almost double length.
Mini-reviews per episode:
Two Tonys: The old guard’s the new guard, Christopher and Paulie are (still) butting heads and perhaps they don’t have to whack Carmine after all.</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/10/stargate-atlantis-season-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/10/stargate-atlantis-season-4/</guid><description>Onward!
It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy season in how it begins (lost in space!) and ends (lost in time!). More replicators, more wraith, more variations thereof. A handful of smaller episodes with only small combinations of main cast really shine. We lose a few of the big leads and gain a few more old names. It&amp;rsquo;s also always interesting how shows deal with the pregnancy of a main cast member.
Onwards and Season 5-wards!</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/stargate-atlantis-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/stargate-atlantis-season-3/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like in this series. We get new, complicate Wraith threats (Michael and Todd!), Replicators, lost Ancients, and some of the best McKay episodes in the show (McKay and Mrs. Miller and Tao of Rodney). Not to mention Lucius Lavin. No really. :) And then there&amp;rsquo;s Sunday&amp;hellip; Man it sucks to kill off major characters just to raise the stakes, but it still works as an episode.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-sopranos-season-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-sopranos-season-4/</guid><description>Man that was another season. Ralphie is a great character to love to hate, Christopher is really having some drug issues, and things really come to a head between Tony and Carmela. A great season and I look forward to the next.
Mini-reviews per episode:
All Debts, Public and Private: Ralphie and Janice now… come on . No-Show: Meadow is moody, Christopher is moving up—that’s going to be trouble.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 9</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</guid><description>A great season! I loved all of the people on here. I was writing up my favorite and &amp;hellip; I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it. They&amp;rsquo;re all a lot of fun.
First entry in the first task: How large are Greg Davies’ shits… We’re off to quite a season. Hiding eggplants is a wonderful task. “It’s amazing how much it compacts down into a baby’s head.” “You scored the same as Rose… and she couldn’t see.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 9</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</guid><description>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s quite a cast.
Alan Davies: The old one. Desiree Burch: She certainly goes all out. Guz Khan: Those eyes. Morgana Robinson: So very emotive… The word that comes to mind is ‘fae’ Victoria Coren Mitchell: Subtle and hilarious when you realize it. Series reviews:
An inbalance in the poppability
Well that started delightfully risqué, escalates to swearing at Alex, and ended up with a prize task submission… of Personally the chair he’s sitting on.</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/09/stargate-atlantis-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/09/stargate-atlantis-season-2/</guid><description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a beginning and ending, with a whole lot in between. One of the biggest changes is the introduction of Ronan Dex. Replacement for Lt. Ford who has a tendency to shoot first and ask questions&amp;ndash;well, never. He&amp;rsquo;s quite the character and a good addition to the team. Interesting that the main team is half from Pegasus now.
Mini-reviews (potential spoilers):
Siege, Part 3: Man this is a fun three parter.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/28/the-sopranos-season-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/28/the-sopranos-season-3/</guid><description>That&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an odd season. The original plotline had to be thrown out on account of the actress that played Tony's mom dying , so the whole &amp;lsquo;do they have a case against Tony&amp;rsquo; thing falls through. As a result, it&amp;rsquo;s not the most cohesive of seasons, but there are a few gems in here still.
Episode mini reviews:
Mr. Ruggerino’s Neighborhood: All sorts of crazy editing.</description></item><item><title>Loki</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/</guid><description>Another MCU made for Disney+ TV outing. After the amazing WandaVision and Falcon and the Winter Soldier, Loki had a high bar to clear. In my nutshell: they nailed it.
I am Loki of Asgard, and I am burdened with glorious purpose.
Loki (the character) is fascinating. He started out a well cast mostly villain of his own in Thor and became the first recurring villain in The Avengers.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/27/the-sopranos-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/27/the-sopranos-season-2/</guid><description>Man this show just keeps going.
They actually lowered the amount of nudity a bit from Season 1 (as HBO tends to do), but the violence is still going strong… It’s fascinating (and solid writing) to see the fall out from the big events of season 1, along with entirely new plotlines with Janice (Tony’s brother), Richard Aprile (who’s got crazy eyes), Christopher really getting into (and out of) writing, and drama with the entire Soprano family/children.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 7</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/07/taskmaster-series-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/07/taskmaster-series-7/</guid><description>Rounding out the first 8 series that are available directly on YouTube in the US, finally Series 7!
Man this was a season. Man those are some characters. James Acaster has a barely contained rage beneath his humor (sometimes now so barely). Jessica Knappett, hilarious with some crazy outfits. Kerry Godliman: a wonderfully direct way to solving tasks. Phil Wang (and Phil Wang&amp;rsquo;s wang). That outfit&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a thing.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/04/the-sopranos-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/04/the-sopranos-season-1/</guid><description>After the crazy violence and nudity of Watchmen, you&amp;rsquo;d think perhaps we&amp;rsquo;d go for something a little more &amp;hellip; safe for next time around.
Nah.
The Sopranos.
It&amp;rsquo;s one of the best rated TV shows of all time (on IMDb, only Breaking Bad (which I watched just before I started reviewing TV series), Avatar: The Last Airbender (it&amp;rsquo;s great), and Game of Thrones (pre Season 8) are rated higher among fiction).</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/29/stargate-atlantis-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/29/stargate-atlantis-season-1/</guid><description>And so it begins again.
While Stargate SG-1 really has a solid place in my heart, in a way I like Atlantis even better. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it could have been what it is without SG-1, but with it, it&amp;rsquo;s made even better.
You have a generally optimistic can do attitude, backed up by McKay quite often saving the day (which is crazy coming off SG-1, I forgot how annoying he is and just how much he grows throughout the seasons of Atlantis).</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-1/</guid><description>Finally back to where it all began. We have a bit of trying to find the show&amp;rsquo;s footing. I think Romesh Ranganathan was my favorite this series.
Favorite task:
Episode 1, Task 2: Eat as much watermelon as possible in one minute. HULK SMASH! Also, totally throwing up. It&amp;rsquo;s probably the weakest season, but it more than gets a pass for all the wonderful things that came to be later.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-6/</guid><description>I really like most of the people in this season. Alice Levine seems straight laced and perhaps sweet until she throws something at you out of left field. Asim Chaudhry hit the &amp;lsquo;you&amp;rsquo;re going to lose now&amp;rsquo;, although didn&amp;rsquo;t actually end up coming in last. Tim Vine though&amp;hellip; oh Tim Vine. There always has to be one in a crazy outfit and he performs most of the tasks in some sort of safari outfit and hat.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/23/taskmaster-series-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/23/taskmaster-series-4/</guid><description>Oh Noel Fielding. You&amp;rsquo;re &amp;hellip; a class all your own. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many other people that had so very many 1 and 5 point tasks with little in between. Having Mel Giedroyc there as well (also from the Great British Bake Off) was extra amusing. Another favorite of mine though was Hugh Dennis. So very British sense of humor.
Favorite tasks:
Episode 1, Task 1: Most unusual autograph on the most unusual vegetable.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/taskmaster-series-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/taskmaster-series-2/</guid><description>Back one more!
Richard Osman is just wonderful in this season. He can really give Greg Davies a run for his money. But I think even better is Katherine Ryan. She&amp;rsquo;s snarky and hilarious. I wish they had more than one woman on the earlier seasons, but if you only have one, she was a good one!
Favorite tasks:
Episode 1, Task 2: Place three exercise balls on a yoga mat on top of a hill.</description></item><item><title>Watchmen</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/watchmen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/watchmen/</guid><description>Oof. On one hand, Watchmen is a very HBO show. Violence all over the place, blood spraying, nudity (both male and female), language.
On another hand, it&amp;rsquo;s Watchmen. At first, it feels like a completely new story set in the same world. There are vague comments relating to the series, but where the graphic novel (I need to reread that) and movie were set decades ago closer to where Watchmen&amp;rsquo;s Alternate Reality splits, this show starts and mostly stays in the world of the 2010s America.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/07/taskmaster-series-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/07/taskmaster-series-3/</guid><description>Further back! Season 3!
I don&amp;rsquo;t have as much to say about the contestants this time around, except for Paul Chowdhry. Such a resting emotionless face&amp;hellip; unless he&amp;rsquo;s full of a deep rage. It makes it hilarious. And he got robbed&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s starting to seem kinda racist. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s just my own viewing order?
A few favorite moments:
Episode 1, Task 3: Propel a pea the furthest distance and land on a red carpet.</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/taskmaster-series-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/taskmaster-series-5/</guid><description>More out of order! This time back to Series 5!
Contestants:
Aisling Bea: Irish names are kind of crazy looking sometimes. And so is Aisling Bea. She has a wonderful sort of manic energy throughout the show. Bob Mortimer: He has some of the most bananas ways of solving tasks. Great fun. Mark Watson: A wonderfully dry sense of humor. You can never quite be sure if he&amp;rsquo;s serious or messing with you.</description></item><item><title>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/</guid><description>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier basically takes place where Avengers: Endgame left off. Steve Rogers as Captain America has stepped down, leaving his shield to Sam Wilson/The Falcon/the (rumored) future Captain America. And on a superficial level, that&amp;rsquo;s about where it ends: Sam Wilson has the shield and is expected to take up the mantle of Captain America.
But, oh the story it tells along the way.
On one hand, you have the dynamic between titular Falcon and Winter Soldier.</description></item><item><title>The Good Place: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/the-good-place-season-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/the-good-place-season-4/</guid><description>The Good Place is an absolute gem of a show. It&amp;rsquo;s hilarious, it&amp;rsquo;s touching, and it even manages to make you think.
I watched the first three seasons a year or more ago, before the 4th season was out (let alone on Netflix), so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit out of order, but from the beginning or jumping in on season 4, it&amp;rsquo;s a show well worth watching.
In a nutshell, the main characters die and end up in the afterlife: The Good Place.</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 10</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/19/stargate-sg-1-season-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/19/stargate-sg-1-season-10/</guid><description>Whoo boy. And so it ends. It&amp;rsquo;s a different sort of excellent from the peak of early SG-1, but the new team is really gelling, the Ori are a decent new threat, and it&amp;rsquo;s quite a ride to go out on. Not all shows end so well. I&amp;rsquo;m happy with this.
Excellent episodes: The Pegasus Project, crossover with Atlantis! 200, the best parody episode ever. The Quest: Part 1/2, a big team up with SG-1, Ba&amp;rsquo;al, and even eventually Adria, off to find a magic doodad&amp;ndash;plus, a dragon!</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 9</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/22/stargate-sg-1-season-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/22/stargate-sg-1-season-9/</guid><description>And now we&amp;rsquo;re really getting into the cast shake ups. Richard Dean Anderson has mostly moved on and the powers that be have finally realized the team needs a new lead: So we get Ben Browder as Lt. Colonel Cameron Mitchell. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have minded Carter keeping the reigns and Browder certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t Anderson, but unlike the whole Jonas mess, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to be. He&amp;rsquo;s still a fairly straight laced military leader, but he&amp;rsquo;s his own kind and I really like it.</description></item><item><title>WandaVision</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/wandavision.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Wanda Maximoff: We are an unusual couple, you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vision: Oh, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that was ever in question.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well. That was most certainly a thing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Queen's Gambit</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/11/the-queens-gambit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/11/the-queens-gambit/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/the-queens-gambit.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>A TV show about chess set in the 1960s? How good could that even be?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out: very very good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 8</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/taskmaster-series-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/taskmaster-series-8/</guid><description>Oh Taskmaster. It&amp;rsquo;s such a wonderfully ridiculous show. Whoever decided that they should upload the episodes to YouTube for everyone* to watch should absolutely be given a shiny golden metallic head.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, go watch it right now. Each series has five different mostly British comedians competing in a number of inane tasks and being judged harshly (if humorously) by Taskmaster Greg Davis while Little Alex Horne (who actually produces the show) keeps everything more or less on track.</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 8</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/01/stargate-sg-1-season-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/01/stargate-sg-1-season-8/</guid><description>Things are getting shaken up yet again. O&amp;rsquo;Neill is the big boss now and isn&amp;rsquo;t going on missions any more, leaving SG-1 down a member. Dr. Weir has a new face (Torri Higginson); who will continue the role in Atlantis is kind of weird, but knowing already how well she did there, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see it any other way. Anubis is gone for the moment and the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld are in disarray.</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 7</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/stargate-sg-1-season-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/stargate-sg-1-season-7/</guid><description>Daniel Jackson is back! (they could have done rather a bit more with re-integrating him I think)
The beginning of the search for Atlantis! (it&amp;rsquo;s amusing, if a bit annoying how long that takes)
Stronger episodes: Lifeboat (Michael Shanks can really act; the plot is weird and weak but the acting is pretty dang impressive), Heroes (Oy. Just Oy. It&amp;rsquo;s a slow burn, but very very good), *Lost City( (woo the beginning of Atlantis!</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/03/stargate-sg-1-season-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/03/stargate-sg-1-season-6/</guid><description>The first big shake up of the main SG-1 cast. For better or for worse (or for out of universe negotiating reasons), Daniel Jackson is no longer part of SG-1 (or, truly, this mortal plane), so instead we have Jonas: who&amp;rsquo;s basically a carbon copy of Daniel Jackson, but without all the history. I think he absolutely did a great job&amp;ndash;and props to Corin Nemec for pulling that off&amp;ndash;but I really wish that they could have done something a little more different since they were already shaking things up.</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/22/stargate-sg-1-season-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/22/stargate-sg-1-season-5/</guid><description>Great episodes: 2001 (echoes of 2010 from last season), Wormhole X-Treme! (the parody episode to end all parody episodes), Summit/Last Stand (Goa&amp;rsquo;uld politics! A new bigger bad?!)
Less great episodes: Threshold (Jaffa weirdness and Teal&amp;rsquo;c defection didn&amp;rsquo;t last nearly long enough), Beast of Burden (we did this already)
Towards the end, we do get one interesting bit of shake up with the death of Daniel Jackson. Of course it's not the first time , but I imagine that for anyone watching this in real time, that was quite the shake up.</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/07/stargate-sg-1-season-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/07/stargate-sg-1-season-4/</guid><description>Another great seasons.
Good episodes: Small Victories (Replicators!), Upgrades (SG-1 on PCP!), Divide and Conquer (oh O&amp;rsquo;Neill and Carter&amp;hellip;), and 2010 (time travel!)
Not as great: Crossroads (Jaffa episodes) and Entity (we&amp;rsquo;ve done this before).
The Best of the Best: Window of Opportunity. Groundhog Day done Stargate style. It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely wonderful and the only episode I&amp;rsquo;ll just randomly watch out of order.
Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly middling seasons. It&amp;rsquo;s still a great show, but (other than Window of Opportunity), a general dearth of amazing.</description></item></channel></rss>