<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2021 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2021-tv-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2021 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 23:59:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2021-tv-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2021 TV &amp; Movies Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-tv-movies-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-tv-movies-retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I do a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-reading-retrospective/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; each year on books, but this year I also started reviewing movies and TV shows! I have &lt;em&gt;absolutely&lt;/em&gt; no idea how much value people get out of this (and I&amp;rsquo;d love to &lt;a href="mailto:blog@jverkamp.com"&gt;hear from you&lt;/a&gt;), but I enjoy doing it, so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to stop any time soon. :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s been a good year for movies and TV!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I watched:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;55 movies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25 from the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-cinematic-universe/"&gt;Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 Disney Animated Classics + 1 Home Release sequel (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/04/bambi-2-the-great-prince-of-the-forest/"&gt;Bambi 2: The Great Prince of the Forest&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;35 on Disney+ (mostly the MCU + kid&amp;rsquo;s movies above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 on HBOMax (new releases!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 in theaters (oh Covid and having a baby&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 TV shows (46 total seasons)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Wheel of Time: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/23/the-wheel-of-time-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wheel of Time turns, and ages come and pass, leaving memories that become legend. Legend fades to myth, and even myth is long forgotten when the Age that gave it birth comes again. In one Age, called the Third Age by some, an Age yet to come, an Age long past, a wind rose in the Mountains of Mist. The wind was not the beginning. There are neither beginnings nor endings to the turning of the Wheel of time. But it was a beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hawkeye</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/22/hawkeye/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/22/hawkeye/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed Hawkeye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt;, which compared to &lt;em&gt;Wandvision&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Loki&lt;/em&gt; and really even &lt;em&gt;What If&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; is a worthwhile goal and really does a lot to show off the more human scale of superheroes. It&amp;rsquo;s never really made much sense that Hawkeye and Black Widow were Avengers&amp;hellip; and it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But they do it anyways. Because what Heroes do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see them building up the new &amp;lsquo;Young Avengers&amp;rsquo; and branching out as much as they are. I think Hailee Steinfeld did a great job, especially when acting against &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;Florence Pugh's Yelena&lt;/span&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mr. Robot: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/20/mr.-robot-season-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/20/mr.-robot-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh boy. This one really dug into the darker parts of character growth. Elliot finds new ways to be even crazier, Angela is&amp;hellip; off the rails entirely, Moustache Guy (Bobby Cannavale/Irvin) is awesome, and the entire plot of Darlene, Dominque, and the FBI was fascinating to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep being pleasantly surprised with where this show keeps going. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have expected them to make it past the first season plotwise&amp;hellip; yet here we are. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to where we can go from here!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mr. Robot: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/mr.-robot-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/mr.-robot-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After Season 1 wrapped up, where do you even go from there? They finished their big goal. Dealing with the fallout is the obvious answer&amp;hellip; or ramping things up even further. We get a bit of both in Season 2, mostly with even more big twists from Elliot&amp;rsquo;s entirely confusing mind but also a plot that is both deeper and more terrifying than I would have thought at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not quite as solid as Season 1, in most part because it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as new and fresh. But it&amp;rsquo;s still very good and well worth the watch. Whatever shall we learn in Season 3?!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mr. Robot: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/mr.-robot-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/mr.-robot-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s a heck of a show. Given that I&amp;rsquo;m do computer security for a living (albeit with a bit less of the black hat revolutionary mindset) and have my own problems figuring out how brains&amp;ndash;mine and others&amp;ndash;work (albeit not nearly to that extent&amp;hellip;) I feel like the perfect audience for this show. I&amp;rsquo;m honestly impressed with how well they got the hacking in this show. It&amp;rsquo;s not 100%&amp;ndash;that would be boring&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s miles closer than two-hackers-typing-on-a-keyboard-is-faster. On top of that, I knew going in there would be twists and turns, but this&amp;hellip; I didn&amp;rsquo;t not expect all of this.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Squid Game</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/squid-game/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/squid-game/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t actually do much social media (other than a relatively limited set of subreddits), so I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually notice what was apparently a fairly large storm of people watching Squid Game, but when it came up on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Akm4BdBIMXQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Honest Trailers&lt;/a&gt; it seemed pretty interesting. 9 episodes and I just finished &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/stargate-universe/"&gt;Stargate Universe&lt;/a&gt;, so I figured, let&amp;rsquo;s give it a spin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s at once exactly what I expected, but even then had a few interesting twists and turns. It&amp;rsquo;s a battle royale of sorts, centered around (mostly Korean) kids&amp;rsquo; games, where the winners in the running for tens of millions of dollars and the losers&amp;ndash;well, let&amp;rsquo;s just say they aren&amp;rsquo;t. There&amp;rsquo;s a whole pile (heh) of interesting characters, blood and gore a plenty, a bit of nudity (although that&amp;rsquo;s not really the focus), and a fair bit of digging into just how dark people can get when money is on the line. I want to believe that such a thing couldn&amp;rsquo;t happen ever happen in the real world&amp;hellip; but sometimes I wonder.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos-season-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s a lot. In order to finish all of the stories they wanted to tell&amp;ndash;but also not to have to negotiate another season&amp;rsquo;s worth of contracts with the actors, season 6 is really two seasons in one. The first is slightly shorter than the other seasons at 12 (instead of 13), while the second half is only 9. So one big season? Two small? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that much when you&amp;rsquo;re streaming them back to back.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate Universe: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/stargate-universe-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/stargate-universe-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Each time I rewatch Stargate (and with 17 seasons and a handful of movies, that&amp;rsquo;s something of a time commitment), I forgot just how much better Stargate Universe season 2 is than season 1. And I &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; liked Season 1. But 2 is where things really get on their own. The crew trapped on Destiny is really learning how to use the ship and making it their own, finding new (huge) mysteries, and actually getting a few big bads on a scale with the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld/Ori/Wraith. And with how things end up&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s such a bummer it has to end. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to check out the follow up graphic novel this time around, official canon or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What If...?</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;What if…?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a wacky title, but it sums up the series pretty well. Take what the MCU has spent a decade building on top of half a century of comics before that&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The comics have done all manner of continuity resets and what-ifs, so it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual to see the stories as they could have been&amp;ndash;if only one thing changed. But this is a first for the MCU. I fully expect with the coming Phase 4, we&amp;rsquo;ll see a bit more of this though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate Universe: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/30/stargate-universe-season-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/30/stargate-universe-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Onward to another universe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stargate SG-1 started it all, focusing mostly on adventure and exploring a brand new universe. Stargate Atlantis took that feeling and went hard into the sci-fi nature of the show, giving us an entirely different galaxy and people, dealing with (in some ways) much larger and more complicated threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stargate Universe&amp;hellip; in some ways takes us even father, across tens or hundreds of galaxies to an Ancient (both in manufactory and age) ship&amp;ndash;the Destiny. And there&amp;rsquo;s a fair bit of the sci-fi thriller feel of trying to survive in difficult times, learning about the ship and galaxy you&amp;rsquo;ve found yourself in. But really, at it&amp;rsquo;s heart, Stargate Universe is about people. And man are they some messed up and drama-filled people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/23/stargate-atlantis-season-5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/23/stargate-atlantis-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so it ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do sorely wish that Atlantis could have gotten another season. There are some &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; strong episodes in this seaon. As much as I liked Weir and Carter, Woolsey is another huge case of character improvement (almost as much as McKay).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini-reviews (potential spoilers):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Search and Rescue&lt;/em&gt;: Half a closed room, buried deep in a collapsed building, half Teyla. Neither quite what I was hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/18/the-sopranos-season-5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/18/the-sopranos-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a season. It&amp;rsquo;s great to see how Christopher has been growing over the series&amp;ndash;man that penultimate episode though. The introduction and arc of Tony B (Buscemi is wonderful) is quite a thing. It just keeps picking up. Crazy to think there&amp;rsquo;s only one more season, even if almost double length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini-reviews per episode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two Tonys&lt;/em&gt;: The old guard’s the new guard, Christopher and Paulie are (still) butting heads and perhaps they don’t have to whack Carmine after all. Unexpected turn with Dr. Melfi too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rat Pack&lt;/em&gt;: Hustling air bags… yup. they’re expensive. Wait, this one isn’t called two Tonys? He’s very Buscemi. He just makes everything slightly more… odd. Also wait what… Janice &lt;em&gt;married&lt;/em&gt; Bobby? When? Why?!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where’s Johnny?&lt;/em&gt;: Old faces make for rather a mess in the leadership. Oh and Uncle Junior is having some issues. Oy an episode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;All Happy Families…&lt;/em&gt; Ooh boy the Sopranos are a mess. And Feech is a mess. AJ is a mess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Irregular Around the Margins&lt;/em&gt;: Kind of surreal listening to them talk about war in the Middle East… 20 years later. And then… Ade and Tony. I just. Oy. I guess I didn’t expect sobriety to Kay forever, but… Oy. Buscemi is wonderful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sentimental Education&lt;/em&gt;: A very strange episode. I… kept expecting things to go sidewise. I guess in the end…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Camelot&lt;/em&gt;: Things worse than drugs, Tony’s father’s old flame (of course not everything was rosy) and Uncle Junior’s a funeral junky. Quite an episode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marco Polo&lt;/em&gt;: Mostly a surprise party foot Carmela’s father, but also a bit of redemption perhaps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unidentified Black Males&lt;/em&gt;: Finn’s in over his head… And Carmela learns the hard way about breaking up with a mob boss. Oy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cold Cuts&lt;/em&gt;: Oh Janice. Could have done without … any of her plotlines really. I guess she did try. And Tony’s reaction is worth it. But… why don’t they just dump the bodies i. thw water to begin with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Test Dream&lt;/em&gt;: Well… that went quickly weird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Long Term Parking&lt;/em&gt;: And that was intense. That’s what a penultimate episode should be. Oy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;All Due Respect&lt;/em&gt;: Well. That’s an ending. It’s all about family, but sometimes family has conflicts. No idea where they are going with AJ.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/10/stargate-atlantis-season-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/10/stargate-atlantis-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy season in how it begins (lost in space!) and ends (lost in time!). More replicators, more wraith, more variations thereof. A handful of smaller episodes with only small combinations of main cast really shine. We lose a few of the big leads and gain a few more old names. It&amp;rsquo;s also always interesting how shows deal with the pregnancy of a main cast member.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onwards and Season 5-wards! To the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/stargate-atlantis-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/stargate-atlantis-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like in this series. We get new, complicate Wraith threats (Michael and Todd!), Replicators, lost Ancients, and some of the best McKay episodes in the show (McKay and Mrs. Miller and Tao of Rodney). Not to mention Lucius Lavin. No really. :) And then there&amp;rsquo;s Sunday&amp;hellip; Man it sucks to kill off major characters just to raise the stakes, but it still works as an episode.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-sopranos-season-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-sopranos-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Man that was another season. Ralphie is a great character to love to hate, Christopher is really having some drug issues, and things really come to a head between Tony and Carmela. A great season and I look forward to the next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini-reviews per episode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Debts, Public and Private: &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;Ralphie and Janice now… come on &lt;/span&gt;
.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No-Show: Meadow is moody, Christopher is moving up—that’s going to be trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christopher: Columbus versus Native Americans. That’s a complicated issue… not about to be resolved in an episode. Add on another random death &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;poor Bacala :/&lt;/span&gt;
. And Ralphie continues to be an ass. But that’s not new. Weird one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Weight: The power of a mobster when a slight is felt. Eventually that will (I hope) catch up with Ralphie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pie-o-My: Adriana, trying to do the right thing in a tricky situation. Carmela, trying to do the right thing in a tricky situation. And… horses. Apparently. Odd sometimes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everybody Hurts: Oh Christopher. Oh Artie. Oh AJ. Man everything is about to blow one way or another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching Too Much Television: Well Christopher is an ass… The politics of real estate is fascinating. Also Furio feels the same… it doesn’t?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mergers and Acquisitions: Ah. Cancer. And Tony and Ralphie are so going to have to end things one way or another… And Furio. So many things… Looking forward to some endings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whoever Did This: Finally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Strong, Silent Type: Well, that’s a thing. Drugs are one hell of a drug.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calling All Cars: What is Janice doing… What is AJ doing… man this is screwy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eloise: Speaking of what are they doing… Furio and Carmela. Oy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whitecaps: And that’s the straw that broke the camels back. On to next season… At least the HUD/Carmine, Uncle Junior, and Christopher on drugs plots are resolved. More or less.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 12</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-12/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-12/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s quite a cast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alan Davies: The old one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desiree Burch: She certainly goes all out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guz Khan: Those eyes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morgana Robinson: So very emotive… The word that comes to mind is ‘fae’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Victoria Coren Mitchell: Subtle and hilarious when you realize it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Series reviews:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An inbalance in the poppability&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well that started delightfully risqué, escalates to swearing at Alex, and ended up with a prize task submission… of Personally the chair he’s sitting on. And the tasks haven’t even started yet. I expect to enjoy this series.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 9</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/12/taskmaster-series-9/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A great season! I loved all of the people on here. I was writing up my favorite and &amp;hellip; I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it. They&amp;rsquo;re all a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;First entry in the first task: How large are Greg Davies’ shits… We’re off to quite a season. Hiding eggplants is a wonderful task. “It’s amazing how much it compacts down into a baby’s head.” “You scored the same as Rose… and she couldn’t see.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*It&amp;rsquo;s always fascinating when something that seems so obvious in hindsight takes absolutely forever to figure out. Scavenger hunts on steroids. Jo has tremendous DGAF energy and Rose makes hilarious faces. *&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jo suggesting Mein Kampf is an important read for democracy&amp;hellip; The look on Greg Davies face! I also love when they combine tasks, such as building a solid statue&amp;hellip; and then scoring a soccer goal against it&amp;hellip; with a steamroller. Wonderful. &amp;ldquo;Now I&amp;rsquo;ve destroyed the statue. I haven&amp;rsquo;t even scored. For the second time. In 40 years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*The water feature task is one of my favorites. Oh&amp;hellip; Alex. You really make this show. I&amp;rsquo;m never going to get those out of my head. Katy&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;subtle&amp;rsquo; flirting (bra begins with B) is a lot of fun. The final task (throw your thing far but not too far) was fun. *&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aw, poor Katy Wix. Kerry Godliman is wonderful though. &amp;ldquo;And this is Monkey now&amp;hellip; &amp;hellip; KEEP IT LIGHT!&amp;rdquo; Also: &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s his name? (Alex, not missing a beat): David Baddiel.&amp;rdquo; And that&amp;rsquo;s just the prize task.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*Katherine Ryan! Missed her. Live task, sliding full glasses bar style at Greg Davies was wonderful. *&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Katy Wix is back! And she stole Kerry Godliman&amp;rsquo;s Taskmaster prize :D. And then, &amp;lsquo;Make Mount Rushmore&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip; and they all talk about Trump. We are/were a joke&amp;hellip; And it ends with a rousing game of horse or laminator (that old gem) with POSSIBLY INFINITE POINTS!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Making sound effects was lovely, especially with a live screamoff in the studio!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;So many balloons!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*&amp;ldquo;To hold aloft my smelted golden likeness and scream into the void. I AM BECOME LIGHT. I AM BECOME IMMORTAL. THE WORLD SHALL NOT FORGET MY NAME.&amp;rdquo; Oh Greg Davies. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing them all dressed up in matching suits and bowties. Did any of the other seasons do that? Why are they so orange? So many questions. Last task?! :( Last seven tasks? EXCELLENT. Quite the final task&amp;hellip; The tie breaker was delightful. *&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/09/stargate-atlantis-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/09/stargate-atlantis-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a beginning and ending, with a whole lot in between. One of the biggest changes is the introduction of Ronan Dex. Replacement for Lt. Ford who has a tendency to shoot first and ask questions&amp;ndash;well, never. He&amp;rsquo;s quite the character and a good addition to the team. Interesting that the main team is half from Pegasus now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini-reviews (potential spoilers):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Siege, Part 3: Man this is a fun three parter. I don’t care as much for the repeated theme of military taking over, but it is still a great episode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intruder: Computer virus running the show. we’ve done this before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runner: Ford’s passing of the torch to Ronon Dex. Ford never quite works and I really end up liking Dex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duet: Two minds stuck in McKay’s body. A story we’ve seen before, but I really like in particular how it humanizes him.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Condemned: Penal colony/execution and overzealous laws. Again, we’ve done it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trinity: McKay discovers a super weapon research station and he believes he can fix it better than the Ancients. The hubris of McKay is a great contrast to Duet and I b really enjoy the relationship between Sheppard and McKay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instinct: The first hints that it may be possible to &amp;lsquo;cure&amp;rsquo; the Wraith. Also Jewel Staite, which is amusing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conversion: Fallout from Instinct leads to a return of Iratus bugs (Sheppard is thrilled).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aurora: Ancients! Virtual reality! a fascinating episode and a poignant ending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lost Boys: Highs to lows. Ford is back and still… questionable at best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hive: Teyla is Wraith-psychic. Sheppard falls for any pretty face. Cool action scenes though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epiphany: Time dilation! The way to fit a lifetime in an episode. A lot like Brief Candle from SG-1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Critical Mass: Crossover, chock full of mostly minor characters from SG-1! It&amp;rsquo;s interesting watching them out of order, since the Ori aren&amp;rsquo;t about yet. The Twilight Bark analogy falling flat to a room full of SGC is hilarious. Cadman back is great. Wish she has a bigger roll over all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grace Under Pressure: McKay stuck in a jumper deep in the ocean, hallucinating. One of the best McKay episodes in the show.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tower: Of course the Ancients had more cities. And of course Sheppard&amp;rsquo;s, &amp;ldquo;I never see this coming&amp;rdquo;. An interesting exploration of what the ancients left behind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael: I remember watching this the first time and feeling something was vaguely wrong from the beginning. Knowing just what that is just means that I can be on the look out for it the whole way through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inferno: The Ancients were really good at finding creative ways to harness huge amounts of power. It&amp;rsquo;s amusing how often they tend to explode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allies: The enemy of my enemy&amp;hellip; Should damn will still be my enemy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On to Season 3! Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m glad to be watching these now and not having to wait a year or more for the &amp;lsquo;To Be Continued&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/28/the-sopranos-season-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/28/the-sopranos-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an odd season. The original plotline had to be thrown out on account of &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;the actress that played Tony's mom dying&lt;/span&gt;
, so the whole &amp;lsquo;do they have a case against Tony&amp;rsquo; thing falls through. As a result, it&amp;rsquo;s not the most cohesive of seasons, but there are a few gems in here still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Episode mini reviews:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mr. Ruggerino’s Neighborhood: All sorts of crazy editing. Bizarre start to the new season. Amusing watching the FBI try to bug Tony and Tony being … surprisingly competent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proshai Livushka: &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;Tony’s mom dies. What are you going to do? Especially when it’s the actress that died.&lt;/span&gt;
. It would have been fascinating to see the original plot, but they certainly made it work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fortunate Son: All about sons. Christopher, AJ, Jackie Jr. So many things ramping up. Should be an interesting season. Also Janice is set up to be hated. Weird set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employee of the Month: Dr. Melfi and her relationship with Tony is one of the best parts of this show. It’s a hard episode to watch, but oy. Quite the episode. Also I didn’t notice before but that’s Cypher from the Matrix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another Toothpick: Dr. Melfi, Tony, … and Carmela? Oy. Also awkward Artie and family troubles. Not quite as intense as the last episode, but that’s a good thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;University: Oh Meadow. It’s not a mob plotline, but it’s a fascinating counterpoint. And Ralphie, like Aprile but crazier… And the whole ‘stripper with a heart of gold’ only to be shut down hard. Oh that’s an episode. The number of cuts is pretty bizarre.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second Opinion: “F*** the orange juice”. Oh the Sopranos have a weird relationship. As do Christopher and Ade. Also also cancer. And bullying Doctors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He Is Risen: Man Ralphie is hateable. The look into mafia rules and politics is pretty fascinating though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Telltale Moozadell: Christopher and Adriana moving up in the world. Jackie Jr is … getting in over his head. Also random AJ plotline at school. Also also I fully expect Gloria to be trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To Save Us All from Satan’s Power: Flashbacks to Pussy, apparently the mob’s Santa? Weird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pine Barrens: Russians and a frozen night in the woods. How bad could it be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amour Fou: Crazy love. Certainly crazy something. Things are so going to explode next episode. Also interesting the conversation about the Clintons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Army of One: And so ends one problematic plotlines in true Sopranos fashion. Others only amping up. Seems a bit anticlimactic for a season finale. OTOH, Tobin Bell is a treasure (seen him otherwise in Stargate)—maybe AJ’s plot will go somewhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Long Goodbye: Body snatchers again! Of course things go sideways. It&amp;rsquo;s quite an experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coup D&amp;rsquo;etat: I never much cared for the human factions in SG-1, but I actually like the Genii as an adversary. I think it&amp;rsquo;s the fact that they&amp;rsquo;re a more alien sort of human.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;span class="spoiler"&gt; No, okay I’m annoyed. We didn’t get anything. Ralphie is still an ass, no one is questioning Jackie’s death, AJ is in limbo, and the while thing ended with… a bizarrely long singing section? &lt;/span&gt;</description></item><item><title>Loki</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Another MCU made for Disney+ TV outing. After the amazing &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/"&gt;WandaVision&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/"&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/a&gt;, Loki had a high bar to clear. In my nutshell: they nailed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am Loki of Asgard, and I am burdened with glorious purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loki (the character) is fascinating. He started out a well cast mostly villain of his own in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/"&gt;Thor&lt;/a&gt; and became the first recurring villain in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/"&gt;The Avengers&lt;/a&gt;. And after that, he&amp;rsquo;s back again and again in each of the Thor and Avengers movies. In a universe where every other villain (even Thanos) is basically a one and done, it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating way to do it. On top of that, he&amp;rsquo;s interesting. Over the years, he&amp;rsquo;s grown to be rather likeable (if you ignore the fact that he&amp;rsquo;s killed how many people?) and even a hero. So of course when you set him up as the protagonist of his own show&amp;hellip; expect great things.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/27/the-sopranos-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/27/the-sopranos-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Man this show just keeps going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They actually lowered the amount of nudity a bit from Season 1 (as HBO tends to do), but the violence is still going strong… It’s fascinating (and solid writing) to see the fall out from the big events of season 1, along with entirely new plotlines with Janice (Tony’s brother), Richard Aprile (who’s got crazy eyes), Christopher really getting into (and out of) writing, and drama with the entire Soprano family/children. It’s quite a ride and just keeps getting better.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 7</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/07/taskmaster-series-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/07/taskmaster-series-7/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rounding out the first 8 series that are available directly on YouTube in the US, finally Series 7!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man this was a season. Man those are some characters. James Acaster has a barely contained rage beneath his humor (sometimes now so barely). Jessica Knappett, hilarious with some crazy outfits. Kerry Godliman: a wonderfully direct way to solving tasks. Phil Wang (and Phil Wang&amp;rsquo;s wang). That outfit&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a thing. And Rhod Gilbert. Perhaps the best at lateral thinking with decades of a relationship of history with Greg Davies, and an obsession with a picture of Davies in a speedo. Oh they&amp;rsquo;re all great.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/04/the-sopranos-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/04/the-sopranos-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After the crazy violence and nudity of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/watchmen/"&gt;Watchmen&lt;/a&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;d think perhaps we&amp;rsquo;d go for something a little more &amp;hellip; safe for next time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sopranos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s one of the best rated TV shows of all time (on IMDb, only Breaking Bad (which I watched just before I started reviewing TV series), Avatar: The Last Airbender (it&amp;rsquo;s great), and Game of Thrones (pre Season 8) are rated higher among fiction). It&amp;rsquo;s a mob story set in late 90s New Jersey produced for HBO and has all the sex, violence, and language you&amp;rsquo;d expect from that combination. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; quite a show. Dealing with family, the moral complexity (at best) of mob life, and mental health issues&amp;hellip; and that&amp;rsquo;s just season 1. Oh it&amp;rsquo;s a show.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate Atlantis: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/29/stargate-atlantis-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/29/stargate-atlantis-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so it begins again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Stargate SG-1 really has a solid place in my heart, in a way I like Atlantis even better. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it could have been what it is without SG-1, but with it, it&amp;rsquo;s made even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a generally optimistic can do attitude, backed up by McKay quite often saving the day (which is crazy coming off SG-1, I forgot how annoying he is and just &lt;em&gt;how much&lt;/em&gt; he grows throughout the seasons of Atlantis). On top of that, the second weird (Torri Higginson) is back as the woman in charge and plays that well. I think perhaps my favorite character though (if not McKay, I know right?) is Joe Flanigan as Lt. Colonel John Sheppard. He&amp;rsquo;s a military leader that cares more for his people than for the rules (seen that before), but he&amp;rsquo;s smart (although he keeps it low key) and snarky rather than cynical as Jack could be. It&amp;rsquo;s a good mix. Teyla&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ve never quite cared for, but she&amp;rsquo;s portrayed well enough.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally back to where it all began. We have a bit of trying to find the show&amp;rsquo;s footing. I think Romesh Ranganathan was my favorite this series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favorite task:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 2: Eat as much watermelon as possible in one minute. HULK SMASH! Also, totally throwing up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably the weakest season, but it more than gets a pass for all the wonderful things that came to be later.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/26/taskmaster-series-6/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I really like most of the people in this season. Alice Levine seems straight laced and perhaps sweet until she throws something at you out of left field. Asim Chaudhry hit the &amp;lsquo;you&amp;rsquo;re going to lose now&amp;rsquo;, although didn&amp;rsquo;t actually end up coming in last. Tim Vine though&amp;hellip; oh Tim Vine. There always has to be one in a crazy outfit and he performs most of the tasks in some sort of safari outfit and hat. Fun times.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/23/taskmaster-series-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/23/taskmaster-series-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh Noel Fielding. You&amp;rsquo;re &amp;hellip; a class all your own. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many other people that had so very many 1 and 5 point tasks with little in between. Having Mel Giedroyc there as well (also from the Great British Bake Off) was extra amusing. Another favorite of mine though was Hugh Dennis. So very British sense of humor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favorite tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 1: Most unusual autograph on the most unusual vegetable. Any time they try to get Greg Davies to participate in tasks is the best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 2: Beautifully destory a cake. I&amp;rsquo;m surprised at how &lt;em&gt;few&lt;/em&gt; fireworks there were.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 3: Draw a caricature of a person you can&amp;rsquo;t see. Medusa eat your heart out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 4: Knock all the rubber ducks down. Planning!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 3, Task 2: Camouflage and hide yourself. Some silly, some impressive. And then Noel just &amp;hellip; being Noel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 3, Task 5: Transfer water using only supplied items. Hidden bonus points! Moving water!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh Noel. Kind of warps the show around himself. He&amp;rsquo;s hilarious though, so it works!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/taskmaster-series-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/taskmaster-series-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Back one more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Osman is just wonderful in this season. He can really give Greg Davies a run for his money. But I think even better is Katherine Ryan. She&amp;rsquo;s snarky and hilarious. I wish they had more than one woman on the earlier seasons, but if you only have one, she was a good one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favorite tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 2: Place three exercise balls on a yoga mat on top of a hill. Watching the chaos as they blow away and amusing cheating are the best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 4: Get information from a Swede without communicating in English. Call a friend!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 2, Task 2: Eat an egg the fastest. And only one ate it raw.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 4, Task 4: Build a bridge for a potato with the supplied items. I love when they hide something that would make the task easier. Much better when they don&amp;rsquo;t find it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another short season, but a good one.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Watchmen</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/watchmen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/watchmen/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oof. On one hand, Watchmen is a very HBO show. Violence all over the place, blood spraying, nudity (both male and female), language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On another hand, it&amp;rsquo;s Watchmen. At first, it feels like a completely new story set in the same world. There are vague comments relating to the series, but where the graphic novel (I need to reread that) and movie were set decades ago closer to where Watchmen&amp;rsquo;s Alternate Reality splits, this show starts and mostly stays in the world of the 2010s America. Things circle back towards the end (in a rather satisfying way, at least in my opinion), but it&amp;rsquo;s still very much it&amp;rsquo;s own story.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/07/taskmaster-series-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/07/taskmaster-series-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Further back! Season 3!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have as much to say about the contestants this time around, except for Paul Chowdhry. Such a resting emotionless face&amp;hellip; unless he&amp;rsquo;s full of a deep rage. It makes it hilarious. And he got robbed&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s starting to seem kinda racist. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s just my own viewing order?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few favorite moments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 3: Propel a pea the furthest distance and land on a red carpet. I love tasks where the&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 1, Task 4: Make the best snowman. In the summer. It&amp;rsquo;s hilarious and surprisingly existential at times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 2, Task 2: Surprise Alex. FIREWORKS are surprising!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 3, Task 2: Fill an egg cup with sweat. Well, that&amp;rsquo;s gross.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 4, Task 2: Spread your clothes as far and wide as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to bend the rules (and spend money).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 5, Task 2: Transfer water between buckets without moving either. Cheating!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pity it&amp;rsquo;s only 5 episodes, but they&amp;rsquo;re still good ones.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/taskmaster-series-5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/taskmaster-series-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;More out of order! This time back to Series 5!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contestants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aisling Bea: Irish names are kind of crazy looking sometimes. And so is Aisling Bea. She has a wonderful sort of manic energy throughout the show.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bob Mortimer: He has some of the most bananas ways of solving tasks. Great fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mark Watson: A wonderfully dry sense of humor. You can never quite be sure if he&amp;rsquo;s serious or messing with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nish Kumar: Poor Nish. He totally got robbed. I&amp;rsquo;m noticing a theme here&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sally Phillips: You never expect half the things she does. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason she did as well as she did.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few favorite moments:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Falcon and the Winter Soldier basically takes place where Avengers: Endgame left off. Steve Rogers as Captain America has stepped down, leaving his shield to Sam Wilson/The Falcon/the (rumored) future Captain America. And on a superficial level, that&amp;rsquo;s about where it ends: Sam Wilson has the shield and is expected to take up the mantle of Captain America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, oh the story it tells along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, you have the dynamic between titular Falcon and Winter Soldier. Brought together by their respective friendships with Captain America, it&amp;rsquo;s quite often hilarious listening to them bicker. They really do respect and care about one another, and that makes the bickering all the better.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Good Place: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/the-good-place-season-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/the-good-place-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Good Place is an absolute gem of a show. It&amp;rsquo;s hilarious, it&amp;rsquo;s touching, and it even manages to make you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched the first three seasons a year or more ago, before the 4th season was out (let alone on Netflix), so it&amp;rsquo;s a bit out of order, but from the beginning or jumping in on season 4, it&amp;rsquo;s a show well worth watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, the main characters die and end up in the afterlife: The Good Place. Except&amp;ndash;things aren&amp;rsquo;t quite like they seem. One thing leads to another, our unlikely heroes have to save the afterlife; again and again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 10</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/19/stargate-sg-1-season-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/19/stargate-sg-1-season-10/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Whoo boy. And so it ends. It&amp;rsquo;s a different sort of excellent from the peak of early SG-1, but the new team is really gelling, the Ori are a decent new threat, and it&amp;rsquo;s quite a ride to go out on. Not all shows end so well. I&amp;rsquo;m happy with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excellent episodes: &lt;b&gt;The Pegasus Project&lt;/b&gt;, crossover with Atlantis! &lt;b&gt;200&lt;/b&gt;, the best parody episode ever. &lt;b&gt;The Quest: Part 1/2&lt;/b&gt;, a big team up with SG-1, Ba&amp;rsquo;al, and even eventually Adria, off to find a magic doodad&amp;ndash;plus, a dragon! &lt;b&gt;The Road Not Taken&lt;/b&gt;, more parallel world shenanigans! &lt;b&gt;The Shroud&lt;/b&gt;, Daniel as a prior!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 9</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/22/stargate-sg-1-season-9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/22/stargate-sg-1-season-9/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And now we&amp;rsquo;re really getting into the cast shake ups. Richard Dean Anderson has mostly moved on and the powers that be have finally realized the team needs a new lead: So we get Ben Browder as Lt. Colonel Cameron Mitchell. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have minded Carter keeping the reigns and Browder certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t Anderson, but unlike the whole Jonas mess, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t try to be. He&amp;rsquo;s still a fairly straight laced military leader, but he&amp;rsquo;s his own kind and I really like it. It works out pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>WandaVision</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wanda Maximoff: We are an unusual couple, you know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vision: Oh, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that was ever in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well. That was most certainly a thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Queen's Gambit</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/11/the-queens-gambit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/11/the-queens-gambit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A TV show about chess set in the 1960s? How good could that even be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out: very very good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taskmaster: Series 8</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/taskmaster-series-8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/taskmaster-series-8/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh Taskmaster. It&amp;rsquo;s such a wonderfully ridiculous show. Whoever decided that they should upload the episodes to YouTube for everyone* to watch should absolutely be given a shiny golden metallic head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCT5C7yaO3RVuOgwP8JVAujQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;go watch it right now&lt;/a&gt;. Each series has five different mostly British comedians competing in a number of inane tasks and being judged harshly (if humorously) by Taskmaster Greg Davis while Little Alex Horne (who actually produces the show) keeps everything more or less on track.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 8</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/01/stargate-sg-1-season-8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/01/stargate-sg-1-season-8/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Things are getting shaken up yet again. O&amp;rsquo;Neill is the big boss now and isn&amp;rsquo;t going on missions any more, leaving SG-1 down a member. Dr. Weir has a new face (Torri Higginson); who will continue the role in Atlantis is kind of weird, but knowing already how well she did there, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see it any other way. Anubis is gone for the moment and the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld are in disarray. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a weird season overall, but things really pick up in the second half with a number of old threats all gaining ground at the same time in one big what could have been series finale.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 7</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/stargate-sg-1-season-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/stargate-sg-1-season-7/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Daniel Jackson is back! (they could have done rather a bit more with re-integrating him I think)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beginning of the search for Atlantis! (it&amp;rsquo;s amusing, if a bit annoying how long that takes)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stronger episodes: &lt;em&gt;Lifeboat&lt;/em&gt; (Michael Shanks can really act; the plot is weird and weak but the acting is pretty dang impressive), &lt;em&gt;Heroes&lt;/em&gt; (Oy. Just Oy. It&amp;rsquo;s a slow burn, but very very good), *Lost City( (woo the beginning of Atlantis! on man that battle scene!)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/03/stargate-sg-1-season-6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/03/stargate-sg-1-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The first big shake up of the main SG-1 cast. For better or for worse (or for out of universe negotiating reasons), Daniel Jackson is no longer part of SG-1 (or, truly, this mortal plane), so instead we have Jonas: who&amp;rsquo;s basically a carbon copy of Daniel Jackson, but without all the history. I think he absolutely did a great job&amp;ndash;and props to Corin Nemec for pulling that off&amp;ndash;but I really wish that they could have done something a little more different since they were already shaking things up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/22/stargate-sg-1-season-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/22/stargate-sg-1-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Great episodes: &lt;em&gt;2001&lt;/em&gt; (echoes of &lt;em&gt;2010&lt;/em&gt; from last season), &lt;em&gt;Wormhole X-Treme!&lt;/em&gt; (the parody episode to end all parody episodes), &lt;em&gt;Summit&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;em&gt;Last Stand&lt;/em&gt; (Goa&amp;rsquo;uld politics! A new bigger bad?!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less great episodes: &lt;em&gt;Threshold&lt;/em&gt; (Jaffa weirdness and Teal&amp;rsquo;c defection didn&amp;rsquo;t last nearly long enough), &lt;em&gt;Beast of Burden&lt;/em&gt; (we did this already)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end, we do get one interesting bit of shake up with the &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;death of Daniel Jackson. Of course it's not the first time&lt;/span&gt;
, but I imagine that for anyone watching this in real time, that was quite the shake up.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stargate SG-1: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/07/stargate-sg-1-season-4/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/07/stargate-sg-1-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Another great seasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good episodes: &lt;em&gt;Small Victories&lt;/em&gt; (Replicators!), &lt;em&gt;Upgrades&lt;/em&gt; (SG-1 on PCP!), &lt;em&gt;Divide and Conquer&lt;/em&gt; (oh O&amp;rsquo;Neill and Carter&amp;hellip;), and &lt;em&gt;2010&lt;/em&gt; (time travel!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not as great: &lt;em&gt;Crossroads&lt;/em&gt; (Jaffa episodes) and &lt;em&gt;Entity&lt;/em&gt; (we&amp;rsquo;ve done this before).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Best of the Best: &lt;em&gt;Window of Opportunity&lt;/em&gt;. Groundhog Day done Stargate style. It&amp;rsquo;s absolutely wonderful and the only episode I&amp;rsquo;ll just randomly watch out of order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly middling seasons. It&amp;rsquo;s still a great show, but (other than &lt;em&gt;Window of Opportunity&lt;/em&gt;), a general dearth of amazing. So it goes. Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>