<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2025 Movie Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2025-movie-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2025 Movie Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2025-movie-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aliens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/19/aliens/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/19/aliens/</guid><description>&lt;p>Where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/alien/">Alien&lt;/a> was a genre defining entry into scifi/horror, Aliens takes that a step in a different direction, keeping the horrifying alien monster roots and adding in a pile of action scenes. Space marines, big guns, and flamethrowers&amp;ndash;oh my.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, taking the (more or less) single alien of Alien and upping the ante to a whole pile of them&amp;ndash;and then blowing at least some of them away&amp;ndash;lessons the mystique. They&amp;rsquo;re not unkillable perfect monsters any more. But it&amp;rsquo;s still a good way to up the ante rather than just putting us through more of the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sigourney Weaver remains a star of the episode, this time mixing her tough surviverness with a &amp;lsquo;save the child&amp;rsquo; complex that I think just works. But this time around, we have a whole pile of soldiers, playing up every stereotype you can think of.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Vasquez: Look, man. I only need to know one thing: where they are.&lt;br>
Drake: Go, Vasquez. Kick ass.&lt;br>
Vasquez: Anytime, anywhere, man!&lt;br>
Hudson: Right, right. Somebody said &amp;ldquo;alien&amp;rdquo; she thought they said &amp;ldquo;illegal alien&amp;rdquo; and signed up!&lt;br>
Vasquez: Fuck you, man!&lt;br>
Hudson: Anytime, anywhere.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And some &lt;em>very&lt;/em> memorable lines.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Private Hudson: That&amp;rsquo;s it, man. Game over, man. Game over! What the fuck are we gonna do now? What are we gonna do?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>(You can hear it, can&amp;rsquo;t you? Even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the movie?)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ripley: I say we take off and nuke the entire site from orbit. It&amp;rsquo;s the only way to be sure.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a different feel of movie, but every bit as good as &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/alien/">Alien&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that Alien³ is a step down, but honestly, it would be hard to believe they could do it a &lt;em>third&lt;/em> time in the first place. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alien</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/15/alien/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/15/alien/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>That transmission—Mother&amp;rsquo;s deciphered part of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like an S.O.S.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is it, then?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, I—It looks like a warning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m gonna go out after them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What&amp;rsquo;s the point?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean, by the time it takes to get there, you&amp;rsquo;ll—they&amp;rsquo;ll know if it&amp;rsquo;s a warning or not, yes?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost 50 years and it&amp;rsquo;s impressively how well Alien hold ups.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, the tech is a product of the time, looking impressively retrofuturistic, given the ways we&amp;rsquo;ve actually advanced since then. And the pacing is a bit slow and the jump scares not quite so scary in comparison to more modern scifi horror films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there&amp;rsquo;s a reason Alien is widely thought of as a progenitor of the scifi/horror genre. It&amp;rsquo;s just a really good film. The effects and design hold up and Sigourney Weaver&amp;rsquo;s Ripley is a powerhouse of a performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A solid movie&amp;ndash;and I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow managed to never watch &lt;em>any&lt;/em> of the sequels. As they say, the second best time to do anything you&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to do is &lt;em>right now&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moana 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/16/moana-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/16/moana-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Moana 2! Now with more &amp;rsquo;this was supposed to be a TV show'.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So basically, we have the introduction&amp;ndash;oh how great was the first Moana?!&amp;ndash;, the baby sister, the quest&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, collecting the party and heading out, a series of semi-connected adventures, the fake out failure, and the season finale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moana 2 was apparently supposed to be a TV show and&amp;hellip; in a lot of ways, it shows? The film has the feel of a bunch of plot lines one after another, none particularly given room to breathe (or dopped entirely) and only a bit related. Which&amp;hellip; is exactly how TV shows are structured.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain America: Brave New World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/21/captain-america-brave-new-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/21/captain-america-brave-new-world/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>President Thaddeus Ross: When a Celestial mass emerged in the Indian Ocean, we did what we often do. We squabbled over it. Countries rushed in to claim it as their own, setting up research facilities to exploit its resources. What was found inside that island is nothing short of the discovery of the millennium. Its potential applications in tech, in medicine, in defense are immeasurable. It&amp;rsquo;s even more indestructible than vibranium. And it&amp;rsquo;s not controlled by an isolationist nation. Ladies and gentlemen, I present to you adamantium.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So. We&amp;rsquo;re going to not only finally deal with that mess from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/25/eternals/">Eternals&lt;/a>, but we&amp;rsquo;re also going to finally get in universe adamantium? Interesting strategy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, we have a new Captain America. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure Anthony Mackie could head a movie in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/">The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/a> (or S2 of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/altered-carbon/">Altered Carbon&lt;/a> for that matter), but I actually quite enjoyed him this time around. I think Danny Ramirez / Joaquin Torres / the new Falcon really helped with that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise, we have Harrison Ford taking over for William Hurt as Ross. I&amp;rsquo;m&amp;hellip; still surprised when I see Harrison Ford still being quite as active an actor as he is. It was already slightly odd in Kindom of the Crystal Skull&amp;hellip; and that was more than 15 years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a step up from the recent spate of Marvel movies/TV. Hnoestly, it&amp;rsquo;s been probably since &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/">Spider-Man: No Way Home&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/29/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/">Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; Still, a decent action flick?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Marvels</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/31/the-marvels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/31/the-marvels/</guid><description>&lt;p>You know, for the first half of the movie, that was actually a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Then why did you touch it?&lt;br>
Because it was glowing and mysterious.&lt;br>
Okay new rule - No touching shit&lt;br>
I’m getting a lot of negative energy from you and I don’t need that right now.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Chaos ensues and bad decisions mean that the Marvels (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/">Ms. Marvel&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/">Captain Marvel&lt;/a>, and&amp;hellip; the other one? (Monica Rambeau, most recently from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/">WandaVision&lt;/a>)) are now suddenly swapping places across time and space. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>really&lt;/em> make any sense, but it&amp;rsquo;s fun to watch!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then&amp;hellip; the whole thing starts going off the rails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why don&amp;rsquo;t they have help? Why does Ms. Marvel even wear that bangle?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And&amp;hellip; seriously? A planet where they &lt;em>sing&lt;/em> instead of speak and can&amp;rsquo;t understand if you don&amp;rsquo;t sing? That&amp;rsquo;s a comics silly reason; it just feels weird on the big screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what in the &lt;em>world&lt;/em> is with those Flerken scenes&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s already the shortest movie in the MCU. Did they just really not have enough content so they had to pad it with &lt;em>something&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it was almost there, but like much of the MCU for&amp;hellip; a while now. It could have been so much better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Night at the Museum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/26/night-at-the-museum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/26/night-at-the-museum/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another on that list of movies I&amp;rsquo;m a little surprised I&amp;rsquo;d never seen before&amp;ndash;yet I&amp;rsquo;ve seen enough random clips on YouTube shorts at this point that I feel like I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Side note: This also came back to mind since Ben Stiller wrote a good amount of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/severance/">Severance&lt;/a> of all things.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s a ridiculous and fun movie. The whole premise&amp;ndash;that a magical artifact somehow animates all the exhibits at the museum every night&amp;ndash;yet somehow no one has ever noticed this? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the list bit of sense. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any less fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Easter Island Head: HEY!&lt;br>
[pauses]&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: Dum-dum.&lt;br>
Larry: Yes?&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: You give me gum-gum!&lt;br>
Larry: I give you gum-gum?&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: You new Dum-dum. You give me gum-gum.&lt;br>
Larry: Gee, okay, you know what? I have no gum-gum. Sorry. And my name isn&amp;rsquo;t Dum-dum. My name&amp;rsquo;s Larry.&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: No, your name Dum-dum.&lt;br>
[some people are running away]&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: Oh, you in trouble, Dum-dum. You better run-run. From Attila the Hun-hun.&lt;br>
[Attila yells and chases Larry]&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: See you later, Dum-dum!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There are a lot of fun action scenes in the movie. Just don&amp;rsquo;t think about it all too hard and enjoy the ride. I especially loved the chaos of the dioramas of thousands of tiny men come to life and fighting one another. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Jedediah: No problemo, Gigantor.&lt;br>
Larry: Um, my name&amp;rsquo;s Larry, first of all okay, Jed? See, I call you Jed, I don&amp;rsquo;t call you tiny, right?&lt;br>
Jedediah: What&amp;rsquo;s that supposed to mean?&lt;br>
Larry: Hey teeny, how does that sound?&lt;br>
Jedediah: I&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t like it. It hurts my feelings.&lt;br>
Larry: Okay, well Gigantor makes me feel like some sort of freak.&lt;br>
Octavius: I don&amp;rsquo;t. I just call you Larry.&lt;br>
Larry: Don&amp;rsquo;t be a kiss-ass.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The casting in this movie is a big strength! Dick Van Dyke was a lot of fun as old former night watchman Cecil. Robin Williams (RIP :sad:) is always a delight and his Teddy Roosevelt was no exception. Rami Malek is certainly no &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mr.-robot/">Mr. Robot&lt;/a>, but he&amp;rsquo;s got a perfect presence as Ahkmenrah. And Steve Coogan as Octavius and Owen Wilson&amp;rsquo;s Jedediah were hilarious (especially since the latter was originally a minor cameo).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And you know? Apparently &amp;lsquo;The real-life American Museum of Natural History had 20% more visitors during the holiday season following this movie&amp;rsquo;s opening.&amp;rsquo; So good on them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now the sequels? No idea where they go from here, but you know what? Worth a try!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/">Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade&lt;/a> was such a good movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then they made another one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as I remembered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harrison Jones isn&amp;rsquo;t getting younger&amp;hellip; but he still really makes Indiana Jones. Full stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I bet they were expecting this film (and especially Shia LeBeouf&amp;rsquo;s Mutt) to go better and possibly pass the torch. It was an echo of the same dynamic as Indy and his father in The Last Crusade. Just not quite done as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was kind of fun to see the Soviets be the bad guys this time around and it more or less fits this new, older Indy.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Dean Charles Stanforth: I barely recognize this country anymore. The government&amp;rsquo;s got us seeing Communists in our soup. When the hysteria reaches academia, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to call it a career.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On top of that, seeing Karen Allen&amp;rsquo;s Marion Ravenwood again after all these years? And with the obvious fallout of that? That was more fun than I expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man. Cate Blanchett act the heck out of that role. But still, she just wasn&amp;rsquo;t as much a villain as previous films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;ndash;the action scenes. A bit more over the top than previous movies? Do you even &lt;em>remember&lt;/em> the roller coaster mine cart of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/">Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom&lt;/a>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed the opening in the warehouse. The nuclear bomb-fridge scene has been talked about to death. The motorcycle chase (through the library!) was a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Indiana Jones: You want to be a good archaeologist&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
[Mutt drives them out of the building on his motorcycle]&lt;br>
Indiana Jones: &amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ve got to get out of the library!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The jungle fight between the jeeps was pretty cool&amp;ndash;but the Tarzan bits? a bit much&amp;hellip; The temple was technically neat, even if it didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense. And the &lt;span class="spoiler">alien&lt;/span>
 finale wasn&amp;rsquo;t really that much weirder than centuries old knights and Nazi face melting artifacts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I think I&amp;rsquo;d place it above Temple of Doom, but below Raiders and the Last Crusade. A fun action flick and&amp;ndash;not as bad as I initially thought.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s my favorite of teh trilogy by a solid margin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s great! All the way from the introduction with a young Indy. The introduction of the whip. The hat. His love of snakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From there, we get a big world trotting mystery with some great action scenes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Are you crazy? Don&amp;rsquo;t go between them.&lt;br>
Go between them, are you crazy?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;big archeological puzzles&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But in the Latin alphabet, &amp;ldquo;Jehovah&amp;rdquo; begins with an &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;the dynamic between Indy and his father&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I suddenly remembered my Charlemagne. Let my armies be the rocks and the trees and the birds in the sky.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;Nazis&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I hate these guys.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;and a big supernatural finale.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He choose&amp;hellip; poorly.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Watch it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which of course means &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/">Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull&lt;/a> is up next&amp;hellip; hmm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="temple-of-doom">Temple of Doom&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Temple of Doom has some major middle film issues going on. Both &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/24/indiana-jones-and-the-raiders-of-the-lost-ark/">Raiders of the lost Ark&lt;/a> and The Last Crusade are far better films. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say Temple of Doom is bad, just lesser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Actionwise, there&amp;rsquo;s a ton. Gun fights, bailing out a plane, tons of bugs, several fights in a mine, and a giant drop? There is barely time to breathe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Real world ethicswise&amp;hellip; this is even worse than Raiders, which is saying something. There are a fair few &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; racist, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo; moments and a helping of &amp;ldquo;are they just evil for the sake of bring evil?&amp;rdquo; I suppose one can always go with the &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s an action movie, don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it&amp;rdquo; mindset.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Raiders of the Lost Ark</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/24/indiana-jones-and-the-raiders-of-the-lost-ark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/24/indiana-jones-and-the-raiders-of-the-lost-ark/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been a long time since I&amp;rsquo;ve watched these movies, but man do they actually hold up. From the moment the score first hits, through all the adventure and action scenes, right up to that face melting(ly awesome!) conclusion? There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of nostalgia, granted, but I still think it holds up even so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an introduction, we have it all!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomb robbing!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Indiana needs his bullwhip to swing across a chasm]&lt;br>
Indiana: Give me the whip.&lt;br>
Satipo: Throw me the idol.&lt;br>
[they both see a stone door closing]&lt;br>
Satipo: No time to argue! Throw me the idol, I&amp;rsquo;ll throw you the whip!&lt;br>
Indiana: [throws the idol] Give me the whip!&lt;br>
Satipo: [drops the whip] Adiós, señor.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A fear of snakes!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Upon opening the Well of the Souls and peering down]&lt;br>
Sallah: Indy, why does the floor move?&lt;br>
Indiana: Give me your torch.&lt;br>
[Indy takes the torch and drops it in, revealing hundreds of snakes all over floor of the Well of Souls]&lt;br>
Indiana: Snakes. Why&amp;rsquo;d it have to be snakes?&lt;br>
Sallah: Asps&amp;hellip; very dangerous. You go first.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A mostly grounded world (if larger than life), before edging into the fantastical!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Indiana: The Ark of the Covenant, the chest that the Hebrews used to carry around the Ten Commandments.&lt;br>
Major Eaton: What, you mean &lt;em>the&lt;/em> Ten Commandments?&lt;br>
Indiana: Yes, the actual Ten Commandments, the original stone tablets that Moses brought down from Mt. Horeb and smashed, if you believe in that sort of thing&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
[the officers stare at him blankly]&lt;br>
Indiana: Didn&amp;rsquo;t any of you guys ever go to Sunday school?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Characterwise, Harrison Ford as Indiana Jones really makes the movie, but Karen Allens&amp;rsquo; Marion and John Rhys-Davies&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> are great supporting cast and man Ronald Lacey makes quite the villain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a pulpy adventure film. The plot is about as clearly good guys (even if Indy is totally looting) versus bad guys, loaded with some awesome action scenes along the way, and a solid ending where the good guys win. And sometimes, that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what you want.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a great fun movie. I&amp;rsquo;m going to rewatch them all now! (The original trilogy. I suppose I&amp;rsquo;ll have to watch the new ones too? We&amp;rsquo;ll see.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oppenheimer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/">Barbenheimer&lt;/a>!&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Oppenheimer: Albert? When I came to you with those calculations, we thought we might start a chain reaction that would destroy the entire world&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
Einstein: I remember it well. What of it?&lt;br>
Oppenheimer: I believe we did.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That is a long, dense film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s complicated and there are &lt;em>long&lt;/em> stretches with little going on by talking and setting. But&amp;hellip; man, is it thematic talking and setting?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s all about the story of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J.%20Robert%20Oppenheimer">J. Robert Oppenheimer&lt;/a>, the so called &amp;lsquo;father of the atomic bomb&amp;rsquo; and&amp;hellip; well, how he earned that title. I knew bits and pieces of the story, but having watched this, bits and pieces were apparently all I knew. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of amazing how many of the names I recognize from physics classes were involved in either the project or Oppenheimer&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was at times difficult to follow, there are a ton of jumps (mostly stylistically) and it makes me wander just how much of that was actually problems in Oppenheimer&amp;rsquo;s mind and how much was style. That&amp;rsquo;s not really clear, even by the end of the movie. I certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised though if he was having issues like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Einstein: When they&amp;rsquo;ve punished you enough, they&amp;rsquo;ll serve you salmon and potato salad, make speeches, give you a medal, and pat you in the back telling all is forgiven. Just remember, it won&amp;rsquo;t be for you&amp;hellip; it would be for them.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I think the cast was another impressive part of this film. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t speak to just how perfectly accurate it was, but I think Cillian Murphy was an excellent casting for Oppenheimer. He&amp;rsquo;s got just the right amount of strange charisma to really pull you into the film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matt Damon and Robert Downey Jr. were solid roles, enough to actually remind me why they&amp;rsquo;re considered solid actors&amp;ndash;and not just playing themselves as some do. Alden Ehrenreich I thought looked familiar, but had to look up where I&amp;rsquo;d seen him recently (Solo and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/17/beautiful-creatures/">Beautiful Creatures&lt;/a> (that&amp;rsquo;s been a while)). There are just a bunch of people I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in other things before&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, quite the solid movie. I think I learned something and enjoyed the process of doing something, which is something always worth saying. It&amp;rsquo;s long, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth a watch!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Personally, I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s any reason to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/">Barbenheimer&lt;/a> it though, although it is amusing.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last note:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Oppenheimer: Now I am become Death, the destroyer of worlds.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The first time he says it&amp;hellip; was surprising and kind of weird. I expect they were going with &amp;rsquo;everyone is waiting for him to say the line&amp;hellip; psyche!&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave it at that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Barbie</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/">Barbenheimer&lt;/a>!&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbie is quite a movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An entire world populated entirely by every single variant of Barbie and Ken&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. All named Barbie and Ken, all living their lives in the most &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo;re sort of toys and sort of real&amp;rsquo; way possible. Drinking your morning coffee? Tip the empty cup to your mouth. Need to get out of the second floor? Just jump down! And of course&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ken: I thought I might stay over tonight.&lt;br>
Barbie: Why?&lt;br>
Ken: Because we&amp;rsquo;re girfriend and boyfriend.&lt;br>
Barbie: To do what?&lt;br>
[pause]&lt;br>
Ken: I&amp;rsquo;m actually not sure.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh this movie is weirdly(ly on point) at times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we get the &amp;rsquo;toy in the real world and DOESN&amp;rsquo;T UNDERSTAND THINGS&amp;rsquo; scenes. I feel like a lot of those were dialed up &lt;em>just&lt;/em> to the edge of over-parody, but really, it somehow just works? Barbie is so out of sorts and just doesn&amp;rsquo;t realize it&amp;hellip; until she does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things go wrong&amp;hellip; and suddenly the movie isn&amp;rsquo;t just the Barbie movie anymore. Now, it&amp;rsquo;s all about Ken. And the PATRIARCHY.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ken: To be honest, when I found out the patriarchy wasn&amp;rsquo;t just about horses, I lost interest.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I knew that we were going to have some major conflict there, in a world (almost) entirely populated by Barbies and Kens&amp;hellip; who else is there? But it&amp;rsquo;s kind of weird. I feel like Ken honestly has more of a story arc for a lot of the movie does than Barbie. Which&amp;hellip; feels kind of against the entire point of the movie?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It works though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course, we have the big Mattel in the room. Of &lt;em>course&lt;/em> we have to have a dig about companies making toys for girls run by powerful men. But man, did they dial that one up to 11 on a rediculous scale. A bicycle built for&amp;hellip; a boardroom. That is all. Will Ferrell is a delight as the CEO. After Lord Business in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/02/15/the-lego-movie/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; this is a weird role to be typecast as, but it really works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of casting, I did love Margot Robbie as Barbie&lt;sup id="fnref:5">&lt;a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Barbie: [in tears] I&amp;rsquo;m not pretty anymore!&lt;br>
Gloria: What? You&amp;rsquo;re so pretty!&lt;br>
Barbie: I&amp;rsquo;m not stereotypical Barbie pretty!&lt;br>
Narrator: Note to the filmmakers: Margot Robbie is the wrong person to cast if you want to make this point.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>She just &amp;hellip; epitomizes Barbieness in the movie? I don&amp;rsquo;t know who esle could possibly have carried that role quite as well. Kate McKinnon as Weird Barbie was great as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Ryan Gosling as Ken&lt;sup id="fnref:6">&lt;a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. This one I think could have been differently cast with less issue, but he still did a wonderful job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that stood out was how at times uncomfortably on point Barbie managed to be on various social commentary issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sasha: You&amp;rsquo;re a fascist!&lt;br>
Barbie: How can I be a fascist?&lt;br>
[through tears]&lt;br>
Barbie: I don&amp;rsquo;t control the railways or the flow of commerce&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
[cries]&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh this movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it was a movie better than it had any right to be and far better than I expected, even with generally positive reviews going on. Worth watching. Not sure it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/">Barbenheimer&lt;/a> it though&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>