<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2019 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2019-book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2019 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2019-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2019 Reading List Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/31/2019-reading-list-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/31/2019-reading-list-retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year older and another year of reading. I set myself the entirely insane goal of 120 books this year&amp;ndash;10 a month&amp;ndash;almost one every three days. And for most of the year, I was actually hitting that goal. And then October hit, with a pile of birthdays. And November, with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/25/nanowrimo-2019-the-twilight-between-the-stars/">NaNoWriMo&lt;/a> (still going strong at just over 120k words; I should be done in the next day or two). And then the holidays. Thanksgiving. Christmas. Not really an excuse. More of an explination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alltogether, I read 113 books this year. One of those I finished today&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll do that again next year. Perhaps we&amp;rsquo;ll go for 100 again and try to hold to ten books a year up through October. That seems much more manageable now&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Raise the Titanic!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/24/raise-the-titanic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/24/raise-the-titanic/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="41706" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41706.raise-the-titanic">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/raise-the-titanic.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="41706" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41706.raise-the-titanic"> Raise the Titanic! &lt;/a> is one of the Dirk Pitt books that I remember reading years and years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating story, mixing secret government espionage with the underwater salvage details that are one of the reasons I really do enjoy this series on the greatest salvage mission you could expect: The Titanic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to realize that this book was published 10 years before the remains of the Titanic were discovered&amp;ndash;and yet it&amp;rsquo;s set in 1987, 2 years after. As such, you realize now that there are a few details that aren&amp;rsquo;t entirely correct (such as the ship breaking in half). Also we&amp;rsquo;re near the fall of the USSR, but they&amp;rsquo;re quite the villains to be reckoned with hereabouts. Still, from the point of view it was written, it all seems reasonable enough. Otherwise, just treat it as a parallel universe and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go. And both the salvage mission plus the harrowing account of &lt;span class="spoiler">Russian agents and a hurricane once the Titanic is raised&lt;/span>
makes it a solid action book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rise of the Alliance</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/23/rise-of-the-alliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/23/rise-of-the-alliance/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="23363485" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23363485.rise-of-the-alliance">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/rise-of-the-alliance.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>With &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="23363485" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/23363485.rise-of-the-alliance">Rise of the Alliance&lt;/a>, we&amp;rsquo;re really getting towards the end of the series. The stakes are getting higher, the enemy ships are getting bigger, and the battle jargon is getting denser.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first Aurora and Celestia are all beat up again (of course), but for the moment, they have time. By the end, battle has escalated heartily. The Alliance fleet is growing, there are even more jump capable ships, and even more Ghatazhak. They&amp;rsquo;re going to win eventually, that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected, but it&amp;rsquo;s still interesting to see how they get there.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iceberg</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/19/iceberg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/19/iceberg/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="41710" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41710.iceberg">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/iceberg.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="41710" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41710.iceberg"> Iceberg &lt;/a> opens with a solid enough set piece/action scene: a burnt out wreck of a luxary yacht, long since missing, found melted into an iceberg. One thing leads to another and Dirk Pitt stumbles into a cadre of billionaires with a plot to take over not only businesses but countries. For that&amp;ndash;plot and set pieces&amp;ndash;Iceberg is a solid enough read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then&amp;hellip; you get to the pretty terrible sexism and homophobia. Pitt finds out the woman he&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be getting information out of is in a serious relationship (which for plot reasons he must not threaten), so decides in the spur of the moment to play a caricature of a gay man and&amp;hellip; oof. You can tell this book was published in the 70s and not the particularly progressive sort of 70s either. On top of that, you have sexism wrapped up in a neat little bow with how Pitt and his boss Admiral Sandecker treat Tidi Royal (the latter&amp;rsquo;s secretary). They all treat it so normal that Tidi exists to make coffee and should be yelled at for spilling it on a tossing ship&amp;hellip; oy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mediterranean Caper</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/14/the-mediterranean-caper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/14/the-mediterranean-caper/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="41701" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41701.the-mediterranean-caper">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-mediterranean-caper.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The first &lt;a data-goodreads-type="series" data-goodreads-id="40653" href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/40653.dirk-pitt">Dirk Pitt&lt;/a> book published and the second chronologically, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="41701" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41701.the-mediterranean-caper">The Mediterranean Caper&lt;/a> is kind of ridiculous. It&amp;rsquo;s 70s action at it&amp;rsquo;s finest, with more of a focus on old airplanes (the novel opens with a dogfight between a World War II flying boat against a World War I fighter plane) and smuggling than ocean salvage, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a enough fun read. I miss the ocean focus and salvage we saw in &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="361081" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/361081.pacific-vortex">Pacific Vortex!&lt;/a> and later books though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sexism is &amp;hellip; pretty ridiculous in this book, wherein early in the book, Pitt meets a woman, finds out she&amp;rsquo;s a widow of several years, slaps her and tells her to move on with her life, and has sex with her&amp;ndash;all within minutes of meeting her. Add that to all manner of comments about &amp;lsquo;feminine&amp;rsquo; so and such. It&amp;rsquo;s maddening. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that changes as the series continues to advance through the years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Born of the Ashes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/10/born-of-the-ashes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/10/born-of-the-ashes/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="22300522" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22300522.born-of-the-ashes">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/born-of-the-ashes.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Getting a bit harder to find things to say. The Aurora/Celestia/their crews may have kicked the Jung off the Earth for now, but there&amp;rsquo;s an entire fleeting coming their way and not nearly enough time to do everything they really need to defeat them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All sorts of ridiculous (both in the crazy and the awesome sense of the word) space battles and of course eventually the Aurora will save the day&amp;ndash;but at what cost. The idea of the Jung bombing entire cities out of existence out of little more than spite and to deny them to the Terrans escalates the scale of battle yet again.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pacific Vortex!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/09/pacific-vortex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/09/pacific-vortex/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="361081" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/361081.pacific-vortex">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/pacific-vortex.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Every ocean takes its toll of men and ships, yet none devours them with the voracious appetitive of the Pacific&amp;hellip;.Despite all this, the world&amp;rsquo;s largest ocean tends to be a tranquil place; even its name means peaceful and mild of temper.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Clive Cussler&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a data-goodreads-type="series" data-goodreads-id="40653" href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/40653.dirk-pitt">Dirk Pitt&lt;/a> and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="series" data-goodreads-id="42640" href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/42640.numa-files">NUMA Files&lt;/a> are two more series, much like Ben Bova&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a data-goodreads-type="series" data-goodreads-id="51185" href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/51185.the-grand-tour">Grand Tour&lt;/a> which I remember reading years (more than a decade now) ago, borrowed from the local library whenever I could find them and often in no particular order. I remember enjoying them then, so let&amp;rsquo;s see how they hold up! I&amp;rsquo;ll be listening to them on audiobook as I go.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dead Man's Hand</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/02/dead-mans-hand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/02/dead-mans-hand/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="147912" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/147912.dead-mans-hand">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/dead-mans-hand.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>This is a strange book. Rather than the previous format of two short story collections and a mosaic novel, this subseries has two collections and now two mosiac novels (&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="1281216" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1281216.ace-in-the-hole">Ace in the Hole&lt;/a> being the other). What&amp;rsquo;s strange is that it continues the same plotlines of the first two books and mostly takes place at the same time as Ace in the Hole. Rather than focusing primarily on Puppetman and the political plotline in Atlanta, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="147912" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/147912.dead-mans-hand">Dead Man&amp;#39;s Hand&lt;/a> is set mostly in New York and deals with the death of Chrysalis, the investigation of Ti Malice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a stand alone or complete alternative to Ace in the Hole, I think it would have been a lot stronger. Once the stories merge and start replaying events we&amp;rsquo;ve already seen in Atlanta (albeit with a different point of view), it feels a lot more repetitive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Liberation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/27/liberation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/27/liberation/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="20508635" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20508635.liberation">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/liberation.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>This was a pretty crazy book so far as progressing the story. The Aurora, Celestia, and their crews and allies have a long slog ahead of themselves to free the Earth from the Jung, but they all have one huge advantage: nine books worth of experience in using the jump drive in combat!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are battles galore, some people die, we get a few new allies and piles and piles of &amp;lsquo;five minutes to impact, three to jump&amp;rsquo;. Everything you&amp;rsquo;ve come to know and except from a Frontiers Saga book. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Resistance</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/24/resistance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/24/resistance/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="18690610" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18690610.resistance">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/resistance.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>After &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="18335627" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18335627.celestia-cv-02">Celestia CV-02&lt;/a>, I was worried that the Aurora and her crew would take the backseat for the rest of the series. Luckily, from &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="18690610" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18690610.resistance">Resistance&lt;/a>, this appears to not be the case. We still do get a wider selection of points of view&amp;ndash;on the Aurora, the Celestia, on the Jung controlled world Tanna, and even back on Earth&amp;ndash;but the Aurora is once again the core of the story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things are really moving along now, with various space battles and intrigue. I do appreciate the focus on the Aurora, but the mechanics of living on a barely functional Celestia, where you can&amp;rsquo;t even get between the two sections of the ship are fascinating. I&amp;rsquo;m curious to see if the Celestia can be finished, especially without the resources and allies the Aurora had a thousand light years away.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ace in the Hole</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/21/ace-in-the-hole/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/21/ace-in-the-hole/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="1281216" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1281216.ace-in-the-hole">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/ace-in-the-hole.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="1281216" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1281216.ace-in-the-hole"> Ace in the Hole &lt;/a> completes the second internal trilogy of the Wild Cards, finishing up many of the plotlines of &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="984792" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/984792.aces-abroad"> Aces Abroad &lt;/a> and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="67959" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/67959.down-and-dirty"> Down and Dirty &lt;/a> and bringing the Puppetman plotline to the end. The main plot centers around a presidential convention, which is already a bizarre enough system on its own. Bring super powers and assassins&amp;ndash;and super powered assassins into the mix&amp;ndash;and things go very very sideways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This book really does show what makes the Wild Cards books shine, with just enough real world (and real world characters) to make it feel like a solid &amp;lsquo;what if&amp;rsquo; while at the same time, bringing in the Wild Card and how it changed the world at every level. It&amp;rsquo;s good to meet a wide variety of previous characters on both sides and, as the stories go on, to see some of those same characters fall.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Celestia CV-02</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/21/celestia-cv-02/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/21/celestia-cv-02/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="18335627" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18335627.celestia-cv-02">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/celestia-cv-02.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>As one could probably guess from the title, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="18335627" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18335627.celestia-cv-02">Celestia CV-02&lt;/a> is the first book (after 7!) of the series that doesn&amp;rsquo;t focus on the Aurora and her crew.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a nice change of pace and gives a much broader view of the universe the Aurora (and now Celestia) and their crews inhabit. On the other, we&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time with the Aurora now! I want to know what&amp;rsquo;s next! (We do get some Aurora time though.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Last Lecture</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/21/the-last-lecture/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/21/the-last-lecture/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="40611510" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40611510.the-last-lecture">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-last-lecture.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="40611510" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40611510.the-last-lecture">The Last Lecture&lt;/a> is quite a book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It hits all the harder reading it for the first time now, knowing that Randy Pausch died a year after this lecture/book came out, but even that was a decade ago. His children are in high school/college now. His wife Jai eventually remarried. Some things change and move on. Some don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Pillars of the Earth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/15/the-pillars-of-the-earth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/15/the-pillars-of-the-earth/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="5043" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5043.the-pillars-of-the-earth">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-pillars-of-the-earth.com/cover/9781429586764">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The most expensive part of building is the mistakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="5043" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5043.the-pillars-of-the-earth">The Pillars of the Earth&lt;/a> is not what I expected. As the blurb said, it&amp;rsquo;s a book full of &lt;em>intrigue, action, and romance&lt;/em> , but it&amp;rsquo;s also a giant of a book, set in the twelfth century, following the life and times of several families in a Middle Age English town through everything from daily life to the decades long building of a cathedral to a civil war.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Down and Dirty</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/05/down-and-dirty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/05/down-and-dirty/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="67959" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/67959.down-and-dirty">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/down-and-dirty.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="67959" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/67959.down-and-dirty">Down and Dirty&lt;/a> is a bit of an odd duck, with some stories taking place at the same time as the world tour of &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="984792" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/984792.aces-abroad">Aces Abroad&lt;/a> while others take place after. There are mafia plotlines, political plotlines with the Puppetman, and a bit of an internal struggle for both Tachyon and the Turtle. As with any of the short story collections, there&amp;rsquo;s a wide variety of stories, for better and for worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Individual stories:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Expanse</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/05/the-expanse/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/05/the-expanse/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="18085924" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18085924.the-expanse">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-expanse.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>After half a dozen books, the Aurora is finally back at full strength and on the way home. Their adventures in the Pentaurus Cluster were pretty cool, but it&amp;rsquo;s about time to move on. All things considered, it was a crazy journey, with a black hole and a centuries old lost colony ship. A thousand light years in a book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that has been a little crazy this entire series but really comes to a head is that Nathan was charged with bringing the Aurora home. I don&amp;rsquo;t begrudge many of the decisions he made to make new allies and gain new technology, but the number of times he delays and/or risks the irreplaceable Aurora and her crew is maddening.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Procedural Content Generation in Games</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/25/procedural-content-generation-in-games/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/25/procedural-content-generation-in-games/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="29339831" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29339831.procedural-content-generation-in-games">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/procedural-content-generation-in-games.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve read a textbook. :) This is exactly the sort I would have lost myself in during undergrad (and to some extent did even now).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one level, there is a lot more summary and general content that I could probably have done without. But on the other, the few concrete examples were intriguing and even the summary sections gave me other papers and terms to search for and read more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Head of the Dragon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/24/head-of-the-dragon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/24/head-of-the-dragon/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="17336361" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17336361.head-of-the-dragon">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/head-of-the-dragon.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>The first large section of &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="17336361" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17336361.head-of-the-dragon">Head of the Dragon&lt;/a> follows the Aurora and her crew as they plan just what they have to do to maintain what little surprise Einstein has allowed them before the Ta’Akar learn who, what, and where they are. It&amp;rsquo;s somewhat plodding and slower than a lot of the previous books, but still relatively interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last third or so&amp;hellip; dang that just doesn&amp;rsquo;t let go. Ground forces dropping from space, ships jumping all over the place, orbital bombardment, a whole handful of capital ship to ship combats &amp;hellip; and a big twist that we really all should have seen coming, but was still well enough done. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a send off to the first long section of the Frontiers Saga.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aces Abroad</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/17/aces-abroad/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/17/aces-abroad/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="984792" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/984792.aces-abroad">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/aces-abroad.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>After &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="67955" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/67955.jokers-wild"> Jokers Wild &lt;/a> , I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="984792" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/984792.aces-abroad"> Aces Abroad &lt;/a> move on from Fortunato/the Masons (although Fortunato isn&amp;rsquo;t gone for good just yet). After listening to the afterward by George RR Martin, that seems to have been intentional: the first three books were ordered together and made a self contained arc. A similar pattern will continue through the rest of the books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also interesting this time that where we were mostly limited to New York and Jokertown before, now we&amp;rsquo;re getting a look at the rest of the world&amp;ndash;in the guise of a world tour taken on by a number of famous Aces, Jokers, and Nats (listening to the audiobooks, I was wondering why in the world they&amp;rsquo;d be called gnats&amp;hellip; swattable? nats makes much more sense). The Wild Card virus may be rare the further you get from New York, but it seems to have impacted every corner of the world in various ways.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rise of the Corinari</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/17/rise-of-the-corinari/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/17/rise-of-the-corinari/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="16081718" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16081718.rise-of-the-corinari">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/rise-of-the-corinari.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It ain&amp;rsquo;t life that left you no choice, its honor!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Things are really moving now. Captain Nathan Scott and the crew of the Aurora are making allies (and enemies), repairing their ship, and taking on new crew. Perhaps the Aurora will finally be up to full fighting strength&amp;hellip; at least for a page or two.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ZACH-LIKE, A Game Design History</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/14/zach-like-a-game-design-history/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/14/zach-like-a-game-design-history/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="46158812" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/46158812.zach-like-a-game-design-history">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/zach-like-a-game-design-history.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve played a number of Zachtronics games. &lt;a href="http://www.zachtronics.com/spacechem/">SpaceChem&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.zachtronics.com/opus-magnum/">Opus Magnum&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="http://www.zachtronics.com/tis-100/">TIS-100&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.zachtronics.com/ironclad-tactics/">Ironclad Tactics&lt;/a>. For a programmer/code geek/puzzle lover like me, they&amp;rsquo;re a wonderful sort of thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And from the standpoint of someone that&amp;rsquo;s made a few very small games, loves to learn about how they&amp;rsquo;re made, and would like to do more with game design, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="46158812" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/46158812.zach-like-a-game-design-history">ZACH-LIKE, A Game Design History&lt;/a> is a fascinating read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Freedom's Dawn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/10/freedoms-dawn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/10/freedoms-dawn/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="15737118" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15737118.freedoms-dawn">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/freedoms-dawn.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="15737118" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15737118.freedoms-dawn"> Freedom&amp;#39;s Dawn &lt;/a> continues the Frontiers Saga as Captain Nathan and the crew of the Aurora find themselves a thousand light years from home, embroiled in a rebellion against the EVIL EMPIRE etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One nice thing though is that with each book, we&amp;rsquo;re getting more away from the Star Trek Voyager tropes of a crew far from home and their journey home&amp;ndash;where nothing matters. In the case of The Frontiers Saga, actions have consequences and it really does feel that they&amp;rsquo;re changing the world(s) with their actions, which I greatly appreciate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jokers Wild</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/05/jokers-wild/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/10/05/jokers-wild/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="67955" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/67955.jokers-wild">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/jokers-wild.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Rather than the collection of short stories found in &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="147908" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/147908.wild-cards">Wild Cards&lt;/a> and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="67961" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/67961.aces-high">Aces High&lt;/a>, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="67955" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/67955.jokers-wild">Jokers Wild&lt;/a> is instead a mosaic novel, with the storylines all mixed into a single novel length story, with less clear distinction between the characters and their storylines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;hellip; not thrilled with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aces High</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/26/aces-high/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/26/aces-high/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="67961" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/67961.aces-high">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/aces-high.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Where &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="147908" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/147908.wild-cards">Wild Cards&lt;/a> introduced the setting and spanned decades dealing with the introduction of the wild card virus and how the world diverged from our own, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="67961" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/67961.aces-high">Aces High&lt;/a> feels a lot more focused, dealing primarily with two plot lines: the arrival of an alien &amp;lsquo;swarm mother&amp;rsquo; (a hive mind/bio ship intent on eating planets, as one does) and the Masonic conspiracy we first got a glimpse of in Fortunato&amp;rsquo;s introduction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story starts out a bit rough. I don&amp;rsquo;t really care for the Mason/Fortunato&amp;rsquo;s plotline. But the swarm stuff is pretty cool and there are a number of fun new characters along with expanded worldbuilding. I like the additional focus. It makes me wonder/expect if each book will have a single topic or two to focus around.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Legend of Corinair</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/24/the-legend-of-corinair/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/24/the-legend-of-corinair/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="13575890" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13575890.the-legend-of-corinair">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-legend-of-corinair.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Now we&amp;rsquo;re getting somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Aurora is on the move again, jumping (literally) from system to system and battle to battle. It&amp;rsquo;s still a fairly light read, with plenty of action and sci fi goodies to keep you occupied. It&amp;rsquo;s actually starting to feel more like it&amp;rsquo;s own flavor, rather than just cribbing hard core on Star Trek, particularly Voyager (and there&amp;rsquo;s still nothing wrong with that).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spinning Silver</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/21/spinning-silver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/21/spinning-silver/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="36896898" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36896898.spinning-silver">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/spinning-silver.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The real story isn’t half as pretty as the one you’ve heard. The real story is, the miller’s daughter with her long golden hair wants to catch a lord, a prince, a rich man’s son, so she goes to the moneylender and borrows for a ring and a necklace and decks herself out for the festival. And she’s beautiful enough, so the lord, the prince, the rich man’s son notices her, and dances with her, and tumbles her in a quiet hayloft when the dancing is over, and afterwards he goes home and marries the rich woman his family has picked out for him. Then the miller’s despoiled daughter tells everyone that the moneylender’s in league with the devil, and the village runs him out or maybe even stones him, so at least she gets to keep the jewels for a dowry, and the blacksmith marries her before that firstborn child comes along a little early. Because that’s what the story’s really about: getting out of paying your debts.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The only other Naomi Novik book I&amp;rsquo;ve read was &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="28876" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28876.his-majestys-dragon">His Majesty&amp;#39;s Dragon&lt;/a>, which I . Which makes it all the more surprising how much I loved Spinning Silver.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Rings of Haven</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/19/the-rings-of-haven/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/19/the-rings-of-haven/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="13516287" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13516287.the-rings-of-haven">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-rings-of-haven.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="13516287" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13516287.the-rings-of-haven">The Rings of Haven&lt;/a> takes up right where &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="13504505" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13504505.aurora-cv-01">Aurora: CV-01&lt;/a> left off: a ship and her crew, stranded a thousand light year, having to make friends&amp;ndash;and sometimes enemies&amp;ndash;in a desperate struggle to survive and make their ways home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a way, The Rings of Haven really feels a lot smaller than Aurora: CV-01. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly about establishing a new &amp;rsquo;normal&amp;rsquo; and introducing a few new faces. Which it does well enough, but it&amp;rsquo;s nothing compared to a new world and new technologies and getting blown across the galaxy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wild Cards</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/10/wild-cards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/10/wild-cards/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="147908" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/147908.wild-cards">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/wild-cards.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Finally got around to it. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find the whole series on audiobook, but at least I have the first few, so let&amp;rsquo;s give it a go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a surprisingly fun and rather different sort of book. Rather than a single overarching plot and series of books, you have a world with a few key events and then a number of short stories with only a few characters crossing over. An anthology as it were. :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aurora: CV-01</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/05/aurora-cv-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/05/aurora-cv-01/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="13504505" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13504505.aurora-cv-01">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/aurora-cv-01.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Huh. I picked up &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="13504505" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13504505.aurora-cv-01"> Aurora: CV-01 &lt;/a> based on the recommendation of Steve Gibson of the &lt;a href="https://www.grc.com/securitynow.htm"> Security Now &lt;/a> podcast. Other than a glowing review and knowing it was sci-fi, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know anything else about the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out, it feels an awful lot like a Star Trek series with the labels filed off. Which isn&amp;rsquo;t actually a bad thing, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen all of the Star Trek series and movies. What&amp;rsquo;s more, I&amp;rsquo;m one of the weird ones who started with and actually prefers Voyager to all the others, which &lt;span class="spoiler">when we find out the Aurora is a thousand light years from home&lt;/span>
intrigued me somewhat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Venus</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/02/venus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/02/venus/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="768918" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/768918.venus">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/venus.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>18 books in and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="768918" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/768918.venus"> Venus &lt;/a> is the only body this side of &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64703" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64703.saturn"> Saturn &lt;/a> that the Grand Tour hasn&amp;rsquo;t explored, so it seems a perfectly fitting place to end (I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to that). There&amp;rsquo;s something of a continuation of the The Asteroid Wars, with Martin Humphries and his sons as the focus of the books. One (Alex, &lt;span class="spoiler">his clone&lt;/span>
) attempted to be the first to reach the surface of Venus and died in the attempt. The other (Van, &lt;span class="spoiler">actually not his biological son at all, but rather the son of his longtime enemy from the Asteroid Wars: Lars Fuchs (I know, right?)&lt;/span>
) decides to take on the task of recovering his remains&amp;ndash;a pot sweetened by ten billion dollars of his father&amp;rsquo;s money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that actually makes Venus somewhat interesting and unique among the Grand Tour novels. It&amp;rsquo;s not really one of the corporate war books, such as the early Moonbase books or the Asteroid Wars, but it&amp;rsquo;s also not a purely scientific exploration of Venus&amp;ndash;although there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of that. It&amp;rsquo;s really more an an adventure novel with a sci-fi setting and backing in the hellscape that is Venus. That actually makes it a surprisingly solid book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Imago</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/01/imago/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/01/imago/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="60934" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60934.imago">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/imago.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="60934" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60934.imago">Imago&lt;/a> closes out the Lilith&amp;rsquo;s Brood trilogy, continuing and building on a lot of the general world building set out in &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="60929" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60929.dawn">Dawn&lt;/a> and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="116249" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/116249.adulthood-rites">Adulthood Rites&lt;/a>. This time around, we&amp;rsquo;re not directly following either Lilith or Akin, but rather Jodahs, perhaps the least human protagonist of the series&amp;ndash;as he will be the first human/Oankali hybrid that appears to be growing up to be neither male nor female, instead growing up ooloi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating and weird point of view, especially given that he&amp;rsquo;s even more alien than the ooloi have been all along&amp;ndash;which is saying something. With his human traits, he has even more power to literally rewrite the genes of anything he touches.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mars Life</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/27/mars-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/27/mars-life/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="908284" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/908284.mars-life">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/mars-life.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="908284" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/908284.mars-life">Mars Life&lt;/a> continues the story set out in &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267282" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267282.mars">Mars&lt;/a> and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267310" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267310.return-to-mars">Return to Mars&lt;/a>, with much the same setting and characters (particularly of the latter). Seventeen books in, there&amp;rsquo;s little particularly surprising about Mars Life, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a solid enough entry to the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the most part, we&amp;rsquo;re back to dealing with the New Morality (which makes me wonder about the timeline a bit) and greenhouse flooding on Earth. In particularly how they just want to put their heads in the sand and ignore concrete evidence of intelligent life on Mars and user their oomph to get the Mars project shut down entirely. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting enough on one hand, but as mentioned, it&amp;rsquo;s starting to feel like more of the same.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dune</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/23/dune/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/23/dune/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="43419431" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43419431.dune">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/dune.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little-death that brings total obliteration. I will face my fear. I will permit it to pass over me and through me. And when it has gone past I will turn the inner eye to see its path. Where the fear has gone there will be nothing. Only I will remain.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I last read &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="43419431" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/43419431.dune"> Dune &lt;/a> more than a decade ago and saw both the movie and the TV mini-series about as long ago. From this long ago, and from being such a stable in the science fiction mindspace, I remember a lot of the general things that would happen, but had forgotten most of the details. Unfortunately, I think that might be the best way to remember it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Adulthood Rites</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/22/adulthood-rites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/22/adulthood-rites/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="116249" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/116249.adulthood-rites">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/adulthood-rites.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="116249" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/116249.adulthood-rites"> Adulthood Rites &lt;/a> follows up with the story of Lilith and the alien invasion / our alien saviors set out in &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="60929" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60929.dawn"> Dawn &lt;/a> . This time around though, the main point of view follows Akin. A first generation child of an Oankali/human/Ooloi five parent mating&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s about as weird and interesting as it sounds-who starts the story as a rather precocious (for a human) one year old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see a more alien and childlike point of view on the world &lt;a data-goodreads-type="author" data-goodreads-id="29535" href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/29535.octavia-e-butler"> Octavia E. Butler &lt;/a> built, especially as Akin spends a chunk of time among pure human resistors, becoming something of their champion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mercury</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/18/mercury/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/18/mercury/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="768916" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/768916.mercury">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/mercury.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="768916" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/768916.mercury"> Mercury &lt;/a> is one of the better books of the Grand Tour, which is a relief after &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64703" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64703.saturn"> Saturn &lt;/a> and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267281" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267281.titan"> Titan &lt;/a> .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It starts feeling like one of the more &amp;lsquo;sciency&amp;rsquo; books, with the discovery of life on Mercury&amp;ndash;because of course. But that feeling is short lived, as it turns out the life &lt;span class="spoiler">is actually from Mars&lt;/span>
, leaving Astrobiologist Victor Molina framed and disgraced&amp;ndash;although the &amp;lsquo;who&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; are left unclear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dawn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/15/dawn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/15/dawn/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="60929" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60929.dawn">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/dawn.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Octavia Butler&amp;rsquo;s Xenogenesis / &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="60926" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60926.liliths-brood">Lilith&amp;#39;s Brood&lt;/a> (&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="60929" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60929.dawn">Dawn&lt;/a>, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="116249" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/116249.adulthood-rites">Adulthood Rites&lt;/a>, and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="60934" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60934.imago">Imago&lt;/a>) have been on my &amp;rsquo;to read&amp;rsquo; list for rather a long while, highly recommended by any number of people. I see why now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dawn starts with humanity wiping itself mostly out and the titular Lilith waking up in the next best thing to a cell on what she later learns is an alien spacecraft. The aliens (the Oankali) are alien, with a culture and lifestyle built around exchanging genetic material with races across the universe, changing themselves radically along the way. They&amp;rsquo;ve given humanity a chance to survive&amp;ndash;but only if we change ourselves along the way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Third Shift: Pact</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/14/third-shift-pact/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/14/third-shift-pact/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="16183060" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16183060.third-shift-pact">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/third-shift-pact.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="16183060" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16183060.third-shift-pact">Third Shift: Pact&lt;/a> doesn&amp;rsquo;t really feel like an ending. Although I guess given that Shift is a prequel of sorts to Wool, it makes sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The stories this time around are split between Donny (who&amp;rsquo;s taken Thurman&amp;rsquo;s place &amp;hellip; somehow?) and Solo. Donny&amp;rsquo;s storyline does finally answer a few more questions: what is the real purpose of so many Silos and why are the powers that be okay with entirely losing them from time to time. It also serves as closure for Donny&amp;rsquo;s feeling of betrayal and loss of his wife&amp;ndash;in rather a dramatic manner. The lack of fallout is a bit of a problem though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Titan</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/09/titan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/09/titan/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267281" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267281.titan">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/titan.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s better than &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64703" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64703.saturn"> Saturn &lt;/a> . At least this time around, we spend the entire book around Saturn and Titan, with a bit more exploration into the rings of the former and on the surface of the latter. There are essentially three plotlines: a robotic probe sent to Titan is refusing to phone home, someone has to go back to rings to verify that they&amp;rsquo;re alive, and it&amp;rsquo;s election season again&amp;ndash;this time with Zero Population Growth as the main issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first&amp;ndash;going into the rings to collect samples to prove that they actually found life&amp;ndash; doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the least bit of sense. There are arguments back and forth about who is going to go and how dangerous it is. But&amp;hellip; why? Couldn&amp;rsquo;t they just use a probe? It honestly fills like filler, although there are some hints of something much bigger going on here, since the life in the rings now seems to be &lt;span class="spoiler">alien nanomachines&lt;/span>
(which: why? couldn&amp;rsquo;t they just be different?) After the &lt;span class="spoiler">artifact in the asteroid belt&lt;/span>
plotline doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have gone anywhere, there are at least hints on more of a story to tell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Second Shift: Order</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/05/second-shift-order/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/05/second-shift-order/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="16148938" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16148938.second-shift-order">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/second-shift-order.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="16148938" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16148938.second-shift-order">Second Shift: Order&lt;/a> definitely has &amp;lsquo;middle book&amp;rsquo; syndrome going for it, but in this case, it certainly works. You get a pile of answers to questions raised both in &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="13603717" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13603717.first-shift-legacy">First Shift: Legacy&lt;/a> and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="12287209" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12287209.wool">Wool&lt;/a> along with filling out the world of the Silos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating dystopia and feels just real enough to be terrifyingly possible. I do prefer Order over Legacy in that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the &amp;lsquo;modern day&amp;rsquo; / pre-Silo points of view. I find it more interesting to get hints of that world from after the fall, rather than having everything spelled out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leviathans of Jupiter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/02/leviathans-of-jupiter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/02/leviathans-of-jupiter/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="8730311" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8730311.leviathans-of-jupiter">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/leviathans-of-jupiter.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="8730311" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8730311.leviathans-of-jupiter">Leviathans of Jupiter&lt;/a> takes what made &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267334" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267334.jupiter">Jupiter&lt;/a> so enjoyable (the exploration of the oceans of Jupiter and interactions with the creatures that live there) and takes another visit. This time around, we have even more content from the Leviathan&amp;rsquo;s perspective and first attempts at actually communicating with them, which is pretty cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the science is cool, the characters and drama isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as strong as Jupiter. Grant Archer is still around and in charge now, which is an interesting point. We also get more of Dorn, finding his way out after the Asteroid War. He&amp;rsquo;s been through quite a lot and it&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing his point of view, especially since he&amp;rsquo;s fairly unique in this universe in being a cyborg.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Shift: Legacy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/01/first-shift-legacy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/01/first-shift-legacy/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="13603717" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13603717.first-shift-legacy">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/first-shift-legacy.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I read &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="12287209" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12287209.wool">Wool&lt;/a>. Long enough that I&amp;rsquo;d started to forget the general shape of things, but as I went through &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="13603717" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13603717.first-shift-legacy">First Shift: Legacy&lt;/a>, things started to come back. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing the gaps in Wool&amp;rsquo;s history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, the prequel chapters (of a prequel) just feel wrong. The Silos were built in a matter of years by the government? With apparently minimal or no leaks? Run by a Senator which apparently gets two Representatives to do his absolute bidding (What about their own jobs? It would have made more sense had Donald remained an architect).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Conjuring of Light</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/29/a-conjuring-of-light/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/29/a-conjuring-of-light/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="29939230" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29939230.a-conjuring-of-light">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-conjuring-of-light.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>And so it ends. Where &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="20764879" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20764879.a-gathering-of-shadows">A Gathering of Shadows&lt;/a> was the bright(ish) interlude, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="29939230" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29939230.a-conjuring-of-light">A Conjuring of Light&lt;/a> goes dark quick. The magic that killed Black London is free in Red London and trying it&amp;rsquo;s damnedest to &amp;hellip; take over the world? It&amp;rsquo;s a little unclear. I guess a piece of sentient magic gets a pass on the &amp;rsquo;evil for the sake of being evil&amp;rsquo; card.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, we don&amp;rsquo;t really have anyone know, although we get a lot more of Rhy who actually gets to explore being given a literal second chance at life and what it means to be king. Speaking of which, King Maxim and Queen Emira had a lot going for them. I &amp;hellip; just wish they were developed a bit more. Rhy&amp;rsquo;s relationship with Alucard gets a fair bit more time. It&amp;rsquo;s complicated (in a good way) and well done. I wish them the best.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Saturn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/24/saturn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/24/saturn/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64703" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64703.saturn">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/saturn.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64703" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64703.saturn"> Saturn &lt;/a> was something of a bummer, especially coming off &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267334" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267334.jupiter"> Jupiter &lt;/a> and the Asteroid Wars, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="768917" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/768917.the-aftermath"> The Aftermath &lt;/a> in particular. It might as well have been called &amp;lsquo;adventures of a colony ship&amp;rsquo;, since it&amp;rsquo;s only in the last fraction of the book that we actually make it to Saturn. The rest of the book is spent by power hungry religious zealots trying to take over a ship ostensibly populated by ten thousand people trying to escape exactly that sort of behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about any of the characters. They&amp;rsquo;re all either cartoonishly evil or inept or scientists that need concepts they should know cold explained to them. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a bummer also that the main character went through the cryogenic freeze/thaw that we&amp;rsquo;ve seen discussed in other books, leaving her having to rebuild her life from scratch. But it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually go anywhere. A missed opportunity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Gathering of Shadows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/21/a-gathering-of-shadows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/21/a-gathering-of-shadows/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="20764879" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/20764879.a-gathering-of-shadows">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-gathering-of-shadows.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Oh yes, your relationship with Miss Bard is positively ordinary.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Be quiet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Crossing worlds, killing royals, saving cities. The marks of every good courtship.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Aftermath</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/17/the-aftermath/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/17/the-aftermath/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="768917" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/768917.the-aftermath">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-aftermath.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>As a standalone story, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="768917" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/768917.the-aftermath">The Aftermath&lt;/a> would have been pretty good. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting story from a sci-fi take: a family on a space ship out in the belt, hauling ore. They&amp;rsquo;re attacked. One member escapes back to the belt and the rest are sent out on a long orbit with a broken ship, years before they&amp;rsquo;ll return to civilization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting story, showing just how big space is and how dangerous a frontier it can be in a science fiction story can be in the near future solar system, where they don&amp;rsquo;t have magical engines that can go through the system in days (well, they do, but not on a cargo ship like this). And if you don&amp;rsquo;t have an antenna and can&amp;rsquo;t aim a laser, then you can&amp;rsquo;t very well talk to anyone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Darker Shade of Magic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/11/a-darker-shade-of-magic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/11/a-darker-shade-of-magic/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="22055262" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22055262.a-darker-shade-of-magic">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-darker-shade-of-magic.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="22055262" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22055262.a-darker-shade-of-magic">A Darker Shade of Magic&lt;/a> is a surprisingly fantastic book&amp;ndash;and I mean that in the true sense of the word &lt;em>fantastic&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The core worldbuilding conceit of the book is that of four parallel worlds, specifically four Londons. Gray London (our London?), a dull world with little to no magic left; Red London, with magic full of life; White London, with a more sharp and controlling feel; and lost Black London. The feel and description of each London really makes the book, with Schwab evoking each London with colors and scents and even feelings. It&amp;rsquo;s a really interesting take and done rather well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Silent War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/07/the-silent-war/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/07/the-silent-war/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267285" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267285.the-silent-war">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-silent-war.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267285" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267285.the-silent-war"> The Silent War &lt;/a> feels like a conclusion to the Asteroid Wars ( &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267302" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267302.the-precipice"> The Precipice &lt;/a> and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267349" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267349.the-rock-rats"> The Rock Rats &lt;/a> ), with the war continuing to escalate to father and father atrocities with even more sides to the conflict than before ( &lt;span class="spoiler">Yamagata is back! If a bit weirdly.&lt;/span>
). It&amp;rsquo;s a bit strange to see what feels like such a conclusion with one book left, but I guess that&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="768917" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/768917.the-aftermath"> The Aftermath &lt;/a> ? We&amp;rsquo;ll just have to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, The Silent War is a satisfying enough conclusion to the Asteroid Wars (as a war and as a subseries) building up both the overall conflict and one within the book itself. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to actually see everything come to a head and I think the conclusion is workable, if a little ridiculous. It really feeds into the idea that behind every powerful corporation is a handful (or one) of powerful men and women really driving things forward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Republic of Thieves</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/03/the-republic-of-thieves/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/03/the-republic-of-thieves/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="2890090" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2890090.the-republic-of-thieves">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-republic-of-thieves.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I don’t expect life to make sense,” he said after a few moments, “but it would certainly be pleasant if it would stop kicking us in the balls.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="29588376" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29588376.the-lies-of-locke-lamora"> The Lies of Locke Lamora &lt;/a> was all about revenge and gang warfare. &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="40604556" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40604556.red-seas-under-red-skies"> Red Seas Under Red Skies &lt;/a> branched out to an Ocean&amp;rsquo;s Eleven style casino heist and piracy on the high seas. So what do we get in &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="2890090" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2890090.the-republic-of-thieves"> The Republic of Thieves &lt;/a> ? Infighting between political factions of mages and election fraud, apparently.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children of Blood and Bone</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/02/children-of-blood-and-bone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/02/children-of-blood-and-bone/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="34728667" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34728667.children-of-blood-and-bone">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/children-of-blood-and-bone.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You crushed us to build your monarchy on the backs of our blood and bone. Your mistake wasn&amp;rsquo;t keeping us alive. it was thinking we&amp;rsquo;d never fight back.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="34728667" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34728667.children-of-blood-and-bone">Children of Blood and Bone&lt;/a> is a rather good book. You have a West African world one generation removed from a genocide which managed to take magic from the world. Radically oppressed former magic users with pockets of resistance here and there&amp;ndash;and a main character tossed headfirst into the struggle to return their power.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Rock Rats</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/01/the-rock-rats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/01/the-rock-rats/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267349" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267349.the-rock-rats">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/the-rock-rats.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267349" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267349.the-rock-rats">The Rock Rats&lt;/a> continues the story of &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267302" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267302.the-precipice">The Precipice&lt;/a>, following the story of humanity&amp;rsquo;s expansion into the Asteroid Belt and all the atrocities that entails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, this book is all over the place. Pancho is great fun, but we don&amp;rsquo;t see nearly enough of her. Lars is &amp;hellip; kind of crazy and revenge driven, a long descent from liking him well enough in The Precipice. Amanda is pretty great, but only when she&amp;rsquo;s away from either Lars or Humpries. Of all the marriages in the series thus far, why does this have to be the one to stick beyond a single book? They really don&amp;rsquo;t make much sense together&amp;hellip; Trite as the saying may be, she could do better.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>