<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MCU Phase 5 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-phase-5/</link><description>Recent content in MCU Phase 5 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-phase-5/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Captain America: Brave New World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/21/captain-america-brave-new-world/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/21/captain-america-brave-new-world/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>President Thaddeus Ross: When a Celestial mass emerged in the Indian Ocean, we did what we often do. We squabbled over it. Countries rushed in to claim it as their own, setting up research facilities to exploit its resources. What was found inside that island is nothing short of the discovery of the millennium. Its potential applications in tech, in medicine, in defense are immeasurable. It&amp;rsquo;s even more indestructible than vibranium. And it&amp;rsquo;s not controlled by an isolationist nation. Ladies and gentlemen, I present to you adamantium.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So. We&amp;rsquo;re going to not only finally deal with that mess from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/25/eternals/">Eternals&lt;/a>, but we&amp;rsquo;re also going to finally get in universe adamantium? Interesting strategy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, we have a new Captain America. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure Anthony Mackie could head a movie in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/">The Falcon and the Winter Soldier&lt;/a> (or S2 of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/altered-carbon/">Altered Carbon&lt;/a> for that matter), but I actually quite enjoyed him this time around. I think Danny Ramirez / Joaquin Torres / the new Falcon really helped with that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise, we have Harrison Ford taking over for William Hurt as Ross. I&amp;rsquo;m&amp;hellip; still surprised when I see Harrison Ford still being quite as active an actor as he is. It was already slightly odd in Kindom of the Crystal Skull&amp;hellip; and that was more than 15 years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a step up from the recent spate of Marvel movies/TV. Hnoestly, it&amp;rsquo;s been probably since &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/">Spider-Man: No Way Home&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/29/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/">Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; Still, a decent action flick?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Marvels</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/31/the-marvels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/31/the-marvels/</guid><description>&lt;p>You know, for the first half of the movie, that was actually a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Then why did you touch it?&lt;br>
Because it was glowing and mysterious.&lt;br>
Okay new rule - No touching shit&lt;br>
I’m getting a lot of negative energy from you and I don’t need that right now.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Chaos ensues and bad decisions mean that the Marvels (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/">Ms. Marvel&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/">Captain Marvel&lt;/a>, and&amp;hellip; the other one? (Monica Rambeau, most recently from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/">WandaVision&lt;/a>)) are now suddenly swapping places across time and space. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>really&lt;/em> make any sense, but it&amp;rsquo;s fun to watch!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then&amp;hellip; the whole thing starts going off the rails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why don&amp;rsquo;t they have help? Why does Ms. Marvel even wear that bangle?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And&amp;hellip; seriously? A planet where they &lt;em>sing&lt;/em> instead of speak and can&amp;rsquo;t understand if you don&amp;rsquo;t sing? That&amp;rsquo;s a comics silly reason; it just feels weird on the big screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what in the &lt;em>world&lt;/em> is with those Flerken scenes&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s already the shortest movie in the MCU. Did they just really not have enough content so they had to pad it with &lt;em>something&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it was almost there, but like much of the MCU for&amp;hellip; a while now. It could have been so much better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Agatha All Along</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/21/agatha-all-along/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/21/agatha-all-along/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that was a delight. Take Agatha (and the general fallout of her created world) from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/">WandaVision&lt;/a>, turn up the witchiness, and go on a magical mystical, somewhat terrifying adventure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating story and, honestly, if you would have left out a few scenes it would have worked perfectly well completely outside of the Marvel Cinematic Universe as well. And at this point, that&amp;rsquo;s a strong point in its favor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man Kathryn Hawn does great in this. I loved the supporting witch cast, especially Aubrey Plaza. She does unsettling and off kilter so well. And Teen&amp;ndash;he was an interesting counterpoint. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about the worldbuilding around either Rio (Plaza) or Teen (Locke), those parts felt weird, but the actors were awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;hellip; &lt;strong>the song&lt;/strong> (I don&amp;rsquo;t see this version as spoilers, but some might).&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VnjYeJ5blxo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Man that song has been stuck in my head for weeks now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I personally would have dropped the last half of the last episode, the penultimate really works better as a conclusion. This really doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a sequel (although apparently there will be a third show as a &amp;lsquo;TV trilogy&amp;rsquo; sort of thing?), but so it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/02/deadpool-wolverine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/02/deadpool-wolverine/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so here it is, (almost) the entire reason I rewatched &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/deadpool/">Deadpool&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/28/deadpool-2/">Deadpool 2&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much exactly what you get if you took the (crass) humor of Deadpool, jammed in as many cameos as you could, and shoved it into the modern &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-cinematic-universe/">MCU&lt;/a>, multiverse, TVA, and all&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Deadpool: Welcome to the MCU. You&amp;rsquo;re joining at a bit of a low point.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m still not &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> sure if that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loki: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/12/loki-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/12/loki-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year, another Loki. I really enjoyed &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/">Season 1&lt;/a>. No idea if they could top it. And I&amp;rsquo;m still not 100% sure if they made it better, but they most certainly made it weirder. And I&amp;rsquo;m here for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cast is great of course, with Tom Hiddleston&amp;rsquo;s Loki carrying the show. I really did quite enjoy Jonathan Majors&amp;rsquo; new double role as He Who Remains but also now as Victor Timely. That&amp;rsquo;s most certainly something&amp;ndash;and makes me wonder if they can/could have actually pulled it all off, depending on if Majors sticks around in the MCU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I mentioned in &lt;a href="#6-glorious-purpose">the last episode review below&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s a crazy show, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like about it. It could really change everything&amp;hellip; but I have the unfortunate feeling they&amp;rsquo;re not going to let it. We shall have to see!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Secret Invasion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/secret-invasion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/secret-invasion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s fine. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see some spy stories in the MCU, even if they&amp;rsquo;re light on the spy stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have Fury again, even if (in hindsight) I was perfectly fine without knowing more about Fury&amp;rsquo;s backstory. And the introduction of Super Skrulls? Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really need that in the MCU. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fan of it in either of the previous story lines I&amp;rsquo;ve read them in (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/13/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-6-frightful/">Ultimate Fantastic Four&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/04/runaways-vol.-8-dead-end-kids/">Runaways&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you know what I really think bothers me about the Skrull? All through the Infinity Saga, we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to believe they&amp;rsquo;ve been here, working with Fury. And we never heard even a hint about them. I get it. They’re shapeshifters. The perfect secret agents. Still weird to add something like this after 15 years&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If it had been something tied into each movie and show, leading up to an event (like the Infinity Saga), it could have worked. As it is, it really feels like the concept of an MCU is working against them here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-3/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Rocket: Someday I&amp;rsquo;m gonna make great machines that fly. And me and my friends are gonna go flying together, into the forever and beautiful sky.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was fun. If you liked the previous two Guardians of the Galaxy entries (or especially the Holiday Special), I expect you&amp;rsquo;ll love this. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t care for them, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/21/ant-man-and-the-wasp-quantumania/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/21/ant-man-and-the-wasp-quantumania/</guid><description>&lt;p>Upside: It&amp;rsquo;s visually super colorful and weird and it&amp;rsquo;s got a lot of potential for the new MCU Phase 5!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Downside: It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; weird and chaotic and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really fit with anything else we particularly know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; fine? I enjoyed watching it, but it&amp;rsquo;s in the category of MCU films that I doubt I&amp;rsquo;d watch again unless I&amp;rsquo;m doing a full rewatch (which is getting to be quite the endeavor).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>