<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Iain M. Banks on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/iain-m.-banks/</link><description>Recent content in Iain M. Banks on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/iain-m.-banks/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Use of Weapons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/use-of-weapons/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/use-of-weapons/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The way to a man’s heart is through his chest!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another day, another Culture novel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After how much I liked &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/the-player-of-games/">The Player of Games&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting how much less I got into Use of Weapons. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s the setting and main character&amp;ndash;Zakalwe is closer to Horza than Gurgeh. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s the structure&amp;ndash;with one set of chapters going forward in time, one going backward, and a prologue and epilogue after either of them, it&amp;rsquo;s complicated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s certainly not a bad book. The Culture is a fascinating setting and getting into the darker corners is exactly where you learn the most about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Zakalwe, in all human societies we have ever reviewed, in every age and every state, there has seldom if ever been a shortage of eager young males prepared to kill and die to preserve the security, comfort and prejudices of their elders, and what you call heroism is just an expression of this simple fact; there is never a scarcity of idiots.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Worth reading as a continuation of the Culture, but probably not one I&amp;rsquo;ll revisit. Such is life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Player of Games</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/the-player-of-games/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/the-player-of-games/</guid><description>&lt;p>I &lt;em>really&lt;/em> liked this book. Far more than &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/consider-phlebas/">Consider Phlebas&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, the story follows Jernau Gurgeh, one of (if not the) best &amp;lsquo;Player of Games&amp;rsquo; in the entire Culture. We had a hint of how important games could be in Consider Phlebas, with the stakes literally being life and death (although not of the player, /of course/), but here we see it can be so much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Gurgeh is &lt;em>really&lt;/em> into games.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I get that. I appreciate that. Games have this special spot in the universe. A microcosm of all that can be, following very specific and often completely knowable rules. It&amp;rsquo;s a way to compete (or co-operate (or both)) with other game players, to get to know them and the game you&amp;rsquo;re all playing together. Sometimes, it&amp;rsquo;s all about winning&amp;hellip; but sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s so much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Gurgeh gets that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when he&amp;rsquo;s offered (when Special Circumstances offers&amp;hellip; you accept) to travel two years, almost out of the galaxy, to visit an alien empire where there is incredibly complicated thousand year old game that essentially dominates their entire society&amp;ndash;choosing their leaders, guiding their religious views.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, I love it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the detail there, but the entire idea that a not entirely likeable (especially at first) player of games can be the protagonist. Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s just lovely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Easily my favorite book of the Culture so far (even if I&amp;rsquo;ve only read the two so far &amp;#x1f604;). I really will have to check at the end if it stands up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Consider Phlebas</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/consider-phlebas/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/11/consider-phlebas/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Culture: a &amp;ldquo;a utopian, post-scarcity space society of humanoid aliens, and advanced superintelligent artificial intelligences living in artificial habitats spread across the Milky Way galaxy&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Culture%20series">Culture series&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Besides, it left the humans in the Culture free to take care of the things that really mattered in life, such as sports, games, romance, studying dead languages, barbarian societies and impossible problems, and climbing high mountains without the aid of a safety harness.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;d think (or at least I did) from that description that we&amp;rsquo;d have everything starting in a state of wonder and harmony&amp;hellip; and only then watch things go to hell (because otherwise, where&amp;rsquo;s the story?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So imagine my surprise where (in Consider Phlebas), we start in the middle of a war between the Culture and another group (the Idirans) told from the point of a view of a shape shifting secret agent (more or less) who ends up with a crew of mercenaries (no, they&amp;rsquo;re a &amp;lsquo;Free Company&amp;rsquo;), goes through a few disastrous missions with them, almost gets eaten by a disgusting gigantic blob of a religious cult leader, breaks into a card game where the stakes are real human lives, and finally comes back to a graveyard system and then just about everyone dies.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Experience as well as common sense indicated that the most reliable method of avoiding self-extinction was not to equip oneself with the means to accomplish it in the first place.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I &amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t even know what to say.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>