<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Demonology on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/writing/novels/computational-demonology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computational Demonology on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/writing/novels/computational-demonology/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 20 - The Morning After</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/11/chapter-20-the-morning-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 14:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/11/chapter-20-the-morning-after/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maxwell came to visit Andi in the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her and Jenny had been given a shared room. The hospital had plenty of rooms and both of the women luckily had insurance that would have even covered a private room, but neither of them wanted it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had just been through too much in the past few weeks to want to be alone. Andi still had that feeling running up and down her spine that Percy couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly be dead&amp;ndash;well, dead again if her suspicions were correct&amp;ndash;and that he&amp;rsquo;d just come after them yet again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 19 - Final Jeopardy</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/08/chapter-19-final-jeopardy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 14:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/08/chapter-19-final-jeopardy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Somehow, they made it away from the train. They left just as the emergency crews were starting to arrive and cordon off the area. Anyone still there was being checked over by the medical crews first and then the cops after that. With how Andi looked&amp;ndash;covered head to foot in a tarry, black paste even after some had begun to dissipate&amp;ndash;she was sure they would have had all sorts of questions for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worse yet, Officer Williams was one of the first cops on the scene. She didn&amp;rsquo;t think that she would ever see him again, not if she had anything to say about it. Not after he had stopped by and all but accused them of Ms. Morris&#39; death. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be good, not at all, for them to be here, now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 18 - Demon in Black</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/04/chapter-18-demon-in-black/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/04/chapter-18-demon-in-black/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;She jerked her head up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxwell stood there, towards the doors on one side&amp;ndash;the side without the demon banging at the door. She How had he gotten over there? Hadn&amp;rsquo;t he been thrown out of the train on the opposite side just a little big before? For that matter, hadn&amp;rsquo;t he been &lt;em&gt;thrown out a window&lt;/em&gt;? He looked absolutely none the worse for the wear. He could have just stepped onto the car, a normal passenger.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 17 - Showdown</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/01/chapter-17-showdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 14:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/01/chapter-17-showdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The three of them fanned out immediately, forgetting that less than an hour before they&amp;rsquo;d been doing their best to kill one another. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to realize what had happened thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura&amp;rsquo;s car was gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to figure out what must have happened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 16 - Counterpoint</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/28/chapter-16-counterpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/28/chapter-16-counterpoint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One might imagine that the two of you have a good reason for being here?&amp;rdquo; Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s voice was smooth and disturbingly calm. He didn&amp;rsquo;t seem at all perturbed by the forces arrayed against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, his demon &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; bigger after all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 15 - Revelation</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/25/chapter-15-revelation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/25/chapter-15-revelation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andi blinked. &amp;ldquo;Break into&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; she said under her breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure you were coming back,&amp;rdquo; Laura said, speaking right over her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We did come back,&amp;rdquo; Andi said slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura nodded. &amp;ldquo;I see that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No. Earlier. We were already here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 14 - Maxwell&#39;s Demon</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/21/chapter-14-maxwells-demon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/21/chapter-14-maxwells-demon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;thwip&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a sudden blur and a quick sound, something like the sound a whip might make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;thwip&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another blur and this time a thin red line appeared across the demon&amp;rsquo;s ink black flesh.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 13 - Descent</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/18/chapter-13-descent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/18/chapter-13-descent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;They arrived back at the winery nice and early. Too early in fact; the winery wasn&amp;rsquo;t scheduled to open for a solid hour after they got there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Think we should just head on out?&amp;rdquo; Jenny suggested. There was no one else even parked at the winery. Granted, serving only sandwiches, wine, and cheese meant they didn&amp;rsquo;t have to do much so far as setting up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andi considered. She didn&amp;rsquo;t want to head out there without Laura. Just in case they didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything demonic, the situation was going to be all sorts of awkward. But on the other hand, if Laura wasn&amp;rsquo;t here, they didn&amp;rsquo;t have to figure out how to get her to look the other way when they just walked through the walls&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s do it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 12 - Big Red</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/14/chapter-12-big-red/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/14/chapter-12-big-red/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t know the passcode?&amp;rdquo; Andi asked. She knew that Laura had said she was locked out, but somehow she still expected her to know the code. How else were they supposed to get in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura shook her head though. &amp;ldquo;I was hoping you might have a better idea.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andi couldn&amp;rsquo;t think why. The problem was, she did have a few better ideas. But they relied on either revealing their demonic powers or getting Laura to leave and on doing a bit of damage to the Clerk family shed. Neither was a particularly palatable first option.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11 - Clerk Family Winery</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/11/chapter-11-clerk-family-winery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/11/chapter-11-clerk-family-winery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t you just have gotten his phone number or something?&amp;rdquo; Jenny was obviously joking, but there was just enough of an undercurrent of truth there that Andi couldn&amp;rsquo;t well ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As I&amp;rsquo;ve told you a dozen times, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a physical body. How could he have a cell phone?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenny smiled, but she wasn&amp;rsquo;t about to let the point go that easily. &amp;ldquo;Yeah, but he has to be some sort of demon or angel right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10 - About Time</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/07/chapter-10-about-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/07/chapter-10-about-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the demonic manipulation of temporal dynamics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked up at Jenny with a doubtful look on her face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s about what I thought.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And then?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It looks feasible. I mean, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing completely insane in there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time travel isn&amp;rsquo;t insane?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9 - Keep Your Friends Close</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/04/chapter-9-keep-your-friends-close/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/04/chapter-9-keep-your-friends-close/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andi couldn&amp;rsquo;t help herself. &amp;ldquo;Dead?&amp;rdquo; She&amp;rsquo;d seemed perfectly fine when they&amp;rsquo;d been there. Who could she be dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The officer watched her for a moment more. She realized belatedly that he had dropped that particular nugget on them precisely in order to elicit a reaction. Hopefully surprised was the correct response…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she didn&amp;rsquo;t say anything else, the officer continued. &amp;ldquo;Dead. The neighbors called us at about 3:30 pm about a potential disturbance. They said that they&amp;rsquo;d heard someone screaming and then several gunshots. When we arrived shortly later, she was dead.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8 - And Something Else</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/30/chapter-8-and-something-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/30/chapter-8-and-something-else/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;She found him within ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More accurately&amp;ndash;he found her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One moment, she was alone. At this hour, there weren&amp;rsquo;t many other passengers. The last of the daytime passengers had already gone home and the late night partiers had hours to go yet. She was the only person on the lower level of her car and there was only one couple on the upper floor. However, they seemed otherwise occupied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7 - Angels and Demons</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/27/chapter-7-angels-and-demons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 14:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/27/chapter-7-angels-and-demons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If she hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen her with her own two eyes, she wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have believed it. The demon was still burning away behind them&amp;ndash;she could feel the heat&amp;ndash;but that meant&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Of course dear. Now, how can I help you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andi and Jenny looked at each other. Without a word, they moved together, doing their best to hide the still burning body behind them. Andi stole a quick glance behind her&amp;ndash;not long left now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6 - Buyer Beware</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/23/chapter-6-buyer-beware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/23/chapter-6-buyer-beware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After bandaging up her hand, Jenny brought up a point that Andi hadn&amp;rsquo;t even considered. Had Morris&amp;ndash;the old lady who owned the bookstore where Andi had originally found the book&amp;ndash;known about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had she had anything to do with the book showing up in Andi&amp;rsquo;s bag?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5 - Armed and Dangerous</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/20/chapter-5-armed-and-dangerous/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 14:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/20/chapter-5-armed-and-dangerous/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It turned out that the more powerful the demon was you were trying to summon, the more complicated the summoning became. This was going to take hours of prep work and the better part of half an hour just to do the summoning. Honestly, she would have liked to take longer, but she didn&amp;rsquo;t know that she would be able to. The new chapters of the book had laid out what she&amp;rsquo;d expected&amp;ndash;the more you tried to add to a summoning, the less time you had to do it in. That seemed to set a hard limit on just what could be done, but it was hard to calculate. Perhaps there were exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4 - The Man on the Train</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/16/chapter-4-the-man-on-the-train/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 14:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/16/chapter-4-the-man-on-the-train/</guid>
      <description>The next morning, she didn&amp;rsquo;t even glance at the book on her way out of the apartment, instead opting to grab her own breakfast on the way rather than chance waiting in the kitchen. The idea of using her newly &amp;hellip; enhanced burner was there in the corner of her mind, but she wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite sure hot to deal with that just yet. Yet the summoning having been done had rather an effect on her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3 - Summoning a Demon</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/13/chapter-3-summoning-a-demon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/13/chapter-3-summoning-a-demon/</guid>
      <description>The last ingredient that Andi had to track down was the blood. She had a few ideas how to go about it, but none of them particularly appealed to her. Her best options at the moment were to go to a butcher and just flat out ask if they sold blood&amp;ndash;she thought that they might, to make certain sausages and other foods out of.
Alternatively, she could just a cut of meat and hope that enough drained out that she could get by that way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2 - Writings in Silver</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/09/chapter-2-writings-in-silver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/09/chapter-2-writings-in-silver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andi awoke the next morning, sure that the entire night&amp;rsquo;s activities had been a dream. Sure, she couldn&amp;rsquo;t particularly remember how she had gotten to bed&amp;ndash;or even how she had gotten home, if her memories of the bookstore and the train were not to be believed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it had all been too ridiculous. A book that had somehow followed her home. The feeling of falling, even if it hadn&amp;rsquo;t come back. The man on the train; had he even been related to all the rest of it? A book that her cat irrationally hated&amp;ndash;and she couldn&amp;rsquo;t even read. Writing that wasn&amp;rsquo;t writing, at least until it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computational Demonology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1 - The Book</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/06/chapter-1-the-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/06/chapter-1-the-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It all started with a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t look terribly out of place&amp;ndash;it was a book store after all&amp;ndash;and Andi&amp;rsquo;s eyes just slid right over it at first. But something drew them back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NaNoWriMo 2013 - Computational Demonology</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/06/nanowrimo-2013-computational-demonology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 04:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/06/nanowrimo-2013-computational-demonology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yup, I&amp;rsquo;m doing it again. And this time, I&amp;rsquo;m doing it while finishing my PhD, working a full time job, and adapting to life two thousand miles away from where I was born. Should be interesting. 😄&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
