<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R/Fantasy Book Bingo on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/r/fantasy-book-bingo/</link><description>Recent content in R/Fantasy Book Bingo on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/r/fantasy-book-bingo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2025 Book Bingo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/01/2025-book-bingo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/01/2025-book-bingo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s do it again (again (again (again)))!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous years:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/01/2024-book-bingo/">2024 Book Bingo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/01/2023-book-bingo/">2023 Book Bingo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/01/2022-book-bingo/">2022 Book Bingo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/01/2021-book-bingo/">2021 Book Bingo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Rules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Must be speculative fiction (SF, fantasy, horror with speculative elements)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Limit the number of novellas (fewer than 40k words or defined by the author as such) or combine them&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A book of short stories counts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graphic novels/manga should be treated as novellas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web novels count (if they&amp;rsquo;re long enough)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Audiobooks count&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/1joxlrr/official_rfantasy_2025_book_bingo_challenge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Official thread&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2024 Book Bingo Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/31/2024-book-bingo-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/31/2024-book-bingo-retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;p>BINGO!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here we go. Bingo: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2024-book-bingo/">2024 Book Bingo&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bingo-card">Bingo Card&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mini-reviews">Mini-reviews&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>

&lt;h2 id="bingo-card">Bingo Card&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1>2024 Book Bingo&lt;/h1>
 &lt;button class="bingo-toggle">Toggle Display Mode&lt;/button>

 &lt;table class="bingo">&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 First in a Series
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read the first book in a series.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: The series is more than three books long.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Alliterative Title
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book where multiple words in the title begin with the same letter. For example, Legends and Lattes, A Storm of Swords, Children of Blood and Bone.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: The title has three words or more that start with the same letter.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2024 Book Bingo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/01/2024-book-bingo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/01/2024-book-bingo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s do it again!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previous years:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/01/2023-book-bingo/">2023 Book Bingo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/01/2022-book-bingo/">2022 Book Bingo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/01/2021-book-bingo/">2021 Book Bingo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If anyone I know wants to read along on any of these, drop me a line. Love to chat about books! &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Must be speculative fiction (SF, fantasy, horror with speculative elements)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Limit the number of novellas (fewer than 40k words or defined by the author as such) or combine them&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A book of short stories counts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graphic novels/manga should be treated as novellas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web novels count (if they&amp;rsquo;re long enough)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Audiobooks count&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/1bt4iqf/official_rfantasy_2024_book_bingo_challenge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Official thread&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2023 Book Bingo Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/15/2023-book-bingo-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/15/2023-book-bingo-retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;p>BINGO!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here we go. Bingo: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2023-book-bingo/">2023 Book Bingo&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#bingo-card">Bingo Card&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#mini-reviews">Mini-reviews&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#some-stats">Some stats&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>

&lt;h2 id="bingo-card">Bingo Card&lt;/h2>
&lt;h1>2023 Book Bingo&lt;/h1>
 &lt;button class="bingo-toggle">Toggle Display Mode&lt;/button>

 &lt;table class="bingo">&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Title with a Title
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book in which the novel title contains a job title, military title, or title of nobility such as locksmith, lieutenant, or lord. This title can be something that is bestowed upon a character (such as &amp;ldquo;hero&amp;rdquo;) and it can include fictional titles that are only in the setting, such as Legendborn by Tracy Deonn*.*&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Not a title of royalty.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Superheroes
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Story focuses on super powered individuals. You know, heroes and villains and capes.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Not related to DC or Marvel.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Bottom of the TBR
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read one of the books that’s been on your To Be Read pile (TBR) the longest. If you do not keep a TBR, read one of the books that you have been meaning to read for the longest time but haven’t yet.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: None. Actually finishing a book you’ve been putting off for so long is already hard enough.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Magical Realism or Literary Fantasy
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book that portrays magical or unreal elements in an otherwise realistic or mundane environment. These books are often found on literary fiction shelves and book lists and not always shelved as genre fiction. This is a hard square to pin down as what makes something literary or magical can often come down to vibes, so use your best judgment. No saying A Game of Thrones is literary fiction since there aren’t a lot of magical elements. Check out &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/4bhiua/proposed_magical_realism_recommendation_list/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this thread&lt;/a> for further ideas and guidelines.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Not one of the thirty books in the linked thread.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Young Adult
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book that was written for young adults.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Published in the last 5 years.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Mundane Jobs
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>The protagonist has a commonplace job that can be found in the real world (so no princes or monster hunters!). We are also excluding soldiers as they are already extremely prominent in SFF.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Does not take place on Earth.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Published in the 00s
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book that was published between 2000 and 2009.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Not in the top 30 of r/Fantasy’s &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/11mvwsa/rfantasy_top_novels_2023_results/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Best of 2023 List&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Angels and Demons
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Story must feature angels or demons or both in a prominent role.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: The protagonist is an angel or demon.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Five SFF Short Stories
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Any short SFF story as long as there are five of them.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Read an entire SFF anthology or collection.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Horror
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book from the horror genre.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Not Stephen King or H. P. Lovecraft.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Self-Published OR Indie Publisher
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Self-published or published through a small, indie publisher. If the novel has been picked up by a publisher, it only counts for this challenge if you read it when it was still self-published.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Self-published and has fewer than 100 ratings on Goodreads, OR an indie publisher that has done an &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/wiki/ama/small-press-friday/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AMA with r/Fantasy&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Set in the Middle East/Middle Eastern SFF
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book that is set in the Middle East or in an analogous setting that is based on real-world Middle Eastern settings, myths, and culture. See these pages for more info on which countries and regions qualify: Wikipedia page for &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Middle_East" target="_blank" rel="noopener">the Middle East&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://swanaalliance.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SWANA page&lt;/a>. Example novels would include The Daevabad Trilogy by S. A. Chakraborty and The Candle and the Flame by Nafiza Azad&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Author is of Middle Eastern heritage.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Published in 2023
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>A book published for the first time in 2023 (no reprints or new editions).&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: It&amp;rsquo;s also a debut novel&amp;ndash;as in it&amp;rsquo;s the author&amp;rsquo;s first published novel.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Multiverse and Alternate Realities
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book in which the setting contains at least two universes, dimensions, planes, realities, etc. that characters within the book can travel between. Multiple worlds in the same physical plane of existence - such as planets within a universe - would not count for this square.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Characters do not walk through a literal door in order to get to another world.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 POC Author
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Author must be Person of Color.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Novel takes place in a futuristic, sci-fi world. NOTE: this is now a recurring, yearly square but the hard mode will be changing every year to keep it exciting.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Set in Space&lt;br />(replacing Book Club/Readalong)
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>A book that takes place primarily (at least 50%) off planet. IE: on a spaceship, space station, asteroid, space whale, free floating in space, etc.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Characters are not originally from Earth. It is acceptable for the characters to be descendants of Earthlings as long as they are not themselves from Earth.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Novella
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a work of fiction of between 17,500 and 40,000 words.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Novella is NOT published by Tordotcom Publishing.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Mythical Beasts
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book that prominently features at least one mythical beast, meaning a creature that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist in reality. See &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legendary_creature" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this Wikipedia page&lt;/a> for an idea of what counts.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: No dragons or dragon-like creatures (e.g. wyverns, Draccus in Kingkiller).&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Elemental Magic
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book that has elemental magic. The primary magic within the world deals with the classical elements: Earth, Wind/Air, Water, and Fire.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Not V. E. Schwab’s Shades of Magic series or Jim Butcher’s Codex Alera series.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Myths and Retellings
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book that is based on a myth or preexisting story.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Not Greek or Roman mythology.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Queernorm Setting
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>A book set in a world where queerness is normalized, accepted, and prevalent within communities. Characters are not othered, ostracized, or particularly remarkable in any way for their queerness.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Not a futuristic setting. Takes place in a time akin to ours, in the past, or in a fantasy world that has no science fiction elements.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Coastal or Island Setting
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Story features a major setting that is near or surrounded by the sea.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: The book also features sea-faring.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Druids
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>A book that heavily features druids. This can be a classic druid, a priest or magician in Celtic lore, or a magic user whose powers stem from nature.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Not The Iron Druid Chronicles by Kevin Hearne.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Featuring Robots
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book that features robots, androids, clockwork machines, or automatons.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Robot is the protagonist.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Sequel
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Read a book that is a sequel to another SFF book.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Book 3 or on in the series.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
 &lt;br />
&lt;style>
h1, h2, h3 {
 clear: both;
}

figure.cover-image {
 float: left;
 margin-right: 1em;
}

figure.cover-image img { 
 height: 100px;
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="mini-reviews">Mini-reviews&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>‡ are my favorites, ∿ I listened to the audiobook. Full reviews + all reviews for each author are linked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ &lt;strong>Sequel (HM: Book 3+)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/the-infinite/">The Infinite&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ada-hoffmann/">Ada Hoffmann&lt;/a>. Sci-fi with post-singularity AI acting as gods and a touch of cosmic horror. Interesting discussions about neurodiversity. My favorite of the series and a solid conclusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Mundane Jobs (Not on Earth)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/12/phoenix-extravagant/">Phoenix Extravagant&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/yoon-ha-lee/">Yoon Ha Lee&lt;/a>. A parallel to the China/Japan conflicts of a century ago and the jobs and sacrifices normal people (esp. artists) have to make during times of war and occupation. Also, Arazi (the dragon on the cover) really sells the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>Published in the 00s (HM: (HM: Not top 30 on &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/11mvwsa/rfantasy_top_novels_2023_results/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this list&lt;/a>)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/">Throne of Jade&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/naomi-novik/">Naomi Novik&lt;/a>. What if the Napoleanic Wars, but with DRAGONS. This one now with more travel to China. It&amp;rsquo;s a neat concept and I like throughout the series how the idea is explored in a number of different cultures, although as the series goes on, it starts to wear a bit thin. Temeraire and Laurence (dragon and &amp;hellip; handler? it&amp;rsquo;s complicated) are really the soul of these books. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/temeraire/">Temeraire&lt;/a> is the first book in the series; but I&amp;rsquo;d previously read that years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ &lt;strong>Angels and Demons (HM: Protagonist)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/good-omens-the-nice-and-accurate-prophecies-of-agnes-nutter-witch/">Good Omens: The Nice and Accurate Prophecies of Agnes Nutter, Witch&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/neil-gaiman/">Neil Gaiman&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/terry-pratchett/">Terry Pratchett&lt;/a>. A mix of the wonderful worldbuilding of Pratchett and Gaiman that builds on both their strengths to build a fun ride, political/religious in exactly that fun somewhat blasphemous irreverent sort of way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Bottom of TBR&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/01/blindsight/">Blindsight&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peter-watts/">Peter Watts&lt;/a>. Vampires. In Space. It&amp;rsquo;s such a bonkers idea that I want more of it. Plus you get a surprisingly solid scientific reasoning for a lot of Vampire myths, a discussion on AI and the Chinese Room argument, talk about multiple personalities. It&amp;rsquo;s dense and a bit chaotic and weird. I liked it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Horror (HM: Not King or Lovecraft)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/prodigal-son/">Prodigal Son&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dean-koontz/">Dean Koontz&lt;/a>. What if Frankenstein survived into the modern era and tried to conquer the world Invasion of the Frankenbodysnatchers style. It&amp;rsquo;s a solid Dean Koontz book, which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read in years now. The problem is that it tries to fit far too many threads into one story and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work without the sequels (and only barely works with them). Another book dealing with autism, dealt with mostly well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ &lt;strong>Coastal or Island Setting (HM: Features Seafaring)&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/">Tress of the Emerald Sea&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a>. The feel of Princess Bride told through through the narrative lense of Hoid (which won&amp;rsquo;t make the least bit of sense if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read much of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s Cosmere I suppose). I&amp;rsquo;ve read and enjoyed just about all of Sanderson and he&amp;rsquo;s got 4 novels out this year, so of course I have to use one of them. It&amp;rsquo;s delightful, touching little story and probably worth a read even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the rest of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s work, although the ending will be weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>Queernorm Setting (HM: Not Futuristic)&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/03/under-the-whispering-door/">Under the Whispering Door&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.j.-klune/">T.J. Klune&lt;/a>. So… what do you call a slice of life story when the protagonist dies at the end of the first chapter? Whatever you do, Under the Whispering Door is a delightful example thereof. Despite taking place within our world, I would say it&amp;rsquo;s Queernorm within the much reduced setting of the story (the tea house and this specific corner of the afterishlife).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Set in the Middle East (HM: By an author of Middle Eastern heritage)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/07/girl-serpent-thorn/">Girl, Serpent, Thorn&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/melissa-bashardoust/">Melissa Bashardoust&lt;/a>. Take Persian mythology and worldbuilding, more than a touch of fairy tale feel, a cursed princess, demons, div (what in a Euro-centric story would be probably be fae), a touch of romance, and the spark of revolution. It’s an interesting world, an interesting premise, and you really want everything to go right in the end. I like the variety of non-humans. They feel the same as dozens of stories I read before–and yet, being based on a different set of myths and legends, different. All at the same time. It’s fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Title with a Title (HM: Not Royalty)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/the-handmaids-tale/">The Handmaid’s Tale&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/margaret-atwood/">Margaret Atwood&lt;/a>. Take the extremist end of the American Protestant religious right. Give them everything they want (plus some) over the span of years (if not months). Like any good story of this sort, it takes a potential problem–an idea–and turns it up to eleven. It goes steps further than anything we’ve seen in modern times–or at least differently. And all the more telling when you feel people in today&amp;rsquo;s world taking it as inspiration rather than a cautionary tale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Superheroes (HM: Not DC or Marvel)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/12/zeroes/">Zeroes&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/scott-westerfield/">Scott Westerfield&lt;/a>. The story of six American teenagers who discover they have superpowers. What I like most perhaps was the entire idea of the title: “Zeroes, not Heroes”. They’re not superheroes. (oops, guess it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit after all). I also enjoyed how diverse the cast was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Magical Realism or Literary Fantasy (HM: Not from &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/4bhiua/proposed_magical_realism_recommendation_list/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this list&lt;/a>)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/16/the-cartographers/">The Cartographers&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peng-shepherd/">Peng Shepherd&lt;/a>. Plus side: I love the premise. Take the idea of phantom settlements / copyright traps. Now make it so that if you happen to have the right map–you can actually get to those phantom settlements. I may have to check out Paper Towns. Minus side: it takes forever to actually get to the magic of the book. You (as the reader) are sure there’s more to them than you’d think, either having read the blurb–or just being aware of the book’s genre. But for how magical a concept it is, we barely get anything to do with them until halfway through the book and even then we’re only touching the surface. I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s Magical Realism for you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>Multiverse and Alternate Realities (HM: Not through a literal door)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/18/the-space-between-worlds/">The Space Between Worlds&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/micaiah-johnson/">Micaiah Johnson&lt;/a>. Hopping between worlds–with one big caveat. If you visit a world where another you is still alive, you die. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating digging into the idea that the best world hoppers are those raised under circumstances where they &lt;em>should have died&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Myths and Retellings (HM: Not Greek or Roman)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/23/the-witchs-heart/">The Witch’s Heart&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/genevieve-gornichec/">Genevieve Gornichec&lt;/a>. It seems no matter the culture, myths and legends get weird. Norse mythology is absolutely no exception to that. In this story, we have a novelization of the story of Angrboda. Wife of Loki. Mother of monsters. She’s been around a while (it’s mythology, even she doesn’t know how long) and she just wants to be left alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>Set in Space (HM: Not from Earth)&lt;/strong> (replacing Book Bingo/Readalong): &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/08/house-of-suns/">House of Suns&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/alastair-reynolds/">Alastair Reynolds&lt;/a>. In House of Suns, we have the story of a small subset of humanity writ large. The speed of light is the ultimate limit. Planets are decades apart; the galaxy hundreds of thousands of years around. So how do you continue that oh so human drive for exploration and expansion? Well in House of Suns, you create a thousand clones. Imprint them all with your memories. And send them out into the universe. Set it up so that ever few decades/centuries/millenia, they meet up, share all they’ve been to. What other branches of humanity have risen–or fallen? What other miracles of technology have been discovered? Who’s fallen in love? Sci-fi at it&amp;rsquo;s finest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Druids (HM: Not Iron Druid)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/13/dreamers-pool/">Dreamer’s Pool&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/juliet-marillier/">Juliet Marillier&lt;/a>. Take a bit of magic/folklore in an oldentimes Ireland; add in a Fae bargain (with all the complications that ensues); combine with a prince and princess who’ve never met outside of letters–and seem entirely different in person; and finish it all off with fairy tale magic of Dreamer’s Pool. It&amp;rsquo;s got an interesting cast and a nice fairy tale sort of plot, if a bit incomplete feeling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Mythical Beasts (HM: Not dragons)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/18/the-last-unicorn/">The Last Unicorn&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peter-s.-beagle/">Peter S. Beagle&lt;/a>. It’s one of those books that just feels like a fairy tale. An ageless story. A story passed down from long ago ages of myth and fantasy. Ages with heroes and villains and wizards and–you guessed it–unicorns. It’s beautifully written (for the most part; there are certainly parts that feel overdone), chock full of wonderfully fantastic descriptions and metaphors that just sort of stick around. I really enjoy the characters, especially the titular Last Unicorn&amp;ndash;they don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>feel&lt;/em> human; which I appreciate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Featuring Robots (HM: Robot protagonist)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/lock-in/">Lock In&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/john-scalzi/">John Scalzi&lt;/a>. A near future Earth where a flu-like pandemic (Haden’s Syndrome) has caused locked-in syndrome in some small percent of the world’s population (a small percent of billions is still an awful lot of people). Those affected are completely paralyzed, unable to move, while still being fully aware and conscious. Luckily(ish) a massive global effort has figured out how to embed computer hardware in their brains so as to allow them to remotely pilot either robotic bodies (threeps) or (more rarely) other humans who’ve allowed them access. This of course is widely accepted by the rest of humanity and causes no issues whatsoever. It&amp;rsquo;s arguable if the human minds in robotic bodies (the threeps) counts for the square, but if Murderbot counts, I would think this does too? It&amp;rsquo;s their body (although that&amp;rsquo;s a decent plot point in itself).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Novella (HM: Not Tordotcom)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/26/six-gun-snow-white/">Six-Gun Snow White&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/catherynne-m.-valente/">Catherynne M. Valente&lt;/a>. Take (the vague outline) the story of Snow White. Make it a Western. Things get weird. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting premise and certainly an interesting writing style&amp;ndash;although not my favorite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>5 SFF Shorts (HM: An Anthology)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/30/stories-of-your-life-and-others/">Stories of Your Life and Others&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ted-chiang/">Ted Chiang&lt;/a>. Story of Your Life became the film Arrival, which got me to read the book. The rest are also really good, including some really interesting alternate takes on religion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>‡ ∿ &lt;strong>YA (HM: Published in the last 5 years)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/04/a-wizards-guide-to-defensive-baking/">A Wizard’s Guide to Defensive Baking&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/">T. Kingfisher&lt;/a>. A world with weirdly specialized sorts of wizards. You might be able to cast lightning bolts… or you might have the power to animate and converse with dead horses. Or you might even have magical powers over… bread! It’s such a delightful idea and Kingfisher manages to do all sorts of fun things with it. Some obvious (Mongo eat your gingerbread heart out), some less so (Bob the sourdough starter; so delightful). I need to read more Kingfisher.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>POC Author (HM: Furturistic Sci/fi)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/06/rosewater/">Rosewater&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/tade-thompson/">Tade Thompson&lt;/a>. A fascinating premise. Take the world a half century in the future. Most things are the same, but there’s a bit more tech floating around, mostly. Introduce a massive alien organism that lands in London and ends up burrowing it’s way to Nigeria. From that alien blob, fill the atmosphere with alien microorganisms/cells that create their own xenosphere, enabling (among other things) psychic powers in some very small proportion of the population. Writ rather more gritty than I was expecting with a complicated structure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Self/Indie published (HM: Fewer than 100 ratings)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/10/the-book-of-zog/">The Book of Zog&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/alec-hutson/">Alec Hutson&lt;/a>. Zogrusz is an Eldrich Horror, a being from beyond time and space. But… a nice one? That just wants to do the right thing? It&amp;rsquo;s surprisingly adorable with some interesting cosmic level universebuilding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>∿ &lt;strong>Elemental Magic (HM: Not Shades of Magic or Codex Alera)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/leigh-bardugo/">Leigh Bardugo&lt;/a>. Rather YA and the TV show is better (partially because it pulls from the other series in the same world as well). But I did enjoy the Russian influenced worldbuilding and the slightly more flexible than many YA contemporaries groupings. Has a lot of potential for the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Published in 2023 (HM: Debut)&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/the-scourge-between-stars/">The Scourge Between Stars&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ness-brown/">Ness Brown&lt;/a>. A generation ship with something going bump in the night? Isn&amp;rsquo;t it always night in space? In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s nicely terrifying if rather short (at novella length). Feels &lt;em>very&lt;/em> similar to Alien, but that&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing. A solid debut.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(I originally read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/29/venco/">VenCo&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/cherie-dimaline/">Cherie Dimaline&lt;/a> for this spot, but realized as I was writing this post that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit hard mode.)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="some-stats">Some stats&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Audiobooks: 14. The rest were all ebooks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Borrowed on Libby: 21. Libraries are the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Series (that I read the rest of):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>All 3 of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-outside/">The Outside&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ada-hoffmann/">Ada Hoffmann&lt;/a> (between 2022 and 2023 bingos).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All 9 of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/temeraire/">Temeraire&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/naomi-novik/">Naomi Novik&lt;/a> (reread the first; rest this year).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All 5 of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/dean-koontzs-frankenstein/">Dean Koontz’s Frankenstein&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dean-koontz/">Dean Koontz&lt;/a>. Duh. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>New (to me) authors: 15&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/alec-hutson/">Alec Hutson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/catherynne-m.-valente/">Catherynne M. Valente&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/cherie-dimaline/">Cherie Dimaline&lt;/a> (replaced with a different story for hard mode, but I did read for the bingo)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/genevieve-gornichec/">Genevieve Gornichec&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/juliet-marillier/">Juliet Marillier&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/leigh-bardugo/">Leigh Bardugo&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/margaret-atwood/">Margaret Atwood&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/melissa-bashardoust/">Melissa Bashardoust&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/micaiah-johnson/">Micaiah Johnson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ness-brown/">Ness Brown&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peng-shepherd/">Peng Shepherd&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peter-s.-beagle/">Peter S. Beagle&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/peter-watts/">Peter Watts&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/tade-thompson/">Tade Thompson&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ted-chiang/">Ted Chiang&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Repeat authors for book bingo: 5&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ada-hoffmann/">Ada Hoffmann&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-outside/">The Outside&lt;/a> for 2022&amp;rsquo;s Features Mental Health.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/naomi-novik/">Naomi Novik&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/">A Deadly Education&lt;/a> for 2022&amp;rsquo;s Anti-Hero.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.-kingfisher/">T. Kingfisher&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/">Nettle &amp;amp; Bone&lt;/a> for 2022&amp;rsquo;s Author Uses Initials.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/t.j.-klune/">T.J. Klune&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/18/the-house-in-the-cerulean-sea/">The House in the Cerulean Sea&lt;/a> for 2021&amp;rsquo;s Found Family.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/yoon-ha-lee/">Yoon Ha Lee&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/22/the-vela/">The Vela&lt;/a> for 2022&amp;rsquo;s Two or More Authors.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Other repeat authors: 7&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/alastair-reynolds/">Alastair Reynolds&lt;/a>. Originally &amp;lsquo;read&amp;rsquo; him on the Escape Pod podcast. Also Revelation Space.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve read everything he&amp;rsquo;s written (except Alcatraz). First time a new book fit a Bingo square though.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dean-koontz/">Dean Koontz&lt;/a>. Read a lot of him before I started writing reviews, although only this series since.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/john-scalzi/">John Scalzi&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/old-mans-war/">Old Man’s War&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/neil-gaiman/">Neil Gaiman&lt;/a>. All sorts of things. and&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/scott-westerfield/">Scott Westerfield&lt;/a>. Read Uglies et al years ago; didn&amp;rsquo;t even realize it was the same author.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/terry-pratchett/">Terry Pratchett&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/discworld/">Discworld&lt;/a>. All of it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>2023 Book Bingo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/01/2023-book-bingo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/01/2023-book-bingo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Two years down &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/01/2021-book-bingo/">2021&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/01/2022-book-bingo/">2022&lt;/a> and yet another one to go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Much more breathing room last year than the year before (two weeks!) and I&amp;rsquo;ve already been reading more this year, so I&amp;rsquo;m confident. Let&amp;rsquo;s do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a side note, if anyone I know wants to read along on any of these, drop me a line. Love to chat about books. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Must be speculative fiction (SF, fantasy, horror with speculative elements)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Limit the number of novellas (fewer than 40k words or defined by the author as such) or combine them&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A book of short stories counts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graphic novels/manga should be treated as novellas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web novels count (if they&amp;rsquo;re long enough)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Audiobooks count&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/128oxqt/official_rfantasy_2023_book_bingo_challenge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Official thread&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022 Book Bingo Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/13/2022-book-bingo-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/13/2022-book-bingo-retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;p>BINGO!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One year ago, I started my (second) &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-book-bingo/">2022 Book Bingo&lt;/a>. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how I did!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1>2022 Book Bingo&lt;/h1>
 &lt;button class="bingo-toggle">Toggle Display Mode&lt;/button>

 &lt;table class="bingo">&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 A Book from r/Fantasy&amp;rsquo;s Top LGBTQIA List
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Any book on &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/ifmx04/rfantasys_2020_top_lgbtqa_books_voting_results/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this list&lt;/a>, including sequels.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: A book or series that received ten votes or less.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Weird Ecology
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Story takes place in a world that is wildly different from our own and includes such things as unique environments, strange flora and fauna, unusual ecosystems, etc. The difference in environment, flora and fauna, and ecosystems cannot simply be &amp;ldquo;it’s a fantasy world,&amp;rdquo; but something that is fundamentally different about the world itself. Example: The Bone Ships by RJ Barker counts as this is a poisonous world without trees and the world had to evolve in significantly different ways to deal with that. Meanwhile The Liveship Traders by Robin Hobb would not count, as it is fairly close to our own world’s ecology just with the added presence of dragons.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022 Book Bingo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/01/2022-book-bingo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/01/2022-book-bingo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s do this again! I &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/2021-book-bingo-retrospective/">barely made it&lt;/a>, but there were so many books that I absolutely ended up loving that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I otherwise would have read. So this year, better!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rules:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Must be speculative fiction (SF, fantasy, horror with speculative elements)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Limit the number of novellas (fewer than 40k words or defined by the author as such) or combine them&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A book of short stories counts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Graphic novels/manga should be treated as novellas&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web novels count (if they&amp;rsquo;re long enough)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Audiobooks count&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/ttrev1/official_rfantasy_2022_book_bingo_challenge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Official thread&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2021 Book Bingo Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/2021-book-bingo-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/2021-book-bingo-retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;p>I made it*!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/01/2021-book-bingo/">My original goal&lt;/a> was to finish all 25 books on the Book Bingo card, every one of them on hardmode. With two exceptions, I made it (see below). You can click any book to read my review:&lt;/p>
&lt;h1>2021 Book Bingo&lt;/h1>
 &lt;button class="bingo-toggle">Toggle Display Mode&lt;/button>

 &lt;table class="bingo">&lt;tr>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Five SFF Short Stories
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Any short story as long as there are five of them.&lt;/p>
 &lt;p>Hard Mode: Read an entire SFF anthology or collection.&lt;/p>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/td>&lt;td>&lt;div class="tooltip">
 Set in Asia
 &lt;div class="tooltiptext">
 &lt;p>Any book set in Asia or an analogous fantasy setting that is based on a real-world Asian setting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2021 Book Bingo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/01/2021-book-bingo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/01/2021-book-bingo/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Fantasy/comments/mhz2tt/official_rfantasy_2021_book_bingo_challenge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">/r/Fantasy Book Bingo&lt;/a> cards before a number of times, but this is the first year that I think I&amp;rsquo;m actually going to try it. I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten away from my previous reading lists, but this sounds like a great way to find new things / read a few that are out of my comfort zone. I do read a crazy amount, so I should be able to find time for 25 specific books&amp;ndash;but then again, there are a few rules that might make this more interesting:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>