<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andi C. Buchanan on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/andi-c.-buchanan/</link><description>Recent content in Andi C. Buchanan on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/andi-c.-buchanan/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Microscopes and Magic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/31/microscopes-and-magic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/31/microscopes-and-magic/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much more of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/03/succulents-and-spells/">Succulents and Spells&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s quick, doesn&amp;rsquo;t really go anywhere (huge), and is a fun little read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, I like seeing more of Marigold as the primary point of view. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird to swap, but I think I like her more than Laurel. Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s because she&amp;rsquo;s just coming into the magical world?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the downside&amp;hellip; the (a?) big bad is maginanotech bugs. And there&amp;rsquo;s really no justification for nanotech just &lt;em>existing&lt;/em> in this world. I generally only like one real &amp;lsquo;give&amp;rsquo; to a story and this is a bit much. Especially when it could totally just be magical and that would be fine. Even magical bioengineering would be better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such is life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s cute and if you liked the first, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably like this. I&amp;rsquo;m curious what in the world is next&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Succulents and Spells</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/03/succulents-and-spells/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/03/succulents-and-spells/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Marigold took a deep breath. &amp;ldquo;My name is Marigold Ann Nightfield. I use she/her pronouns. I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD
candidate in biomedical science.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laurel offered her hand across the table, and Marigold took it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Laurel Windflower. She/her as well.&amp;rdquo; She didn’t mention the incomplete MA she&amp;rsquo;d been postponing, for one reason or another, for the past two years. &amp;ldquo;So, is your PhD in monster biology or something?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That was delightful. It&amp;rsquo;s a cozy urban fantasy, light and cute with just enough touches of something bigger and more dangerous out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth a read. And at a novella length 100 pages, it&amp;rsquo;s worth trying just to see if you like it. And if you do, there are a handful more to dig deeper! (I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>