<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rosamund Hodge on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/rosamund-hodge/</link><description>Recent content in Rosamund Hodge on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/rosamund-hodge/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bright Smoke, Cold Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/29/bright-smoke-cold-fire/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/29/bright-smoke-cold-fire/</guid><description>&lt;p>Among the three Hodge books I&amp;rsquo;ve read thus far (&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="15839984" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15839984.cruel-beauty">Cruel Beauty&lt;/a> and &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="21570318" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21570318.crimson-bound">Crimson Bound&lt;/a>), Bright Smoke, Cold Fire is by far my favorite, which is interesting, given that it has the lowest rating on Goodreads by almost half a point. It&amp;rsquo;s actually the lowest rated full I&amp;rsquo;ve finished.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In essence, Bright Smoke, Cold Fire takes place in the single remaining city after a zombie apocalypse. The city is protected by a giant protective bubble powered by human sacrifice. There are a few different kinds of magic systems floating about, one dealing with magic words left over from the language of the gods, the other (powering the bubble) based on blood magic. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s the same fascinating world building that Hodge put into both Cruel Beauty and Crimson Bound, although in this case, it feels rather more fleshed out (pun intended).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crimson Bound</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/12/crimson-bound/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/12/crimson-bound/</guid><description>&lt;p>Originally thought that this was supposed to be a retelling of Little Red Riding Hood, as &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="15839984" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15839984.cruel-beauty">Cruel Beauty&lt;/a> was for Beauty and the Beast. I saw it a lot more in the other and probably would have liked this a bit more had I not thought that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a lot of beautiful visuals and fairly interesting worldbuilders. Unfortunately, it feels like it should be more interesting than it actually is. There are some interesting concepts in there (bloodbound made by murder, etc), but they&amp;rsquo;re barely fleshed out. On top of that, apparently the world was ending and&amp;hellip; no one seemed to care? Except some people knew all along and pass along magic swords to save the day? Meh.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cruel Beauty</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/05/cruel-beauty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/05/cruel-beauty/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cruel Beauty is a re-skinning of Beauty and the Beast, told in a weird, fantastic world with strong influences from ancient Greece and Rome. Among the retold fairy tales that I&amp;rsquo;ve read, it&amp;rsquo;s among the best of them and manages to feel reasonably like the inspiration story while adding a good number of weird twists and beautiful imagery on top of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, the strongest part of the story for me was the world. It seems that a chunk of reality was torn from what could have been our world and set aside, with a sky that looks like parchment and demons that literally roam the land, making deals. There&amp;rsquo;s a castle chock full of magical rooms and artifacts that are all sorts of cool, even when they&amp;rsquo;re just used as background for a single scene. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of world I would absolutely love to explore in a more freeform style (virtual reality?) someday and the author does an excellent job of bringing it all to life and making it feel real.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>