<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jim Butcher on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/jim-butcher/</link><description>Recent content in Jim Butcher on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/jim-butcher/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Battle Ground</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/10/07/battle-ground/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/10/07/battle-ground/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The real battle for your own soul isn&amp;rsquo;t about falling from a great height;
it&amp;rsquo;s about descending, or not, one choice at a time.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That right there. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/10/07/battle-ground/">Battle Ground&lt;/a> That is the second half of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/10/07/peace-talks/">Peace Talks&lt;/a>. They should have been one book, and are best read back to back like that. But so it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Peace Talks</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/10/07/peace-talks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/10/07/peace-talks/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Home, like love, hate, war, and peace, is one of those words that is so
important that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need more than one syllable. Home is part of the
fabric of who humans are. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you&amp;rsquo;re a vampire or a wizard or
a secretary or a schoolteacher; you have to have a home, even if only in
principle-there has to be a zero point from which you can make comparisons
to everything else. Home tends to be it.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Holy crap.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wild Card (Graphic Novel)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/28/wild-card-graphic-novel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/28/wild-card-graphic-novel/</guid><description>&lt;p>So, I did totally miss this one&amp;hellip; But hey, the comics tend to be somewhat less necessary to read in order than the novels, especially with the novels being well ahead in timeline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, this story is a bit crazy. It introduces &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Puck_%5c%28folklore%5c%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Puck&lt;/a> , a character I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed the idea of. The English version of Coyote or Loki essentially. And apparently&amp;hellip; he&amp;rsquo;s a badass wild Fae that can go toe to toe with Lea (under certain conditions)? Sure!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dog Men (Graphic Novel)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/23/dog-men-graphic-novel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/23/dog-men-graphic-novel/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There are two wolves within every man&amp;hellip; One represents our greatest capacities&amp;ndash;compassion, courage, reason. The other embodies our base emotions &amp;ndash;pride, anger, hatred. At every moment of every day, they battle for control of us. But it is we who determine which one win.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just depends on which one you feed&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Down Town (Graphic Novel)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/19/down-town-graphic-novel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/19/down-town-graphic-novel/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s more Dresden at least!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t great, but we get a lot more of Molly in her apprentice level, which I feel was somewhat skipped over in the novels.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>War Cry (Graphic Novel)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/16/war-cry-graphic-novel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/16/war-cry-graphic-novel/</guid><description>&lt;p>War Cry! The second new Dresden comic!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It almost feels like a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bottle_episode" target="_blank" rel="noopener">bottle episode&lt;/a> in that it&amp;rsquo;s very limited in scope, but the action and explosions certainly would have cost a fair penny. There&amp;rsquo;s something underhanded going on, an attack by hundreds of red court vampires, and Dresden coming into his role as a mentor warden. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ghoul Goblin (Graphic Novel)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/13/ghoul-goblin-graphic-novel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/13/ghoul-goblin-graphic-novel/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/03/welcome-to-the-jungle-graphic-novel/">Welcome to the Jungle&lt;/a> was new, but an introduction. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/08/storm-front-graphic-novel/">Storm Front (Graphic Novel)&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/10/fool-moon-graphic-novel/">Fool Moon (Graphic Novel)&lt;/a> are adaptations of previous works I&amp;rsquo;ve read a number of times. But &lt;em>Ghoul Goblin&lt;/em>? NEW CONTENT!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing introductions over and over again. I know the books do the same, but for some reason it feels different in a comic. Perhaps because I&amp;rsquo;m reading them relatively quickly?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fool Moon (Graphic Novel)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/10/fool-moon-graphic-novel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/10/fool-moon-graphic-novel/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/19/fool-moon/">Fool Moon&lt;/a>, but as a comic book/graphic novel!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s one of two novel adaptations (Storm Front being the other) and I think the weaker of the two. Still a lot of fun though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storm Front (Graphic Novel)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/08/storm-front-graphic-novel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/08/storm-front-graphic-novel/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s two parts but I think that&amp;rsquo;s totally just a binding/printing thing. The story isn&amp;rsquo;t really broken up any differently than the novel already was or than the individual issues that make it up have to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All together: it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/16/storm-front/">Storm Front&lt;/a> as a comic book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome to the Jungle (Graphic Novel)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/03/welcome-to-the-jungle-graphic-novel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/03/welcome-to-the-jungle-graphic-novel/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/jungle-01-they-call-me.png" alt="Jungle-01-They-call-me">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s certainly a bit different&amp;ndash;there&amp;rsquo;s less room to breath and less freedom to imagine the characters as you want, but on the other hand, it&amp;rsquo;s more Dresden Files!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Lord's Fury</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/08/first-lords-fury/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/08/first-lords-fury/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Life, Tavi reflected, seldom makes a gift of what one expects or plans for.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s darkest before the dawn.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Princeps' Fury</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/30/princeps-fury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/30/princeps-fury/</guid><description>&lt;p>Compared to the previous books, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/30/princeps-fury/">Princeps’ Fury&lt;/a> changes focus somewhat. For the first time, we&amp;rsquo;re not actually focussed solely around Alera and the domain and battles of the humans. Instead, we&amp;rsquo;re going to Canim where unfortunately &lt;span class="spoiler">the Vord have taken over nearly anything&lt;/span>
 . It&amp;rsquo;s a neat change of focus and a crazy escalation of stakes&amp;ndash;although admittedly not unexpected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The parts with Tavi are pretty wonderful. He&amp;rsquo;s really likeable and does a great job of overcoming problems by outthinking them, even now that he&amp;rsquo;s actually coming into powers of his own. It&amp;rsquo;s almost unbelievable just how good he is at planning, but he&amp;rsquo;s the protagonist. It works.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain's Fury</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/23/captains-fury/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/23/captains-fury/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/23/captains-fury/">Captain’s Fury&lt;/a> takes the &amp;lsquo;Alera at war&amp;rsquo; feel of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/14/cursors-fury/">Cursor’s Fury&lt;/a> and really turns it up a notch. Tavi has done the impossible and fought a war against the Canim for two years now, holding them in place and building the trust of his followers to impressive levels. But now a new foe is coming for him&amp;ndash;a foe far more terrifying than the Canim, or even than the Vord (who are much less interesting when you don&amp;rsquo;t see them on screen for a book or two)&amp;hellip; politicians.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, Tavi remains among the best part of these books:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cursor's Fury</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/14/cursors-fury/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/14/cursors-fury/</guid><description>&lt;p>Were &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/29/furies-of-calderon/">Furies of Calderon&lt;/a> introduced us to the world and the Marat and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/03/academs-fury/">Academ’s Fury&lt;/a> gave us a taste of the politics of Alera along with the threat of the Vord, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/14/cursors-fury/">Cursor’s Fury&lt;/a> where we really shift to the military focus that defines the rest of the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A civil war in Alera plus an invasion by the Canim? Oy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Academ's Fury</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/03/academs-fury/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/03/academs-fury/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/29/furies-of-calderon/">Furies of Calderon&lt;/a> felt like fairly standard high fantasy. It had a Roman theme rather than the more common (in what I&amp;rsquo;ve read) Medieval European and elemental spirits for a magical theme, but it still had a fairly standard &amp;lsquo;farmboy saves the day through strength of character and good triumphs over evil&amp;rsquo; sort of theme. There were hints of a wider world, but for the most part, it was a fairly self contained book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/03/academs-fury/">Academ’s Fury&lt;/a> takes all that and really starts to dig into the world building and expand the scope of the conflict. Where we only had the hints of &amp;lsquo;weird&amp;rsquo; in the Wax Forest, now we have a fully developed and quite frankly terrifying threat in the Vord. While it&amp;rsquo;s not the most original concept (the Borg among many many others), it&amp;rsquo;s well done here. You really get a sense for how alien the Vord are and&amp;ndash;worst&amp;ndash;how smart. They learn and they won&amp;rsquo;t stop until everything is Vord. Also, the Canim. Warrior wolf people. Pretty cool.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Furies of Calderon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/29/furies-of-calderon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/29/furies-of-calderon/</guid><description>&lt;p>Apparently I last read Furies of Calderon before I started writing reviews. That was actually the second time I read it&amp;ndash;the first time I didn&amp;rsquo;t even finish the book, putting it down. It&amp;rsquo;s something of a slow book and a bit strange. But the second time and especially once I got into the sequels, I loved it, it&amp;rsquo;s among my favorite series. This time around, I listened to it and it&amp;rsquo;s even better as an audiobook (since it just keeps right on going through the boring parts).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, the story is that Codex Alera arose out of a bar bet. Take some random topic and write a story about it. In this case, the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Legio_IX_Hispana" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lost Roman Legion&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pokemon" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Pokemon&lt;/a>. Sounds crazy, but it kind of works. From the Roman half, you end up with essentially a Roman empire with holds and legions that have fought to tear out a land for themselves from a variety of enemies all around. From the Pokemon, you have Furies, elemental spirits of the land, sea, and air which all of the Alerans[^Tavi] have some ability to control for various tasks: the strength of an earth fury, healing with water furies, flying with air. Pretty cool.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin Game</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/04/16/skin-game/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/04/16/skin-game/</guid><description>&lt;p>And then there was a heist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book 15, so the Denarians are due. In they came, and not in a way that anyone would have expected. Turns out, Mab owes Nicodemus a favor. She wants Dresden to carry it out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cold Days</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/04/11/cold-days/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/04/11/cold-days/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dresden is remarkably good at weaseling his way out of deals he should never have gotten himself into in the first place. This time around though? His number is up. He has to work for Mab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mab first job for her new Knight? Kill Maeve.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ghost Story</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/04/09/ghost-story/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/04/09/ghost-story/</guid><description>&lt;p>And then he was dead. &lt;span class="spoiler">Ish.&lt;/span>
 .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course the ending of Changes couldn&amp;rsquo;t be the end of Dresden. And after Ghost Story, I think I can forgive Butcher for that cliff hanger. Mostly. :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Changes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/04/06/changes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/04/06/changes/</guid><description>&lt;p>** spoiler alert ** Damn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first chapter of Changes, Dresden learns he has a daughter. Throughout the book, he loses everything (his car, his office, his home&amp;hellip;). He makes deals he promised he would never make.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turn Coat</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/29/turn-coat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/29/turn-coat/</guid><description>&lt;p>Morgan shows up on Dresden&amp;rsquo;s doorstep and asks for his help. Things degrade pretty much exactly as you might expect from there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We do get a third part in the trifeta of styles from the previous two books: mystery to action to political thriller. There is still plenty of the first two, but now we&amp;rsquo;re dealing primarily with the fallout of a politically motivated murder.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Small Favor</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/27/small-favor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/27/small-favor/</guid><description>&lt;p>Small Favor combines my favorite parts of the Dresden Files: the Denarians and Knights of the Cross, Marcone, and the Fae in varying degrees. On top of that, where White Night tended towards mystery, Small Favor is straight up actions. The story hits the ground running and never really stops, right through several big set piece battles and one of the bigger finales we&amp;rsquo;ve seen (albeit not quite up to the level of Sue&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, we get another of Butcher&amp;rsquo;s lovely twists which just drop the bottom out of a story. You think you know what&amp;rsquo;s going on&amp;hellip; turns out you&amp;rsquo;ve missed the same huge clue that Dresden has. I&amp;rsquo;m always impressed with those.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>White Night</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/23/white-night/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/23/white-night/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think this is one of the first of the Dresden Files books that really feels like a more traditional mystery. (Or at least my idea thereof; I don&amp;rsquo;t read much traditional mystery). Mysterious shadowy figures and murders abound and throughout it&amp;rsquo;s unclear exactly who/what is responsible. There are a few clues for the reader that Dresden otherwise misses, but for the most part, we learn about happenings as they happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One really cool scene: Dresden takes advantage of the fact that you can draw energy from the surrounding environment in order to power a spell. He proceed to shoot off a pillar of fire 2-3 feet wide and 20 stories high into the night sky. Can you imagine being a mortal living in Chicago and seeing that? The best part: He didn&amp;rsquo;t even need the fire. He just needed to freeze a chunk of Lake Michigan. Love it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Proven Guilty</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/16/proven-guilty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/16/proven-guilty/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another very solid entry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, there&amp;rsquo;s black magic afoot. Fear monsters from the Nevernever are attacking a horror movie convention and it&amp;rsquo;s up to Dresden to find out why. Add to that complications with Michael&amp;rsquo;s now almost adult daughter Molly. The interactions between Molly and Dresden are weird and uncomfortable at times, but on the other hand they seem for the most part disturbingly realistic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dead Beat</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/13/dead-beat/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/13/dead-beat/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ooh fun. A big bad necromancer (in this world, the driving force behind World War I) got taken out by the White Council decades ago. Unfortunately, he left behind a small pile of minions, who of course came calling on Dresden&amp;rsquo;s home turf.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is right in the running with Death Masks for my favorite thus far. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason it has the highest Goodreads ranking among the first ten Dresden books&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blood Rites</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/05/blood-rites/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/05/blood-rites/</guid><description>&lt;p>I still like Death Masks better, but Blood Rites is still quite good. We&amp;rsquo;re back to big magical rituals (a five book cycle?) but also a bit of goodly hint of vampiric mayhem (the Black and White Courts this time around).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, since it&amp;rsquo;s the White Court, the entire plot this time has to revolve around a ritual curse targetting an adult film director. All righty then.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death Masks</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/02/death-masks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/03/02/death-masks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dang. New favorite Dresden File. More of Michael and the introduction of my favorite baddies in the Dresdenverse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What really makes Death Masks shine is the the characters:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Summer Knight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/26/summer-knight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/26/summer-knight/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sorcerers, werewolves, vampires&amp;hellip; And now the Fae. We already had hints of it from the previous books, particularly in the guise of Lea&amp;ndash;Harry&amp;rsquo;s literal Fairy Godmother.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a very cool bit of worldbuilding. The Fae aren&amp;rsquo;t particularly uncommon in Urban Fantasy and I really like the Dresden Files version thereof. They&amp;rsquo;ve even gotten to the point where they act as background knowledge when reading other series. If something isn&amp;rsquo;t mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;ll fall back to the Dresden Files as ground truth. It&amp;rsquo;s just that solid.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Grave Peril</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/22/grave-peril/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/22/grave-peril/</guid><description>&lt;p>First there was a sorcerer. Then werewolves. Next up, ghosts and vampires. The Dresden Files certainly get around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I already said it last time, but it applies again: Grave Peril is a much better book (in my opinion) than Fool Moon, which in turn is much better than Storm Front. I&amp;rsquo;m sure this won&amp;rsquo;t be the same pattern forever, but it&amp;rsquo;s impressive enough to carry through three books.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fool Moon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/19/fool-moon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/19/fool-moon/</guid><description>&lt;p>Two down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with werewolves. And not just stereotypical werewolves, but a small pile of different forms. People that turn into wolves, people turned into wolves against their will, magic item based wolves&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s a lot. It&amp;rsquo;s getting close (if not outright blowing past) the &amp;lsquo;kitchen sink&amp;rsquo; world building that&amp;rsquo;s rather common in urban fantasy. On the other hand, it&amp;rsquo;s neat to see a few different takes on werewolves.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Storm Front</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/16/storm-front/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/16/storm-front/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it begins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve probably read this series roughly half a dozen times. This time I&amp;rsquo;m listening to them on audiobook. It certainly goes by quick.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Aeronaut's Windlass</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/09/the-aeronauts-windlass/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/02/09/the-aeronauts-windlass/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well. He did it again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love the Dresden Files. I love Codex Alera. I love The Aeronaut&amp;rsquo;s Windlass.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>