<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rin Chupeco on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/rin-chupeco/</link><description>Recent content in Rin Chupeco on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/rin-chupeco/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Never Tilting World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/07/the-never-tilting-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/07/the-never-tilting-world/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of world building. Start with elemental magic, nothing &lt;em&gt;super&lt;/em&gt; new there (although acid is always a fun one). Add in an ancient prophecy and twins where only one can rule. Still not that unusual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then defy the prophecy and &lt;em&gt;literally stop the world spinning&lt;/em&gt;, leaving one side a desert scorched by a never ending noon, the other frozen in perpetual night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re chasing a dying sea under an endless sun that kills us with a thousand little cuts every day. There’ll be nothing left soon. Nothing but sand and bone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool worldbuilding, especially for a fantasy world (it&amp;rsquo;s something you see slightly more in sci-fi).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now on top of that, you have a ruler in each world, each with a daughter. Well, you can guess what probably happened and who these two are (remember those twins I mentioned?), but none of them know that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you get a fascinating ride as each realized just how screwed up their own corner of the world is, falls in love (there is more than a touch of romance in this book)&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the choice is between me risking my life and losing you, I’d choose the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and sets off on a journey to set things right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the dead find words, the goddess and the Devoted son will meet atop a fish not a fish, on a sea not a sea. It is she who travels to the endless Abyss, and it is he who guides her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quite enjoyed this book. It takes a bit of getting into and the leads are&amp;hellip; more than a touch Young Adult/&amp;lsquo;chosen one&amp;rsquo;ish, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a fun read/listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>