<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Night Angel on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/night-angel/</link><description>Recent content in Night Angel on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/night-angel/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beyond the Shadows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/12/beyond-the-shadows/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/12/beyond-the-shadows/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s over. It&amp;rsquo;s a solid series with a lot of interesting world building that kept me turning pages right up to the end and managed to wrap up a surprising number of plotlines up into a huge final battle. If that&amp;rsquo;s all you&amp;rsquo;re looking for and you&amp;rsquo;ve already read the first two books, go ahead and read this one. It&amp;rsquo;s the first two books, only bigger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I still don&amp;rsquo;t like Kylar. He&amp;rsquo;s too powerful almost without ill effect (other than the cost that finally gets revealed for coming back from the dead; that was a well deserved punch to the gut).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Shadow's Edge</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/23/shadows-edge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/23/shadows-edge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Taken as a whole, Shadow&amp;rsquo;s Edge takes everything (the good and the bad) of the first Night Angel book and cranks it up even further. On the plus side, the good becomes even better. It was hard to put this book down. On the down side, a lot of the first part of the book where Kylar tries to run from his powers and live a normal life is honestly fairly boring. Luckily it picks back up and really goes crazy by the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are storylines all over the place. The all manage to tie together more or less, so I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly mind, but there are a few that I feel probably could have been cut to make a tighter story. Kylar&amp;rsquo;s story is interesting, obviously enough, as is that of Vi and the Godking. Sister Ariel&amp;rsquo;s story I feel could actually carry a story of its own and directly relates to the others. Logan&amp;rsquo;s time in the Hole is fascinating, but seemed to drag on forever (which I guess could have been intentional). But the storyline about the prostitute&amp;rsquo;s rebellion? All that about the Ubersword of DESTINY? I trust that eventually they&amp;rsquo;ll pay off. But within the context of this single story, the feel weird.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Way of Shadows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/05/18/the-way-of-shadows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/05/18/the-way-of-shadows/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Well. That was a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, you&amp;rsquo;re sort of tossed into the world and it takes rather a while to really figure out what was going on. For that matter, I still have a handful of questions on exactly how this world works, although I guess that&amp;rsquo;s what sequels are for.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>