<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2017 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2017/</link><description>Recent content in 2017 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2017/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Orville: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/30/the-orville-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/30/the-orville-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a Star Trek parody that&amp;rsquo;s more Star Trek than most (new) Star Trek. It&amp;rsquo;s got a really rough start while it&amp;rsquo;s still trying to lean into the humor, but as the show goes on and it gets more serious, it&amp;rsquo;s so much better. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to what they can do in season 2!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="reviews-by-episode">Reviews by Episode&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="1-old-wounds">1. &lt;em>Old Wounds&lt;/em>&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The truth is, you’re nobody’s first choice for this job. We have 3000 ships to staff and we need captains.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Wow. That was an awkward meet and greet. Supposed to be funny and an introduction to the characters I suppose, but… who would possibly think that’s okay?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arts and crafts meets tardigrade redwood. Hilarious.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Men Tell No Tales</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/07/pirates-of-the-caribbean-dead-men-tell-no-tales/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/07/pirates-of-the-caribbean-dead-men-tell-no-tales/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the smash hit of the first three and the downer that was &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/03/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides/">On Stranger Tides&lt;/a>, I was cautiously hopeful that they could pull something off with Dead Men Tell No Tales. And&amp;hellip; they did? Sort of?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VIII - The Last Jedi</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/05/star-wars-episode-viii-the-last-jedi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/05/star-wars-episode-viii-the-last-jedi/</guid><description>More Star Wars! I remember being&amp;hellip; somewhat disappointed. Tonally, they got away from the nostalgia of the Force Awakens. There are still some absolutely beautiful/powerful moments (the final battles over the salt flats or whatever those were were pretty cool), but not quite as strong as it was before. And there are all sorts of things that just feel &amp;rsquo;less magical&amp;rsquo; and more movie driven than anything.
This time around, I liked it a lot more.</description></item><item><title>The Star</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/03/the-star/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/03/the-star/</guid><description>Not really sure what to say about this one. It&amp;rsquo;s the Nativity story told from the point of view of various animals, voiced by a few famous people (Kris Kristofferson as &amp;lsquo;Old Donkey&amp;rsquo; was pretty awesome&amp;hellip; also Oprah apparently?).
It&amp;rsquo;s a cute enough story and the kids enjoy it. The songs are a nice touch.
I expect this will be fairly low on my list for the year, mostly since I&amp;rsquo;m&amp;hellip; not really the target audience.</description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Homecoming</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</guid><description>That is a truly delightful Spider-Man movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird seeing him introduced after the events of Captain America: Civil War) and completely skipping how he became Spider-Man in the first place&amp;hellip; but it works. I really like the entire plot, dealing with the fallout of the Avengers / super-hero activity and how normal people try to live their lives around it&amp;ndash;and what happens when the powers that be step in and take that away from them.</description></item><item><title>The Greatest Showman</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/21/the-greatest-showman/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/21/the-greatest-showman/</guid><description>&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RW61RQZojMQ" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Now that&amp;rsquo;s music. I can only imagine hearing that on a theater scale sound system. Although my home sound bar certainly tried it&amp;rsquo;s best&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, I know I&amp;rsquo;m behind the times. Better late than never?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid movie that tries to make some big points about everyone having value / sticking it to the people that hate you because you&amp;rsquo;re different and&amp;hellip; mostly hitting the mark? It gets even more complicated when you read up on Barnum&amp;rsquo;s actual history. Very much a serial &amp;lsquo;get rich quick&amp;rsquo;er with some questionable ethics, but there&amp;rsquo;s good parts there as well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor: Ragnarok</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</guid><description>Ooh, that poster. le kiss
Thor was &amp;hellip; fine, a weirdly downscale introduction to a kind of strange character early in the MCU. Thor: The Dark World went the other way, being too bigt and ambitious and suffering somewhat for it. So going into Thor: Ragnarok, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what we were going to get.
An absolute gem of an 80s sci fi/fantasy action superhero comedy that just works. Right from the very intro, you know it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a different sort of movie.</description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</guid><description>After the surprisingly awesome Guardians of the Galaxy, it was really a question of: could they do it again? The answer, a resounding&amp;hellip; sort of?
Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 has some pretty awesome moments. The opening battle in particular is spectacular (I love the contrast of dancing Baby Groot against a big smack down in the background). And we get all piles of additional humor based around Drax&amp;rsquo;s literalness, Rocket being a racoon, &amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>