<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 Book Bingo on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2022-book-bingo/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 Book Bingo on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2022-book-bingo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Deadly Education</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/</guid><description>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s a joy of a book. Saying which I suppose&amp;ndash;after you&amp;rsquo;ve read it&amp;ndash;feels a bit ironic.
It&amp;rsquo;s one part magic school, with your more or less typical teenage protagonists doing more or less typical teenage thing. In my opinion, Novik does this very well. Main character El (short for Galadriel) is so wonderfully snarky and done with it teenage girl that I could practically feel her angst coming off the page&amp;ndash;and it&amp;rsquo;s all the better, because she really does have a good reason for it.</description></item><item><title>Paradise Lost</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/12/paradise-lost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/12/paradise-lost/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="15997" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/15997.paradise-lost">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/paradise-lost.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s an odd sort of book. It&amp;rsquo;s basically the story of the Fall of Satan plus Genesis, wrapped up in some crazy flowery poetry, writ long. It&amp;rsquo;s been on my &amp;lsquo;why not&amp;rsquo; list for a long time and hearing more about it in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/">Daemon Voices&lt;/a> bumped it up a fair bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am I glad to have read it? Yes. Is it a good book? Maybe. The poetry is absolutely beautiful in some places, but the story is one you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard before, if you&amp;rsquo;ve any sort of judeo-christian upbringing, although it does embelish in spots. And oy does it get long. It thought there were 7 books for some reason, so when I finished number 7 and we&amp;rsquo;re barely into Genesis&amp;hellip;, well, I knew I was wrong about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, the first few books with the fall of Satan are very cool and I&amp;rsquo;d say worth reading. The rest, hit or miss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Closed and Common Orbit</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/10/a-closed-and-common-orbit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/10/a-closed-and-common-orbit/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="29475447" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29475447.a-closed-and-common-orbit">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-closed-and-common-orbit.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Life is terrifying. None of us have a rule book. None of us know what we&amp;rsquo;re doing here. So, the easiest way to stare reality in the face and not utterly lose your shit is to believe that you have control over it. If you believe you have control, then you believe you&amp;rsquo;re at the top. And if you&amp;rsquo;re at the top, then people who aren&amp;rsquo;t like you&amp;hellip; well, they&amp;rsquo;ve got to be somewhere lower, right? Every species does this. Does it again and again and again. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if they do it to themselves, or another species, or someone they created.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh. Wow. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/">The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet&lt;/a> felt like lightning in a bottle. Something amazing&amp;ndash;a look at the life in a long haul spaceship full of strange and wonderful characters&amp;ndash;that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how it could possibly be continued.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out&amp;hellip; just like this. This is a very very good sequel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, A Closed and Common Orbit was a bit of a surprise. We only barely get any of the characters we know and love from the first book. There are a few hints of and references to them, but for the most part, we instead focus on Lovey/Sidra* and Pepper, learning once again how two very strange and different sorts of people can grow into a family. The same general idea, approached a totally different way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All Systems Red</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="32758901" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32758901.all-systems-red">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/all-systems-red.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Okay, I get what all the hype is about. Take a heavily armed cyborg/clone, designed entirely as muscle to defend the more squishy &amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; humans, have it turn off the software constraining it from killing everyone, add in a wonderfully snarky sense of humor&amp;hellip; and see what happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I COULD HAVE BECOME a mass murderer after I hacked my governor module, but then I realized I could access the combined feed of entertainment channels carried on the company satellites. It had been well over 35,000 hours or so since then, with still not much murdering, but probably, I don’t know, a little under 35,000 hours of movies, serials, books, plays, and music consumed. As a heartless killing machine, I was a terrible failure.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>