<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 Book Bingo on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2022-book-bingo/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 Book Bingo on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2022-book-bingo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Vela</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/22/the-vela/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/22/the-vela/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Eratos wasn’t the only dying world, just the one dying fastest—the tiny colony on Samos had been gone for a decade, and after Eratos would be Hypatia and then Gan-De, and maybe the Inner Ring would finally come to care when it was their turn to freeze to death as the sun collapsed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A leisurely extinction. One that allowed everyone to push any inconvenience to another place or another generation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Vela is part of a fascinating sort of new/old model: serialized fiction. In this case &lt;a href="https://www.realm.fm/">Realm.fm (formerly Serial Box)&lt;/a> is putting out piles of audio fiction by a number of well known authors chapter by chapter. And yet&amp;hellip; somehow I read the ebook version from the library. I really should check out the audio versions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, The worldbuilding (as in the above quote) in the Vela is fascinating. A nearish-future tech sci-fi universe where humanity has managed to extract enough resources from the local star to freeze out the outer planets, wrecking all manner of havoc among the people that live out there. There&amp;rsquo;s all manner of classism, racism, and other racisms to digest&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Set against the backdrop of a missing starship (the Vela) and the two unlikely companions (Asala and Niko) who are sent to go find it. I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see Becky Chambers as one of the authors here, I really love how she does &amp;lsquo;people stories&amp;rsquo;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet read the other three authors, but they&amp;rsquo;re all on my to-read shelf already and higher up now. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The relationship between Asala (hard bitten mercenary/sniper) and Nike (child of the president; hacker) throughout the stories is really the shining jewel of the series. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the slight (IMO) variations between how the different authors see and write them, but it&amp;rsquo;s still well worth reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well well worth a read. Or a listen. And Season 2 is on Realm? Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People spoke about the death of planets as if the rock itself would shatter, but the truth was never so dramatic. The entire sphere wasn&amp;rsquo;t in danger of ceasing to exist. All that mattered was the inner goings-on of that tiny strip of gauze, that onion skin of atmosphere clinging to the rocky surface like morning dew. The narrowest of margins on which everything depended.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Foundryside</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/06/foundryside/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/06/foundryside/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Every innovation—technological, sociological, or otherwise—begins as a crusade, organizes itself into a practical business, and then, over time, degrades into common exploitation. This is simply the life cycle of how human ingenuity manifests in the material world. What goes forgotten, though, is that those who partake in this system undergo a similar transformation: people begin as comrades and fellow citizens, then become labor resources and assets, and then, as their utility shifts or degrades, transmute into liabilities, and thus must be appropriately managed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was delightful. It&amp;rsquo;s been on my list for a while, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d give it a chance and I&amp;rsquo;m so very glad I did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I highly recommend the book, with the disclaimer that there are some dark scenes, bits (sorry) of body horror, and quite a lot of (made up fantasy) swearing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nettle &amp; Bone</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/01/nettle-bone/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The trees were full of crows and the woods were full of madmen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pit was full of bones and her hands were full of wires.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was a delightful surprise&amp;ndash;in a dark fairytale kind of way. I&amp;rsquo;ve not read any T. Kingfisher before, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have to remedy that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, Nettle &amp;amp; Bone takes the idea of a fairy godmother&amp;rsquo;s blessing at birth and twists it, bringing in the politics of unequal neighboring kingdoms; fae, their bargains, and all the twists that go with that; and a touch of demons and death magic. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun world to build a foundation on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful cast of characters. I love seeing Marra, third-born princess, sent to a religious order (sort of), and originally on her own to solve the world&amp;rsquo;s problems. Only for her to collect a motley band of strange and wonderful allies, each in their own ways: a witch, a reluctant godmother, a night, a dog made of bones, and a demon made of chicken. (It makes sense). They&amp;rsquo;re all great and I love the found family dynamic as they&amp;rsquo;re off to save the world&amp;ndash;or at least some tiny corner of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As if that weren&amp;rsquo;t enough, I love the prose and wordplay. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>written&lt;/em> like a fairytale writ large. It just fits the story so well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, One of the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year and more than worth giving it a try.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Declaration of the Rights of Magicians</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/23/a-declaration-of-the-rights-of-magicians/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/23/a-declaration-of-the-rights-of-magicians/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s fascinating bit of historical fantasy. Take revolutionary era France, introduce various relatively &amp;lsquo;common&amp;rsquo; classes of magicians (fire, water, weather, mind control, etc), and see what shakes out. It&amp;rsquo;s an era of history I&amp;rsquo;m probably not as familiar with as I should be and, while with the introduction of magic things are slightly different, the events actually shake out more or less the same way (as I looked up later). It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to read about people such as William Pitt and Maximilien Robespierre &amp;hellip; and then read about them again in real history.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Starless Sea</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/05/the-starless-sea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/05/the-starless-sea/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Far beneath the surface of the earth, hidden from the sun and the moon, upon the shores of the Starless Sea, there is a labyrinthine collection of tunnels and rooms filled with stories. Stories written in books and sealed in jars and painted on walls. Odes inscribed onto skin and pressed into rose petals. Tales laid in tiles upon the floors, bits of plot worn away by passing feet. Legends carved in crystal and hung from chandeliers. Stories catalogued and cared for and revered. Old stories preserved while new stories spring up around them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>The Starless Sea&lt;/em> is an unfortunate sort of book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, the prose is beautiful. There are some really wonderful passages and smaller stories that really sing on the pages. On top of that, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of delightful visuals described from the book. Often times, I don&amp;rsquo;t really picture what&amp;rsquo;s going on in a lot of stories, I more&amp;hellip; absorb them. But this, this really needs and thrives on the visuals. Especially leaning on the sights and smells of books and libraries and doors, it&amp;rsquo;s the sort of book a physical book lover (not a lover of stories, one of the actual physical books themselves) could really get into.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand&amp;hellip; even after reading through the entire book, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what in the world was going on / what the point of anything was. A book doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to have a point&amp;ndash;I do love a good slice of life story&amp;ndash;but this felt like it was trying to go for something. But with the absolute pile of characters (major, minor, versions of the same) jumping around all the time, it was hard to figure anything out. The prose and settings almost do enough to overcome that&amp;hellip; but not quite enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s a book that was almost really really good&amp;hellip; but didn&amp;rsquo;t quite stick the landing for me. It&amp;rsquo;s probably worth a try, but if you bounce off the first few chapters, consider that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really change that much before the end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bone Ships</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/03/the-bone-ships/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/03/the-bone-ships/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating bit of worldbuilding. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a world (or at least story) dominated by naval superiority&amp;ndash;brought about by ships built on the literal bones of sea dragons. And what&amp;rsquo;s more, the sea dragons appear to have been hunted to extinction, making the warships all the more rare and valuable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a very cool root for the story and Barker only takes it from there with unique twists on vocab and word choice, a few other interesting bits of magic, and more naval everything than you can shake some paint at.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do quite enjoy the characters as well. Setting the story around a prison ship? Not that unusual, but I really do love how much Barker makes the reader care for the people on it&amp;ndash;and to see them grow together as a grow. Lucky Maes is of course awesome as well&amp;ndash;and I do love the more alien birdman. Want to see what more is going on there for sure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a great book and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have read it. Onward to the sequels!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Out of the Blue</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/28/out-of-the-blue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/28/out-of-the-blue/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take part gay teenage lifeguard lover of rom-coms, just broken up with the Love Of His Life(tm), add a non-binary (because they all are) mermaid, sent on a month long &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rumspringa">Rumspringa&lt;/a> to the surface, make it into a love story (of course) with all the (teenage) relationship twists and turns that entails&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&amp;hellip; and you have &lt;em>Out of the Blue&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That &amp;hellip; is not at all the sort of book I normally find myself drawn to (I picked it up for the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2022-book-bingo/">2022 Book Bingo&lt;/a>), but you know&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s actually kind of sweet. And now that it&amp;rsquo;s over, I think I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have read it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Last Argument of Kings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/last-argument-of-kings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/last-argument-of-kings/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I have learned all kinds of things from my many mistakes. The one thing I never learn is to stop making them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And so it ends&amp;hellip; for now. Some of our old friends (more or less) are dead, some are broken, and some &amp;hellip; miraculously seem to have gotten everything they wanted in life. There are more surprises and political shifts than one knows how to deal with, a chunk more of world building around the First and Second Laws, and all manner of battles and death and destruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It remains fascinating what Abercrombie can do with characters. Glokta is a terrible person&amp;ndash;and he makes us root for him. Logen is a berserker in the truest sense&amp;ndash;and he makes us feel sorry for him. Jezal is excellent at failing upward&amp;ndash;and he makes us feel sorry for him. It&amp;rsquo;s all around amazing and the real strength of the series.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/14/the-first-fifteen-lives-of-harry-august/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/14/the-first-fifteen-lives-of-harry-august/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take the timeloop premise of Groundhog Day (et al), apply it to lifetimes, add a few neat worldbuilding twists, break things up with a cataclysm coming back through time&amp;hellip; and you have The First Fifteen Lives of Harry August. I love all of those things, so of course, I love this book as well. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Snake Falls to Earth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/06/a-snake-falls-to-earth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/06/a-snake-falls-to-earth/</guid><description>I do love stories that take mythology I don&amp;rsquo;t know as well and expands on it. In this case, the Lipan (Apache) people of what became the southwestern US down into Mexico. The idea of a world inhabited by animal people&amp;ndash;those that can shape shift between an animal and a human form&amp;ndash;that was once connected to Earth&amp;hellip; and now is not.
“And if they don’t?” I muttered. “Pfft. You’re a cottonmouth,” she snickered.</description></item><item><title>The Outside</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/21/the-outside/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/21/the-outside/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Well, it did what Outside usually did in stories. Showed up. Violated all the known laws of physics. Killed some people and drove the rest mad.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s certainly an interesting book. It&amp;rsquo;s one part autism as &amp;lsquo;different, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay and sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s a superpower and sometimes it sucks&amp;rsquo;, one part cosmic horror, and one part fascinating worldbuilding with technoreligion writ large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it didn&amp;rsquo;t quite feel finished to me. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of setup, but the ending drew somewhere between a true horror ending and something much &amp;lsquo;better&amp;rsquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s potential for a sequel there, but without it, it could have been better. Still an enjoyable enough read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unwritten, Vol. 1: Tommy Taylor and the Bogus Identity</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/the-unwritten-vol.-1-tommy-taylor-and-the-bogus-identity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/the-unwritten-vol.-1-tommy-taylor-and-the-bogus-identity/</guid><description>Well that’s a start. A world where Tommy Taylor is a modern hidden world fantasy even bigger than Harry Potter… until the author disappears, leaving behind disillusioned son Tom Taylor. There are more than hints of a darker truth behind the story, hidden worlds within hidden worlds. And a section at the end establishing how far back in time the truth goes.
So far, a fascinating sort of story. Well written and illustrated.</description></item><item><title>The Rage of Dragons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/the-rage-of-dragons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/the-rage-of-dragons/</guid><description>&lt;p>African-inspired Bronze-age fantasy with piles of caste based tensions, crazy sword battles, interesting magic, demons, dragons, and the distinct feeling that the &amp;lsquo;good guys&amp;rsquo; might not actually be that good after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m reminded a lot of Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game (which I love and need to re-read at some point) in that you have a surprisingly good soldier that manages to train harder and break the rules, breaking down society as he goes. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot darker though and Tau (said soldier) is motivated almost entirely by vengeance. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; a lot to read at times, but it fits. Man he&amp;rsquo;s stupid at times for it though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a great book and worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Deadly Education</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/</guid><description>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s a joy of a book. Saying which I suppose&amp;ndash;after you&amp;rsquo;ve read it&amp;ndash;feels a bit ironic.
It&amp;rsquo;s one part magic school, with your more or less typical teenage protagonists doing more or less typical teenage thing. In my opinion, Novik does this very well. Main character El (short for Galadriel) is so wonderfully snarky and done with it teenage girl that I could practically feel her angst coming off the page&amp;ndash;and it&amp;rsquo;s all the better, because she really does have a good reason for it.</description></item><item><title>Paradise Lost</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/12/paradise-lost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/12/paradise-lost/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s an odd sort of book. It&amp;rsquo;s basically the story of the Fall of Satan plus Genesis, wrapped up in some crazy flowery poetry, writ long. It&amp;rsquo;s been on my &amp;lsquo;why not&amp;rsquo; list for a long time and hearing more about it in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/">Daemon Voices&lt;/a> bumped it up a fair bit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Am I glad to have read it? Yes. Is it a good book? Maybe. The poetry is absolutely beautiful in some places, but the story is one you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard before, if you&amp;rsquo;ve any sort of judeo-christian upbringing, although it does embelish in spots. And oy does it get long. It thought there were 7 books for some reason, so when I finished number 7 and we&amp;rsquo;re barely into Genesis&amp;hellip;, well, I knew I was wrong about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, the first few books with the fall of Satan are very cool and I&amp;rsquo;d say worth reading. The rest, hit or miss.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Closed and Common Orbit</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/10/a-closed-and-common-orbit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/10/a-closed-and-common-orbit/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Life is terrifying. None of us have a rule book. None of us know what we&amp;rsquo;re doing here. So, the easiest way to stare reality in the face and not utterly lose your shit is to believe that you have control over it. If you believe you have control, then you believe you&amp;rsquo;re at the top. And if you&amp;rsquo;re at the top, then people who aren&amp;rsquo;t like you&amp;hellip; well, they&amp;rsquo;ve got to be somewhere lower, right? Every species does this. Does it again and again and again. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if they do it to themselves, or another species, or someone they created.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh. Wow. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/31/the-long-way-to-a-small-angry-planet/">The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet&lt;/a> felt like lightning in a bottle. Something amazing&amp;ndash;a look at the life in a long haul spaceship full of strange and wonderful characters&amp;ndash;that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how it could possibly be continued.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out&amp;hellip; just like this. This is a very very good sequel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, A Closed and Common Orbit was a bit of a surprise. We only barely get any of the characters we know and love from the first book. There are a few hints of and references to them, but for the most part, we instead focus on Lovey/Sidra* and Pepper, learning once again how two very strange and different sorts of people can grow into a family. The same general idea, approached a totally different way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All Systems Red</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, I get what all the hype is about. Take a heavily armed cyborg/clone, designed entirely as muscle to defend the more squishy &amp;rsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; humans, have it turn off the software constraining it from killing everyone, add in a wonderfully snarky sense of humor&amp;hellip; and see what happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I COULD HAVE BECOME a mass murderer after I hacked my governor module, but then I realized I could access the combined feed of entertainment channels carried on the company satellites. It had been well over 35,000 hours or so since then, with still not much murdering, but probably, I don’t know, a little under 35,000 hours of movies, serials, books, plays, and music consumed. As a heartless killing machine, I was a terrible failure.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>