<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guy Gavriel Kay on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/21/guy-gavriel-kay/</link><description>Recent content in Guy Gavriel Kay on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/21/guy-gavriel-kay/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Lions of Al-Rassan</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/21/the-lions-of-al-rassan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/21/the-lions-of-al-rassan/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It was a day that would be remembered all her life by Jehane bet Ishak, the physician, for reasons over and above those of her fellow citizens in that proud, notoriously rebellious town: she lost her urine flask in the afternoon, and a part of her heart forever before the moons had set. The flask, for reasons of family history, was not a trivial matter.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That is a dense book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You have a land in turmoil, warring city states, religious fervor, and the potential (perhaps a bit more than that) of a looming holy war.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Time and steady governance would bring Jad back into Al-Rassan, the king had declared, not burnings and destruction. Ibero wasn’t entirely sure how that meshed with holy doctrine, but he kept silent in the N
presence of his betters.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>You have a half dozen points of view, from a warrior poet to a general to a physician to a young boy and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I am increasingly unlikely to be best remembered, ibn Khairan decided ruefully, entering his home, for my poetry.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>All tangled together in one glorious tangle of a plot.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>