<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/alcatraz-vs.-the-evil-librarians/</link><description>Recent content in Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/alcatraz-vs.-the-evil-librarians/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/10/alcatraz-vs.-the-evil-librarians/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/10/alcatraz-vs.-the-evil-librarians/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve read pretty much all of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s works&amp;hellip; yet somehow I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to completely miss &lt;em>Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians&lt;/em>. Let&amp;rsquo;s remedy that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short version: Alcatraz reminds me a decent bit of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/27/the-frugal-wizards-handbook-for-surviving-medieval-england/">Frugal Wizard&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;which was actually my least favorite of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/year-of-sanderson/">Year of Sanderson&lt;/a> secret projects. But so far at least, I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying this series quite a bit more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Slightly longer version:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the Hushlands—those Librarian-controlled nations such as the United States, Canada, and England—this book will be published as a work of fantasy. Do not be fooled! This is no work of fiction, nor is my name really Brandon Sanderson. Both are guises to hide the book from Librarian agents. Unfortunately, even with these precautions, I suspect that the Librarians will discover the book and ban it. In that case, our Free Kingdom Agents will have to sneak into libraries and bookstores to put it on shelves. Count yourself lucky if you’ve found one of these secret copies.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a (non-&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-cosmere/">Cosmere&lt;/a>) YA novel &amp;lsquo;written by&amp;rsquo; our titular Alcatraz as he learns that the world he&amp;rsquo;s always known is full of lies (perpetrated by a cabal of EVIL LIBRARIANS) who are now, of course, out to capture and/or kill him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As one does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>impressively&lt;/em> meta, with almost constant comments from Alcatraz as narrator, talking about writers, writing, fiction, and just about anything else.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Authors also create lovable, friendly characters, then proceed to do terrible things to them, like throw them in unsightly librarian-controlled dungeons. This makes readers feel hurt and worried for the characters. The simple truth is that authors like making people squirm. If this weren&amp;rsquo;t the case, all novels would be filled completely with cute bunnies having birthday parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Which, from my perspective as both a reader and writer myself, is amusing, but feels like it might be a bit weirder / too meta for a much younger reader?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you don&amp;rsquo;t believe what I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, then ask yourself this: would any decent, kind-hearted individual become a writer? Of course not.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well, so far my children are enjoying it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I suppose we&amp;rsquo;ll see where we go from here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, we haven&amp;rsquo;t learned &lt;em>that&lt;/em> much about how &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; works in this world (we already have technology based almost entirely on glass along with &amp;lsquo;Talents&amp;rsquo;, which seem somewhat chaotic). That&amp;rsquo;s kind of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>thing&lt;/em>, so I expect a lot more there. The world is chaotic and strains believability when it comes to &amp;lsquo;could you &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> have a hidden world like this&amp;rsquo; but&amp;hellip; suspend disbelief and GO WITH IT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not actually sure how &lt;em>much&lt;/em> I like Alcatraz. So far, I like supporting cast Grandpa Smedry and Bastille quite a bit more. I expect that&amp;rsquo;s kind of the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, enjoyed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>