<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/alcatraz-vs.-the-evil-librarians/</link><description>Recent content in Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/alcatraz-vs.-the-evil-librarians/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Dark Talent</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/23/the-dark-talent/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/23/the-dark-talent/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Some of you have been waiting for years to read this, the final volume of my autobiography.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I cannot really imagine that being the last book. Or at least the last one that would be published for another 6 years! Now, in hindsight, it&amp;rsquo;s obvious (and my kids&amp;rsquo; totally already knew), but man. That&amp;rsquo;s NOT AN ENDING.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Fine,” Grandpa said. “You fetch your evil Librarian mother from the jail. I’ll go warm up the giant penguin!”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Ahem.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Well, that was fun,” Grandpa said as he climbed to his feet. “Anyone dead?”&lt;br>
“Does my pride count?” Draulin asked, dusting herself off.&lt;br>
“I don’t think so,” Grandpa said. “I killed that years ago. Dif, I appreciate your enthusiasm, but shoving my grandson out of planes is usually my job. So next time, kindly refrain until I give the word.”&lt;br>
“Sorry, sir,” Dif said, looking abashed.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Dark Talent sees Alcatraz. Sans Dark Talent, off on a mission to save the world &amp;hellip; and to save the girl. Just don&amp;rsquo;t let Bastille hear you say that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a lot like the rest of the series. New Smedrys (oh Dif), new worldbuilding (the HIBRARY! Beneath Washington DC!), new schenanigans (that is &lt;em>quite&lt;/em> a library; also, rocket powered penguins), and a big new battle at the end (leading up to that oft forementioned SACRIFICE UPON AN ALTAR OF ENCYCLOPEDIAS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it&amp;rsquo;s not the ending. And the ending can more than tell you that, which&amp;hellip; is honestly getting kind of old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s doubly painful since not only did it end quickly, but it also ended painfully. In a series where guns put people in comas and main characters have magic powers seemingly purposely designed (hmm) to get them out of trouble&amp;hellip; well, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a shock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of fun and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to where in the &lt;em>world&lt;/em> the series will &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> end&amp;hellip; For real this time? Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alcatraz Versus the Shattered Lens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/26/alcatraz-versus-the-shattered-lens/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/26/alcatraz-versus-the-shattered-lens/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Impossible things are really rough to do, you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And man, Alcatraz does all manner of impossible things this time around. There&amp;rsquo;s wacky tech (like Teddy bear grenades and giant flying bats (not made of glass)), wacky situations (Alcatraz getting a major (temporary) promotion (of sorts)), and powers (a Talent for Being Bad at Math). Pretty much exactly what you&amp;rsquo;d expect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And all along, we&amp;rsquo;re getting more about the world building, one thing that I always enjoy in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s books. There definitely seems to be a connection between it all&amp;ndash;but exactly how it all works together and how that can make things go wrong&amp;hellip; well, that&amp;rsquo;s the story, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Structurally, my kids were absolutely thrilled by the chapter numbering. The books are terribly meta, referring to chapters that don&amp;rsquo;t exist (because of skipping numbers) and with notes and comments going back and forth. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to read and honestly kind of impressive that we&amp;rsquo;ve gone this far&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Boys, welcome to the wonderful world of talking to women about their feelings. As a handy primer, here are a few things you should know:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Women have feelings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You will spend the next seventy years or so trying to guess what they&amp;rsquo;re feeling and why.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You will be wrong most of the time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I like French Fries.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Alcatraz continues to fall for Bastille.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>She was absolutely beautiful. She had long blonde hair, kind of the shade of a bowl of mac and cheese. She was smiling a wide, genuine smile—which was rather the shape of a macaroni and cheese noodle. She seemed to radiate light, much like a bowl of mac and cheese might if you stuffed a lightbulb into it. Her skin was soft and squishy, like— Okay. Maybe I’m too hungry to be writing right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In a very Alcatraz sort of way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun book and quite an ending. Of all the things to Break&amp;hellip; Here we go, one more book from Alcatraz&amp;rsquo;s perspective / in the original series. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to see where it can possible go from here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alcatraz Versus the Knights of Crystallia</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/alcatraz-versus-the-knights-of-crystallia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/alcatraz-versus-the-knights-of-crystallia/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Books are not fish sticks.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Now, we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em>really&lt;/em> in the Free Kingdoms. We spent a book learning that there&amp;rsquo;s a hidden world and another mostly underground (in the Library of Alexandria!), so it&amp;rsquo;s nice to get something really &amp;lsquo;hidden world&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man, the Free Kingdoms are strange. But that&amp;rsquo;s probably just the Librarian brainwashing coming through. Castles. Glass pigs. More castles. Kings. Councils. And even more Smedrys!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Farting barf-faced poop!” a voice exclaimed from inside the pig’s butt.&lt;br>
(Sigh. Sorry. At least that’s another great paragraph to try working into a random conversation.)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Exactly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the hilarious (from our point of view) issues that comes up this book is Alcatraz coming to his &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; moment. A world where he knows next to nothing, but everyone knows who he is. Apparently via the in-universe Alcatraz books, which is an extra level of weirdly meta.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Fame is like a cheeseburger. It might not be the best or most healthy thing to have, but it will still fill you up. You don’t really care how healthy something is when you’ve been without for so long. Like a cheeseburger, fame fills a need, and it tastes so good going down. It isn’t until years later that you realize what it has done to your heart.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There are just so many book/other geeky media references. I love them.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For example, take this story: “Once there was a furry-footed British guy who had to go throw his uncle’s ring into a hole in the ground.” Sounds dumb, doesn’t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Nothing is sacred!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“That’s bad,” Folsom said.&lt;br>
“She Who Cannot Be Named?” I asked. “Why can’t we say her name? Because it might draw the attention of evil powers? Because we’re afraid of her? Because her name has become a curse upon the world?”&lt;br>
“Don’t be silly,” Himalaya said. “We don’t say her name because nobody can pronounce it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Exactly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s more Alcatraz. You have a fun plot, wacky characters, and &lt;em>just&lt;/em> on the edge of too much meta commentary on writing/being a work of &amp;lsquo;fiction&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m still quite enjoying it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this is only halfway.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If a train left Nalhalla traveling at 3.14 miles an hour and a train left Bermuda at 45 MHz, what time does the soup have pancakes?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Where in the world (literally) can they go from here?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alcatraz Versus the Scrivener's Bones</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/20/alcatraz-versus-the-scriveners-bones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/20/alcatraz-versus-the-scriveners-bones/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Once there was a bunny. This bunny had a birthday party. It was the bestest birthday party ever. Because that was the day the bunny got a bazooka.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bunny loved his bazooka. He blew up all sorts of things on the farm. He blew up the stable of Henrietta the Horse. He blew up the pen of Pugsly the Pig. He blew up the coop of Chuck the Chicken.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I have the bestest bazooka ever,&amp;rdquo; the bunny said. Then the farm friends proceeded to beat him senseless and steal his bazooka. It was the happiest day of his life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epilogue: Pugsly the Pig, now without a pen, was quite annoyed. When none of the others were looking, he stole the bazooka. He tied a bandana on his head and swore vengeance for what had been done to him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;From this day on,&amp;rdquo; he whispered, raising the bazooka, &amp;ldquo;I shall be known as Hambo.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/10/alcatraz-versus-the-evil-librarians/">Alcatraz Versus the Evil Librarians&lt;/a> introduced us to the world, now in Alcatraz Versus the Scrivener&amp;rsquo;s Bones we actually get to live in it! A bit. Sort of.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>(Hushlanders, it might be noted, aren’t very imaginative with their idioms. Personally, I say, “Out of the frying pan and into the deadly pit filled with sharks who are wielding chainsaws with killer kittens stapled to them.” However, that one’s having a rough time catching on.)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Essentially, the entire book is an adventure where Alcatraz and co (Bastille, but also newcomers Australia&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and Kaz) are on a mission to mention a recently missing Grandpa Smedry. One thing leads to another, they end up in the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library%20of%20Alexandria">Library of Alexandria&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;which got totally Tardis&amp;rsquo;ed&amp;ndash;and discover all sorts of spooky ghosts, ancient scrolls, hidden messages, &amp;hellip; and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Not all librarians are evil cultists. Some librarians are instead vengeful undead who want to suck your soul.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Alcatraz Versus the Evil Librarians</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/10/alcatraz-versus-the-evil-librarians/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/10/alcatraz-versus-the-evil-librarians/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve read pretty much all of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s works&amp;hellip; yet somehow I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to completely miss &lt;em>Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians&lt;/em>. Let&amp;rsquo;s remedy that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short version: Alcatraz reminds me a decent bit of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/27/the-frugal-wizards-handbook-for-surviving-medieval-england/">Frugal Wizard&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;which was actually my least favorite of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/year-of-sanderson/">Year of Sanderson&lt;/a> secret projects. But so far at least, I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying this series quite a bit more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Slightly longer version:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the Hushlands—those Librarian-controlled nations such as the United States, Canada, and England—this book will be published as a work of fantasy. Do not be fooled! This is no work of fiction, nor is my name really Brandon Sanderson. Both are guises to hide the book from Librarian agents. Unfortunately, even with these precautions, I suspect that the Librarians will discover the book and ban it. In that case, our Free Kingdom Agents will have to sneak into libraries and bookstores to put it on shelves. Count yourself lucky if you’ve found one of these secret copies.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a (non-&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-cosmere/">Cosmere&lt;/a>) YA novel &amp;lsquo;written by&amp;rsquo; our titular Alcatraz as he learns that the world he&amp;rsquo;s always known is full of lies (perpetrated by a cabal of EVIL LIBRARIANS) who are now, of course, out to capture and/or kill him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As one does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>impressively&lt;/em> meta, with almost constant comments from Alcatraz as narrator, talking about writers, writing, fiction, and just about anything else.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Authors also create lovable, friendly characters, then proceed to do terrible things to them, like throw them in unsightly librarian-controlled dungeons. This makes readers feel hurt and worried for the characters. The simple truth is that authors like making people squirm. If this weren&amp;rsquo;t the case, all novels would be filled completely with cute bunnies having birthday parties.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Which, from my perspective as both a reader and writer myself, is amusing, but feels like it might be a bit weirder / too meta for a much younger reader?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you don&amp;rsquo;t believe what I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, then ask yourself this: would any decent, kind-hearted individual become a writer? Of course not.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well, so far my children are enjoying it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I suppose we&amp;rsquo;ll see where we go from here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, we haven&amp;rsquo;t learned &lt;em>that&lt;/em> much about how &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; works in this world (we already have technology based almost entirely on glass along with &amp;lsquo;Talents&amp;rsquo;, which seem somewhat chaotic). That&amp;rsquo;s kind of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>thing&lt;/em>, so I expect a lot more there. The world is chaotic and strains believability when it comes to &amp;lsquo;could you &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> have a hidden world like this&amp;rsquo; but&amp;hellip; suspend disbelief and GO WITH IT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not actually sure how &lt;em>much&lt;/em> I like Alcatraz. So far, I like supporting cast Grandpa Smedry and Bastille quite a bit more. I expect that&amp;rsquo;s kind of the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, enjoyed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>