<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2011 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2011/</link><description>Recent content in 2011 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2011/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/09/downton-abbey-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/09/downton-abbey-season-3/</guid><description>Oh, now that&amp;rsquo;s a season. It starts with a marriage, imprisonment, and money problems and only gets crazier from there.
Death is a theme as well, not once but twice. I get that sometimes actors move on , but they really did Matthew dirty with that one&amp;hellip;
Overall another solid season and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to what happens now!
Per episode reviews. Potential spoilers for the season as a whole.</description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/07/downton-abbey-season-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/07/downton-abbey-season-2/</guid><description>The season with World War I. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of changes, from war wounds to deaths to Downton becoming a temporary hospital.
It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating getting to know all these stories. Oh I wish the best for them all.
Such is life.
Onward!
Per episode reviews. Potential spoilers for the season as a whole.
Episode 2.1 And so&amp;hellip; war. Brutal away and at home for those that go, those that don&amp;rsquo;t, and those that can&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Caribbean: On Stranger Tides</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/03/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/03/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pirates of the Caribbean&amp;hellip; without Bloom or Knightly? At least they still have Johnny Depp I suppose. And Barbossa&amp;ndash;ish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Easily the weakest of the series. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; fine, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the absolutely bonkers charm of the earlier movies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain America: The First Avenger</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/31/captain-america-the-first-avenger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/31/captain-america-the-first-avenger/</guid><description>Now that is how you do a super hero movie.
For anyone that&amp;rsquo;s somehow missed it, Captain America is the story about how a little guy from Brooklyn with a heart of gold and a steadfast determination to serve his country in World War II gets just that chance: taking a super soldier serum to get buff, becomes a showgirl for a while (because of course), fights Nazis, and gets frozen in the ice.</description></item><item><title>Thor</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/</guid><description>Thor is an odd sort of movie for the Marvel Cinematic Universe. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s our first foray into the more &amp;lsquo;magical&amp;rsquo; side of the universe, with ancient Gods and the like. Although in this universe, we&amp;rsquo;re led to believe that it&amp;rsquo;s really just highly advanced science. On the other hand, despite a worlds spanning plot (literally, 3 of them), it still feels oddly &amp;hellip; small.
Plotwise&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s weird. We&amp;rsquo;re supposed to believe that Odin is over a thousand years old and Thor is&amp;hellip; just now coming into his kingship now?</description></item><item><title>The Cabin in the Woods</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/04/18/the-cabin-in-the-woods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 16:55:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/04/18/the-cabin-in-the-woods/</guid><description>&lt;p>I generally don&amp;rsquo;t go for horror movies, but the general premise intrigued me. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt that Joss Whedon co-wrote it. He&amp;rsquo;s had his ups and downs, but in general he&amp;rsquo;s earned at least a second look in my book.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>