<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2011 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2011/</link><description>Recent content in 2011 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2011/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black Mirror: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/black-mirror-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/black-mirror-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Been meaning to watch this for years. Finally got around to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting; especially for only have three episodes in the first season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#1-the-national-anthem">The first episode&lt;/a> is kind of weird and by far the least &amp;lsquo;sci-fi&amp;rsquo; of the bunch&amp;ndash;this could happen now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="#2-fifteen-million-merits">The second&lt;/a> though starts out as fairly straight forward near future dystopia and then goes &lt;em>dark&lt;/em> from there. I like it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And &lt;a href="#3-the-entire-history-of-you">the third&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;take a concept (recording everything), apply the concept to imperfect (honestly fairly terrible) people and see what breaks. It&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to season 2!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pirates of the Caribbean: On Stranger Tides</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/03/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/03/pirates-of-the-caribbean-on-stranger-tides/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pirates of the Caribbean&amp;hellip; without Bloom or Knightly? At least they still have Johnny Depp I suppose. And Barbossa&amp;ndash;ish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Easily the weakest of the series. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; fine, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the absolutely bonkers charm of the earlier movies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain America: The First Avenger</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/31/captain-america-the-first-avenger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/31/captain-america-the-first-avenger/</guid><description>&lt;p>Now that is how you do a super hero movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For anyone that&amp;rsquo;s somehow missed it, Captain America is the story about how a little guy from Brooklyn with a heart of gold and a steadfast determination to serve his country in World War II gets just that chance: taking a super soldier serum to get buff, becomes a showgirl for a while (because of course), fights Nazis, and gets frozen in the ice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thor is an odd sort of movie for the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marvel%20Cinematic%20Universe">Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/a>. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s our first foray into the more &amp;lsquo;magical&amp;rsquo; side of the universe, with ancient Gods and the like. Although in this universe, we&amp;rsquo;re led to believe that it&amp;rsquo;s really just highly advanced science. On the other hand, despite a worlds spanning plot (literally, 3 of them), it still feels oddly &amp;hellip; small.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s weird. We&amp;rsquo;re supposed to believe that Odin is over a thousand years old and Thor is&amp;hellip; just now coming into his kingship now? How long does it take for them to grow up? And Asgardians at some level can die in battle, but in others handle getting thrown around and hit by cars just fine? It&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip; a little weird. The idea of Thor being a spoiled young man and having to show his worthiness is a solid enough plot (and a common enough Thor origin story); although it all comes together a mite quickly for him. And then the final battle&amp;ndash;while it looks cool enough I guess, it&amp;rsquo;s all feels like they could have used a bit more time and money to fill things in a bit more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Cabin in the Woods</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/04/18/the-cabin-in-the-woods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 16:55:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/04/18/the-cabin-in-the-woods/</guid><description>&lt;p>I generally don&amp;rsquo;t go for horror movies, but the general premise intrigued me. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt that Joss Whedon co-wrote it. He&amp;rsquo;s had his ups and downs, but in general he&amp;rsquo;s earned at least a second look in my book.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>