<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>J.J. Abrams on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/j.j.-abrams/</link><description>Recent content in J.J. Abrams on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/j.j.-abrams/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Star Wars: Episode IX - The Rise of Skywalker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/star-wars-episode-ix-the-rise-of-skywalker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/15/star-wars-episode-ix-the-rise-of-skywalker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Given the internet&amp;rsquo;s backlast, I exepcted a lot worse. At least to me, The Rise of Skywalker did a pretty decent job of closing the loop on the saga that began a long time ago with the rise of Palpatine and the fall of Anakin Skywalker. Really, that&amp;rsquo;s the entire story, and you get that here in spades.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were definitely some weird choices made in pacing (in particular, right at the beginning, they sort of drop the whole &amp;lsquo;Emperor is back&amp;rsquo; thing on us&amp;hellip; apparently the reveal came in &amp;hellip; Fortnite? Seriously?). We lose out on a lot of what could have been a cool story with Finn and Poe, although they&amp;rsquo;re still around at least. And I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine that losing Carrie Fisher did filming any favors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VII - The Force Awakens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/04/star-wars-episode-vii-the-force-awakens/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/04/star-wars-episode-vii-the-force-awakens/</guid><description>&lt;p>Woo, new Star Wars! I remember the hype when The Force Awakens first came out. It was pretty crazy to see new Star Wars for the first time (second time?) in years. And it&amp;rsquo;s pretty dang cool. It&amp;rsquo;s shinier than the original trilogy, a bit less stuck in the weeds (trade blockades!) than the prequels, and it leans &lt;em>hard&lt;/em> on nostalgia. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s Star Wars! Could they have done something newer and more unique? Sure they could have.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>