<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pippi Löngstrump on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/12/pippi-l%C3%B6ngstrump/</link><description>Recent content in Pippi Löngstrump on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/12/pippi-l%C3%B6ngstrump/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pippi in the South Seas</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/12/pippi-in-the-south-seas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/12/pippi-in-the-south-seas/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cute enough. For the most part, it&amp;rsquo;s more Pippi stories, but they do finally get out of the town and go with Pippi and her father to the South Seas island where her father is king. Which&amp;hellip; is both the best and worst part of the book. It&amp;rsquo;s zany and fun in true Pippi fashion, but it&amp;rsquo;s also &lt;em>horribly&lt;/em> imperialistic/racist. It&amp;rsquo;s still a fun book, but definitely a product of the times.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pippi Goes on Board</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/19/pippi-goes-on-board/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/19/pippi-goes-on-board/</guid><description>&lt;p>I actually liked this story a lot more than the first Pippi. It&amp;rsquo;s still basically the same idea: girl who is unusually strong and lives on her own gets up to hijinks, but I think that the stories this time around fit a little bit&amp;ndash;and we actually get to meet &lt;span class="spoiler">Pippi's dad--turns out he's not dead after all&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth continuing on. Going to have to check out the third now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pippi Longstocking</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/03/pippi-longstocking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/03/pippi-longstocking/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pippi Longstocking&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an odd character. On one hand, she&amp;rsquo;s a fun loving young girl who happens to have super strength (for some reason). She&amp;rsquo;s lived a pretty crazy life and has stories from all over the world along with a tendency to get herself into (and back out of) wacky adventures and always seems to have a lot of fun doing so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, she&amp;rsquo;s a young girl living on her own. Her parents are (probably) both dead, so she doesn&amp;rsquo;t really have any guiding influence on her life. On top of that, she doesn&amp;rsquo;t exactly seem to have the strongest grasp on reality&amp;ndash;always telling stories from around the world with only a vague relation to real life.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>