<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mistborn Era 1 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mistborn-era-1/</link><description>Recent content in Mistborn Era 1 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mistborn-era-1/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Hero of Ages</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/05/the-hero-of-ages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/05/the-hero-of-ages/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever since the Lord Ruler was killed in the first Mistborn book, things have been getting worse. It all comes to a head in The Hero of Ages. The world is quite literally ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s strength continues to be his world building. We get a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> more details this time around. We learn of a few more Allomantic metals. We learn all about the third metallic art (only previously hinted at): Hemalurgy. On top of that, we expand on what exactly the Koloss and Kandra are, what abilities they have, and how they came to be. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy awesome how it all fits together and would be well worth the read just got that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Well of Ascension</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/16/the-well-of-ascension/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/16/the-well-of-ascension/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since last I read this book, I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten just how much happens in this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the Lord Ruler was killed in The Final Empire, some things have gotten better&amp;hellip; some have gotten much much worse.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Final Empire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/01/the-final-empire/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/01/the-final-empire/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Final Empire is a great read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love the worldbuilding. It&amp;rsquo;s a weird world, with strange nightly mists and a near constant fall of ash that gets on everything. Even stranger, it&amp;rsquo;s hinted that the world was once much more like our own. On top of that, you have a quasi-Feudal society ruled by a powerful, potentially immortal being. All of which leads to some pretty obvious seeds for some crazy stuff to go on.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>