<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ann Leckie on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/21/ann-leckie/</link><description>Recent content in Ann Leckie on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/21/ann-leckie/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ancillary Mercy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/21/ancillary-mercy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/21/ancillary-mercy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ancillary Mercy does a good job blending the larger overarching story and style of Ancillary Justice and the much closer to home sequel Ancillary Sword. The universe is still relatively limited to a pair of star systems plus the planet and station of Athoek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the most part, it&amp;rsquo;s a good mix and a much better sequel to Ancillary Justice than Ancillary Sword was. On the other hand, we still don&amp;rsquo;t get to really deal with any of the overarching story telling that we got at first. We meet a few new ancillaries, but they never really &lt;em>act&lt;/em> as ancillaries. One of Anaander Mianaai shows up, but she&amp;rsquo;s almost comically out classed. There&amp;rsquo;s no real threat there. We meet a new Presger translator who is delightfully odd&amp;hellip; to an extent that pushes past surreal all the way to unbelievable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ancillary Sword</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/03/ancillary-sword/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/03/ancillary-sword/</guid><description>&lt;p>This book was a bit odd so far as sequels go, shrinking the scope of the story significantly from the first book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the first, we have several different points of view, timelines, and locations. In the second, we&amp;rsquo;re almost completely following the former Justice of Toren in a single timeline immediately following the events of the first book in a single system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ancillary Justice</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/22/ancillary-justice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/22/ancillary-justice/</guid><description>&lt;p>High concept: In the future, starships are run by AIs which also control dozens or more previously human bodies known as ancillaries. Occasionally, the ancillaries get &amp;hellip; detached. Ancillary Justice follows the story of one such.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a really neat concept and does a good job of carrying the story on its own. It does make it a bit confusing at times to figure out who exactly is talking; a situation that is compounded by the fact that the story line jumps between a few different timelines and characters (or at least versions of the same character). Ever few chapters I found myself taking a moment to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s going on.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>