<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Hollows on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-hollows/</link><description>Recent content in The Hollows on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-hollows/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Million Dollar Demon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/18/million-dollar-demon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/18/million-dollar-demon/</guid><description>&lt;p>And&amp;hellip; away we go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through the last couple of books, we&amp;rsquo;ve had more than a few shake ups to the power structure of Cincinnati and the Hollows. The return of the demons&amp;ndash;and the death of one master vampire and the whole &amp;lsquo;vampire soul&amp;rsquo; binding mess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sn now when when a new crazy (even by vampire standards) master vampire is sent to take power? Well, it just stands to reason that Rachel is going to have to get involved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seeing Rachel start to stand up and actually take on the power and responsibility that she&amp;rsquo;s been flirting with (and fighting off) for all these books is a worthwhile change. I do hope it sticks. It&amp;rsquo;s a different level of story, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s about time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In addition to that, we have the ongoing Hodin/Al hate triangle.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I don’t know how you survive your ignorance,” he muttered. “I’ve warned you once. Now I’m telling you. If you don’t want to talk to Al, fine. I don’t want to talk to him most days. But you will not take Hodin as your mentor. He is dangerous.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Urban fantasy is famous for having love triangles all over the place, so this is certainly a fun inversion to that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m really curious to see where that goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, another solid entry and I&amp;rsquo;m curiously optimistic to see where Harrison takes it from here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>American Demon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/02/american-demon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/02/american-demon/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. That&amp;rsquo;s how Harrison is going to come back to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-hollows/">The Hollows&lt;/a> after that epilogue&amp;ndash;it was &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/AllJustADream" target="_blank" rel="noopener">all just a dream&lt;/a>&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I actually (mostly) liked that epilogue, so it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a bummer. But if you&amp;rsquo;re going to go back to mostly status quo, well then I suppose you have to do something. I do wonder if that actually means that anyone that showed up in the &amp;lsquo;dream&amp;rsquo; can actually still die off now?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/19/the-witch-with-no-name/">The Witch with No Name&lt;/a> Rachel saved the world! And now she has to deal with the fallout from that. Zombies, mysterious murders, new frenemies, and once again seeing how in the &lt;em>world&lt;/em> demons are going to re-integrate into the world, oh my?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Jesus, Rachel,” Edden coaxed, but I was having none of it. “Don’t take this personally. You can’t deny that forcing couples to kill one another is demonic.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“What’s in it for them?” I asked, waving Ivy’s carefully assembled information. “Demons don’t do anything unless it’s for a profit.” Frustrated, I slapped the reports against his chest, and he fumbled for them. “And neither do I anymore,” I said.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And of course, things go sideways. Because even after everything&amp;ndash;even after it nearly ending the world more than once&amp;ndash;Rachel is still &lt;em>terrible&lt;/em> at listening to the people she&amp;rsquo;s supposed to trust and acting fully on passion first, thinking things through&amp;hellip; sometime&amp;ndash;maybe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, one theme that we continue to seem in this series is the possibility of redemption. You have literal murderers (Trent and Al in particular), but they really are trying to be better people. So how does that work? Are they allowed to work towards a better life? Do they have to pay for what they&amp;rsquo;ve done? What price is high enough murder and thousands of years of torture and slave trading?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“It’s what we do here,” Jenks said. “All are innocent until proven guilty. Even demons.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hodin’s feet scuffed the old wood floor. “How . . . quaint.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But hey, Rachel and Trent are cute together. I hope they get a few books at least to be happy.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Stop,” Trent demanded again, frowning at Quen. “Everyone, stop. Relax. Rachel, you can kill me in a few minutes. I want to talk first. You like to talk, don’t you?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And the girls are so cute.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Because you’re a demon princess,” Lucy said, playing with my curling hair, and from the closet came Trent’s grunt of surprise. “And demon princesses are brave.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Rachel constantly worried about Trent leaving for Ellasbeth and blaming herself for all the elf politics things is growing old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think my biggest negative for this entry comes in the ending. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of mechanical talk about what a soul is and messing with souls, but heroic or not, there&amp;rsquo;s a sacrifice play towards the end that I&amp;rsquo;m hoping gets resolved quickly&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s fun to keep going. I can only imagine having a fairly definite end, waiting the six years between the books and then learning you actually get more! No break for me though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>The Witch with No Name</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/19/the-witch-with-no-name/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/19/the-witch-with-no-name/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it &amp;hellip; ends?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Originally &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/19/the-witch-with-no-name/">The Witch with No Name&lt;/a> was to be &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-hollows/">The Hollows&lt;/a> grand finale. And it certainly feels like that. Blowing up the past, shaking up the power structure of not only the demons and elves but also the vampires, saving the world, saving magic itself, and changing everything. It&amp;rsquo;s one &lt;em>heck&lt;/em> of a busy book.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Head up, I stomped along, eyeing the few pedestrians. Slowly my good mood was tarnished. Love died in the shadows, and it shouldn’t cost so much to keep it in the sun. But as Trent would say, anything gotten cheap wouldn’t last, so do what you need to do to be happy and deal with the consequences. That if love was easy, everyone would find it.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The vampires are a big part of this book&amp;ndash;dealing with what vampire &amp;lsquo;souls&amp;rsquo; are, especially for those that have died their first death. The &amp;rsquo;living vampires&amp;rsquo; in this series have been cool worldbuilding the whole time. In the end, the solution to that is a neat way to tie up a problem I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know I had. I really do wonder how long Harrison had been planning that!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But of course, don&amp;rsquo;t leave out the demons.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Al leaned close, voice dangerous as he whispered, “We don’t forget, Rachel, and it’s not as if it was our ancestors who were betrayed. It was us.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There is so much more about the very beginning of the demons here&amp;ndash;and reminders that they&amp;rsquo;re very nearly extinct&amp;ndash;and have been around a &lt;em>long&lt;/em> time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and Al is a great second example (after Trent) of us, the readers, coming to know and love the villains of the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Rachel is a pus bucket full of miracles,” the demon added, eyes rolling. “Thank you, Bis. I don’t know these new lines yet.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>He&amp;hellip; has done some really terrible things over his thousands of years. But he&amp;rsquo;s cute with the girls and nice to Rachel, so we&amp;rsquo;re just supposed to forgive that? He really does seem to have changed. This is a hard one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I remember a few books back when Rachel called on the witches of San Francisco to ring their bells and work together to help her&amp;ndash;and nothing. This time around, it&amp;rsquo;s the demons she&amp;rsquo;s calling out to. And I think that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much where this series has gone. Demons may do some terrible things&amp;ndash;but in the end, they&amp;rsquo;re also just people. Super long lived powerful people, but still people. And people of all stripes can be good&amp;ndash;or evil.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love how much crazy stuff happens in this book. I love that it was set up as a finale, given Harrison the permission to do some &lt;em>crazy&lt;/em> things that you normally don&amp;rsquo;t see that often in long running series. And I do appreciate getting a happy ever after epilogue (see &lt;a href="#the-ending">later&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, that&amp;rsquo;s quite the book. It actually gives a good point where you could end. And a lot of people probably thought that &lt;em>was&lt;/em> the end. But I have the benefit of having read these a decade later, and there&amp;rsquo;s more! We&amp;rsquo;ll just have to see how in the &lt;em>world&lt;/em> Harrison handles that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr></description></item><item><title>The Undead Pool</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/08/the-undead-pool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/08/the-undead-pool/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Minor spoilers, mostly for the romance bits of the series&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a decade (for people reading along as the series came out) / six months (for me), &lt;span class="spoiler">they're finally together&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Yeah, the elf looks good in the sun,” Jenks smart-mouthed, the pixy currently sitting on the bottom of my hooped earrings and out of the moderate wind. “When you going to put us all out of your misery and boink him?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Given how it all started, you could totally expe4ct it coming&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m actually really rooting for them. I think they&amp;rsquo;ve both become better people through the books. Rachel is at least marginally less terrible at rushing into things and Trent is not outright murdering people quite so often. #goals&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it does lead to all sorts of fun politics. See, she&amp;rsquo;s a demon and he&amp;rsquo;s an elf. And the demons and elves &lt;strong>hate&lt;/strong> one another. Something something, thousands of years of war and slavery. So of course this is going to come with all sorts of drama.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Red finally gave up trying to bolt, and Trent settled into the saddle. The last couple of months with Trent had been… interesting. With Ellasbeth threatening to stay, I was seeing things in the light of “last time” and I was shocked to realize I didn’t like it, especially not with Landon’s threat. If not for the different tax bracket thing, or that he was going to be engaged, or that because of me, he’d lose everything if he didn’t marry Ellasbeth…&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s just the romance part&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of &lt;em>that&lt;/em> we have magic going amuck, going quite a bit deeper into how elf magic works&amp;ndash;and just what/if their &amp;lsquo;goddess&amp;rsquo; actually is.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Duh. You think I’m going to trash anything Newt gives me? The woman is crazy, not stupid.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Rachel of course has to save the day, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a bit of a mess to get there. Rachel is really leveling up. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite a &amp;lsquo;chosen one&amp;rsquo; plot, but given how unique she is in this entire world, it&amp;rsquo;s a near cousin of it. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to think about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But storywise, it&amp;rsquo;s quite an action packed adventure. Romancewise&amp;ndash;like I said&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing how this all shakes out.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Etude nodded, and as Jenks buried himself in my hair, I closed my eyes to block out the dizzy sensation. Behind me, I felt the train race on without the mystics. The splinter was following me, harrowing, nipping, stabbing at my heels. Ill and nauseated, I hung in Etude’s grip, thinking that I should have just called the damn eagles from the beginning and done this alone.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A solid book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ever After</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/30/ever-after/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/30/ever-after/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Everyone needed someone to watch their back.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the world&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&amp;ndash;and it might just be Rachel&amp;rsquo;s fault&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So now she has to do the impossible, save the world&amp;ndash;magic itself&amp;ndash;face off against Ku&amp;rsquo;Sox&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, and somehow work with both Trent and Al at the same time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What could &lt;em>possibly&lt;/em> go wrong?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(A lot. A lot could go wrong.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Perfect Blood</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/27/a-perfect-blood/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/27/a-perfect-blood/</guid><description>&lt;p>So Rachel&amp;rsquo;s still alive and full on recognized as a demon&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Except demons &lt;em>don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em> live in reality. They have no rights. They don&amp;rsquo;t exist. And they most certainly register cars.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh the paperwork.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I should’ve kept my mouth shut,” he said, shooting a quick glance at the knots, and I shrugged. Perhaps, but there was no sense in crying over squished tomatoes.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh. And Rachel&amp;rsquo;s avoiding her magic, Trent&amp;rsquo;s embracing his, and an anti-interland hate group is of course up to &lt;em>no&lt;/em> good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Million Dollar Baby</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/17/million-dollar-baby/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/17/million-dollar-baby/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another novella from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/into-the-woods-tales-from-the-hollows-and-beyond/">Into the Woods&lt;/a>: The story of what Jenks and Trent were up to during &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/13/pale-demon/">Pale Demon&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>ELF QUEST!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s really quite spoilery (for Pale Demon) to really get into what that &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> means, but the short version is that we get another major magical heist novel, which is all sorts of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Trent and Jenks are a surprisingly fun combo. It&amp;rsquo;s nice every once in a while to have parts about Rachel without having her on screen.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“No, not really.” One hand holding his wings tight to his body, Jenks turned to look behind him at their forward progress. “Rachel makes enough mistakes in one week to fill a twenty-yard dump truck.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Exactly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and more elf politics:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He trusted people. He trusted quite a few, and quite a few had “screwed him over” as Jenks put it. The difference was that when people betrayed him, sometimes other people died. And then other people thought it was his fault. He was tired of it. Everything he had was at risk for the next four hours. Quen said he was not his father, but he was doing the same damning things. &amp;hellip; The Goddess help him, they had to come out of the closet if only so he could stop killing people.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A fun short story! And with even &lt;em>more&lt;/em> implications to the broader Hollows universe than Pale Demon. It&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see how that all shakes out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pale Demon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/13/pale-demon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/07/13/pale-demon/</guid><description>&lt;p>So Rachel is sanctioned. She has one chance to travel (on purpose this time) to San Francisco to try to clear her name. Except&amp;hellip; she can&amp;rsquo;t fly, because politics&amp;ndash;road trip! And has to take Trent, also because politics&amp;ndash;road trip with Jenks, Ivy, Rachel, and Trent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What could possibly go wrong?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Jenks: Relax cookie maker. They’ve been there since Terre Haute.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>lol. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keebler%20elves">Keebler elves&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terre%20Haute">Terre Haute&lt;/a>. I went to school there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then they blew up a national monument.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And freed a demon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And saved another demon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And learned what is actually &lt;em>different&lt;/em> about the female demons.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But Al was shaking his head, looking ill. “I am not going to be the person who completes you,” he said, glancing at me and turning away. “You are one messed-up bitch.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And suddenly&amp;hellip; &lt;em>baby&lt;/em>! (I&amp;rsquo;ll leave you to guess if it&amp;rsquo;s who you expect or not).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a lot for a single book. And with what looks like might be permanent reprecussions across the Hollows universe (and Rachel especially) that we&amp;rsquo;re only barely beginning to feel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: This was a fun line:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“So all those buttons are different restaurants?” I asked, looking at the jukebox, now totally out of place, like a British police call box on the deck of the Titanic.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I understood that reference. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second side note: So&amp;hellip; how many cross breeds are possible in this universe? We have some hints because of how species diverged from one another. And we also have elves with some human lineage. But what else is possible? And what if we include all sorts of genetic tampering that is seemingly possible in this world&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Magic Sanction</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/19/black-magic-sanction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/19/black-magic-sanction/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. Alcatraz is back in service. That&amp;rsquo;s kind of brilliant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, Rachel is dealing with her shunning&amp;ndash;and far far worse. The witches of the world aren&amp;rsquo;t on her side any more, but perhaps she can get some help from&amp;hellip; Trent? Al? Nick?! (Why is Nick back around&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the only way out is&amp;hellip; suddenly, we have a heist novel now. It seems like this is &lt;em>really&lt;/em> not the time. And double that, when Rachel randomly decides to use that Pandora charm that&amp;rsquo;s been floating around. &lt;em>now?!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man she has issues with long term thinking.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;How did you know we were in trouble?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re always in trouble, Rachel,&amp;rdquo; he said, fixing his hat firmly back on his head.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And seems &lt;em>so very&lt;/em> deadset on not killing anything ever. Which, I suppose if you&amp;rsquo;re going to do black magic, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to give anyone any other reasons to hate you. But sometimes, especially in a world like this, there are people you just can&amp;rsquo;t hang on to. Oy. (Not to mention that she seems fine with those around her killing&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially after 8 books. And after what happened to Jenks&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, another good story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Random world building notes:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>His eyes were alight. I&amp;rsquo;d seen that look on college students debating such ridiculous stuff as how the world would be today if Napoleon hadn&amp;rsquo;t stirred that misaligned spell and won Waterloo, or if the Turn had never happened and we&amp;rsquo;d gone to the moon instead. &amp;ldquo;Okay, I got that,&amp;rdquo; I said, and Pierce pushed from the table to take his plate to the sink.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I do love the subtle(ish) nods to our world / what might have been. Good times those.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ley Line Drifter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/15/ley-line-drifter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/15/ley-line-drifter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another novella from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/into-the-woods-tales-from-the-hollows-and-beyond/">Into the Woods&lt;/a>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, this time with Jenks striking out on his own (more or less) to save the day!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First thought: Jenks and Bis is a fun dynamic. Jenks is a lot when he&amp;rsquo;s a side character, but somehow seeing into his head is so much better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In that reguard, have we actually seen on screen/page what Jenks wished for all the way back in the first book? Daw.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And has Rachel figured out what I think Jenks already knows here about what the embeggining actually did to him?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second thought:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Jenks?” Bis said loudly, half hiding behind Sylvan’s statue. “Maybe we should leave the goddess alone.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Huh. So thinking about it, have we really seen much in the way of &amp;rsquo;tiers&amp;rsquo; of creatures in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-hollows/">The Hollows&lt;/a>? There are some that are difficult for others to fight, but nothing truly &amp;lsquo;godly&amp;rsquo;. Interesting that.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And what about Daryl, anyway? A deluded nymph, Sylvan had said. A goddess, Daryl claimed. There were no gods or goddesses. Never had been, but there were documented histories of Inderlanders taking advantage of humans, posing as deities. He frowned. Her eyes were downright creepy, and he hadn’t liked demons being mentioned, either.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I wonder if that will stick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise&amp;hellip; we learn in this book that apparently Pixies can &lt;span class="spoiler">make explosives&lt;/span>
. Delightful. And no one knows. Probably for the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally, some last bits of world building around pixies and gargoyles. They eat pigeons (the latter) and their names get longer the further down the birth order they are (the former).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a fun little story. Always neat to see the side characters get their chance to shine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do bet that, just like banshees, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the last we&amp;rsquo;ll see of nymphs/dryads in this series. Or at least I hope it isn&amp;rsquo;t!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>White Witch, Black Curse</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/11/white-witch-black-curse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/11/white-witch-black-curse/</guid><description>&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; banshee?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Heh. Called it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So basically, we have Rachel dealing with the events/fallout of &lt;em>Dirty Magic&lt;/em> (from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/into-the-woods-tales-from-the-hollows-and-beyond/">Into the Woods&lt;/a>): wherein we find out what banshees are in the world of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-hollows/">The Hollows&lt;/a> and see Ivy dealing with one&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, I think this might be the first main book in which we see Robbie (also in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/two-ghosts-for-sister-rachel/">Two Ghosts for Sister Rachel&lt;/a>)&amp;hellip; and he&amp;rsquo;s not the only one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So anyways, we have Rachel still dealing with the fallout of Kistin&amp;rsquo;s death, a new uber-predator on the loose (banshees are basically vampires on steroids it seems), a blast from the past (both in general and Rachel&amp;rsquo;s specifically), Al, witch sex, auras, and SHUNNING (all caps).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Sweet mother of Tink,” Jenks whispered from the ladle. “What just happened?&amp;quot;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Quite a book.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Jenks flew two circles around me to stretch his wings, then landed on Ivy’s shoulder. She was staring at the city, mesmerized. “It looks peaceful from up here,” she said when her line of sight was broken by a member of the waitstaff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jenks snorted. “It looks peaceful when you get up real close, too,” he said, and I thought of my garden. “It’s only the middle ground that’s ugly.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But hey, (minor spoilers), we do get at least some forward progress on Kistin&amp;rsquo;s murderer!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, another solid entry. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Outlaw Demon Wails</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/03/the-outlaw-demon-wails/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/06/03/the-outlaw-demon-wails/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, enough side stories (and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/19/the-turn-the-hollows-begins-with-death/">prequels&lt;/a>!). Back to the main story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, Rachel can do demon things. And in doing so, she&amp;rsquo;s managed to really piss off one demon: Algaliarept (Al). Now he&amp;rsquo;s out every night on a technicality and coming for Rachel.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You can’t forget anything,” I said, watching the words vanish into nothing. “And even if you do, it always comes back to bitch-slap you in the morning.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So how in the world is she going to solve this one? Well&amp;hellip; perhaps not in &lt;em>the world&lt;/em> after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Rache?” Jenks said warily, hovering as I hid my hands so he couldn’t see them shake. “What did you do?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, more elf shenanigans with Trent and Ceri (although not the two of them together :whew:).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Relationship drama, both with Ivy and perhaps with Marshal (from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/a-fistful-of-charms/">A Fistful of Charms&lt;/a>). It&amp;rsquo;s not quite Kistin, but it will be interesting to see. And uniting auras. What&amp;rsquo;s up with that? A mystery for another book I suppose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and historical drama with Rachel&amp;rsquo;s mom (now that was a bombshell&amp;hellip;). I figured something was up with that, but man that was still a hit. It will be interesting to see where that goes&amp;ndash;and if her mom will become a larger player going forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and suddenly Ryn Cormel. Who I just met in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/19/the-turn-the-hollows-begins-with-death/">The Turn&lt;/a>. Interesting that. If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read the prequel, would I have missed out on anything? Probably not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and a Gargoyle. I expected more from that. But perhaps next book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I &lt;em>really&lt;/em> enjoyed this one. This series has turned out to be primarily about demons, but&amp;hellip; perhaps that makes sense given, well, everything. I&amp;rsquo;m here for it though!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Side note: I&amp;rsquo;ve been listening to these on audiobok. Why&amp;hellip; does this one have a different narrator? It&amp;rsquo;s a bit jarring. Piss-ker-ee. Lee line. Jenks&amp;rsquo; new voice. I think it&amp;rsquo;d be perfectly fine (although lee line would probably still bother me), but I&amp;rsquo;d just gotten so used to the other!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It turns out &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/topic/show/21045927-a-change-in-narrator-for-this-book" target="_blank" rel="noopener">there is a discussion about this&lt;/a> on Goodreads.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ms. Gavin and I are both working to get her to read AMERICAN DEMON. Should happen!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; Kim Harrison&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Not a why, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s known? And apparently we&amp;rsquo;ll go back to Marguerite Gavin after this one!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Second side note: The fact that they said &amp;lsquo;Al went into human resources&amp;rsquo; is certainly a choice. And they just skate &lt;em>right on&lt;/em> by that one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Into the Woods: Tales from the Hollows and Beyond</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/into-the-woods-tales-from-the-hollows-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/into-the-woods-tales-from-the-hollows-and-beyond/</guid><description>&lt;iframe src="https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/1mGnIAxWGb2DBnlqwCqOuO?utm_source=generator&amp;theme=0"
 width="100%" height="80"
 frameBorder="0" allowfullscreen=""
 allow="autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture">
&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>Now that that is out of the way &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Into the Woods is a collection of Hollows Shorts. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve liked the series enough to go ahead and want todo everything about it, I decided to pick up all the shorts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because I track my reading, I have to draw the line somewhere, so here it is: all of the short stories will be collected here (updating as I read them). Novellas (and novelettes?) will get their own posts.&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-bespelled">The Bespelled&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#two-ghosts-for-sister-rachel">Two Ghosts for Sister Rachel&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#undead-in-the-garden-of-good-and-evil">Undead in the Garden of Good and Evil&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#dirty-magic">Dirty Magic&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#the-bridges-of-eden-park">The Bridges of Eden Park&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#ley-line-driver">Ley Line Driver&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#million-dollar-baby">Million Dollar Baby&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#pet-shop-boys-todo">Pet Shop Boys (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#temson-estates-todo">Temson Estates (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#spider-silk-todo">Spider Silk (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#grace-todo">Grace (&lt;em>todo&lt;/em>)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav></description></item><item><title>Two Ghosts for Sister Rachel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/two-ghosts-for-sister-rachel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/two-ghosts-for-sister-rachel/</guid><description>&lt;p>So that&amp;rsquo;s a story. Young Rachel (finishing school, desperately wanting to go to the IS), still living at home with her mother, when her brother comes to visit! Given that we&amp;rsquo;ve barely seen them on page (&lt;em>have&lt;/em> we see her brother?), it&amp;rsquo;s some fun bit of backstory&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then the entire story revolves around trying to contact Rachel&amp;rsquo;s dead father to win a bet (and to join the IS in his footsteps), well, of course things are going to get complicated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun story with just the right amount of gut punches and backstory. I do wonder what we&amp;rsquo;ll see &amp;lsquo;in between&amp;rsquo;. How does Rachel end up strong enough to go on runs? She certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t doing that well here. And will see see her time at that camp?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, worth the read!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: red eye flights being renamed to &amp;lsquo;vamp flights&amp;rsquo; is a fun detail.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also: &amp;lsquo;Spell checker&amp;rsquo;. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also also: Man Rachel really will fall for anyone, won&amp;rsquo;t she&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Undead in the Garden of Good and Evil</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/20/undead-in-the-garden-of-good-and-evil/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/20/undead-in-the-garden-of-good-and-evil/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Life was more than waiting for it to end so she could started living.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Man Ivy is a mess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is the/a story of how Ivy came to be, how screwy (heh) vampires can be, how she got to be working as a runner, and how she came to meet Rachel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a pretty fun way to set it up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and much like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/22/into-the-woods-tales-from-the-hollows-and-beyond/#the-bridges-of-eden-park">The Bridges of Eden Park&lt;/a> this (especially the Kisten parts) back to back with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/11/for-a-few-demons-more/">For a Few Demons More&lt;/a> is certainly a touch of whiplash.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Turn: The Hollows Begins with Death</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/19/the-turn-the-hollows-begins-with-death/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/19/the-turn-the-hollows-begins-with-death/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The only thing worse than starting a plague on purpose was being stupid enough to start it by accident.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Okay, I&amp;rsquo;ve read (and quite enjoyed) enough of the Hollows that I want to go back and pick up the short stories and other supplementary stories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Enter: The Turn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The story of science, betrayal, tomatoes, and a whole bunch of deaths that changed the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun story. While I really do appreciate that the Hollows is a world with without a &amp;lsquo;masquerade&amp;rsquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see the world before (and &lt;em>as&lt;/em>) all of the various Interlanders came out into the open. Especially seeing who was involved&amp;ndash;and wondering just what they&amp;rsquo;re all up to in the more modern time I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“A person is okay,” he said, peering into the darkness and the open street. “But when you put a bunch of us together, something is switched on, something ugly.” He glanced at her apologetically. “All of us, humans and nonhumans alike, are genetically primed to attack what’s different from the collective.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, a fun story to set up. As far as I&amp;rsquo;ve read, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to read for the main series, but I&amp;rsquo;ms till glad to have read it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For a Few Demons More</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/11/for-a-few-demons-more/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/11/for-a-few-demons-more/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There were no more choices, no more options, no more clever ways out of a tough situation. And the rush, I realized in a brutal wash of despair, is a false god I’ve chased my entire life. One that cost me everything in the blind search for sensation. My entire existence amounted to nothing.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That title is not a lie&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not just Algaliarept (Al &amp;#x1f604;) this time around. We also are introduced to Newt&amp;ndash;just sort of pops in and shows off some serious magical chops&amp;hellip; and then reveals that she&amp;rsquo;s not entirely sane any more. Mildly terrifying that. Plus Minias, her minder, who actually seems decent&amp;ndash;for a demon. Rachel is getting in pretty hard with all of these different favors owed (both ways). Makes for quite the story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that Trent&amp;rsquo;s getting married. And Rachel&amp;rsquo;s not only invited&amp;hellip; but in the wedding party? Well, actually it&amp;rsquo;s to provide security (hint: demons). But of course any time you put Trent and Rachel together there&amp;rsquo;s going to be trouble.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if &lt;em>that&lt;/em> wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough&amp;hellip; we have even more vampire trouble. Rachel and Ivy are such a mess&amp;ndash;and that one really can&amp;rsquo;t last too many more books. One step forward&amp;ndash;and another two back. And Kisten. Oh Kisten. Still not a good person, but perhaps good for Rachel? &lt;span class="spoiler">Oh Harrison, *that* was a low blow.&lt;/span>
&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I’ve got your back. Nothing alive will ever hurt you if I have breath in me. And nothing dead will hurt you if I don’t.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a story. Probably the most intense so far. I fully expect (and hope) that this really shakes up the world of the Hollows and I&amp;rsquo;m curious where in the &lt;em>world&lt;/em> we can go from here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Fistful of Charms</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/a-fistful-of-charms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/a-fistful-of-charms/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, enough vampire/demon nonsense for a moment, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about weres.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>As the joke goes, you don’t have to be faster than the wolf chasing you, just faster than everyone else running away.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Turns out that trying to get letter-of-the-law against multiple packs of werewolves has consequences. For everyone involved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick&amp;hellip; is a real piece of work. I will grant him the one small saving grace that he (along with most of the world) thought Rachel dead as part of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/14/every-which-way-but-dead/">Every Which Way But Dead&lt;/a>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&amp;hellip; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make him any better a person. At least Rachel eventually realizes it? Sort of. Mostly. Ish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel and Ivy&amp;hellip; come to a serious head in this book. Which went about as badly as I expected. I do wish the best for Ivy, but she certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t make that easy at times and Rachel is &lt;em>not&lt;/em> helping matters here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It (among a number of other plotlines in these books) are yet a bit more of Rachel being so sure she&amp;rsquo;s right and never quite taking responsibility for when that goes sidewise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jenks? I am &lt;em>so&lt;/em> glad to see him back again. The whole running off because of not being trusted last book, I get that. But Jenks is just so fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Plan B?&amp;rdquo; Ivy said. &amp;ldquo;What is plan B?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
Jenks reddened. &amp;ldquo;Grab the fish and run like hell,&amp;rdquo; he muttered, and I almost giggled.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And now there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em>whole lot more&lt;/em> Jenks. Which &amp;hellip; kind of weird and I don&amp;rsquo;t really get it. I do wonder if that&amp;rsquo;s going to be a recurring theme or was a one off. Half-related, the entire premise that Pixies only live ~20 years and Jenks is just about there? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to deal with this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a fun read and I appreciated a new set of problems. Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: Trent&amp;rsquo;s near complete absense was a bit strange. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s not his flavor of nonsense going on this time around, so it makes sense. But on the other hand, we have crime and rare artifacts, I fully expected that to bring him in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every Which Way But Dead</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/14/every-which-way-but-dead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/14/every-which-way-but-dead/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And oh, that climax. This is most certainly going to come back and bite Rachel. But honestly, what other choice did she even have?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; me, re: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/08/the-good-the-bad-and-the-undead/">The Good, the Bad, and the Undead&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that vampire/demon business of the previous book? Causing all sorts of chaos this time around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel, remaining entirely &lt;em>absolutely sure she is right about everything to the detriment of everyone around her&lt;/em>? Also chaos-causing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick-trauma and Rachel not realizing that &amp;rsquo;thing never done before&amp;rsquo; was causing some serious issues? Chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick is out of town, so totally platonic date with Kristen&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Who apparently has murdered people, because&amp;hellip; duh? Vampire?&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, but he promised not to do it anymore. Chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do appreciate seeing Demon Al as an actual &lt;em>demon&lt;/em>. Holding a prisoner for a thousand years. I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting for an attempted redemption arc there, but as it is it &lt;em>feels good&lt;/em> when Rachel gets one over on him. And Ceri has some interesting potential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh these books. Onwards!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Good, the Bad, and the Undead</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/08/the-good-the-bad-and-the-undead/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/08/the-good-the-bad-and-the-undead/</guid><description>&lt;p>And away we go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/">Dead Witch Walking&lt;/a> set up the world, it&amp;rsquo;s here where we really start setting up Rachel Morgan and go as investigators in their own right. And of course, they&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled right into a serial killer targeting leyline witches. Good times that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is quite the cast of characters this time around. Trent Kamalack is back and as morally &amp;rsquo;totally morally gray, but maybe for good reasons&amp;rsquo; kind of person&amp;ndash;and we do get to learn the what/why he is, which is neat.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Come work for me, and I’ll tell you.”&lt;br>
My eyes went to his. “You are a thief, a cheat, a murderer, and a not-nice man,” I said calmly. “I don’t like you.”&lt;br>
He shrugged, the motion making him look utterly harmless. “I’m not a thief,” he said. “And I don’t mind manipulating you into working for me when I need it.” He smiled, showing me perfect teeth. “I enjoy it, actually.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Head local vamp Piscary is scary and understated. Rachel&amp;rsquo;s mother is wacky. Her father&amp;hellip; had secrets. And Nick&amp;hellip; well, I&amp;rsquo;m happy if Rachel is happy, but that is so not going to go well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, getting more into what exactly layline magic is, how demons work in this world (parallel reality that&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em>really&lt;/em> Hell go!), how these vampires are different, and more &amp;lsquo;humans are terrified of tomatoes&amp;rsquo; than you can shake a stick at. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun world and I always like seeing how many different ways you can turn common tropes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On another hand&amp;hellip; man Rachel is kind of an idiot sometimes. She&amp;rsquo;s so absolutely sure shre&amp;rsquo;s right even when &lt;em>everyone&lt;/em> around her is trying to get her see the truth. Oy that was frustrating. One would htink that trying to set out on her own would make her a little more risk averse&amp;ndash;but I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s not in the cards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And oh, that climax. This is most certainly going to come back and bite Rachel. But honestly, what other choice did she even have?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun series and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to keep going. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dead Witch Walking</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Making a spell is easy. It&amp;rsquo;s trusting you did it right that&amp;rsquo;s hard.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another new (to me) urban fantasy in a &amp;rsquo;the supernatural world has been made public&amp;rsquo; world? Yes please!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, we have Rachel a witch and, as of the start of the story, bounty hunter. Frustrated with her job, she decides to quit.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I sighed. I hated the maze of bureaucracy with a passion, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found the best way to deal with it is to smile and act stupid. That way, no one gets confused.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And in this world, you just &lt;em>don&amp;rsquo;t do that&lt;/em>. So now she&amp;rsquo;s gone from bounty hunter to having a price oh &lt;em>her&lt;/em> head, backed only by her friend(ish) and former co-worker, living Vamp Ivy and Jenks&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, a four-inch tall pixie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, she&amp;rsquo;s also stumbling into a super natural drug trade, a whole rat fighting ring (from impressively up close and personal), and summoned demons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel is a lot of fun. Perfectly competent and willing to fight for it, even if things don&amp;rsquo;t always go right. I enjoy Ivy, even if she&amp;rsquo;s still mostly closed off through this book. Room to grow. And Jenks is hilarious. &amp;ldquo;You think my kids just popped out of the ground?&amp;rdquo; and all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worldbuilding is a lot of fun. I always like trying to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s diffrerent about this particular urban fntasty world and there is plenty of that here. Born vampires&amp;ndash;&lt;em>living&lt;/em> and only turning more traditional after death. Pixies and fairies, running their own smaller scale wars over garden space. Genetic engineering run amuck&amp;ndash;leading to a perfectly reasonable fear of tomatoes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite a a world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it&amp;rsquo;s fun to have the main character be a witch. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely certain how much of a witch&amp;rsquo;s magic is natural versus learned just yet, but mostly human magic user is always a fun point of view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far I&amp;rsquo;m cautiously optimistic. I do love a good urban fantasy. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun world (with openly acknowledged supernatural characters!) with fun characters and a lot of room to grow. And grow it did&amp;ndash;with 18 out as of now&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>