<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Hollows on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-hollows/</link><description>Recent content in The Hollows on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-hollows/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Fistful of Charms</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/a-fistful-of-charms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/a-fistful-of-charms/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, enough vampire/demon nonsense for a moment, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about weres.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>As the joke goes, you don’t have to be faster than the wolf chasing you, just faster than everyone else running away.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Turns out that trying to get letter-of-the-law against multiple packs of werewolves has consequences. For everyone involved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick&amp;hellip; is a real piece of work. I will grant him the one small saving grace that he (along with most of the world) thought Rachel dead as part of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/14/every-which-way-but-dead/">Every Which Way But Dead&lt;/a>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&amp;hellip; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make him any better a person. At least Rachel eventually realizes it? Sort of. Mostly. Ish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel and Ivy&amp;hellip; come to a serious head in this book. Which went about as badly as I expected. I do wish the best for Ivy, but she certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t make that easy at times and Rachel is &lt;em>not&lt;/em> helping matters here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It (among a number of other plotlines in these books) are yet a bit more of Rachel being so sure she&amp;rsquo;s right and never quite taking responsibility for when that goes sidewise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jenks? I am &lt;em>so&lt;/em> glad to see him back again. The whole running off because of not being trusted last book, I get that. But Jenks is just so fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Plan B?&amp;rdquo; Ivy said. &amp;ldquo;What is plan B?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
Jenks reddened. &amp;ldquo;Grab the fish and run like hell,&amp;rdquo; he muttered, and I almost giggled.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And now there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em>whole lot more&lt;/em> Jenks. Which &amp;hellip; kind of weird and I don&amp;rsquo;t really get it. I do wonder if that&amp;rsquo;s going to be a recurring theme or was a one off. Half-related, the entire premise that Pixies only live ~20 years and Jenks is just about there? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to deal with this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a fun read and I appreciated a new set of problems. Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: Trent&amp;rsquo;s near complete absense was a bit strange. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s not his flavor of nonsense going on this time around, so it makes sense. But on the other hand, we have crime and rare artifacts, I fully expected that to bring him in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Every Which Way But Dead</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/14/every-which-way-but-dead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/14/every-which-way-but-dead/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And oh, that climax. This is most certainly going to come back and bite Rachel. But honestly, what other choice did she even have?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; me, re: &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/08/the-good-the-bad-and-the-undead/">The Good, the Bad, and the Undead&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that vampire/demon business of the previous book? Causing all sorts of chaos this time around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel, remaining entirely &lt;em>absolutely sure she is right about everything to the detriment of everyone around her&lt;/em>? Also chaos-causing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick-trauma and Rachel not realizing that &amp;rsquo;thing never done before&amp;rsquo; was causing some serious issues? Chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nick is out of town, so totally platonic date with Kristen&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Who apparently has murdered people, because&amp;hellip; duh? Vampire?&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, but he promised not to do it anymore. Chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do appreciate seeing Demon Al as an actual &lt;em>demon&lt;/em>. Holding a prisoner for a thousand years. I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting for an attempted redemption arc there, but as it is it &lt;em>feels good&lt;/em> when Rachel gets one over on him. And Ceri has some interesting potential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh these books. Onwards!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Good, the Bad, and the Undead</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/08/the-good-the-bad-and-the-undead/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/08/the-good-the-bad-and-the-undead/</guid><description>&lt;p>And away we go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/">Dead Witch Walking&lt;/a> set up the world, it&amp;rsquo;s here where we really start setting up Rachel Morgan and go as investigators in their own right. And of course, they&amp;rsquo;ve stumbled right into a serial killer targeting leyline witches. Good times that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is quite the cast of characters this time around. Trent Kamalack is back and as morally &amp;rsquo;totally morally gray, but maybe for good reasons&amp;rsquo; kind of person&amp;ndash;and we do get to learn the what/why he is, which is neat.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Come work for me, and I’ll tell you.”&lt;br>
My eyes went to his. “You are a thief, a cheat, a murderer, and a not-nice man,” I said calmly. “I don’t like you.”&lt;br>
He shrugged, the motion making him look utterly harmless. “I’m not a thief,” he said. “And I don’t mind manipulating you into working for me when I need it.” He smiled, showing me perfect teeth. “I enjoy it, actually.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Head local vamp Piscary is scary and understated. Rachel&amp;rsquo;s mother is wacky. Her father&amp;hellip; had secrets. And Nick&amp;hellip; well, I&amp;rsquo;m happy if Rachel is happy, but that is so not going to go well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, getting more into what exactly layline magic is, how demons work in this world (parallel reality that&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em>really&lt;/em> Hell go!), how these vampires are different, and more &amp;lsquo;humans are terrified of tomatoes&amp;rsquo; than you can shake a stick at. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun world and I always like seeing how many different ways you can turn common tropes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On another hand&amp;hellip; man Rachel is kind of an idiot sometimes. She&amp;rsquo;s so absolutely sure shre&amp;rsquo;s right even when &lt;em>everyone&lt;/em> around her is trying to get her see the truth. Oy that was frustrating. One would htink that trying to set out on her own would make her a little more risk averse&amp;ndash;but I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s not in the cards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And oh, that climax. This is most certainly going to come back and bite Rachel. But honestly, what other choice did she even have?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun series and I&amp;rsquo;m happy to keep going. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dead Witch Walking</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/02/dead-witch-walking/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Making a spell is easy. It&amp;rsquo;s trusting you did it right that&amp;rsquo;s hard.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another new (to me) urban fantasy in a &amp;rsquo;the supernatural world has been made public&amp;rsquo; world? Yes please!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, we have Rachel a witch and, as of the start of the story, bounty hunter. Frustrated with her job, she decides to quit.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I sighed. I hated the maze of bureaucracy with a passion, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found the best way to deal with it is to smile and act stupid. That way, no one gets confused.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And in this world, you just &lt;em>don&amp;rsquo;t do that&lt;/em>. So now she&amp;rsquo;s gone from bounty hunter to having a price oh &lt;em>her&lt;/em> head, backed only by her friend(ish) and former co-worker, living Vamp Ivy and Jenks&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, a four-inch tall pixie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, she&amp;rsquo;s also stumbling into a super natural drug trade, a whole rat fighting ring (from impressively up close and personal), and summoned demons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel is a lot of fun. Perfectly competent and willing to fight for it, even if things don&amp;rsquo;t always go right. I enjoy Ivy, even if she&amp;rsquo;s still mostly closed off through this book. Room to grow. And Jenks is hilarious. &amp;ldquo;You think my kids just popped out of the ground?&amp;rdquo; and all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worldbuilding is a lot of fun. I always like trying to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s diffrerent about this particular urban fntasty world and there is plenty of that here. Born vampires&amp;ndash;&lt;em>living&lt;/em> and only turning more traditional after death. Pixies and fairies, running their own smaller scale wars over garden space. Genetic engineering run amuck&amp;ndash;leading to a perfectly reasonable fear of tomatoes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite a a world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it&amp;rsquo;s fun to have the main character be a witch. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely certain how much of a witch&amp;rsquo;s magic is natural versus learned just yet, but mostly human magic user is always a fun point of view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far I&amp;rsquo;m cautiously optimistic. I do love a good urban fantasy. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun world (with openly acknowledged supernatural characters!) with fun characters and a lot of room to grow. And grow it did&amp;ndash;with 18 out as of now&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>