<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2024 Movie Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2024-movie-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2024 Movie Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2024-movie-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alita: Battle Angel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/13/alita-battle-angel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/13/alita-battle-angel/</guid><description>&lt;p>That is a very pretty movie. The city had a great aesthetic. I loved the variety of cyborgs, many just trying to live their lives (in the background) or&amp;hellip; becoming ridiculously overdone weapons platforms. And I especially loved Motorball!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, Rosa Salazar as Alita really carried the show. I actually really enjoyed the oversized eyes (true to the manga apparently?) and her whole way of interacting with the world, the way she fights, the way she &lt;em>moves&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating combination of innocence and excellence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that&amp;hellip; I wanted to like Christoph Walz&amp;rsquo;s Dr. Ido more than I did&amp;ndash;he&amp;rsquo;s generally a wonderful actor, but I feel he just didn&amp;rsquo;t have much to do. Likwise, Jennifer Connelly&amp;rsquo;s Chiren. I did enjoy Mahershala Alis&amp;rsquo; Vector and most of the evil cyborgs. They did a good job of evil/menacing!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise? Straight forward. And the ending&amp;hellip; really is asking for a sequel that so far as I know isn&amp;rsquo;t coming. It&amp;rsquo;d be neat! But you can&amp;rsquo;t just end a movie like that! Really leaves a poor taste on an otherwise quiet enjoyable movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/02/deadpool-wolverine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/02/deadpool-wolverine/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so here it is, (almost) the entire reason I rewatched &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/26/deadpool/">Deadpool&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/28/deadpool-2/">Deadpool 2&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much exactly what you get if you took the (crass) humor of Deadpool, jammed in as many cameos as you could, and shoved it into the modern &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-cinematic-universe/">MCU&lt;/a>, multiverse, TVA, and all&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Deadpool: Welcome to the MCU. You&amp;rsquo;re joining at a bit of a low point.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m still not &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> sure if that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadpool 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/28/deadpool-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/28/deadpool-2/</guid><description>language warning (duh?)
Well that certainly started with a bang.
After the surprsing (to some I suppose) success of Deadpool, of course they&amp;rsquo;re going to make another. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; pretty much exactly what you&amp;rsquo;d expect if you took Deadpool and turned it up to, well, as far as Cable&amp;rsquo;s gun goes. 😄
We have more X-Men! Well, we have Yukio. And a delightful blink and you&amp;rsquo;ll miss it group cameo. And Cable!</description></item><item><title>Deadpool</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/26/deadpool/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/26/deadpool/</guid><description>language warning (duh?)
Oh hey, Deadpool &amp;amp; Wolverine is out on streaming (and it&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I reviewed or even watched a movie). Let&amp;rsquo;s rewatch these!
From the studio that inexplicably sewed his fucking mouth shut the first time comes five-time Academy Award viewer, Ryan Reynolds in an eHarmony date with destiny. Ladies and gentlemen, I give you&amp;hellip; me! Deadpool.
I&amp;hellip; totally forgot that this movie starts with the highway shootout scene that made the demo reel.</description></item><item><title>Ponyo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/04/ponyo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/04/ponyo/</guid><description>&lt;p>That is a strange movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s slower movie, with a magical style to the animation that&amp;rsquo;s both truly beautiful and surprisingly terrifying at times. The plot is somewhere between simple and mostly absent and the characters are mostly&amp;ndash;there?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it was fascinating to catch in theaters as part of the &lt;a href="https://gkids.com/ghiblifest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Studio Ghibli Fest 2024&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; but not really something I&amp;rsquo;d ever choose to watch again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such is life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Across the Spider-Verse</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/30/spider-man-across-the-spider-verse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/30/spider-man-across-the-spider-verse/</guid><description>&lt;p>I still think the first one was the better movie, but man I still enjoyed this one. Biggest negative: I&amp;rsquo;d totally forgotten this is a part one / to be continued. That was&amp;hellip; not fun to find out right at the end with no current release date for the next sequel!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a great film. I love seeing more of Miles and Gwen, especially a couple of years later. I love the introduction to even more Spider-People (and not-people even, oh Peter Parkedcar) and the introduction of even more multiverse concepts that brings to mind. And the idea that there are fixed points in each Spider&amp;rsquo;s story that makes them who they are is great fuel, both for this and I hope the eventual sequel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Visually, this story once again shines. I love seeing all the different styles, especially when you have more than one on screen at once.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now, on seeing this, I learn that Marvel 2099 with more Miguel O&amp;rsquo;Hara is a thing. I should read that next!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward! (And hopefully not too long to a sequel.)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>