<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Trials of Apollo on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/11/17/the-trials-of-apollo/</link><description>Recent content in The Trials of Apollo on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/11/17/the-trials-of-apollo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Burning Maze</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/11/17/the-burning-maze/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/11/17/the-burning-maze/</guid><description>&lt;p>On one hand, the Apollo books are getting better. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly more of the same, bringing myths to life in the real world combined with a constant sense of the world ending, but if that&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for &amp;hellip; power to you?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then there&amp;rsquo;s a prophecy that &lt;span class="spoiler">either Pipe or Jason&lt;/span>
 is going to die. Of course you expect they&amp;rsquo;ll figure out a way around it&amp;hellip; Apollo is a (former?) god of prophecy after all? But madman that Riordan is, he actually does it. Ow. That was not at all what I expected to see in one of these books. Given the Doors of Death etc we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in these series, it&amp;rsquo;s still possible they&amp;rsquo;ll figure out a work around&amp;hellip; but still. Wow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Dark Prophecy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/27/the-dark-prophecy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/27/the-dark-prophecy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/10/27/the-dark-prophecy/">The Dark Prophecy&lt;/a> is straight up a sequal to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/30/the-hidden-oracle/">The Hidden Oracle&lt;/a>. Pretty much all of my comments from apply here. Apollo is still a decent but not great main character, Meg is still odd and weirdly powerful. The world still feels like something we&amp;rsquo;ve seen done better in Riordan&amp;rsquo;s other series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The main different of the Dark Prophecy and the part that amused me the most: it&amp;rsquo;s almost completely set in Indianapolis. You don&amp;rsquo;t get that overly often in fiction and it&amp;rsquo;s always amusing to see it done. For someone that lives within spitting distance of Indianapolis, close enough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hidden Oracle</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/30/the-hidden-oracle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/30/the-hidden-oracle/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/30/the-hidden-oracle/">The Hidden Oracle&lt;/a> is an odd book. As a second sequel series to first &lt;em>Percy Jackson and the Olympians&lt;/em> and then the &lt;em>The Lost Hero&lt;/em>, we do get new main characters characters: Apollo, now in mortal form and Meg, surprisingly powerful plant magic demigod with some cool Roman swords. But we also get a number of guest appearances and references to previous characters: especially Percy Jackson himself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting have a setting and characters we can relate to to help ground us in the new series, but on the other hand, if I wanted to read about Percy Jackson, couldn&amp;rsquo;t I just read his series again? I remember having the same problem with Heroes of Olympus.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>