<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R.J. Barker on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/02/r.j.-barker/</link><description>Recent content in R.J. Barker on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/02/r.j.-barker/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Bone Ship's Wake</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/02/the-bone-ships-wake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/02/the-bone-ships-wake/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And what is life for us if we are not lurching from one life-or-death situation to another?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Maes is MIA and Joron picks up the slack in quite the way&amp;ndash;as the well named Black Pirate. It&amp;rsquo;s such a huge growth to see from him, from the very beginning when he and Maes first met and probably the best part of the books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also great to see how the increasing worldbuilding around the Guillame and the Keyshan come to bear. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more there than the reader or the characters really had to deal with at first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, I do feel somewhat let down by the latter half of the book. There&amp;rsquo;s an awful lot of interesting in the beginning; however, as everything builds and builds, despite plenty of action&amp;ndash;the story just sort of ends. I feel like there could have been more, but so it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Call of the Bone Ships</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/23/call-of-the-bone-ships/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/23/call-of-the-bone-ships/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/03/the-bone-ships/">The Bone Ships&lt;/a>&lt;/em> introduced us to the world&amp;ndash;where the bones of gigantic sea dragons once provided the building materials for ships, with hints of something even darker and more interesting going on in the background.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Call of the Bones Ships&lt;/em> takes up that up another level, really digging more into the often twisted politics and future of the world. It manages to give us quite a bit more insight into Joron Twiner, who is forced rather handedly to come into his own&amp;ndash;with whatever that ends up meaning&amp;ndash;and torturing him rather much along the way. We also get a lot of more of the gullaime (and the Gullaime specifically). There&amp;rsquo;s still a lot more to unpack there, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking for the third.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It ends up being rather a darker book, which fits even better as the successor to the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, wonderful worldbuilding, a darker tone, fascinating characters, and worth the re-read. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bone Ships</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/03/the-bone-ships/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/03/the-bone-ships/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating bit of worldbuilding. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a world (or at least story) dominated by naval superiority&amp;ndash;brought about by ships built on the literal bones of sea dragons. And what&amp;rsquo;s more, the sea dragons appear to have been hunted to extinction, making the warships all the more rare and valuable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a very cool root for the story and Barker only takes it from there with unique twists on vocab and word choice, a few other interesting bits of magic, and more naval everything than you can shake some paint at.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do quite enjoy the characters as well. Setting the story around a prison ship? Not that unusual, but I really do love how much Barker makes the reader care for the people on it&amp;ndash;and to see them grow together as a grow. Lucky Maes is of course awesome as well&amp;ndash;and I do love the more alien birdman. Want to see what more is going on there for sure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a great book and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have read it. Onward to the sequels!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>