<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Janci Patterson on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/janci-patterson/</link><description>Recent content in Janci Patterson on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/janci-patterson/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bastille vs. the Evil Librarians</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/11/bastille-vs.-the-evil-librarians/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/11/bastille-vs.-the-evil-librarians/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends. Again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the events of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/23/the-dark-talent/">The Dark Talent&lt;/a>, Alcatraz isn&amp;rsquo;t doing so well&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, the Talents are still gone, several Smedrys are dead&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, and the world is about to end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So of course we have one last adventure. Chock full of impossible situations, anti-gravity sharks, a Gak, &lt;em>so&lt;/em> many straw puns&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, and an army of kittens&lt;sup id="fnref:5">&lt;a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, romance&lt;sup id="fnref:6">&lt;a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, and a big battle on top of a giant glass spire in the middle of the ocean!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that was kind of odd to me (having read &lt;em>almost&lt;/em> all of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s works at this point) is how the fine details of the magic system never quite came together&amp;ndash;and now they probably never will. The talents are a lot of fun, magic glass is neat&lt;sup id="fnref:7">&lt;a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">7&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;sup id="fnref:8">&lt;a href="#fn:8" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">8&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, and somehow they are related&amp;hellip; but how does it all work? Is Alcatraz right? Where did it come from?! I know it&amp;rsquo;s not a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-cosmere/">Cosmere&lt;/a> novel, so it gets a bit of a bye for that, but I wanted more. So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, compared to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/23/the-dark-talent/">The Dark Talent&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s actually an ending, which I greatly appreciate. Other than that, I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s a weaker entry into the series. Still a lot of fun to read and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have finally gotten to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;sup id="fnref:9">&lt;a href="#fn:9" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">9&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Evershore</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/25/evershore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/25/evershore/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Like the Saint says, if you don’t have anything to say, you might scare your flightleader into thinking you’re dead.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The one with Jerkface and the Kitsen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like all of the Starsight novellas, we have a focus on what else has been going on while Spena has been doing her &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/cytonic/">Cytonic&lt;/a> things. This time&amp;ndash;as you might guess&amp;ndash;with Jerkface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s actually really great to see his point of view and especially to see just how much he&amp;rsquo;s grown throughout the books. He was always a leader, but he&amp;rsquo;s really coming into it now&amp;ndash;and really realizing that sometimes, just maybe, the books might be &lt;em>wrong&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do also love seeing more of the Kitsen. They&amp;rsquo;re really building up a regular anti-Superiority alliance there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the biggest bummer now is having to wait for Defiant to come out this November&amp;hellip; Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ReDawn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/redawn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/redawn/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A prisoner could be convinced that they lived in a paradise, if the prison was pretty enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>ReDawn is a lot like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/">Sunreach&lt;/a> in that it&amp;rsquo;s a cousin to the main Skyward books, really expanding the universe and letting us know what the rest of Skyward flight (and others) were getting up to while Spensa was&amp;hellip; otherwise occupied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around&amp;hellip; the point of view is Alanik, the near human alien that crashed into Detritus right at the beginning of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/">Starsight&lt;/a>, enabling the events of that book.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I didn’t know enough about human politics to know who was correct, but I did know enough about politics in general to guess that everyone would interpret the law in the way that best suited themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s facinating to have a point of view from someone who grew up in this universe on an alien world (bubbles of air around giant trees!) with an alien culture&amp;ndash;that in this case is actually tied to humanity throughout the past. It gives us a way to dig more into the relationships (especially the &amp;lsquo;relationships&amp;rsquo;) between the humans all the more, which I enjoyed a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;hellip; learning more about the Taynix / slugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty fun story, well worth it&amp;rsquo;s place as a Skyward sidestory novella!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunreach</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s cute. Part teenage romance, part &amp;lsquo;how in the world do we take care of these random alien slugs anyways&amp;rsquo;. Well worth a piece of the Skyward universe.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>