<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ada Hoffmann on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ada-hoffmann/</link><description>Recent content in Ada Hoffmann on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:05:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/ada-hoffmann/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Infinite</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/the-infinite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/the-infinite/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that&amp;rsquo;s quite a conclusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You’re creating hell. And you’re putting yourself inside it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NEMESIS-1’s tone was serene. “Hell is the optimal solution.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-outside/">The Outside&lt;/a>, humanity found something Outside of the Gods&amp;rsquo; influence and managed to tear apart a large part of the world of Jai. In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/28/the-fallen/">The Fallen&lt;/a>, they learned to live with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/04/the-infinite/">The Infinite&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s time to learn more about the Gods themselves&amp;ndash;what they really are and how they came to be&amp;hellip; and perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s time for the Gods&amp;rsquo; reigns to end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating story and, in my opinion, perhaps the best of the trilogy. At once, we get answers for just what lead to the world that the characters live in now&amp;ndash;while at the same time opening so many more questions. What happened in the 700 years between the earliest and latest points of view in the book? What&amp;rsquo;s going on in the rest of the universe? And what happens next?!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But so far as this single story, it&amp;rsquo;s finished and well done. I always do applaud authors able to do that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Fallen</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/28/the-fallen/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/28/the-fallen/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ooh boy. After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-outside/">The Outside&lt;/a> set up the world and characters, ending with &amp;rsquo;the Outside&amp;rsquo; coming in and wrecking havoc on the planet Jai, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what was next but I surely wanted to find out&amp;hellip; I even noted in that review that there were sequels, and yet somehow I never got around to reading them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did now. This is a wonderfully weird (at times) ride into what happened next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once again, I think that one thing that the Fallen does well is dealing with all manner of diversity (particularly in the neuro- space). People are people. And it really makes you think: what if we actually could live in a society where people just expect to meet others where they are and &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s okay&lt;/em>. Everyone has their own strengths and weaknesses and things that make their skin crawl. And &lt;em>that&amp;rsquo;s okay&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see a book really dig into that, all along the backdrop of super powerful AI &amp;lsquo;Gods&amp;rsquo;, their Angels (who have issues all thier own), and monsters (who, it turns out, are sometimes people as well, just a fair bit further away from the &amp;rsquo;norm&amp;rsquo;) from outside space and time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a really solid sequel. Honestly, I loved it even more than the first book. Well, well worth a read. I really look forward to what&amp;rsquo;s next.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Outside</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/21/the-outside/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/21/the-outside/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Well, it did what Outside usually did in stories. Showed up. Violated all the known laws of physics. Killed some people and drove the rest mad.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s certainly an interesting book. It&amp;rsquo;s one part autism as &amp;lsquo;different, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay and sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s a superpower and sometimes it sucks&amp;rsquo;, one part cosmic horror, and one part fascinating worldbuilding with technoreligion writ large.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it didn&amp;rsquo;t quite feel finished to me. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of setup, but the ending drew somewhere between a true horror ending and something much &amp;lsquo;better&amp;rsquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s potential for a sequel there, but without it, it could have been better. Still an enjoyable enough read.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>