<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lev Grossman on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/lev-grossman/</link><description>Recent content in Lev Grossman on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/lev-grossman/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Magician's Land</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/25/the-magicians-land/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/25/the-magicians-land/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It didn’t matter where you were, if you were in a room full of books you were at least halfway home.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/16/the-magicians/">The Magicians&lt;/a>, we had half Harry Potter &lt;em>but cynical&lt;/em> and half Narnia&amp;hellip; &lt;em>but cynical&lt;/em>. In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/20/the-magician-king/">The Magician King&lt;/a>, we mostly stuck around in Fillory (the Narnia analogue). But right at the end&amp;hellip; our well loved (:sarcasm:) main character Quentin pays the ultimate price: he doesn&amp;rsquo;t get to hang out in the magical land anymore and has to go home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Magician&amp;rsquo;s Land picks up from there, with one plot following Quentin as he settles back into a normal life, becomes a teacher, promptly gets fired, and descends to a life of crime. As one does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, we have the (new and improved?) Kings and Queens of Fillory dealingw ith their own sort of armageddon. Turns out saving magic&amp;hellip; wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Magician King</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/20/the-magician-king/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/20/the-magician-king/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>That was the thing about the world: it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that things were harder than you thought they were going to be, it was that they were hard in ways that you didn&amp;rsquo;t expect.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Turns out, if you take &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/16/the-magicians/">The Magicians&lt;/a>, tone down Quentin a bit, and cut the magic school parts to focus mostly on Fillory and adventuring, you get a much better book. It&amp;rsquo;s still a bit much at times and definitely has some &amp;lsquo;middle book syndrome&amp;rsquo; going on, but I quite enjoyed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you didn&amp;rsquo;t like the Magicians, you might like this book. If you liked it, particularly the second half, this is probably right up your alley.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Magicians</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/16/the-magicians/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/16/the-magicians/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I got my heart&amp;rsquo;s desire, and there my troubles began.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well. The majority of comments certainly nailed this one. Two interesting premises in a trenchcoat wrapped in the guise of cynicism and dark humor, underscored by the most depressed to the point of hard to read main character I think I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a long time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interesting enough I&amp;rsquo;ll give the sequel a try (I really liked the ending twists(ish)). I wish it were better.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>