<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MCU TV on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-tv/</link><description>Recent content in MCU TV on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-tv/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Werewolf by Night</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/05/werewolf-by-night/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/05/werewolf-by-night/</guid><description>&lt;p>I managed to skip by this last fall, much to my now dismay. It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;ndash;only sort of an MCU special; focused on the monster/&amp;lsquo;horror&amp;rsquo; side of Marvel comics rather than the super-hero business. They do open with a sillouette of the heroes we know and love&amp;hellip; before all color drains out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What comes next? An introduction to a monster hunting family/society and a competition to win the mysterious &amp;lsquo;Bloodstone&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;which gives you a sort of power over/against monsters. And then&amp;ndash;the HUNT/BATTLE ROYALE!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>She-Hulk: Attorney at Law</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/14/she-hulk-attorney-at-law/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/14/she-hulk-attorney-at-law/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not easy being green.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a strange one. She&amp;rsquo;s the Hulk&amp;rsquo;s cousin. One things lead to another, and she gets all Hulked out&amp;hellip; but without any of the downsides?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The contrast between being a Hulk and being a lawyer (and being a big green lawyer) is pretty cool, Tatiana Maslany does a wonderful job in the titular role, and it was great fun to see Tim Roth&amp;rsquo;s Abomination again, not to mention Charlie Cox&amp;rsquo;s Daredevil. Fun casting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a really weird show. And they&amp;rsquo;re rather solidly into the whoe 4th wall breaking thing, which is kind of amusing. Weird. But amusing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I enjoyed the show. Not my favorite of the MCU TV shows, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have watched it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Am Groot</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/28/i-am-groot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/28/i-am-groot/</guid><description>&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re ~3 minute shorts (with 3+ minutes of credits each) about a young reincarnation of a tree-person who can&amp;rsquo;t talk, other than to say &amp;lsquo;I Am Groot&amp;rsquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I was expecting, but for what they are&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;re cute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth the 15 minutes to watch them all. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ms. Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ms. Marvel is not particularly earth-shattering. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t deal with the end of the world and only barely with the greater MCU (although there is a decent bit of &amp;lsquo;how the world changes with superheroes in it, like Ant-Man&amp;rsquo;s podcast and Avengercon).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What it is though? A awful lot of fun. Iman Vellani as Kamala Khan is just an absolute delight and really looks like she had a great time in the role. The whole supporting cast is great as well, especially Kamala&amp;rsquo;s family and friends Bruno and Nakia.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Kamala Khan: [whispers] I&amp;rsquo;m a super hero.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[She runs off gleefully]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed this. Especially when it leaned into the Muslim + Pakistani culture and the family dynamics of the whole thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: I don’t need anyone on my side. I’m not even concerned if God is on my side as long as I am on His side. God is always right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Agent Deever: I don’t have time for Quranic quotes. Excuse me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: Actually, that was Abraham Lincoln.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The big fights and greater threats were kind of cheesey and didn&amp;rsquo;t mesh as well (especially the big showpiece in the final episode), but the down to earth human parts of being a teenager superhero? Awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so hard to rank these any more, since there&amp;rsquo;s just so much to love in the MCU. I think Ms. Marvel ends up pretty squarely in the middle of the pack&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;d still say it&amp;rsquo;s worth a watch. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moon Knight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/moon-knight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/moon-knight/</guid><description>&lt;p>That &amp;hellip; was truly bizarre. A main character with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/dissociative%20identity%20disorder">dissociative identity disorder&lt;/a> where their powers deal with but &lt;em>are not&lt;/em> caused by their disorder is fascinating (and truly weird to be watching at the same time as &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/01/altered-carbon-season-1/">Altered Carbon: Season 1&lt;/a>&amp;hellip;), the Egyptian background and characters are great, and there&amp;rsquo;s are some pretty awesome scenes, fight and otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Castingwise, Oscar Isaac is awesome. I&amp;rsquo;m amazed at how he brings both Marc and Steven to life. Ethan Hawke is a great maybe-baddie-but-maybe-just-a-different-point-of-view. And May Calamawy as Layla El-Faouly is a real stand out in just about everyway. I hope that we get to see more of them in the greater MCU, although I have no idea how that&amp;rsquo;s going to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of which, this was so different from other MCU properties. It&amp;rsquo;s got Egyptian gods and powers more or less walking around, which fits, but I do really wander how/if we&amp;rsquo;d see them or their avatars square off against normal MCU level heroes. Tonally, it&amp;rsquo;s rather different too. There&amp;rsquo;s still an end of the world threat, but a lot of it&amp;rsquo;s dealing with the internal struggles of Steven/Marc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s probably my favorite of the MCU TV shows so far&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll have to rewatch it and see if it holds up. It&amp;rsquo;s really quite good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hawkeye</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/22/hawkeye/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/22/hawkeye/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really enjoyed Hawkeye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s just &lt;em>fun&lt;/em>, which compared to &lt;em>Wandvision&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Loki&lt;/em> and really even &lt;em>What If&amp;hellip;&lt;/em> is a worthwhile goal and really does a lot to show off the more human scale of superheroes. It&amp;rsquo;s never really made much sense that Hawkeye and Black Widow were Avengers&amp;hellip; and it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But they do it anyways. Because what Heroes do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see them building up the new &amp;lsquo;Young Avengers&amp;rsquo; and branching out as much as they are. I think Hailee Steinfeld did a great job, especially when acting against &lt;span class="spoiler">Florence Pugh's Yelena&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What If...?</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</guid><description>What if…?
It&amp;rsquo;s a wacky title, but it sums up the series pretty well. Take what the MCU has spent a decade building on top of half a century of comics before that1. The comics have done all manner of continuity resets and what-ifs, so it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual to see the stories as they could have been&amp;ndash;if only one thing changed. But this is a first for the MCU. I fully expect with the coming Phase 4, we&amp;rsquo;ll see a bit more of this though.</description></item><item><title>Loki</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/</guid><description>Another MCU made for Disney+ TV outing. After the amazing WandaVision and Falcon and the Winter Soldier, Loki had a high bar to clear. In my nutshell: they nailed it.
I am Loki of Asgard, and I am burdened with glorious purpose.
Loki (the character) is fascinating. He started out a well cast mostly villain of his own in Thor and became the first recurring villain in The Avengers. And after that, he&amp;rsquo;s back again and again in each of the Thor and Avengers movies.</description></item><item><title>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/</guid><description>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier basically takes place where Avengers: Endgame left off. Steve Rogers as Captain America has stepped down, leaving his shield to Sam Wilson/The Falcon/the (rumored) future Captain America. And on a superficial level, that&amp;rsquo;s about where it ends: Sam Wilson has the shield and is expected to take up the mantle of Captain America.
But, oh the story it tells along the way.
On one hand, you have the dynamic between titular Falcon and Winter Soldier.</description></item><item><title>WandaVision</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Wanda Maximoff: We are an unusual couple, you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vision: Oh, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that was ever in question.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well. That was most certainly a thing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>