<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MCU TV on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-tv/</link><description>Recent content in MCU TV on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mcu-tv/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moon Knight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/moon-knight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/moon-knight/</guid><description>&lt;p>That &amp;hellip; was truly bizarre. A main character with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/dissociative%20identity%20disorder">dissociative identity disorder&lt;/a> where their powers deal with but &lt;em>are not&lt;/em> caused by their disorder is fascinating (and truly weird to be watching at the same time as &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/01/altered-carbon-season-1/">Altered Carbon: Season 1&lt;/a>&amp;hellip;), the Egyptian background and characters are great, and there&amp;rsquo;s are some pretty awesome scenes, fight and otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Castingwise, Oscar Isaac is awesome. I&amp;rsquo;m amazed at how he brings both Marc and Steven to life. Ethan Hawke is a great maybe-baddie-but-maybe-just-a-different-point-of-view. And May Calamawy as Layla El-Faouly is a real stand out in just about everyway. I hope that we get to see more of them in the greater MCU, although I have no idea how that&amp;rsquo;s going to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of which, this was so different from other MCU properties. It&amp;rsquo;s got Egyptian gods and powers more or less walking around, which fits, but I do really wander how/if we&amp;rsquo;d see them or their avatars square off against normal MCU level heroes. Tonally, it&amp;rsquo;s rather different too. There&amp;rsquo;s still an end of the world threat, but a lot of it&amp;rsquo;s dealing with the internal struggles of Steven/Marc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s probably my favorite of the MCU TV shows so far&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll have to rewatch it and see if it holds up. It&amp;rsquo;s really quite good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hawkeye</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/22/hawkeye/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/22/hawkeye/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really enjoyed Hawkeye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s just &lt;em>fun&lt;/em>, which compared to &lt;em>Wandvision&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Loki&lt;/em> and really even &lt;em>What If&amp;hellip;&lt;/em> is a worthwhile goal and really does a lot to show off the more human scale of superheroes. It&amp;rsquo;s never really made much sense that Hawkeye and Black Widow were Avengers&amp;hellip; and it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But they do it anyways. Because what Heroes do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s nice to see them building up the new &amp;lsquo;Young Avengers&amp;rsquo; and branching out as much as they are. I think Hailee Steinfeld did a great job, especially when acting against &lt;span class="spoiler">Florence Pugh's Yelena&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What If...?</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/07/what-if.../</guid><description>What if…?
It&amp;rsquo;s a wacky title, but it sums up the series pretty well. Take what the MCU has spent a decade building on top of half a century of comics before that1. The comics have done all manner of continuity resets and what-ifs, so it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual to see the stories as they could have been&amp;ndash;if only one thing changed. But this is a first for the MCU. I fully expect with the coming Phase 4, we&amp;rsquo;ll see a bit more of this though.</description></item><item><title>Loki</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/loki/</guid><description>Another MCU made for Disney+ TV outing. After the amazing WandaVision and Falcon and the Winter Soldier, Loki had a high bar to clear. In my nutshell: they nailed it.
I am Loki of Asgard, and I am burdened with glorious purpose.
Loki (the character) is fascinating. He started out a well cast mostly villain of his own in Thor and became the first recurring villain in The Avengers.</description></item><item><title>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/24/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier/</guid><description>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier basically takes place where Avengers: Endgame left off. Steve Rogers as Captain America has stepped down, leaving his shield to Sam Wilson/The Falcon/the (rumored) future Captain America. And on a superficial level, that&amp;rsquo;s about where it ends: Sam Wilson has the shield and is expected to take up the mantle of Captain America.
But, oh the story it tells along the way.
On one hand, you have the dynamic between titular Falcon and Winter Soldier.</description></item><item><title>WandaVision</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Wanda Maximoff: We are an unusual couple, you know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Vision: Oh, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that was ever in question.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well. That was most certainly a thing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>