<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Darcie Little Badger on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/darcie-little-badger/</link><description>Recent content in Darcie Little Badger on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/darcie-little-badger/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Never Whistle at Night: An Indigenous Dark Fiction Anthology</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/03/never-whistle-at-night-an-indigenous-dark-fiction-anthology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/03/never-whistle-at-night-an-indigenous-dark-fiction-anthology/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Many Indigenous people believe that one should never whistle at night. This belief takes many forms: for instance, Native Hawaiians believe it summons the Hukai’po, the spirits of ancient warriors, and Native Mexicans say it calls Lechuza, a witch that can transform into an owl. But what all these legends hold in common is the certainty that whistling at night can cause evil spirits to appear—and even follow you home.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A collection of two dozen horror (and otherwise dark fiction) stories by a wide variety of indigenous authors. Three of which I&amp;rsquo;d read before:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/rebecca-roanhorse/">Rebecca Roanhorse&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/darcie-little-badger/">Darcie Little Badger&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/cherie-dimaline/">Cherie Dimaline&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Like any anthology there are some stories in here that I didn&amp;rsquo;t care much for&amp;ndash;and some that really hit hard. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating new look (for me) into all sorts of new and interesting creepy things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And all too often, you might just find that people are people. And people are scarier than any monster out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>So, for these next pages, let these writers take you by the hand, lead you into the darkness at the heart of—let me put some quotation marks around it—“America.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>A Snake Falls to Earth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/06/a-snake-falls-to-earth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/06/a-snake-falls-to-earth/</guid><description>&lt;p>I do love stories that take mythology I don&amp;rsquo;t know as well and expands on it. In this case, the Lipan (Apache) people of what became the southwestern US down into Mexico. The idea of a world inhabited by animal people&amp;ndash;those that can shape shift between an animal and a human form&amp;ndash;that was once connected to Earth&amp;hellip; and now is not.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“And if they don’t?” I muttered. “Pfft. You’re a cottonmouth,” she snickered. “Sleep under a bush.” As if to demonstrate, Momma switched from her false form to her true form. She slithered out of her dress and bared curved, venom-filled teeth in my direction, warning me to skedaddle.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>