<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Erik Sommers on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/erik-sommers/</link><description>Recent content in Erik Sommers on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/erik-sommers/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spider-Man: No Way Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/18/spider-man-no-way-home/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Finally got around to watching this. I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did, it&amp;rsquo;s hilarious and an aboslute blast of nostalgia. Similar to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/"&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a&gt;, I don&amp;rsquo;t know know if this would possibly hold up without the weight of all of the movies that came before it (I doubt it), but with that weight&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s really really good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny, it&amp;rsquo;s touching, and there are some really crazy action scenes. But the greatest strength of course comes from &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;bringing back a half dozen villains and all three modern live action Spider-Men into one film&lt;/span&gt;
. Would anyone have believed something that crazy possible, especially before Infinity War/Endgame? I doubt it. But it&amp;rsquo;s quite satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As much as I loved &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/"&gt;Spider-Man: Homecoming&lt;/a&gt;, Spider-Man: Far From Home takes what made it great and turns it up a few levels &lt;em&gt;even further&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One one level, you have Spider-Man being Spider-Man. He&amp;rsquo;s a good kid, trying to make his way in life, trying to deal with the dual life of being a highschooler and being a superhero&amp;ndash;of saving the world and perhaps getting the girl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then you layer all the weight of the greater MCU on top of it. This takes place just after &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/"&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a&gt;. So you have the fallout of Iron Man (Spider-Man&amp;rsquo;s mentor/Uncle Ben figure) being gone and Spider-Man having to step into &lt;em&gt;those&lt;/em&gt; shoes, the first big mention of The Blip&amp;ndash;and how you deal with coming back and the world has changed, and all sorts of dealing with a Nick Fury who&amp;rsquo;s lost several of his heaviest hitters.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Homecoming</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That&lt;/em&gt; is a truly delightful Spider-Man movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird seeing him introduced &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; the events of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/"&gt;Captain America: Civil War&lt;/a&gt;) and completely skipping how he became Spider-Man in the first place&amp;hellip; but it works. I really like the entire plot, dealing with the fallout of the Avengers / super-hero activity and how normal people try to live their lives around it&amp;ndash;and what happens when the powers that be step in and take that away from them. Excellent villain fuel. It&amp;rsquo;s a little silly that &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;the Vulture ends up being Spider-Man's crush's father...&lt;/span&gt;
, but I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s the sort of thing you expect from superhero films. Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid, fun action film.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ant-Man and the Wasp</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ant-Man and his daughter are adorable. Especially with Luis&amp;rsquo; help. Luis is wonderful. Everyone playing Luis as he describes everyone. And Paul Rudd playing Janet van Dyne. Add to that the interactions with/introduction of Jimmy Woo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Lang: Come on, Woo. I&amp;rsquo;ve got three days left. Why would I try to escape?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jimmy Woo: Sorry, Scott, but rules are rules. You trip the perimeter alarm, we search the place. Keel to stern, soup to nuts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>