<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Melissa Marr on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/02/melissa-marr/</link><description>Recent content in Melissa Marr on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/02/melissa-marr/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fragile Eternity</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/02/fragile-eternity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/02/fragile-eternity/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I knew about faeries. They didn’t,” she protested. She hated the faery inability to lie more and more as he spoke. It would be easier to lie and deny how painlessly she had become fey. It would be easier to say that she wasn’t adjusting to her new life far faster than she’d ever thought. It would be easier to say she was struggling. Because then he wouldn’t be doing this to me.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/ink-exchange/">Ink Exchange&lt;/a>, I was worried. For the most part, Fragile Eternity brings it back.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ink Exchange</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/ink-exchange/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/23/ink-exchange/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Getting ink felt right, like it would help her put her life in order, to move forwards. It was her body, despite the things that&amp;rsquo;d been done to it, and she wanted to claim it, to own it, to prove that to herself. She knew it wasn&amp;rsquo;t magic, but the idea of writing her own identity felt like the closest she could get to reclaiming her life. Sometimes there&amp;rsquo;s power in the act; sometimes there&amp;rsquo;s strength in words. She wanted to find an image that represented those things she was feeling, to etch it on her skin as tangible proof of her decision to change.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s not what I expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a sequel to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/02/wicked-lovely/">Wicked Lovely&lt;/a>. In that it&amp;rsquo;s in the same world with many of the same characters and takes place after the events of the first book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; fine? It&amp;rsquo;s interesting, if a bit jarring, to see more of the world and a broader cast of characters. But the plot is ugly, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to root for anyone really, and I missed the continuity you get from sticking with a united point of view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: trigger warning for rape. Off screen, but it&amp;rsquo;s a major plot point of the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll probably try one more in the series, since it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to go back to Ash. We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wicked Lovely</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/12/wicked-lovely/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 17:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/12/wicked-lovely/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s YA Urban Fantasy. Don&amp;rsquo;t go in expecting anything earth shattering&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, wonder what in the world they&amp;rsquo;re all thinking, and have some fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not the best Urban Fantasy I&amp;rsquo;ve read, but it&amp;rsquo;s really not bad. The world-alongside-our-world of the Fae is fairly standard, the romance is mostly predictable, and there are few enough action scenes. But on the other hand, the world feels real enough, I liked Aislinn more than I had any right to, and I&amp;rsquo;m intrigued what happens next. And that&amp;rsquo;s more enough for a quick read in my opinion!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>