<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Secret Projects on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/secret-projects/</link><description>Recent content in Secret Projects on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/secret-projects/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Isles of the Emberdark</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/20/isles-of-the-emberdark/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/09/20/isles-of-the-emberdark/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A trapper, a dragon, a ghost, a feathered man, and a hive mind meet on an island no one can find in a sea that only sort of exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s not even the setup for a joke, but rather a spectacular example of everything the scifi future &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-cosmere/"&gt;The Cosmere&lt;/a&gt; is moving towards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen bits and pieces of Cosmere crossovers and magic turned technology, especially in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/27/the-lost-metal/"&gt;The Lost Metal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-stormlight-archive/"&gt;The Stormlight Archive&lt;/a&gt;, but this is really the first book we&amp;rsquo;ve gotten where the (magi)tech, interworld conflict, and mixmatched crews from many worlds are front and center&amp;ndash;and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At it&amp;rsquo;s core, Isles of the Emberdark is a sequel to the short &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/24/sixth-of-the-dusk/"&gt;Sixth of the Dusk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;which I reread in preparation, although it turns out that wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessary. The entirety of the latter is included as flashback in the former. so it goes. An islander culture, plants and animals that want nothing more than to kill you and eat you (yes, even the plants), and the cost of being left behind as technology runs ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this time around, in addition to Dusk, we also have the aforementioned starship crew. I love a good scifi found family story (this reminds me of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/wayfarers/"&gt;Wayfarers&lt;/a&gt;) with wacky rather different crew growing together and learning to depend on one another. The more &amp;lsquo;alien&amp;rsquo;, the better. Emberdark has that in spades. It&amp;rsquo;s wonderful worldbuilding and I hope a hint of even more to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characterwise, I love Dusk. Full on &amp;lsquo;it wasn&amp;rsquo;t actually a question, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the need to answer&amp;rsquo; and everything. Starling (dragon&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;!) is our scifi point of view and she&amp;rsquo;s just such a fun positive influence, in spite of everything. We don&amp;rsquo;t get quite as much of Nazh as I&amp;rsquo;d like (from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/24/shadows-for-silence-in-the-forests-of-hell/"&gt;Shadows for Silence&lt;/a&gt;), but what we do is full of &amp;lsquo;but how does &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; work. Chrysalis (a Dysian Aimian!) is a favorite &amp;lsquo;weird&amp;rsquo; character and a vehicle for exploring xenophobia. And that&amp;rsquo;s not even everyone&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:3"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:4"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;! It&amp;rsquo;s just such a mix and I think done rather well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this is probably my favorite Cosmere story in a while. I&amp;rsquo;ve loved seeing how Sanderson has taken the idea of a shared universe with related, high details almost &amp;lsquo;sciency&amp;rsquo; hard magic and brought it forward in time&amp;ndash;and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing where it can go next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Sunlit Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/23/the-sunlit-man/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/23/the-sunlit-man/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;And so ends the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/year-of-sanderson/"&gt;Year of Sanderson&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/"&gt;Tress&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/yumi-and-the-nightmare-painter/"&gt;Yumi&lt;/a&gt; already hinted at new and interesting worlds in the far future of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-cosmere/"&gt;The Cosmere&lt;/a&gt;, but the connections were (relatively) small parts of the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sunlit man is a bit more tied in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still in the far future. And oh, the hints we get at where the Cosmere is going&amp;hellip; but this time, we have a protagonist we&amp;rsquo;ve met before, chock full of references to stories we&amp;rsquo;ve seen&amp;ndash;and a few that haven&amp;rsquo;t happened yet. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into who it is&amp;ndash;spoilers!&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s a neat surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid story as all the Cosmere secret projects have been. I think I prefer Tress and Yumi over Sunlit Man, but it&amp;rsquo;s by absolutely no means a bad book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think my only real negative is&amp;hellip; I want more! More of protagonist. More of the Night Brigade. More of this weird offshoot society. More worldbuilding and magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;m worried we won&amp;rsquo;t see more/any of this for at the very least a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still very worth the read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Yumi and the Nightmare Painter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/yumi-and-the-nightmare-painter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/yumi-and-the-nightmare-painter/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh Sanderson. How &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; you do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three of the four novels in the &amp;ldquo;Year of Sanderson&amp;rdquo;. Tress was amazing and if anything&amp;hellip; Yumi is even better. (Frugal Wizard was fine. &amp;#x1f604;)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tress of the Emerald Sea</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Take one part Princess Bride (a modern fairly tale for a grown up audience), one part Hoid as the narrator (even more Wit-like than in Stormlight), and add in weird world&amp;ndash;Sanderson style. It&amp;rsquo;s funny. It&amp;rsquo;s touching. And it&amp;rsquo;s a delight to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voilá. Tress of the Emerald Sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a really good book.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>