<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Grand Tour on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-grand-tour/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Grand Tour on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-grand-tour/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Privateers</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/26/privateers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/26/privateers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;267332&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267332.privateers&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/privateers.jpg&#34;&gt;
                &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;267291&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267291.powersat&#34;&gt;Powersat&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;267332&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267332.privateers&#34;&gt;Privateers&lt;/a&gt; (the suggested chronological order given for [series:The Grand Tour|51185]) is a bit strange, given the former was first published in 2005 and the latter back in 1985.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Powersat, the &amp;lsquo;big bads&amp;rsquo; are informed by the political tensions of the early 2000s, with terrorism (especially Middle Eastern) driving the conflict. When Privateers was written, the Soviet Union had not yet fallen and the Cold War was still going, so it&amp;rsquo;s unsurprising to find that the &amp;lsquo;what if&amp;rsquo; this time around sees the Soviets taking a position of political power and the United States fading to isolationism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powersat</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/20/powersat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/20/powersat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;267291&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267291.powersat&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/powersat.jpg&#34;&gt;
                &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I last read most of the The Grand Tour in high school or earlier, jumping about from book to book in no particular order. I don&amp;rsquo;t even know if I read The Grand Tour, especially given that it might not have been out yet. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a strange book, set first chronologically but written decades after others in the series. I was looking for an audiobook series to listen to next and this seemed worth a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s near future science fiction, with a world similar enough to the modern world that nothing seems impossible but exploring what could be / could have been. It&amp;rsquo;s not the sort of science fiction I generally read, but so it goes. The idea of the powersat and the spaceplanes is neat and the idea of NASA transferring responsibilities to private companies seems increasingly prescient every year (the last space shuttle flight was 6 years after this book was published). The ending in particular has just the right push of scifi action and adventure to keep me reading by itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>