<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Grand Tour on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-grand-tour/</link><description>Recent content in The Grand Tour on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-grand-tour/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Venus</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/02/venus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/09/02/venus/</guid><description>&lt;p>18 books in and is the only body this side of that the Grand Tour hasn&amp;rsquo;t explored, so it seems a perfectly fitting place to end (I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to that). There&amp;rsquo;s something of a continuation of the The Asteroid Wars, with Martin Humphries and his sons as the focus of the books. One (Alex, &lt;span class="spoiler">his clone&lt;/span>
) attempted to be the first to reach the surface of Venus and died in the attempt. The other (Van, &lt;span class="spoiler">actually not his biological son at all, but rather the son of his longtime enemy from the Asteroid Wars: Lars Fuchs (I know, right?)&lt;/span>
) decides to take on the task of recovering his remains&amp;ndash;a pot sweetened by ten billion dollars of his father&amp;rsquo;s money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that actually makes Venus somewhat interesting and unique among the Grand Tour novels. It&amp;rsquo;s not really one of the corporate war books, such as the early Moonbase books or the Asteroid Wars, but it&amp;rsquo;s also not a purely scientific exploration of Venus&amp;ndash;although there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of that. It&amp;rsquo;s really more an an adventure novel with a sci-fi setting and backing in the hellscape that is Venus. That actually makes it a surprisingly solid book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mars Life</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/27/mars-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/27/mars-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="908284" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/908284.mars-life">Mars Life&lt;/a> continues the story set out in &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267282" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267282.mars">Mars&lt;/a> and , with much the same setting and characters (particularly of the latter). Seventeen books in, there&amp;rsquo;s little particularly surprising about Mars Life, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a solid enough entry to the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the most part, we&amp;rsquo;re back to dealing with the New Morality (which makes me wonder about the timeline a bit) and greenhouse flooding on Earth. In particularly how they just want to put their heads in the sand and ignore concrete evidence of intelligent life on Mars and user their oomph to get the Mars project shut down entirely. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting enough on one hand, but as mentioned, it&amp;rsquo;s starting to feel like more of the same.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mercury</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/18/mercury/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/18/mercury/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="768916" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/768916.mercury"> Mercury &lt;/a> is one of the better books of the Grand Tour, which is a relief after and .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It starts feeling like one of the more &amp;lsquo;sciency&amp;rsquo; books, with the discovery of life on Mercury&amp;ndash;because of course. But that feeling is short lived, as it turns out the life &lt;span class="spoiler">is actually from Mars&lt;/span>
, leaving Astrobiologist Victor Molina framed and disgraced&amp;ndash;although the &amp;lsquo;who&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;why&amp;rsquo; are left unclear.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Titan</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/09/titan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/09/titan/</guid><description>&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s better than . At least this time around, we spend the entire book around Saturn and Titan, with a bit more exploration into the rings of the former and on the surface of the latter. There are essentially three plotlines: a robotic probe sent to Titan is refusing to phone home, someone has to go back to rings to verify that they&amp;rsquo;re alive, and it&amp;rsquo;s election season again&amp;ndash;this time with Zero Population Growth as the main issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first&amp;ndash;going into the rings to collect samples to prove that they actually found life&amp;ndash; doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the least bit of sense. There are arguments back and forth about who is going to go and how dangerous it is. But&amp;hellip; why? Couldn&amp;rsquo;t they just use a probe? It honestly fills like filler, although there are some hints of something much bigger going on here, since the life in the rings now seems to be &lt;span class="spoiler">alien nanomachines&lt;/span>
(which: why? couldn&amp;rsquo;t they just be different?) After the &lt;span class="spoiler">artifact in the asteroid belt&lt;/span>
plotline doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have gone anywhere, there are at least hints on more of a story to tell.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leviathans of Jupiter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/02/leviathans-of-jupiter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/08/02/leviathans-of-jupiter/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="8730311" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8730311.leviathans-of-jupiter">Leviathans of Jupiter&lt;/a> takes what made &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267334" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267334.jupiter">Jupiter&lt;/a> so enjoyable (the exploration of the oceans of Jupiter and interactions with the creatures that live there) and takes another visit. This time around, we have even more content from the Leviathan&amp;rsquo;s perspective and first attempts at actually communicating with them, which is pretty cool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While the science is cool, the characters and drama isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as strong as Jupiter. Grant Archer is still around and in charge now, which is an interesting point. We also get more of Dorn, finding his way out after the Asteroid War. He&amp;rsquo;s been through quite a lot and it&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing his point of view, especially since he&amp;rsquo;s fairly unique in this universe in being a cyborg.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Saturn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/24/saturn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/24/saturn/</guid><description>&lt;p> was something of a bummer, especially coming off &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267334" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267334.jupiter"> Jupiter &lt;/a> and the Asteroid Wars, in particular. It might as well have been called &amp;lsquo;adventures of a colony ship&amp;rsquo;, since it&amp;rsquo;s only in the last fraction of the book that we actually make it to Saturn. The rest of the book is spent by power hungry religious zealots trying to take over a ship ostensibly populated by ten thousand people trying to escape exactly that sort of behavior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, I don&amp;rsquo;t really care about any of the characters. They&amp;rsquo;re all either cartoonishly evil or inept or scientists that need concepts they should know cold explained to them. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a bummer also that the main character went through the cryogenic freeze/thaw that we&amp;rsquo;ve seen discussed in other books, leaving her having to rebuild her life from scratch. But it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually go anywhere. A missed opportunity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Aftermath</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/17/the-aftermath/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/17/the-aftermath/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a standalone story, would have been pretty good. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting story from a sci-fi take: a family on a space ship out in the belt, hauling ore. They&amp;rsquo;re attacked. One member escapes back to the belt and the rest are sent out on a long orbit with a broken ship, years before they&amp;rsquo;ll return to civilization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting story, showing just how big space is and how dangerous a frontier it can be in a science fiction story can be in the near future solar system, where they don&amp;rsquo;t have magical engines that can go through the system in days (well, they do, but not on a cargo ship like this). And if you don&amp;rsquo;t have an antenna and can&amp;rsquo;t aim a laser, then you can&amp;rsquo;t very well talk to anyone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Silent War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/07/the-silent-war/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/07/the-silent-war/</guid><description>&lt;p> feels like a conclusion to the Asteroid Wars ( and ), with the war continuing to escalate to father and father atrocities with even more sides to the conflict than before ( &lt;span class="spoiler">Yamagata is back! If a bit weirdly.&lt;/span>
). It&amp;rsquo;s a bit strange to see what feels like such a conclusion with one book left, but I guess that&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s called ? We&amp;rsquo;ll just have to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, The Silent War is a satisfying enough conclusion to the Asteroid Wars (as a war and as a subseries) building up both the overall conflict and one within the book itself. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to actually see everything come to a head and I think the conclusion is workable, if a little ridiculous. It really feeds into the idea that behind every powerful corporation is a handful (or one) of powerful men and women really driving things forward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Rock Rats</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/01/the-rock-rats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/01/the-rock-rats/</guid><description>&lt;p> continues the story of , following the story of humanity&amp;rsquo;s expansion into the Asteroid Belt and all the atrocities that entails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, this book is all over the place. Pancho is great fun, but we don&amp;rsquo;t see nearly enough of her. Lars is &amp;hellip; kind of crazy and revenge driven, a long descent from liking him well enough in The Precipice. Amanda is pretty great, but only when she&amp;rsquo;s away from either Lars or Humpries. Of all the marriages in the series thus far, why does this have to be the one to stick beyond a single book? They really don&amp;rsquo;t make much sense together&amp;hellip; Trite as the saying may be, she could do better.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jupiter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/24/jupiter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/24/jupiter/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the first 8 books in The Grand Tour (&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267282" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267282.mars">Mars&lt;/a> in particular), &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267334" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267334.jupiter">Jupiter&lt;/a> feels a bit odd at the start. We&amp;rsquo;re not building up to the eventual discovery of life&amp;ndash;the fact that there&amp;rsquo;s life on Jupiter is presented fait accompli in the first chapters. And not only life&amp;hellip; intelligent life (or so is claimed). Jupiter isn&amp;rsquo;t really about the discovery of life or even really about the idea of life on a research station around Jupiter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What Jupiter is really about the conflict between religion and science as humanity continues to expand outwards into the solar system. The New Morality controls the politics of the Earth and is doing everything it can to control the solar system. In doing so, they send Grant Archer&amp;ndash;a believer and an astrophysicist&amp;ndash;to spy on what in the world is going on far out in the dark reaches of the solar system. There&amp;rsquo;s conflict between science and religion, both on the large scale with the New Morality and the small scale within Grant himself, especially as he begins to settle in and befriend those living on Jupiter station.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Precipice</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/14/the-precipice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/14/the-precipice/</guid><description>&lt;p> does two things rather well: it introduces technology that will change the Grand Tour universe and it makes me actually &amp;hellip; kind of like Dan Randolph.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the former, we finally have one possible solution to the fundamental problem of near future science fiction:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Return to Mars</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/08/return-to-mars/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/08/return-to-mars/</guid><description>&lt;p> finishes what &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267282" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267282.mars">Mars&lt;/a> started&amp;ndash;and I really feel like they might have been better as one book. There was such a huge tantalizing idea dangled in front of us in the first book&amp;ndash;not only life on Mars, but &lt;strong>intelligent&lt;/strong> life?&amp;ndash;only for a rush to the ending so that we never got to actually get answers. At least we do actually get answers in Return to Mars, but in such a way that it really feels like half the same book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, Return to Mars does at least explore some interesting ideas in how Martian exploration may actually take shape in the future, with private backing and a profit motive, rather than as a purely government run, scientific endeavor. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting contrast to Mars at least, even if it feels like they&amp;rsquo;ve taken a number of steps back from the first mission in effort to cut costs (one assumes).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moonwar</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/30/moonwar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/30/moonwar/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267298" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267298.moonwar">Moonwar&lt;/a> finishes the story of &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267287" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267287.moonrise">Moonrise&lt;/a>, really establishing Moonbase as a power in the solar system in its own right and a refuge from the growing New Morality movements on Earth&amp;ndash;especially when it comes to developing nano-technology.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are certainly parts of the story that are hard to believe&amp;ndash;particularly just how much control the UN has over &amp;hellip; well, anything, but especially the media. It&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip; strange and feels like a manufactured threat. On the other hand, the idea of a religious far right growing to power and working to completely ban &amp;lsquo;unnatural&amp;rsquo; technology (like nanomachines) feels altogether too prescient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moonrise</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/23/moonrise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/23/moonrise/</guid><description>&lt;p>A bit of a jump in focus and topic from &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267282" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267282.mars"> Mars &lt;/a> , &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267287" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267287.moonrise"> Moonrise &lt;/a> is more similar to et al (the Dan Randolph books), with more of a focus on corporate structure over science.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amusingly, despite the title/series, Moonrise is only tangentially about the Moonbase, despite a large chunk of the book taking place there. Really, it&amp;rsquo;s about the bizarre broken family and corporate dynamic of Masterson Aerospace and the rise of nanotechnology in Ben Bova&amp;rsquo;s universe. From what I remember of other books in the series (from more than a decade ago), the rise of technology and the idea of it being banned on Earth for religious reasons is a fairly major plot point from here on out, so it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see how that all began.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mars</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/14/mars/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/14/mars/</guid><description>&lt;p>My favorite of [ The Grand Tour ](&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/51185-the-" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.goodreads.com/series/51185-the-&lt;/a> grand-tour) books so far, by a decent margin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s closer to &amp;lsquo;pure&amp;rsquo; science fiction than the previous three, with the exploration of Mars and the science of getting there and exploring taking the front seat, with a lesser focus on politics and character than the previous books (although there still a decent amount of both).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Empire Builders</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/05/empire-builders/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/05/05/empire-builders/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267291" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267291.powersat">Powersat&lt;/a>, the big bads were terrorists. In , the Russians. In it&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; global warming and the mob?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given how times have changed, it&amp;rsquo;s amusing to see the specter of a &amp;lsquo;greenhouse cliff&amp;rsquo; looming over the world, with no one believing at first that such a thing is even possible. Nowdays, you&amp;rsquo;ll see arguments over if it&amp;rsquo;s happening or not (more and more rarely) and if we caused it in the first place (of course we did), but you&amp;rsquo;d be hard pressed to find too many people that have never even heard of the idea. That&amp;rsquo;s what you get for reading near future sci- fi written a quarter century ago I guess. It&amp;rsquo;s a straight forward enough plot with a few twists through politics, squatters on the moon and natural disasters and an engaging read. I find myself increasingly interested in what happens to this other Earth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privateers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/26/privateers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/26/privateers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reading &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="267291" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/267291.powersat">Powersat&lt;/a> and then (the suggested chronological order given for [series:The Grand Tour|51185]) is a bit strange, given the former was first published in 2005 and the latter back in 1985.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Powersat, the &amp;lsquo;big bads&amp;rsquo; are informed by the political tensions of the early 2000s, with terrorism (especially Middle Eastern) driving the conflict. When Privateers was written, the Soviet Union had not yet fallen and the Cold War was still going, so it&amp;rsquo;s unsurprising to find that the &amp;lsquo;what if&amp;rsquo; this time around sees the Soviets taking a position of political power and the United States fading to isolationism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Powersat</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/20/powersat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/20/powersat/</guid><description>&lt;p>I last read most of the The Grand Tour in high school or earlier, jumping about from book to book in no particular order. I don&amp;rsquo;t even know if I read The Grand Tour, especially given that it might not have been out yet. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a strange book, set first chronologically but written decades after others in the series. I was looking for an audiobook series to listen to next and this seemed worth a try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s near future science fiction, with a world similar enough to the modern world that nothing seems impossible but exploring what could be / could have been. It&amp;rsquo;s not the sort of science fiction I generally read, but so it goes. The idea of the powersat and the spaceplanes is neat and the idea of NASA transferring responsibilities to private companies seems increasingly prescient every year (the last space shuttle flight was 6 years after this book was published). The ending in particular has just the right push of scifi action and adventure to keep me reading by itself.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>