<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dan Wells on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dan-wells/</link><description>Recent content in Dan Wells on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dan-wells/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nothing Left to Lose</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/02/nothing-left-to-lose/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/02/nothing-left-to-lose/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;John is down to the last few Withered and he&amp;rsquo;s got a lead. One thing leads to another and he ends up in another small midwestern town, working at a mortuary. Sound familiar? It&amp;rsquo;s a nice blend of old and new and works well as a conclusion for the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the FBI show up and help to wrap up that storyline through the previous three books. We meet a handful of new Withered (including some surprising new powers) and get a bit more backstory. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain as much as I still want to know, but it&amp;rsquo;s more at least.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Over Your Dead Body</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/31/over-your-dead-body/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/31/over-your-dead-body/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Following the disastrous ending of The Devil&amp;rsquo;s Only Friend, John and Brooke are out hunting Withered on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of John&amp;rsquo;s sociopathy in the previous four books, we now have Brooke with a supernatural cousin of multiple personality disorder as she has to deal with the fallout of ten thousand years of Nobody&amp;rsquo;s memories and suicides. It&amp;rsquo;s also interesting to watch John try to figure out how to deal with this, both as a source of information in his hunt against the Withered but also as Brooke&amp;rsquo;s friend.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Devil's Only Friend</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/25/the-devils-only-friend/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/25/the-devils-only-friend/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Devil&amp;rsquo;s Only Friend&lt;/em&gt; , John Cleaver is at it again. As I hoped, the story has moved away from Clayton County. This time around, John and Brooke&amp;ndash; now with many of the memories and personalities of the demon (Cursed/Withered) Nobody&amp;ndash;are part of an FBI task force tasked with hunting down and killing as many of the demons as they can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a cool way to take the story and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see the change. I like seeing how John interacts with his new team members. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that they&amp;rsquo;re all screwed up in their own ways, but they&amp;rsquo;re still trying to hunt something even worse. I wish we&amp;rsquo;d gotten a bit more depth on them before the end of the book, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a new situation to see John react to.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Next of Kin</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/24/next-of-kin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/24/next-of-kin/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I died again last night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well. That&amp;rsquo;s a way to start a story.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Don't Want to Kill You</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/23/i-dont-want-to-kill-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/23/i-dont-want-to-kill-you/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So at the end of Mr. Monster, John literally called up a demon and told them to bring it on. So of course there&amp;rsquo;s another serial killer in Clayton County.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mr. Monster</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/22/mr.-monster/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/22/mr.-monster/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My favorite part of family togetherness is when we aspirate body cavities. What’s yours?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Monster takes basically everything that was in I Am Not a Serial Killer and cranks it up another notch. Creepy supernatural serial killer? Check. Long detailed descriptions of embalming? Check. John trying and sort of succeeding in coming to terms with being a sociopath? Check.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Am Not a Serial Killer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/16/i-am-not-a-serial-killer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/07/16/i-am-not-a-serial-killer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Warning: This book contains some really dark imagery and supernatural elements. If either of those is not what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for, look elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first heard about the John Cleaver books while listening to the &lt;a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Writing Excuses&lt;/a&gt; podcast, which gave me a fairly good idea what I was getting into before I started it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ruins</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/ruins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/ruins/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A solid ending to a solid series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Ruins actually managed to pull things together in a way without feeling (too) rushed that none of the other YA series recently have managed to pull off. The previous plotlines (Kira&amp;rsquo;s conflicted nature, the rest of the Trust, the cure(s)) all come to a head in a way that&amp;rsquo;s still driving enough to finish the series but don&amp;rsquo;t feel like the author was just phoning it in.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fragments</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/11/fragments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/11/fragments/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A good continuation to Partials. In this book, we see Kira start to come to terms with who she is as she sets off with Samm and Heron across what&amp;rsquo;s left of the United States in search of answers&amp;ndash;only to find more than she was looking for. Meanwhile, Marcus is back home, stuck between two warring Partial factions, trying desperately to broker a piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a neat continuation. I like watching the world expand, exploring more of what happened in the decade and change since everything fell apart. We&amp;rsquo;re starting to get some answers, which of course lead to more questions. I look forward to Ruins, cautiously hoping that Wells can pull everything together for the finale.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Isolation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/05/isolation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/05/isolation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Quick and to the point, Isolation tells the story of Heron (who we met briefly in Partials) during the Isolation War. It gives a better picture into the Partials: how they are made, how they are trained, and why they might not only want to, but even been the right to, kill us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good story and I hope to see more of Heron in the second and third books of the Partials Sequence. It&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see how she&amp;rsquo;s grown and changed in the intervening years and how she interacts with the other human (and not) protagonists.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Partials</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/partials/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/partials/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The story of Partials takes place 11 years after humanity lost a terrible war. Basically, we created super soldiers (Partials) to fight for us. Of course, after they won the war they turned on us&amp;hellip; Worse yet, right at the same time, there was a virus which killed 99.96% of humanity&amp;ndash;including any new pregnancies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s where we start. Humanity is stuck on Long Island while the Partials are &lt;em&gt;out there&lt;/em&gt; ™. Because no babies can survive the virus, the youngest living people are 14. The main characters are roughly 16. Even stranger, in an effort to figure out how to cure the virus, the Hope Act has been enacted. All women 18 or older must get pregnant as often as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>