<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The First Law on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-first-law/</link><description>Recent content in The First Law on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-first-law/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Last Argument of Kings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/last-argument-of-kings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/17/last-argument-of-kings/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have learned all kinds of things from my many mistakes. The one thing I never learn is to stop making them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it ends&amp;hellip; for now. Some of our old friends (more or less) are dead, some are broken, and some &amp;hellip; miraculously seem to have gotten everything they wanted in life. There are more surprises and political shifts than one knows how to deal with, a chunk more of world building around the First and Second Laws, and all manner of battles and death and destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It remains fascinating what Abercrombie can do with characters. Glokta is a terrible person&amp;ndash;and he makes us root for him. Logen is a berserker in the truest sense&amp;ndash;and he makes us feel sorry for him. Jezal is excellent at failing upward&amp;ndash;and he makes us feel sorry for him. It&amp;rsquo;s all around amazing and the real strength of the series.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Before They Are Hanged</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/before-they-are-hanged/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/20/before-they-are-hanged/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should forgive our enemies, but not before they are hanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before They Are Hanged takes &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/31/the-blade-itself/"&gt;The Blade Itself&lt;/a&gt; and takes everything up a notch. It&amp;rsquo;s still a dark and twisted world, there are still terrible people on all sides&amp;hellip; but now we have even more hints and worldbuilding on darker things coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a worthwhile continuation to the first story and I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to see where it goes next. The narration in particular remains well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Blade Itself</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/31/the-blade-itself/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/31/the-blade-itself/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every man has his excuses, and the more vile the man becomes, the more touching the story has to be. What is my story now, I wonder?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Abercrombie / The Blade Itself have long held a highly recommended spot on my to read lis, so when I caught the audiobook on Libby/the Indiana Digital Library&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I figured it was about time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick version: it&amp;rsquo;s wonderful, but also &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; dark. One of the main characters is a barbarian who&amp;rsquo;s family was recently killed, another is a soldier crippled in war turned torturer. And somehow, Abercrombie actually really makes you feel for the both of them, but man it takes a bit&amp;hellip; On top of that, there&amp;rsquo;s some fascinating hints of magic&amp;ndash;plus some more overt examples, no less terrible, when we meet Bayaz&amp;ndash;the First of the Magi&amp;hellip; or is he?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>