<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2020 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2020-book-reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2020 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2020-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vixen 03</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/vixen-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/vixen-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;41700&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41700.vixen-03&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/vixen-03.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;41700&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41700.vixen-03&#34;&gt; Vixen 03 &lt;/a&gt; was a surprisingly good listen. From the reviews, I expected something far worse. It&amp;rsquo;s Pitt to the core, with crazy action scenes, ocean (more lake really) salvage, weird ships where they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be, and Pitt getting himself mixed up in situations he has no reason to be involved in. Oh, and a sprinkling of racism and misogyny. At least it&amp;rsquo;s getting better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plotwise, the story of the doomed Vixen 03, it&amp;rsquo;s discovery, and the involved salvage mission is the best part of the book. The final conclusion with a retired battleship, retrofitted, and sailed up  &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;the Potomac to train their guns on Washington DC&lt;/span&gt;
  is ridiculous and would make an excellent blockbuster sequence. The plot about the African revolutionaries feels&amp;hellip; rather racist and bizarre? I&amp;rsquo;m not actually sure, but it certainly feels very strange. That level of hatred between races and peoples is something that I thankfully have little personal experience with and felt odd in the story. It probably could have been traded out for any sort of terrorist group with little change to the plot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to a Suffering Church: A Bishop Speaks on the Sexual Abuse Crisis</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/letter-to-a-suffering-church-a-bishop-speaks-on-the-sexual-abuse-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/letter-to-a-suffering-church-a-bishop-speaks-on-the-sexual-abuse-crisis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;45731096&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/45731096.letter-to-a-suffering-church-a-bishop-speaks-on-the-sexual-abuse-crisis&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/letter-to-a-suffering-church-a-bishop-speaks-on-the-sexual-abuse-crisis.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Emperor Napoleon is said to have confronted Cardinal Consalvi, the secretary of state to Pope Pius VII, saying that he, Napoleon, would destroy the Church—to which the Cardinal deftly responded, “Oh my little man, you think you’re going to succeed in accomplishing what centuries of priests and bishops have tried and failed to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not Catholic, although I go to mass every Sunday (plus a few). My immediate family and much of my extended family are Catholic and I&amp;rsquo;ve always seen a certain beauty to the core of Catholic belief and the idea of thousands of years of tradition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Show of Force</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/a-show-of-force/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/a-show-of-force/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;25271140&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25271140.a-show-of-force&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/a-show-of-force.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;25271140&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25271140.a-show-of-force&#34;&gt;A Show of Force&lt;/a&gt; escalate from where we were earlier in the series. The Aurora and her crew have kicked one evil empire&amp;rsquo;s butt, freed the Earth, and are now taking the fight to the Jung, clearing a 20 light year radius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty crazy book, with lots of fights, both on the ground and in space. Nothing &lt;em&gt;hugely&lt;/em&gt; surprising happens, with most of the book pushing towards the final confrontation I expect we&amp;rsquo;ll see shortly. We do see a lot more of the Jung now, seeing them as at once more human and at the same time as a force worth fighting. It&amp;rsquo;s far better than the faceless evil enemies that we&amp;rsquo;ve had for so long.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Reading List</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/2020-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/2020-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year, a reading list. I didn&amp;rsquo;t make 120 books per year last year. As mentioned, I was doing pretty well until. And then October hit, with a pile of birthdays. And November, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/11/25/nanowrimo-2019-the-twilight-between-the-stars/&#34;&gt;NaNoWriMo&lt;/a&gt;. And then the holidays. Thanksgiving. Christmas. So I think this year, I&amp;rsquo;m going to back down to 100 again, trying to hit that by the end of October. Then I can read with less pressure through the rest of the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>