<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adam Kubert on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/adam-kubert/</link><description>Recent content in Adam Kubert on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/adam-kubert/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 6: Return of the King</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/ultimate-x-men-vol.-6-return-of-the-king/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/26/ultimate-x-men-vol.-6-return-of-the-king/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wherein we get this universe’s history. How the a Professor and Magneto started out to build a mutant utopia, how some minor* differences in option came between them, and how Xavier ended up in a wheelchair.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a nice longer story and I really do dig the conflict between the Professor and Magneto. There are also some really interesting ideas buried within the action. Ends justifying the means. The cost(s) of rehabilitation or even imprisonment of a super powered prisoner. What it means to be human.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A solid story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 4: Hellfire and Brimstone</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/22/ultimate-x-men-vol.-4-hellfire-and-brimstone/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/22/ultimate-x-men-vol.-4-hellfire-and-brimstone/</guid><description>&lt;p>All the fallout and barely time to process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now Jean is having hallucinations and Beast’s new flame is digging for secrets…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quite a ride, setting up all sorts of what’s next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, sudden art shifts yo. I like the new one. Don&amp;rsquo;t think that will ever stop being surprising.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 1: The Tomorrow People</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-x-men-vol.-1-the-tomorrow-people/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/12/ultimate-x-men-vol.-1-the-tomorrow-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>Getting the team together, sleeper agent Wolverine, love triangles, betrayal, mass murder, and the bluening of Beast.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is an awful lot to fit into a single volume…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The philosophical differences between Professor X and his X-Men versus Magneto and his Brotherhood is quite often at the core of these stories, so it’s no surprise to see it here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only question is… what comes next?!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>