<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Noah Baumbach on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/noah-baumbach/</link><description>Recent content in Noah Baumbach on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/noah-baumbach/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Barbie</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/"&gt;Barbenheimer&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barbie is quite a movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An entire world populated entirely by every single variant of Barbie and Ken&lt;sup id="fnref:4"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. All named Barbie and Ken, all living their lives in the most &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo;re sort of toys and sort of real&amp;rsquo; way possible. Drinking your morning coffee? Tip the empty cup to your mouth. Need to get out of the second floor? Just jump down! And of course&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken: I thought I might stay over tonight.&lt;br&gt;
Barbie: Why?&lt;br&gt;
Ken: Because we&amp;rsquo;re girfriend and boyfriend.&lt;br&gt;
Barbie: To do what?&lt;br&gt;
[pause]&lt;br&gt;
Ken: I&amp;rsquo;m actually not sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh this movie is weirdly(ly on point) at times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we get the &amp;rsquo;toy in the real world and DOESN&amp;rsquo;T UNDERSTAND THINGS&amp;rsquo; scenes. I feel like a lot of those were dialed up &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; to the edge of over-parody, but really, it somehow just works? Barbie is so out of sorts and just doesn&amp;rsquo;t realize it&amp;hellip; until she does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things go wrong&amp;hellip; and suddenly the movie isn&amp;rsquo;t just the Barbie movie anymore. Now, it&amp;rsquo;s all about Ken. And the PATRIARCHY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ken: To be honest, when I found out the patriarchy wasn&amp;rsquo;t just about horses, I lost interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that we were going to have some major conflict there, in a world (almost) entirely populated by Barbies and Kens&amp;hellip; who else is there? But it&amp;rsquo;s kind of weird. I feel like Ken honestly has more of a story arc for a lot of the movie does than Barbie. Which&amp;hellip; feels kind of against the entire point of the movie?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, we have the big Mattel in the room. Of &lt;em&gt;course&lt;/em&gt; we have to have a dig about companies making toys for girls run by powerful men. But man, did they dial that one up to 11 on a rediculous scale. A bicycle built for&amp;hellip; a boardroom. That is all. Will Ferrell is a delight as the CEO. After Lord Business in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/02/15/the-lego-movie/"&gt;The Lego Movie&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip; this is a weird role to be typecast as, but it really works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of casting, I did love Margot Robbie as Barbie&lt;sup id="fnref:5"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barbie: [in tears] I&amp;rsquo;m not pretty anymore!&lt;br&gt;
Gloria: What? You&amp;rsquo;re so pretty!&lt;br&gt;
Barbie: I&amp;rsquo;m not stereotypical Barbie pretty!&lt;br&gt;
Narrator: Note to the filmmakers: Margot Robbie is the wrong person to cast if you want to make this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She just &amp;hellip; epitomizes Barbieness in the movie? I don&amp;rsquo;t know who esle could possibly have carried that role quite as well. Kate McKinnon as Weird Barbie was great as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Ryan Gosling as Ken&lt;sup id="fnref:6"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This one I think could have been differently cast with less issue, but he still did a wonderful job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that stood out was how at times uncomfortably on point Barbie managed to be on various social commentary issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sasha: You&amp;rsquo;re a fascist!&lt;br&gt;
Barbie: How can I be a fascist?&lt;br&gt;
[through tears]&lt;br&gt;
Barbie: I don&amp;rsquo;t control the railways or the flow of commerce&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
[cries]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh this movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a movie better than it had any right to be and far better than I expected, even with generally positive reviews going on. Worth watching. Not sure it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/"&gt;Barbenheimer&lt;/a&gt; it though&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>