<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Christopher L. Yost on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/christopher-l.-yost/</link><description>Recent content in Christopher L. Yost on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/christopher-l.-yost/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thor: Ragnarok</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ooh, that poster. &lt;em>le kiss&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/">Thor&lt;/a> was &amp;hellip; fine, a weirdly downscale introduction to a kind of strange character early in the MCU. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/">Thor: The Dark World&lt;/a> went the other way, being too bigt and ambitious and suffering somewhat for it. So going into Thor: Ragnarok, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what we were going to get.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An absolute gem of an 80s sci fi/fantasy action superhero comedy that just works. Right from the very intro, you know it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a different sort of movie. They lean hard into the Norse/Asgardian mythos, with Thor in the underworld, chained up (but not concerned) by a giant flaming skeleton who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to signify the end of days. One spectacular Thor&amp;rsquo;ful action scene later and we&amp;rsquo;re back on Asgard, dealing with the missing Odin. Then we&amp;rsquo;re off to Earth, only to bump into Doctor Strange, now fully into his powers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor: The Dark World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>One problem that comic book universes in general and the MCU in specific have always had is that of scale. How in the world do you have a man in a suit, a literal &amp;lsquo;god&amp;rsquo;, a rage monster, a super soldier, and a couple &amp;hellip; regular people ever interact on the same scale? For the most part, it&amp;rsquo;s hand waved away. Everyone is paired up with an opponent of roughly the same power level and we move on with our lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No where those is this contrast more apparent than in the Universe of Thor. The people of Asgard are supposed to be gods. They live thousands of years. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen them shrug off some pretty crazy weapons. And yet here they are, dying to spears and falling rocks. It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean, there are any number of brilliant CGI shots of the weird world of Asgard, and it at least has a much bigger scope than the first Thor, but it still feels &amp;hellip; hollow. It&amp;rsquo;s a pity, because I enjoy Thor&amp;rsquo;s super powerful fish out of water story well enough in the combined movies, but this is not my favorite of the combined films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s always interesting to re-read my older reviews: &lt;a href="#original-2013-review">see below&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="original-2013-review">Original 2013 review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The first Thor was a bit disappointing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There, I said it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It could certainly have been worse, but it really felt like the entire movie served solely to set up Thor&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> for the Avengers. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t terrible, it just &amp;hellip; was.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>