<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philip Pullman on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/philip-pullman/</link><description>Recent content in Philip Pullman on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/philip-pullman/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Daemon Voices</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/07/daemon-voices/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He is interested in the discoveries of science (“intellectual daring and imaginative brilliance without parallel”), the freedoms of democracy (in particular “the great democracy of reading and writing”), the evils of authoritarianism (“always reductive whether it’s in power or not”) and the pitfalls of education (“any education that neglects the experience of delight will be a dry and tasteless diet with no nourishment in it”). He is profoundly interested in religion, while remaining puzzled by aspects of it. “The first thing to say about the Bishop’s arguments in his book,” he writes in “God and Dust,” “is that I agree with every word of them, except the words I don’t understand; and that the words I don’t understand are those such as spirit, spiritual and God.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Philip Pullman is an interesting author, which makes Daemon Voices an interesting sort of book. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a selected collection of essays and presentation he&amp;rsquo;s given over the years on a wide range of topics. In particular, he talks a lot about Paradise Lost (makes me want to actually read it), his religious and philosophical views (and a dive into Gnosticism) and how those interact with his writing, and a bit on writing advice and his own particular style.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating look and there&amp;rsquo;s a little for everyone, so if you like what Pullman has written, you can certainly do worse than give it a chance!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below are a few interesting quotes that I highlighted for just about every essay. It&amp;rsquo;s not really the sort of book where one should worry about spoilers, but just in case that&amp;rsquo;s not a shared option, you have been warned. (Also: &lt;em>long&lt;/em>)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Amber Spyglass</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/the-amber-spyglass/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/the-amber-spyglass/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/20/the-amber-spyglass/">The Amber Spyglass&lt;/a> is really a sequel to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/17/the-subtle-knife/">The Subtle Knife&lt;/a> more than a conclusion to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/14/the-golden-compass/">The Golden Compass&lt;/a> . Most everything that I liked in the Golden Compass but was missing in The Subtle Knife is still missing here, while the new additions that annoyed me about The Subtle Knife are turned up to 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We get fascinating new worlds (miniature spies with poisonous spines on their feet! creatures with wheels! how weird!) but to the most part they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to really lead to the story. Lyra&amp;hellip; is growing up and supposed to be super important to the upcoming battle, but really this is again a book about Will. And Lyra&amp;rsquo;s big part? Growing up. That&amp;rsquo;s about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Subtle Knife</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/17/the-subtle-knife/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/17/the-subtle-knife/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/17/the-subtle-knife/">The Subtle Knife&lt;/a> takes off where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/14/the-golden-compass/">The Golden Compass&lt;/a> left off, with Lyra leaving her world behind, traveling across a bridge originally torn by the death of a friend. On top of that, we have a new character in Will, a boy searching for his missing father, instead finding another, must less dramatic way to travel between worlds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To some extent, The Subtle Knife feels like an odd sequel. Where the Golden Compass centered almost entirely around Lyra, this time around, we&amp;rsquo;re split between Lyra and Will, with Will really the driving force behind the story. I don&amp;rsquo;t mind Will&amp;ndash;he&amp;rsquo;s unlikable at first, but you fell that&amp;rsquo;s mostly because&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Golden Compass</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/14/the-golden-compass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/14/the-golden-compass/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/09/14/the-golden-compass/">The Golden Compass&lt;/a> before, but it&amp;rsquo;s been a few years. On top of that, this time around, I listened to it as an audiobook (the full cast reading, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there is another). I have fond memories of this book and for the most part, they were met on re-read, which is something you don&amp;rsquo;t always get.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The core of the book is a world where people&amp;rsquo;s spirits / souls / conscious exists as a separate being, a daemon who takes the form of an animal companion &amp;ndash;changing and mutable at first and eventually settling into a single form for adults that represents the core of who they are. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting idea and well done, to the point that it feels natural, to the point that I almost wish I could live in this world, just to see who my daemon might be.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>