<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Newsflesh on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/newsflesh/</link><description>Recent content in Newsflesh on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/newsflesh/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blackout</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/blackout/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/blackout/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A solid ending to a solid series. I think that I liked it more than Deadline, but less than Feed, owing entirely to one thing: George.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup, she&amp;rsquo;s back. Literally the last thing that happens in Deadline gets fleshed out (heh) in Blackout as we alternate once again between Shaun&amp;rsquo;s and Georgia&amp;rsquo;s viewpoints. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly obvious what&amp;rsquo;s happened (and a neat extension of what we already know about the zombie virus), but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I was still rooting for her nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deadline</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/25/deadline/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/25/deadline/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I was curious to see where Grant would take this, after killing off a small pile of main characters in the first book. It turns out: somewhere right between what I expected and what I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, Shaun is crazy now. He hears George&amp;rsquo;s voice in his head and answers her out loud. Everyone around him of course thinks he&amp;rsquo;s crazy, but they mostly seem to give him space. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what I think about that. Shaun is still probably my least favorite of the main characters from the first book, which is certainly suboptimal, given that he&amp;rsquo;s the only one to survive&amp;hellip; (Also, the Coke fixation is weird.) But why does everyone else keep him around?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Feed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/20/feed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/20/feed/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, zombies are here and bloggers have taken over the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>