<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Monika Kim on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/monika-kim/</link><description>Recent content in Monika Kim on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/monika-kim/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Eyes Are the Best Part</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/28/the-eyes-are-the-best-part/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/28/the-eyes-are-the-best-part/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A salty liquid trickles down my throat. The outside is crunchy cartilage. I jam it into my left cheek and bite down with my molars; jellylike matter explodes within my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whelp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is most definitely a horror book. Not in the &amp;lsquo;jump and scare you&amp;rsquo; sort of vibe or really even the &amp;lsquo;serial killer is coming for you sort. But an ever building sense of what is real and what isn&amp;rsquo;t, body horror, and what-the-heckery? This book has &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; in spades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all built on a foundation of a messy home life going multiple periods of transition all at once. A feeling of alienation. Sexism and racism, sometimes subtle, sometimes &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;. Learning to deal with (or not) their changing world(s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I explain to her that the home I miss isn’t a place? It’s a time when my life made sense. When things made sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Characterwise, I think Ji-won&amp;rsquo;s point of view did a good job of being just as (eventually) freaked out as the reader is getting as her life gets upended. That, I appreciated. And I really feel for her mother and sister, both before the events of the story and just maybe even more after&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New mother&amp;rsquo;s boyfriend George is&amp;hellip; kind of cartoonish, but dealing with a divorced mother and a man who will say the right things? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s part of the mess of the situation, no?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then new school friends Alexis and Geoffrey. I &amp;hellip; the change with Geoffrey felt like Ji-won reacted before she knew what might be going on there. And perhaps I missed something, but&amp;hellip; he did not deserve everything he got. Which I suppose leads all the more into the horror of it all.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>