<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>1999 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/1999/</link><description>Recent content in 1999 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/1999/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Toy Story 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/toy-story-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/toy-story-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>For me, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/02/toy-story/">Toy Story&lt;/a> falls at just the right time for a blast of nostalgia. It came out when I was a kid and I watched it over and over again. Somehow, Toy Story 2, despite only coming out 4 years later, just doesn&amp;rsquo;t hit the same mark. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s still a good fun movie and worth watching, but&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s just not quite as good.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Buzz Lightyear: Woody, stop this nonsense and let&amp;rsquo;s go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Woody: Nah, Buzz.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sigh]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Woody: I can&amp;rsquo;t go. I can&amp;rsquo;t abandon these guys. They &lt;em>need&lt;/em> me to get into this museum. Without me, they&amp;rsquo;ll go back into storage. Maybe forever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Buzz Lightyear: Woody, you&amp;rsquo;re not a collector&amp;rsquo;s item, you&amp;rsquo;re a child&amp;rsquo;s plaything. You - are - a &lt;em>toy&lt;/em>!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Matrix</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/the-matrix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/the-matrix/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh the Matrix. This movie came out at just the perfect time for me&amp;ndash;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t into the counter culture as much, but even then I was messing around with computers and hacking&amp;ndash;and I absolutely love every minute of it. It stands up even today, with a retrofuturistic sort of vibe that really still works even though it&amp;rsquo;s been twenty years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode I - The Phantom Menace</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/29/star-wars-episode-i-the-phantom-menace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/29/star-wars-episode-i-the-phantom-menace/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, that opening score. The title crawl. That&amp;rsquo;s a blast of nostalgia right there. I&amp;rsquo;m too young to have seen the original trilogy in theaters, but I watched the VHS tapes what felt like a million times. When The Phantom Menace came out, that was &lt;em>right&lt;/em> in my wheelhouse. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how many times I saw that movie in theaters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And you know what? It&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as it&amp;rsquo;s often rated. Granted, if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t leaning so heavily on the rest of the Star Wars franchise, well&amp;hellip; it would probably be about that bad. But I disagree that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t disserve a place in the core &amp;lsquo;Skywalker Saga&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun action movie wrapped around the rise of dark powers and corruption in the guise of&amp;ndash;a trade war and senatorial discourse of all things. It&amp;rsquo;s weird, but I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to accept it at least?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Obi-Wan: You were right about one thing master. The negotiations were short.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s my favorite Star Wars movie so far&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and only a hint of things to come!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>