<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Sandman on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-sandman/</link><description>Recent content in The Sandman on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-sandman/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Wake</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/11/the-wake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 14:19:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/11/the-wake/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so as all things must end, so too do the Endless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After uncountable years, Dream of the Endless has died. Another Dream has risen to take up the mantle (as must be), but before, it&amp;rsquo;s time to say goodbye to the Dream we&amp;rsquo;ve all come to know over the last 10 volumes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Kindly Ones</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/09/the-kindly-ones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/09/the-kindly-ones/</guid><description>&lt;p>More than ever before, we&amp;rsquo;re seeing things from the past Sandman stories come back to haunt Dream. We have Lyta Hall and her baby (from way back in the beginning), Nuala of the Fae, and the Corinthian (man he&amp;rsquo;s creepy) all back and ready to wreck havoc (in wildly varied ways). And that ending&amp;hellip; knowing there&amp;rsquo;s only one more book makes me really look forward to finishing this series, as weird as that sounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/sandman-9-01.jpg" alt="Sandman-9-01">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Worlds' End</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/08/worlds-end/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/08/worlds-end/</guid><description>&lt;p>A Tavern at the World&amp;rsquo;s End. Travellers from all manner of realities, thrown together. Stories around the fire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/sandman-8-01.png" alt="Sandman-8-01">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brief Lives</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/05/brief-lives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/05/brief-lives/</guid><description>&lt;p>Destruction of the Endless is missing (and has been missing for a very long time). Delerium&amp;ndash;the strangest by far&amp;ndash;seeks him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh it&amp;rsquo;s quite a story. I think this is the most we&amp;rsquo;ve seen about the other Endless yet, and it&amp;rsquo;s truely bizarre. I think that Delerium being a core point of view helps that along nicely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fables &amp; Reflections</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/02/fables-reflections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/02/fables-reflections/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Death was a little older than Dream. Things had the potential to die before
they had the potential to dream.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Endless are so fascinating. As it this story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Game of You</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/31/a-game-of-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/31/a-game-of-you/</guid><description>&lt;p>This time around, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll just start with the summary from Goodreads:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Take an apartment house, mix in a drag queen, a lesbian couple, some talking
animals, a talking severed head, a confused heroine, and the deadly Cuckoo.
Stir vigorously with a hurricane and Morpheus himself and you get this fifth
installment of the Sandman series.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Season of Mists</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/30/season-of-mists/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/30/season-of-mists/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To reign is worth ambition though in Hell: Better to reign in Hell, then
serve in Heav&amp;rsquo;n.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Wherein Lucifer (yes that Lucifer) is, after thousands of years, &lt;em>done&lt;/em> with his job (yes that job) and decides to leave his keys to Dream to figure out what the Hell (heh) to do with.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dream Country</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/25/dream-country/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/25/dream-country/</guid><description>&lt;p>A bit of an odd one. Despite the series being named for Dream, herein we have a handful of mostly disconnected stories with Dream as only a minor character. They&amp;rsquo;re still absolutely fascinating and do give us a much deeper look at the world (both the analogue to our own world and the Dream). The second is especially funny, Dream as a cat. Sure. :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Doll's House</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/25/the-dolls-house/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/25/the-dolls-house/</guid><description>&lt;p>Herein we get a bit more worldbuilding, seeing how Dream is taking back his world after decades of capture. For the most part, we deal with the fallout around a family of one of the women from Sandman 1 (the one who found herself pregnant), but there&amp;rsquo;s also a very well told story of a man granted immortality&amp;ndash;on the condition that he checks up with Dream once every hundred years at the same old pub. Also a &amp;lsquo;Cereal&amp;rsquo; convention (that took me longer than it should have). Of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s well written, beautifully (in the creepy sort of way at times) illustrated, and well worth the read. Onwards!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preludes &amp; Nocturnes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/16/preludes-nocturnes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/16/preludes-nocturnes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sandman is often considered one of the best of the best when it comes to graphic novels and&amp;hellip; for good reason. It&amp;rsquo;s very very good. It&amp;rsquo;s got immortal &amp;lsquo;anthropomorphic personifications&amp;rsquo; (Dream is the main character, but we also get a bit of Death), a crazy deep/complicate mythos, dark and creepy imagery, and a wacky awesome storyline. Pretty much right up my alley. There&amp;rsquo;s little I could do better than the blurb on Goodreads:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In PRELUDES &amp;amp; NOCTURNES, an occultist attempting to capture Death to bargain
for eternal life traps her younger brother Dream instead. After his 70 year
imprisonment and eventual escape, Dream, also known as Morpheus, goes on a
quest for his lost objects of power. On his arduous journey, Morpheus
encounters Lucifer, John Constantine, and an all-powerful madman.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>