<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2016 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2016-book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2016 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2016-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2016 Reading List Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/31/2016-reading-list-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/31/2016-reading-list-retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;p>Once again, a crazy goal. This year, I &lt;em>officially&lt;/em> set a goal of 50 books. &lt;em>Unofficially&lt;/em>, I was still trying to read 100 books. Almost made it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I read 91 books, totaling 35,154 pages (an average of ~96 pages per day). Still a bit of a range on length, from at only 23 pages up to 995 in . An average of 386 per book comes in just 2 shy of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/2015-reading-list-retrospective/">last year&lt;/a>, so I think the short stories still count. 😄&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Coraline</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/31/coraline/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/31/coraline/</guid><description>&lt;p>Before I ever read Coraline, I watched the movie and read &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="4407" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4407.american-gods">American Gods&lt;/a>. I quite enjoyed the former, while the latter was&amp;hellip; not exactly my favorite. So I was cautiously optimistic that I would like Coraline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, consider the optimism well founded. I&amp;rsquo;ll never know if I enjoyed the book more because of the film or if I would have liked it as much had I read it first. So it goes. As it stands, I got a nice mix of the book&amp;rsquo;s / Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s way with words combined with the wonderfully bizarre visuals from the film. It made for quite the experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Light Fantastic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/30/the-light-fantastic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/30/the-light-fantastic/</guid><description>&lt;p>I still feel like The Light Fantastic and The Color of Magic could really be combined into a single larger novel, given that the second takes off running pretty much where there first went off&amp;hellip; and promptly dumps Rincewind and Twoflower back onto the disc somehow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an odd little story, jumping from section to section with a whole cast of new bizarre and amusing character (including the spell in Rincewind&amp;rsquo;s head and a small pile of trees) and locations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Time Machine</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/27/the-time-machine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/27/the-time-machine/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Time Machine is something of a science fiction classic, among the first (if not &lt;em>the&lt;/em> first well known time travel stories). As such, it reads a bit differently than more modern books of the same genre. Rather than dealing overmuch with character or plot, it takes an idea (a time machine!) and runs with it, exploring how such an idea might change the world and exploring our own world through the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far as that goes, The Time Machine is an interesting book. We get a look at one possible future, some 800,000 years in the future, where humanity has evolved into two radically different peoples. It&amp;rsquo;s something of a depressing look at the future, looking into what might be if the gap between the wealthy and the working classes continues to widen and the downfall of both. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting read and works either as philosophical musing or as an adventure tale, which is pretty cool.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Color of Magic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/22/the-color-of-magic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/22/the-color-of-magic/</guid><description>&lt;p>Once upon a time, I tried to read the Discworld books, starting (against several people&amp;rsquo;s advise) with the first and working through all of them. I made it a few books in and put them down, saying that some day I would give them another chance. Well, this is that chance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, I&amp;rsquo;m listening to them all on audiobook. This actually seems to help quite a lot, since it allows me to keep listening while at the same time doing something with my hands and, unless I stop it myself, will keep going without me. It turns out that, given those circumstances, I quite enjoyed the Color of Magic this time around.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/20/harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/20/harry-potter-and-the-deathly-hallows/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows has some of the most powerful moments in the entire series. There are a number of powerful deaths, made all the worse by how we&amp;rsquo;ve grown to know and love (or at least know) these characters over the years. We finally get the last few pieces of how everything fits together &amp;ndash;why Dumbledore trusts Snape for example; and more backstory on Voldemort. All of that would make for probably outright the best book in the series.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/17/harry-potter-and-the-half-blood-prince/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/17/harry-potter-and-the-half-blood-prince/</guid><description>&lt;p>Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince is an excellent story and does quite a lot to offset how much I didn&amp;rsquo;t care for Order of the Phoenix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, Harry is not nearly as annoying as he is in Order of the Phoenix. Perhaps he&amp;rsquo;s growing up, perhaps Rowling realized that she&amp;rsquo;d perhaps overdone it and turned it down again. There are a few iffy moments around relationships this time around, but they&amp;rsquo;re much easier to read and feel much more natural, at least to me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Invention of Hugo Cabret</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/17/the-invention-of-hugo-cabret/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/17/the-invention-of-hugo-cabret/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was a cute little book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, a young boy lives in the walls of a train station, keeping all of the clocks running. He rebuilds a fantastic automaton and meets a toy maker with a bit more in his past than at first meets the eye.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome to Night Vale</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/16/welcome-to-night-vale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/16/welcome-to-night-vale/</guid><description>&lt;p>DNF at 25%.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While I absolutely love the podcast, there&amp;rsquo;s just something about the novel that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work nearly as well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calamity</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/10/calamity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/10/calamity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reading some of the other reviews on Goodreads, I was afraid that Calamity wouldn&amp;rsquo;t live up to the expectation of the previous two Reckoners books. Luckily, at least so far as I&amp;rsquo;m concerned, it not only met the expectations I had for it, it exceeded them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far as the world building / settings go, each of the Reckoners books takes an ordinary city in the former United States and weirds it. First, we had Chicago made of steel. Then New York, mostly underwater and covered with glowing spray paint. This time around? The city of Atlanta, made of salt and on the move. It&amp;rsquo;s just such a bizarre visual that it could carry a decent bit of the story just on that alone. All the little details that entails (sweat breaks down the salt, buildings crumble) just make it all the more interesting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Firefight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/08/firefight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/08/firefight/</guid><description>&lt;p>Firefight is a an excellent followup to Steelheart, taking everything I liked about the first book&amp;ndash;the variety of the Epics&amp;rsquo; powers and the ruined world they&amp;rsquo;ve left behind&amp;ndash;and making it better while at the same point smoothing out my one real complaint&amp;ndash;the &amp;lsquo;bad analogies&amp;rsquo;. They&amp;rsquo;re still there, but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t mention them every page or two, so they actually feel funny this time around, rather than so forced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the upside, the new setting is just as crazy and cool this time around. Last time&amp;ndash;Chicago turned to steel. This time, New York City flooded to the point only the tops of skyscrapers stick out of the water, where fruit trees grow freely in buildings and spray paint glows in the night. It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful image and an interesting contrast to the relentlessly gritty steel of Newcago.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/07/harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/07/harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix/</guid><description>&lt;p>Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix is my least favorite book of the series. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it a bad book, by any stretch of the imagination, but it&amp;rsquo;s just not as fun to read as the others and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really feel like it advances the story in any way. We all know Voldemort is back now&amp;ndash;although the ministry denies it, which is interesting but stretches credulity somewhat. Other than that, not terribly much world-changing happens. We get a lot of angsty teenage Harry, a bit of Hogwarts dating life, and a frankly terrifying new Defense Against the Dark Arts teachers&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Specifically, teenage angsty Harry is thoroughly annoying. I get that teens are angsty and Harry in particular has more reason than most, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any easier to read. Especially since it feels like such a drastic change from previous books.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cruel Beauty</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/05/cruel-beauty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/05/cruel-beauty/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cruel Beauty is a re-skinning of Beauty and the Beast, told in a weird, fantastic world with strong influences from ancient Greece and Rome. Among the retold fairy tales that I&amp;rsquo;ve read, it&amp;rsquo;s among the best of them and manages to feel reasonably like the inspiration story while adding a good number of weird twists and beautiful imagery on top of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, the strongest part of the story for me was the world. It seems that a chunk of reality was torn from what could have been our world and set aside, with a sky that looks like parchment and demons that literally roam the land, making deals. There&amp;rsquo;s a castle chock full of magical rooms and artifacts that are all sorts of cool, even when they&amp;rsquo;re just used as background for a single scene. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of world I would absolutely love to explore in a more freeform style (virtual reality?) someday and the author does an excellent job of bringing it all to life and making it feel real.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/11/15/harry-potter-and-the-goblet-of-fire/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/11/15/harry-potter-and-the-goblet-of-fire/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the most part, Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire is one of the best entries into the series. The worldbuilding and characterization are very cool, expanding on what we&amp;rsquo;ve already seen and making the magical world come alive in all sorts of wonderful ways. Despite a few immersion-defying ideas scattered thoughout the book (we&amp;rsquo;ll get to that later), it&amp;rsquo;s very well written and keeps pulling you through the longest book in the series thus far by almost double.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, nitpick time, since this is getting to be my favorite part of writing these reviews :) &lt;strong>Warning: spoilers, stop reading now if that matters to you&lt;/strong> :&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/11/02/harry-potter-and-the-prisoner-of-azkaban/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/11/02/harry-potter-and-the-prisoner-of-azkaban/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think on previous readings/viewings, the Prisoner of Azkaban was my favorite book/movie. Wacky things happen, you get some cool magical thingie moments (the Marauders map is &lt;em>cool&lt;/em> as is the &lt;em>Monster Book of Monsters&lt;/em> ), you see a bit more of the magical world (Hogsmeade!), and you learn a bit more about Harry&amp;rsquo;s parents and how Hogwarts was before Voldemort was at the height of his power.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of which: another strength of this book is that it basically completely ignores Voldemort. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice switch; one that we don&amp;rsquo;t get to see again.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/27/harry-potter-and-the-chamber-of-secrets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/27/harry-potter-and-the-chamber-of-secrets/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so my re-listen continues. Much as the first book, Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets feels like it&amp;rsquo;s primarily aimed as a children&amp;rsquo;s book, but most definiately enjoyable for adults as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mostly random thoughts: McGonagall makes a good point at the beginning of the books, pointing out that the main characters are kids. They don&amp;rsquo;t always think things through. Miss the train? Perhaps you should just call ahead and someone can fetch you. Nope, have to do things the crazy well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Morning Star</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/26/morning-star/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/26/morning-star/</guid><description>&lt;p>A fitting end to a surprisingly solid (to me at least) end to a surprisingly good series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morning Star basically finishes everything that Golden Son set out to do. It starts out crazy and takes you on a wild roller coaster ride. Things blow up, people die (some more permanently than others), and &amp;hellip; revolution!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Harry Potter and the Sorcerer's Stone</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/18/harry-potter-and-the-sorcerers-stone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/18/harry-potter-and-the-sorcerers-stone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Harry Potter is such a huge thing that I&amp;rsquo;m honestly not sure what in the world I could say that would convince anyone to read/not read it that hasn&amp;rsquo;t already made up their mind. So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short version: Harry Potter and the Sorcerer&amp;rsquo;s Stone is at times clearly intended for a younger audience, but it&amp;rsquo;s a solid book even for an older audience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Steelheart</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/10/steelheart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/10/steelheart/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Reckoners is everything that I love in a Sanderson book, with the main exception being that it&amp;rsquo;s not set in the otherwise shared universe of the Cosmere. It makes sense though, given that Steelheart is set in our universe (more or less).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, a bunch of people gained superpowers. In Sanderson fashion, their powers are varied and interesting and the &amp;lsquo;rules&amp;rsquo; are fairly solid. Powers range from illusions and fire to turning an entire city into metal. On top of that, every Epic (the word &amp;lsquo;Superhero&amp;rsquo; having some legal oddities around it) also has a weakness, thus fulfilling &lt;a href="http://coppermind.net/wiki/Sanderson%27s_Laws_of_Magic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sanderson&amp;amp;rsquo;s Second Law&lt;/a>. Also, they&amp;rsquo;re all pretty much evil. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty neat world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dead Heat</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/01/dead-heat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/01/dead-heat/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hope you like horses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, Dead Heat has two themes that are really interesting and worth exploring within the universe that Briggs is building. First is Charles&amp;rsquo; relationship with an old, non-werewolf friend. They&amp;rsquo;ve touched some on what happens when everyone you know ages and dies, but it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see it in first person. Especially knowing that they don&amp;rsquo;t have to die&amp;ndash;they could be changed instead&amp;ndash;but refuse to do so.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fair Game</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/26/fair-game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/26/fair-game/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People as old and powerful as he should never be given someone to love. For Anna he would destroy the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Fair Game continues the story of Anna and Charles, this time to Boston, getting themselves involved in the investigation of a supernatural-hunter serial killer who&amp;rsquo;s been killing people (including Fae and werewolves) for decades.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Three-Body Problem</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/26/the-three-body-problem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/26/the-three-body-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Three-Body Problem is an interesting book. It was originally written in Chinese and won a whole pile of awards, earning lots of interesting ratings. That was enough to get me to put it on my list for this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the downside, I almost put the book down after the first 10%. It starts with historical backstory and even when the timeline advances to the present day, I still wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly caught up in the story. I very rarely read books without at least some sort of fantastical element to them and even a decent chunk into this book, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hunting Ground</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/23/hunting-ground/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/23/hunting-ground/</guid><description>&lt;p>This time around, we leave the icy mountains to instead to head to Seattle. Long story short, the werewolves are coming out as the Fae did back in the 80s (in this universe). In order to make the transition a bit smoother, Charles and Anna are traveling to Seattle as representatives of the Marrok in order to meet with various delegations of the European wolves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After so many books (if you read the Mercy Thompson books first), it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the first real look at the European wolves , or really European characters in general. We have one wolf who rules most of mainland Europe as an unofficial, cruel mirror of the Marrok, another who believes himself to be King Arthur reborn, and another Omega whereby Anna can learn more about her powers. On top of that, there&amp;rsquo;s a Fae apparently powerful enough to hold the negotiations in check and a white which who gets her power from a rather interesting sacrifice. After only half a dozen characters in the first Alpha and Omega, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see so many more here. It brings Hunting Ground much closer to the Mercy Thompson books in style.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cry Wolf</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/20/cry-wolf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/20/cry-wolf/</guid><description>&lt;p>First off: no, you didn&amp;rsquo;t miss anything. This book really does start a few days after Anna&amp;rsquo;s and Charles&amp;rsquo; are mated, skipping to the end of what essentially makes up the Alpha and Omega short story. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a rough start, especially since so much of Anna&amp;rsquo;s character comes from those events that we never actually see, but I think it works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That leads into the next interesting part / potential problem with these books. Anna was tortured and raped by her first pack. Even though you never actually directly read the scenes in question, they&amp;rsquo;re an unrelenting part of Anna&amp;rsquo;s characters through not only this book but the entire series. On top of that, the paranormal romance parts (read: sex scenes) of Alpha and Omega are far more direct than they ever were in Mercy Thompson. Putting the two together leads to some rather strange and questionable scenes, in particular between Anna and Charles that, at least in my opinion, feel like they were never dealt with as they should/could have been.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fire Touched</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/15/fire-touched/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/15/fire-touched/</guid><description>&lt;p>In some ways, Fire Touched manages to back down from the scale of the previous two books. We&amp;rsquo;re no longer fighting primordial spirits or gods, but rather &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo; the Fae. Of course, as we see through the course of the book, there are some Fae who might as well be gods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, this book as many as any that came before will really change the shape of the future of the universe that Briggs is building. In a nutshell, the wolves are going politically toe to toe with the Fae. Anything more than that would be even more a spoiler, but it&amp;rsquo;s still another interesting bit of worldbuilding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Aurora</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/08/aurora/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/08/aurora/</guid><description>&lt;p>Aurora is something of a strange book. The core of the story follows a generation ship heading out to Tau Ceti at 1/10th the speed of light. The story starts after six generations and more than a hundred years have already passed, just before they arrive. Things are already going wrong and never really get better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that I really didn&amp;rsquo;t expect was how quickly the story goes. Perhaps influenced by &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="686344" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/686344.coyote"> Coyote &lt;/a> novels by &lt;a data-goodreads-type="author" data-goodreads-id="73419" href="https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/73419.allen-steele"> Allen Steele &lt;/a> . This time around though, maybe 10% of the way through and we&amp;rsquo;re already at Tau Ceti. Halfway through and things have already gone terribly. Another quarter and we&amp;rsquo;ve got &lt;span class="spoiler">half the ship heading back and half staying on another world, never to be heard from again&lt;/span>
. The last section deals with &lt;span class="spoiler">returning to Earth&lt;/span>
and is honestly pretty skippable in my opinion. Any one of these could have been a decent chunk of a story all by itself, but all together and there&amp;rsquo;s a constant feeling of flux from story to story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Night Broken</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/06/night-broken/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/06/night-broken/</guid><description>&lt;p>Interesting thing about tight first person point of view: when the main character feels strongly about another character, it comes through really strongly. Take for example Christy, Adam&amp;rsquo;s ex-wife. On one hand, I&amp;rsquo;m sure she&amp;rsquo;s not quite as bad as she appears, given that all we see is from Mercy&amp;rsquo;s point of view. On the other hand, she&amp;rsquo;s really a fairly troubled person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the supernatural scale, we actually manage to step up another level from the River Devil and Coyote and friends. This time around we get an ancient big bad from the Canary Islands who&amp;rsquo;s just as hard to kill as the River Devil but has even more firepower (heh) on their side. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating bit of mythology I&amp;rsquo;ve never come across anywhere else and manages to fit well enough into the current world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frost Burned</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/03/frost-burned/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/09/03/frost-burned/</guid><description>&lt;p>Frost Burned feels almost like two novels sort of smooshed together. In starts out with something of a bang with the entire pack getting kidnapped by people apparently mad enough to take on an entire pack of werewolves at once. By the second half though, that&amp;rsquo;s shifted into a little bit of Fae and a lotta bit of vampire trouble which&amp;ndash;don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong&amp;ndash;is related, but feels like a different sort of book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It actually works surprisingly well though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>River Marked</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/29/river-marked/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/29/river-marked/</guid><description>&lt;p>River Marked takes what we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in the previous 5 Mercy Thompson books and turns it somewhat on its head. Previously, we&amp;rsquo;ve had interesting but not entirely unbelievable versions of werewolves, vampires, ghosts, and fae&amp;ndash;all with a distinctly Old World influence on them. This time around though, we finally dig a bit into Mercy&amp;rsquo;s father&amp;rsquo;s family and get a big nasty beastie from the Americas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to get a bigger world to interact with. I&amp;rsquo;ve read fewer books than I&amp;rsquo;d like dealing with non-European myths and legends, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing to scratch that particular itch. On the other hand, the way it&amp;rsquo;s introduced in this story makes for a rather abrupt &amp;lsquo;power level&amp;rsquo; jump. We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen centuries (millennia?) old vampires and (possibly) wolves and the Gray Lords are nothing to sneeze at, but this is perhaps the first time that &lt;span class="spoiler">literal gods takes the stage&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin Deep</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/21/skin-deep/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/21/skin-deep/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stephen Leeds returns!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, the &amp;lsquo;big idea&amp;rsquo; plot that sort of fades into the background is the idea of encoding research into DNA. It&amp;rsquo;s something that&amp;rsquo;s actually happening now, although (so far as we know) not actually being used to store anything in a person&amp;rsquo;s genetic code. But it&amp;rsquo;s certainly not out of the realm of possibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Legion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/19/legion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/19/legion/</guid><description>&lt;p>After reading so may of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s cosmere novels, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit odd to read one that isn&amp;rsquo;t. There&amp;rsquo;s still a &amp;lsquo;Sanderson feel&amp;rsquo; to it, both in how the characters think and interact and also in this novel&amp;rsquo;s version of a magic system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basic premise: the main character&amp;ndash;Stephen Leeds&amp;ndash;has manifest many &amp;lsquo;aspects&amp;rsquo; that only he can see. Each is a specialist in a specific field that Leeds needed to solve a particular problem. It&amp;rsquo;s left vague if the aspects are actually real (in the sense of being conscious entities, separate from Leeds himself), which makes the story all the more interesting. So far as Leeds is concerned, they are, and his mind will jump through some pretty crazy hoops to keep that illusion going.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>At the Mountains of Madness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/18/at-the-mountains-of-madness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/18/at-the-mountains-of-madness/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is really a great place to end my current reading of HP Lovecraft. Here we get the story of an Antarctic expedition that goes off the rails in the most Lovecraftian way possible. They find not only the madness inducing beasties but a whole civilization thereof from billions of years ago.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, Mountains of Madness plays directly to Lovecraft&amp;rsquo;s strengths: the world building. There isn&amp;rsquo;t much in the way of plot or character (although more than in some of his stories). Instead what we get is a mix of history spanning literally billions of years with the human narrators exploring the ruins.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Horror from the Mound</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/18/the-horror-from-the-mound/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/18/the-horror-from-the-mound/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently read through a large part of Lovecraft&amp;rsquo;s work. It was interesting seeing the first of what eventually became the Lovecraftian Mythos, but there were still some issues with it&amp;ndash;Lovecraft wasn&amp;rsquo;t really the best when it came to plot or character and was very much a product of his times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If The Horror from the Mound is any indication, Howard took the feel of the world that Lovecraft had build and really built on it. The Horror from the Mound takes something that we&amp;rsquo;ve heard of a thousand times before (the vampire) and takes it in another direction. Well worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Golden Son</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/14/golden-son/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/14/golden-son/</guid><description>&lt;p>Golden Son takes up where Red Rising left off, following the continuing adventures of Darrow, the Red turned Gold as he tries to tear apart society&amp;hellip; and hopefully rebuild it for the better?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, the world building is about the same as the first book in that it&amp;rsquo;s better/more believable than the conceits of most YA novels and I like the sci fi tropes. We&amp;rsquo;re also starting to see some of the exceptions to the rules that everyone (in universe) thinks were so unassailable the first time around, which is interesting. We do get a more expanded scope though, seeing much of the rest of the Solar System, which is neat. And there are interesting hints at some of the history of this world; like how the Obsidians got to where they are and why there are no robots or anything quite like that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Silver Borne</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/11/silver-borne/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/11/silver-borne/</guid><description>&lt;p>No more vampires, which is a plus for me at least. Your milage may vary. Instead we get a mix of wolves and Fae, which in my opinion are the best parts of the Mercyverse worldbuilding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The subplot with Samuel is interesting. One thing that many urban fantasies tend to sweep under the rug is exactly how hard it could be to live for century after century. Many will pay lip service to it, mentioning it from time to time, but the characters often still feel relatively young. Samuel has some of that as well, but there are at least hints of of it here that he is really an old wolf.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bone Crossed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/08/bone-crossed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/08/bone-crossed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Back to vampires for a little while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Remember back when Mercy pissed off the local vampire leadership? Well now she&amp;rsquo;s run out of town&amp;hellip; and of course bumps into more vampires. One thing leads to another&amp;hellip; vampires die&amp;hellip; and Mercy saves the day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Short Stay in Hell</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/04/a-short-stay-in-hell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/04/a-short-stay-in-hell/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was reading about the Borges &amp;ldquo;The Library of Babel&amp;rdquo; all about a huge (albeit finite) library containing every book that could ever be written (so long as it contains 410 pages containing 40 lines of 80 characters each), which reminded me of the short story A Short Stay in Hell, so I re-read it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a thoroughly intriguing exploration of that same idea, wrapped in the idea that this is an afterlife (turns out the Zoroastrians were right all along). There are some interesting consequences to a library light-years across and the societies that develop therein.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Shadow Out Of Time</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/04/the-shadow-out-of-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/04/the-shadow-out-of-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was kind of a bizarre story, bouncing around in time and space a bit. Then again, it sounds like perhaps the narrator had a bizarre life, bouncing around in time and space. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, an interesting read and one of the better Lovecraft stories I&amp;rsquo;ve read. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting trying to figure out how much of the story actually happened (in universe) and how much might just be some sort of mental health issues on the part of the narrator.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iron Kissed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/02/iron-kissed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/02/iron-kissed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Iron Kissed gets into one of the most interesting parts of the Mercy Thompson universe: the Fae. They may have come out to the public a few decades ago, but only the least of the Fae. When a small pile of the greater Fae are brutally murdered, Mercy gets involved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We get to learn a fair bit more about the Fae in general and Uncle Mike and Zee in particular, which is nice. They&amp;rsquo;re fascinating and just alien enough to be believable. On top of that, Mercy finally manages to choose between Sam and Adam, although if it will stick, who can say&amp;hellip; We start getting into a bit more of the romance aspects that some readers of the series are expecting&amp;ndash;and then the final section of the book happens (see spoiler section below).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blood Bound</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/23/blood-bound/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/23/blood-bound/</guid><description>&lt;p>Blood Bound follows Mercy Thompson as Stefan the vampire calls in a favor owed from the events of the first book. What follows is a violent, blood soaked look into the darker parts of the world Patricia Briggs has built.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While there was a decent amount of violence in Moon Called, Blood Bound out does it easily. Given that the big bad is a demon possessed vampire (as if one or the other wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be enough), it&amp;rsquo;s not surprising, but there are a few fairly intense scenes in here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Shadow Over Innsmouth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/23/the-shadow-over-innsmouth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/23/the-shadow-over-innsmouth/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Shadow Over Innsmouth introduces the coastal town of Innsmouth and the amphibious Deep Ones to Lovecraft&amp;rsquo;s mythos. It&amp;rsquo;s a well put together story, all about a traveler that decided to take a detour he was warned against and ends up in a town with something of a dark secret.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, the plot is relatively straight forward and even the twist at the end was sort of expected (given the narrators genealogical bent). It&amp;rsquo;s still interesting to read though and there are some really tense moments and shiver inducing descriptions of the Deep Ones.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moon Called</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/18/moon-called/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/18/moon-called/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take a kitchen sink urban fantasy world (vampires and werewolves and Fae, oh my), toss in a few interesting twists and head it with a woman mechanic protagonist with a flair of Native American magic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuilding-wise, there are a lot of urban fantasy tropes in here, but on the other hand tropes are tropes for a reason. The werewolves are extremely hierarchical (despite the fact that real world wolves aren&amp;rsquo;t actually, but it makes for a more interesting story) and there are some interesting aspects to pack magic that I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen elsewhere. Vampires are fairly typical thus far, although having one that drives around in a Mystery Machine van is kind of hilarious. (Plus I know we get more of him later). Walkers I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in other books and we really know little about them thus far (although to be fair, neither does Mercy), but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a bit of non-European flavor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Dunwich Horror</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/17/the-dunwich-horror/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/17/the-dunwich-horror/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reading The Dunwich Horror back to back with Call of Cthulhu is an interesting experience. The former is everything I wanted the latter to be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The core of the Horror itself (Yog-Sothoth) is described just enough to be terrifying, but not so much as to be anything concrete. It impacts on the people and land around Dunwhich just keep building up, growing more and more horrible. In particular, the Whateley family&amp;hellip; Wilbur and his even more monstrous brother. &lt;em>&lt;em>shivers&lt;/em>&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bands of Mourning</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/12/the-bands-of-mourning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/12/the-bands-of-mourning/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sanderson has this tendency to completely change the world in ways that you&amp;rsquo;d never think could possibly work&amp;hellip; and yet pull them off. He did it between the first and second Mistborn books and he just did it again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuilding-wise, so many things have changed. Yet he hasn&amp;rsquo;t really broken the rules that he set down in the previous books, just expanded them, exploring areas that we&amp;rsquo;ve never seen before. We learn about people that live far from the Lord Ruler&amp;rsquo;s rule. We learn about new and fascinating ways that the Metallic Arts can be used&amp;ndash;Feruchemy in particular. And we start to see just how magic and technology can be combined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Call of Cthulhu</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/11/the-call-of-cthulhu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/11/the-call-of-cthulhu/</guid><description>&lt;p>For all I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of The Call of Cthulhu, I expected more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, you have three short stories about perhaps the best known of the Old Ones. Truly ancient cults. Even Cthulhu himself rising. But it&amp;rsquo;s all just a little underwhelming, especially when read back to back with The Festival and The Colour out of Space.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Colour Out of Space</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/08/the-colour-out-of-space/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/08/the-colour-out-of-space/</guid><description>&lt;p>Who would have thought that a colour could be so terrifying&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess it helps that it&amp;rsquo;s actually some life devouring, madness inducing shade that fell to earth in a meteorite and proceeded to wreck havoc on a local farm.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Festival</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/08/the-festival/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/08/the-festival/</guid><description>&lt;p>References abound to things I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of before. Arkham. The Necronomicon. The mad Arab Abdul Alhazred. Miskatonic University.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is the narrator the same man as in The Nameless City? No idea. Feels like not. But it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a shared universe. One with an impressive feeling of size for only a pair of short stories thus far.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Fifth Season</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/07/the-fifth-season/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/07/the-fifth-season/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Fifth Season takes place in what could easily by (may intentionally be?) a far future Earth where volcanoes, earthquakes, and various other seismic disasters have an annoying tendency to kill off large portions of humanity every few centuries. Combine that with a few powerful individuals (orogenes) who have magical abilities associated with said earthquakes that they cannot always control&amp;hellip; And you have quite the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It took me a while to realize that the various different sections of the book were following the story of &lt;span class="spoiler">a single character. She went by different names at different times and didn't always have the same powers,&lt;/span>
so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t always easy to tell who you were dealing with. On top of that, there are jumps in the timeline from chapter to chapter, covering years (if not decades). Once you finally figure out who and when you&amp;rsquo;re reading about, it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see how everything fits together. Before that&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s confusing and a bit frustrating.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Nameless City</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/07/the-nameless-city/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/07/the-nameless-city/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. That&amp;rsquo;s Lovecraft.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the first of his that I&amp;rsquo;ve read (complete works for 99¢ on Amazon), although I&amp;rsquo;m relatively familiar with the mythos. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Red Rising</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/03/red-rising/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/03/red-rising/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take one part Hunger Games, one part Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game, and mix in some Harry Potter to taste. Take the whole thing and put it on Mars. Voila Red Rising.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Despite the description&amp;ndash;or perhaps because of it&amp;ndash;I did actually enjoy Red Rising quite a bit. Essentially Red Rising follows the story of Darrow, a Red (slave caste) of Mars who, with the help of the local freedom fighters / terrorist cell is biomodded to be a Gold (ruling caste) instead. That&amp;rsquo;s the first third or so of the book. After that, we switch to full Hunger Games meets Ender&amp;rsquo;s Game mode with a game of capture the flag cranked up to 11 taking up the rest of the book.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>