<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Religious Fiction on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/writing/genres/religious-fiction/</link><description>Recent content in Religious Fiction on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 14:00:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/writing/genres/religious-fiction/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 20 - The Morning After</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/11/chapter-20-the-morning-after/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 14:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/11/chapter-20-the-morning-after/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Maxwell came to visit Andi in the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her and Jenny had been given a shared room. The hospital had plenty of rooms and both of the women luckily had insurance that would have even covered a private room, but neither of them wanted it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had just been through too much in the past few weeks to want to be alone. Andi still had that feeling running up and down her spine that Percy couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly be dead&amp;ndash;well, dead again if her suspicions were correct&amp;ndash;and that he&amp;rsquo;d just come after them yet again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 19 - Final Jeopardy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/08/chapter-19-final-jeopardy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 14:00:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/08/chapter-19-final-jeopardy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Somehow, they made it away from the train. They left just as the emergency crews were starting to arrive and cordon off the area. Anyone still there was being checked over by the medical crews first and then the cops after that. With how Andi looked&amp;ndash;covered head to foot in a tarry, black paste even after some had begun to dissipate&amp;ndash;she was sure they would have had all sorts of questions for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worse yet, Officer Williams was one of the first cops on the scene. She didn&amp;rsquo;t think that she would ever see him again, not if she had anything to say about it. Not after he had stopped by and all but accused them of Ms. Morris&amp;rsquo; death. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be good, not at all, for them to be here, now.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 18 - Demon in Black</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/04/chapter-18-demon-in-black/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/04/chapter-18-demon-in-black/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;She jerked her head up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maxwell stood there, towards the doors on one side&amp;ndash;the side without the demon banging at the door. She How had he gotten over there? Hadn&amp;rsquo;t he been thrown out of the train on the opposite side just a little big before? For that matter, hadn&amp;rsquo;t he been &lt;em&gt;thrown out a window&lt;/em&gt;? He looked absolutely none the worse for the wear. He could have just stepped onto the car, a normal passenger.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 17 - Showdown</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/01/chapter-17-showdown/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 14:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/01/chapter-17-showdown/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The three of them fanned out immediately, forgetting that less than an hour before they&amp;rsquo;d been doing their best to kill one another. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to realize what had happened thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura&amp;rsquo;s car was gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to figure out what must have happened.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 16 - Counterpoint</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/28/chapter-16-counterpoint/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 14:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/28/chapter-16-counterpoint/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One might imagine that the two of you have a good reason for being here?&amp;rdquo; Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s voice was smooth and disturbingly calm. He didn&amp;rsquo;t seem at all perturbed by the forces arrayed against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, his demon &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; bigger after all.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 15 - Revelation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/25/chapter-15-revelation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/25/chapter-15-revelation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Andi blinked. &amp;ldquo;Break into&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; she said under her breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure you were coming back,&amp;rdquo; Laura said, speaking right over her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We did come back,&amp;rdquo; Andi said slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura nodded. &amp;ldquo;I see that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No. Earlier. We were already here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 14 - Maxwell's Demon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/21/chapter-14-maxwells-demon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/21/chapter-14-maxwells-demon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;thwip&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a sudden blur and a quick sound, something like the sound a whip might make.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;thwip&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another blur and this time a thin red line appeared across the demon&amp;rsquo;s ink black flesh.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 13 - Descent</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/18/chapter-13-descent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 14:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/18/chapter-13-descent/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;They arrived back at the winery nice and early. Too early in fact; the winery wasn&amp;rsquo;t scheduled to open for a solid hour after they got there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Think we should just head on out?&amp;rdquo; Jenny suggested. There was no one else even parked at the winery. Granted, serving only sandwiches, wine, and cheese meant they didn&amp;rsquo;t have to do much so far as setting up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andi considered. She didn&amp;rsquo;t want to head out there without Laura. Just in case they didn&amp;rsquo;t find anything demonic, the situation was going to be all sorts of awkward. But on the other hand, if Laura wasn&amp;rsquo;t here, they didn&amp;rsquo;t have to figure out how to get her to look the other way when they just walked through the walls&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s do it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 12 - Big Red</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/14/chapter-12-big-red/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2013 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/14/chapter-12-big-red/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t know the passcode?&amp;rdquo; Andi asked. She knew that Laura had said she was locked out, but somehow she still expected her to know the code. How else were they supposed to get in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laura shook her head though. &amp;ldquo;I was hoping you might have a better idea.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andi couldn&amp;rsquo;t think why. The problem was, she did have a few better ideas. But they relied on either revealing their demonic powers or getting Laura to leave and on doing a bit of damage to the Clerk family shed. Neither was a particularly palatable first option.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 11 - Clerk Family Winery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/11/chapter-11-clerk-family-winery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 14:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/11/chapter-11-clerk-family-winery/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t you just have gotten his phone number or something?&amp;rdquo; Jenny was obviously joking, but there was just enough of an undercurrent of truth there that Andi couldn&amp;rsquo;t well ignore it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As I&amp;rsquo;ve told you a dozen times, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have a physical body. How could he have a cell phone?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenny smiled, but she wasn&amp;rsquo;t about to let the point go that easily. &amp;ldquo;Yeah, but he has to be some sort of demon or angel right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 10 - About Time</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/07/chapter-10-about-time/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 14:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/07/chapter-10-about-time/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the demonic manipulation of temporal dynamics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked up at Jenny with a doubtful look on her face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s about what I thought.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And then?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It looks feasible. I mean, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing completely insane in there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time travel isn&amp;rsquo;t insane?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 9 - Keep Your Friends Close</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/04/chapter-9-keep-your-friends-close/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 14:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/04/chapter-9-keep-your-friends-close/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Andi couldn&amp;rsquo;t help herself. &amp;ldquo;Dead?&amp;rdquo; She&amp;rsquo;d seemed perfectly fine when they&amp;rsquo;d been there. Who could she be dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The officer watched her for a moment more. She realized belatedly that he had dropped that particular nugget on them precisely in order to elicit a reaction. Hopefully surprised was the correct response…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she didn&amp;rsquo;t say anything else, the officer continued. &amp;ldquo;Dead. The neighbors called us at about 3:30 pm about a potential disturbance. They said that they&amp;rsquo;d heard someone screaming and then several gunshots. When we arrived shortly later, she was dead.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 8 - And Something Else</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/30/chapter-8-and-something-else/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/30/chapter-8-and-something-else/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;She found him within ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More accurately&amp;ndash;he found her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One moment, she was alone. At this hour, there weren&amp;rsquo;t many other passengers. The last of the daytime passengers had already gone home and the late night partiers had hours to go yet. She was the only person on the lower level of her car and there was only one couple on the upper floor. However, they seemed otherwise occupied.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 7 - Angels and Demons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/27/chapter-7-angels-and-demons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 14:00:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/27/chapter-7-angels-and-demons/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If she hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen her with her own two eyes, she wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have believed it. The demon was still burning away behind them&amp;ndash;she could feel the heat&amp;ndash;but that meant&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Of course dear. Now, how can I help you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andi and Jenny looked at each other. Without a word, they moved together, doing their best to hide the still burning body behind them. Andi stole a quick glance behind her&amp;ndash;not long left now.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NaNoWriMo 2013 - Whee!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/26/nanowrimo-2013-whee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 14:00:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/26/nanowrimo-2013-whee/</guid><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/2013/2013-Winner-NaNoWriMo.png"&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five days ahead of time and I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished my 50,000 words for the month!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 6 - Buyer Beware</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/23/chapter-6-buyer-beware/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 14:00:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/23/chapter-6-buyer-beware/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After bandaging up her hand, Jenny brought up a point that Andi hadn&amp;rsquo;t even considered. Had Morris&amp;ndash;the old lady who owned the bookstore where Andi had originally found the book&amp;ndash;known about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had she had anything to do with the book showing up in Andi&amp;rsquo;s bag?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 5 - Armed and Dangerous</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/20/chapter-5-armed-and-dangerous/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 14:00:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/20/chapter-5-armed-and-dangerous/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It turned out that the more powerful the demon was you were trying to summon, the more complicated the summoning became. This was going to take hours of prep work and the better part of half an hour just to do the summoning. Honestly, she would have liked to take longer, but she didn&amp;rsquo;t know that she would be able to. The new chapters of the book had laid out what she&amp;rsquo;d expected&amp;ndash;the more you tried to add to a summoning, the less time you had to do it in. That seemed to set a hard limit on just what could be done, but it was hard to calculate. Perhaps there were exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 4 - The Man on the Train</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/16/chapter-4-the-man-on-the-train/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 14:00:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/16/chapter-4-the-man-on-the-train/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The next morning, she didn&amp;rsquo;t even glance at the book on her way out of the apartment, instead opting to grab her own breakfast on the way rather than chance waiting in the kitchen. The idea of using her newly &amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;enhanced&lt;/em&gt; burner was there in the corner of her mind, but she wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite sure hot to deal with that just yet. Yet the summoning having been done had rather an effect on her. She felt lighter than she had in far longer than when she had just first seen the book. She felt lighter than she had in months. It was a great feeling.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 3 - Summoning a Demon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/13/chapter-3-summoning-a-demon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/13/chapter-3-summoning-a-demon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The last ingredient that Andi had to track down was the blood. She had a few ideas how to go about it, but none of them particularly appealed to her. Her best options at the moment were to go to a butcher and just flat out ask if they sold blood&amp;ndash;she thought that they might, to make certain sausages and other foods out of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, she could just a cut of meat and hope that enough drained out that she could get by that way. She honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t know how pure the blood would have to be. It would be a pity to go through all of this effort and not know if the summoning hadn&amp;rsquo;t worked because it couldn&amp;rsquo;t possibly work or because she hadn&amp;rsquo;t quite followed the directions. Just the same as she knew that she had to try it, she knew that if she didn&amp;rsquo;t give it her all, she wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to stop thinking about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 2 - Writings in Silver</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/09/chapter-2-writings-in-silver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2013 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/09/chapter-2-writings-in-silver/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Andi awoke the next morning, sure that the entire night&amp;rsquo;s activities had been a dream. Sure, she couldn&amp;rsquo;t particularly remember how she had gotten to bed&amp;ndash;or even how she had gotten home, if her memories of the bookstore and the train were not to be believed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it had all been too ridiculous. A book that had somehow followed her home. The feeling of falling, even if it hadn&amp;rsquo;t come back. The man on the train; had he even been related to all the rest of it? A book that her cat irrationally hated&amp;ndash;and she couldn&amp;rsquo;t even read. Writing that wasn&amp;rsquo;t writing, at least until it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computational Demonology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chapter 1 - The Book</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/06/chapter-1-the-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/06/chapter-1-the-book/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It all started with a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t look terribly out of place&amp;ndash;it was a book store after all&amp;ndash;and Andi&amp;rsquo;s eyes just slid right over it at first. But something drew them back.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NaNoWriMo 2013 - Computational Demonology</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/06/nanowrimo-2013-computational-demonology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 04:55:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/11/06/nanowrimo-2013-computational-demonology/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Yup, I&amp;rsquo;m doing it again. And this time, I&amp;rsquo;m doing it while finishing my PhD, working a full time job, and adapting to life two thousand miles away from where I was born. Should be interesting. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 74</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/15/confession-day-74/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 07:30:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/15/confession-day-74/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="163---al-eizariya"&gt;163 - al-Eizariya&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;PRESENT DAY&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and licked my face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was such a surprising yet so absolutely doggy thing to do that I barked out a laugh; I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t help it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 73</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/14/confession-day-73/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 03:00:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/14/confession-day-73/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="159---al-eizariya"&gt;159 - al-Eizariya&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRESENT DAY&lt;/strong&gt;
I could see the two of them struggling for control, each trying to force the Cup from the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far as I knew, Lazarus was still mostly human&amp;ndash;albeit able to appear and disappear in a most unsettling manner. Mr. Average on the other hand&amp;hellip; not so much. He definitely had something going on in the supernatural department.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 72</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/13/confession-day-72/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 04:30:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/13/confession-day-72/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="156---al-eizariya"&gt;156 - al-Eizariya&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRESENT DAY&lt;/strong&gt;
Why did he want the three of us?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason he had gotten it in his head that we would be the perfect bait to lure Lazarus to him.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 71</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/12/confession-day-71/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 06:00:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/12/confession-day-71/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="154---chicago"&gt;154 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
I threw myself at not-Alex&amp;rsquo;s side. I doubted that it would do any good, but there had to be some hope&amp;ndash;although I knew in my heart of hearts that there was none for John. I could see the blood. I could see how still he was. I knew that he was dead. Again, if he had been telling the truth. Not that that mattered any more.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 70</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/11/confession-day-70/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 09:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/11/confession-day-70/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="151---chicago"&gt;151 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
Running into a thick white fog to help a self-proclaimed dead man fight off his once brother turned demon wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly the most intelligent thing that I&amp;rsquo;d ever done. Truth be told, I had no idea what I was even going to do once I got in there, but I knew that I had to try something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Amanda, if nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 69</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/10/confession-day-69/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 09:20:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/10/confession-day-69/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="149---not-rome"&gt;149 - Not Rome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRESENT DAY&lt;/strong&gt;
The instant I saw the all together too average man, I could feel my heartbeat speeding up and mouth mouth drying out. My body was preparing to fight, remembering all to well the last time I&amp;rsquo;d been in his pretense.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 68</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/09/confession-day-68/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 06:30:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/09/confession-day-68/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="146---chicago"&gt;146 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
My cry was in vain. The fire extinguished passed through the air as if it were just that&amp;ndash;air. There was a muted flash of light from right in front of me and a sound like popcorn popping. A heartbeat later and both were gone. The flash hadn&amp;rsquo;t been bright but nevertheless it was more than enough to bring my hands instinctively to my face. When my vision cleared, I saw that the carefully placed gemstones had moved. Several had jumped, leaving tiny black smudges, almost like burn marks. At least three of them appeared to have cracked into several smaller pieces while one of the quartz crystals&amp;ndash;the one closest to me&amp;ndash;had been reduced to little more than a pile of dust.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 67</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/08/confession-day-67/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 08:15:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/08/confession-day-67/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="144---baghdad"&gt;144 - Baghdad&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL YEARS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
The sound in such an enclose space was deafening. I&amp;rsquo;d thought that I knew what to expect, but there&amp;rsquo;s really nothing that can prepare you for something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within moments, my ears were ringing, seconds after that, the world took on a muted quality.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 66</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/07/confession-day-66/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 04:30:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/07/confession-day-66/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="142---romepresent-daya-knock-down-drag-out-preacher-fight-was-coming-between-father-antonio-and-myself-that-much-was-sure-but-whenever-that-might-be-it-most-certainly-wasnt-now"&gt;142 - Rome&lt;strong&gt;PRESENT DAY&lt;/strong&gt;A knock down, drag out preacher fight was coming between Father Antonio and myself, that much was sure. But whenever that might be, it most certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t now.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as I&amp;rsquo;d managed to threaten my fellow priest, there was a sudden grinding sound all around, so loud that for just a moment nothing else seemed to exist. Nothing but that terrible sound.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 65</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/06/confession-day-65/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 03:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/06/confession-day-65/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="139---rome"&gt;139 - Rome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRESENT DAY&lt;/strong&gt;
I turned back into the truck. One of the guards&amp;ndash;the one in the ordinary uniform&amp;ndash;was still unconscious, the other in his black armor was sitting there as if he hadn&amp;rsquo;t a care in the world, despite the gun held on him by Father Antonio.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 64</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/05/confession-day-64/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 03:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/05/confession-day-64/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="135---chicago"&gt;135 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
As Alex appeared I heard several gasps from around the room. For all I knew, one of them could have been mine. It was one thing to know that Alex was a ghost and to know that what we were doing was supposed to call him hear to us. It was quite another for him to just appear there like that.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 63</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/04/confession-day-63/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 09:02:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/04/confession-day-63/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="134---baghdad"&gt;134 - Baghdad&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL YEARS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
It was quick and it was brutal. And then it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like that, a dozen or more men were dead or dying right in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 62</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/03/confession-day-62/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 08:30:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/03/confession-day-62/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="131---chicago"&gt;131 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
Chanting in what felt like Latin&amp;ndash;although a good portion of the words I&amp;rsquo;d never heard before&amp;ndash;brought me back to the days when I&amp;rsquo;d been studying at the seminary. There had been many a class where we&amp;rsquo;d been expected to know the exact text of manuscripts that predated the English language itself by hundreds of years&amp;ndash;translations not allowed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 61</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/02/confession-day-61/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 08:48:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/01/02/confession-day-61/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="130---chicago"&gt;130 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
I arrived back at Mrs. Claire&amp;rsquo;s before John Smith. I debated if I were actually going to tell the women there about the details of our arrangement&amp;ndash;that he&amp;rsquo;d be arriving shortly himself&amp;ndash;but eventually I settled on not. They would find out soon enough; otherwise, it would only serve to complicate things further.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 60</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/31/confession-day-60/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 06:30:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/31/confession-day-60/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="129---rome"&gt;129 - Rome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL YEARS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
&amp;ldquo;What in the world is going on?&amp;rdquo; I heard one of the people I hadn&amp;rsquo;t known that had been abducted with us whisper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have an answer for him, but at the moment, it was just as well. For just when he spoke, the cop in the dark armor&amp;ndash;it was slightly shiny, which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed until we were in the light of the back of the truck&amp;ndash;glared at him and shifted his gun in a way we were all sure to notice.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 59</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/30/confession-day-59/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 09:30:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/30/confession-day-59/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="126---chicago"&gt;126 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
&amp;ldquo;So let me get this straight,&amp;rdquo; I said. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re dead. Your brother is dead. Everyone is dead.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure. Perhaps it was a bit of an overreaction. But my head was still spinning from that particular revelation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 58</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/29/confession-day-58/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 09:04:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/29/confession-day-58/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="125---baghdad"&gt;125 - Baghdad&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL YEARS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
We ran. We ran like the very hounds of hell were after us, across that courtyard, right up to the very front doors of the museum. I kept expecting shots to ring out. To once again be shot, this time in my chest rather than in the back. And this time, I was sure, that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so lucky.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 57</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/28/confession-day-57/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 08:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/28/confession-day-57/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="123---rome"&gt;123 - Rome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRESENT DAY&lt;/strong&gt;
When I saw that angels are fast, that really doesn&amp;rsquo;t help to describe how terrifying it is to be directly in front of not one, but two angels running directly at you&amp;ndash;one with sword raised over his head and the other with a smaller, curved blade to her side.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 56</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/27/confession-day-56/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 09:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/27/confession-day-56/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="122---chicago"&gt;122 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
Time seemed not so much to slow as to go sideways for a moment, a whole series of things not happening so much as at once but rather in a timeless sort of mishmash.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 55</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/26/confession-day-55/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2012 10:55:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/26/confession-day-55/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="121---chicago"&gt;121 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
In the end, we decided on a combination of the first two options, with the third acting as a sort of failsafe. Just in case.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 54</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/25/confession-day-54/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 03:15:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/25/confession-day-54/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="118---baghdad"&gt;118 - Baghdad&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL YEARS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
The sounds of gunfire started just as we were getting into position. that wasn&amp;rsquo;t supposed to happen&amp;ndash;we were supposed to be among the first in. Had we already lost the element of surprise? That didn&amp;rsquo;t bode well. Not at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 53</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/24/confession-day-53/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 09:00:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/24/confession-day-53/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="116---rome"&gt;116 - Rome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRESENT DAY&lt;/strong&gt;
Between Michael, Father Antonio, and Amira, we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the slightest problem getting into Vatican City, despite the late hour. No one even seemed to notice us, although if that was the norm or some sort of supernatural intervention on Michael&amp;rsquo;s part I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have said.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 52</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/23/confession-day-52/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 02:45:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/23/confession-day-52/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="113---rome"&gt;113 - Rome&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRESENT DAY&lt;/strong&gt;
&amp;ldquo;What happened to you?&amp;rdquo; Direct seemed the way to go&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He seemed to be having trouble catching his breath. &amp;ldquo;Big dog.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 51</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/22/confession-day-51/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 04:55:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/22/confession-day-51/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="112---chicago"&gt;112 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
I never would have expected to be going back to Mrs. Claire&amp;rsquo;s so soon. But I needed supplies. If I could believe what Sister Kat had said&amp;ndash;and I had no particular reason to doubt her&amp;ndash;then there were things that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have the first idea how to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I knew someone who did.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 50</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/21/confession-day-50/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 07:25:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/21/confession-day-50/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="110---chicago"&gt;110 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
I made call after call to my fellow priests around the diocese, yet I wasn&amp;rsquo;t having any luck narrowing down exactly what I was supposed to do about the situation. Really, there were two problems that were getting in my way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 49</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/20/confession-day-49/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 07:30:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/20/confession-day-49/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="108---baghdad"&gt;108 - Baghdad&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL YEARS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
I took a gun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight&amp;ndash;which is of course 20/20&amp;ndash;that may not have been the best idea I&amp;rsquo;d ever had.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 48</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/19/confession-day-48/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 09:30:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/19/confession-day-48/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="105---chicago"&gt;105 - Chicago&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL WEEKS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
After that all together too depressing exit, I was more than ready to leave Mrs. Claire&amp;rsquo;s. Now I knew that she had been telling the truth&amp;ndash;she was being haunted. So far as if Alex was actually having any effect on her business, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t say for sure, but that was a completely secondary motivation. And then there was Alex&amp;rsquo;s request. That was something to think about.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Confession - Day 47</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/18/confession-day-47/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 09:30:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/12/18/confession-day-47/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="104---baghdad"&gt;104 - Baghdad&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEVERAL YEARS AGO&lt;/strong&gt;
&amp;ldquo;There has to be more to it then that.&amp;rdquo; I could feel the pitch of my voice rising, but there was little I could do to control it. He just wasn&amp;rsquo;t willing to listen to reason and it was extremely frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>