<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Starship's Mage on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/starships-mage/</link><description>Recent content in Starship's Mage on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/starships-mage/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Starship's Mage</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/14/starships-mage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/14/starships-mage/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This place is always awe-inspiring to me,” Jenna said quietly from the edge of the room, and Damien glanced up from the impossibly perfect model of the ship to look at her. “I don’t understand any of how what you do works, but this room…this is the key to the stars.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“That was the Compact,” Damien half-whispered, reveling in the power pulsing around him. “Peace between Mage and Mundane, between Mars and Earth…and in exchange, we gave you the stars.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On one hand, Starship&amp;rsquo;s Mage is (surprisingly?) hard sci fi. You have starship&amp;rsquo;s dealing with spin induced gravity, limits on acceleration so as not to crush your crew, and no&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> faster than light communication.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, you have magic.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Um, sir, what is that plaque supposed to do?” he asked, intentionally changing the subject.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“It’s a security spell,” the Captain explained, seizing on the topic change. “It detects if anyone enters the office with hostile intent.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Damien traced the flow of energy through the runes and shook his head again. “You might want to have your senior Mage look at it,” he told the Captain. “The scribe used future imperative tenses instead of future-probabilistic. It’s actually slightly encouraging the chance of violence, not predicting it.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s laced throughout the story in a relatively light way&amp;ndash;especially considering that one of the main characters &lt;em>is&lt;/em> a mage. But right where it counts? In the ability to actually &lt;em>travel&lt;/em> faster than light? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s where magic comes into play.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a weirdly fascinating idea and makes me want more of it. Just how many hijinks can you get up to, mixing scifi and fantasy?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Storywise, it&amp;rsquo;s quite the adventure, starting with pirates and a crew on the run and only escalating from there. The final three way chase/showdown is quite spectacular&amp;ndash;only to drop one heck of a cliffhanger. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort that you could leave off and (mostly) have a solid standalone book, but at the same time leaves you wanting more. Which I &lt;em>do&lt;/em> appreciate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One gotcha that at first I thought I was going to be annoyed about was the idea that Damien was a special/one of a kind/chosen one mage. He could do things no other mage could do. I won&amp;rsquo;t go too far into it&amp;ndash;spoilers!&amp;ndash;but suffice it to say that he&amp;rsquo;s not the only &amp;lsquo;impossible&amp;rsquo; thing in this universe&amp;hellip; and the sequels promise more!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a fun story with some fascinating world building. And it&amp;rsquo;s for that alone that I want to read more. It turns out that there are already 18 books in this series (with another &lt;em>60&lt;/em> from the other over the last decade and change). So we&amp;rsquo;ll have to see where it goes next!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>