<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Joss Whedon on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/joss-whedon/</link><description>Recent content in Joss Whedon on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/joss-whedon/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Avengers: Age of Ultron</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Hawkeye: The city is flying and we&amp;rsquo;re fighting an army of robots. And I have a bow and arrow. Nothing makes sense.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Age of Ultron is an odd movie. From the perspective of a summer blockbuster/action movie, it&amp;rsquo;s solid. The opening action scene is wonderfully avengerful, there are all manner of awesome fights (the Hulk versus Iron Man fight and the final battle come to mind), and we get a few new characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Avengers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hooo boy. When I &lt;a href="#original-2012-review">first saw this movie&lt;/a> (in theaters, in the before times), I was pretty much blown away. It was a big budget, box office smasher of a movie, bringing together an entire series of super hero movies in one giant box office smash. It was something that had never really been done before&amp;hellip; and they managed to actually pull it off. And not only that (knowing what I do now), it was the start of something &lt;strong>even bigger&lt;/strong>. Absolutely bonkers to believe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, with the benefit of hindsight, it does have a few issues for it&amp;rsquo;s size: you don&amp;rsquo;t get as much time with all the characters as you need. The jokes are very Whedon-esqe and over the top&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s one thing to have Tony Stark quip, but things like Thor&amp;rsquo;s immediate &amp;ldquo;he&amp;rsquo;s adopted&amp;rdquo; quip just don&amp;rsquo;t feel right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But for what it is&amp;ndash;a giant summer blockbuster and a fantastic action movie&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much top of the line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It actually topped my list back in during my &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2012-movie-reviews/">2012 Movie Revies&lt;/a>, but this time around&amp;hellip; I just really like the other individual films more. So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Still well well worth the watch).&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="original-2012-review">Original 2012 review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s really not much to say about this that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been said / won&amp;rsquo;t be said a thousand times over. Long story short, it&amp;rsquo;s a great movie and a hit out of the park for everyone involved. I liked it enough that I&amp;rsquo;m sure to see it again and I strongly suggest that you go to.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>