<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Joe Robert Cole on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/01/joe-robert-cole/</link><description>Recent content in Joe Robert Cole on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:15:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/01/joe-robert-cole/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wakanda Forever</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/01/wakanda-forever/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/01/wakanda-forever/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>How?&lt;br>
How is never as important as why.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So. How do you fill the giant Chadwick Boseman shaped hole in the MCU?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently&amp;hellip; with funeral services, Atlantis (but not), mer-Hermes (the first self described mutant in the MCU), and&amp;ndash;eventually&amp;ndash;someone new to take up the mantle.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; fine?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There were certainly some pretty spectacular action scenes. The under water scenes are pretty&amp;ndash;even if they only sort of make sense. The character and costume design continues to impress. And there are giant piles of funeral services and mourning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, the sudden introduction of an entire (large) underwater civilization feels&amp;hellip; weird. And as we&amp;rsquo;ve had before with the Marvel movies, some of the big battle set pieces don&amp;rsquo;t make that much sense. They&amp;rsquo;re going out on a boat to fight water people. All to&amp;hellip; limit how many fighters they have to film? And then all but like ten people die and we&amp;rsquo;re just okay with that?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s about the middle of the road so far as Marvel movies go for me. Pretty good, decent action, but there have been better entries. Pretty high up for 2023, but that&amp;rsquo;s probably more because I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen that many movies this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Panther</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a very solid movie. The casting is top notch, the style is wonderfully afrofuturistic, and the plot/motivation is interesting enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting with the plot/motivation, I think that the choice to have Wakanda separated from the rest of the world, all through centuries of slavery and inequality is certainly an interesting one. And I&amp;rsquo;m not at all alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nakia: I came to support you, and to honor your father. But I can&amp;rsquo;t stay. It&amp;rsquo;s just &amp;hellip; ! found my calling out there. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen too many in need just to turn a blind eye. I can&amp;rsquo;t be happy here knowing that there&amp;rsquo;s people out there who have nothing .&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>