<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2025 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2025-book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2025 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2025-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Southern Book Club's Guide to Slaying Vampires</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/11/the-southern-book-clubs-guide-to-slaying-vampires/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/11/the-southern-book-clubs-guide-to-slaying-vampires/</guid><description>&lt;p>If I had a nickel for every book I&amp;rsquo;d read recently where I went into it not really knowing much more than the cover and title and suddenly &lt;em>horror novel&lt;/em>, I&amp;rsquo;d have two nickels. Which isn&amp;rsquo;t a lot, but it&amp;rsquo;s weird that it happened twice.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Fried Green Tomatoes&lt;/em> and &lt;em>Steel Magnolias&lt;/em> meet &lt;em>Dracula&lt;/em> in this Southern-flavored supernatural thriller set in the &amp;rsquo;90s about a women&amp;rsquo;s book club that must protect its suburban community from a mysterious and handsome stranger who turns out to be a blood-sucking fiend.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Which probably should have clued me in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating story that starts out fairly tape. A southern woman settled into a life of housewife&amp;ndash;a life of long days, unthanked by her family.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Why do you pretend what we do is nothing?” she asked. “Every day, all the chaos and messiness of life happens and every day we clean it all up. Without us, they would just wallow in filth and disorder and nothing of any consequence would ever get done. Who taught you to sneer at that? I’ll tell you who. Someone who took their mother for granted.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And to brighten her days&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sometimes she craved a little danger. And that was why she had book club.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That is, until a strange man moves in next door. With a mysterious aversion to sunlight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Uh huh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At some point, the book really gets into that &amp;lsquo;runaway freight train&amp;rsquo; feeling. There are some serious body horror scenes in this book and it gets increasingly dark. I mean, it started with biting an ear off, but it goes quite a bit further than that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah, definitely a horror novel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I enjoyed it. The American South housewife theme isn&amp;rsquo;t something I read overly much and it it&amp;rsquo;s interesting counterpoint to the vampiric horror. They&amp;rsquo;re both great examples of &amp;lsquo;pretty and polite on the surface&amp;ndash;and absolutely &lt;em>not&lt;/em> underneath&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read, I&amp;rsquo;d say.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foxglove Summer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/09/foxglove-summer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/09/foxglove-summer/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We trooped off behind her into waist high bracken, down something that was not so much a path as a statistical variation in the density of the undergrowth.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Tne one where Peter goes to the country.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I wondered just when I’d become “the starling” and why everyone who was anyone in the supernatural community had such a problem with proper nouns.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And he&amp;rsquo;s so out of his element.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are two children missing and it just so happens that one of Nightingale&amp;rsquo;s former colleagues is in the area. So of course Peter has to go check in on him&amp;hellip; and gets entirely too involved in what does (of course) end up being something in the Folly&amp;rsquo;s department.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“What the hell is that?” he asked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“It’s a magic spell,” I said, and Beverley snorted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Show off,” she said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I said I was going to do magic,” I said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“But . . .” Dominic floundered around for a bit before pointing at me accusingly. “You said that there’s weird shit, but it normally turns out to have a rational explanation.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“It does,” said Beverley. “The explanation is a wizard did it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“That’s my line,” I said.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I do like the &amp;lsquo;half in the open&amp;rsquo; stance that this series takes to magic. Most people don&amp;rsquo;t know or care that magic is real, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that Peter can&amp;rsquo;t occasionally show off and actually use his tools for what they are&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There’s nothing quite like Latin for disguising the fact that you’re making it up as you go along.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Such as they are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, I really do like seeing Beverly again. She totally has a point that Peter basically ignored her for a book&amp;hellip; well, not this time around. And there are going to be reprecussions of that, just you wait.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But not for the moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What we do get is a mystery wrapped up in even more slowly extending worldbuilding. Now we know a bit more about the Rivers and more than the very little we knew about the Fae. And of all the things&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Mind you,” said Dominic, “when it comes to finding new ways to get themselves killed, sheep are bloody geniuses.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Didn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/charles-stross/">Charles Stross&lt;/a> go a similar route in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/05/equoid/">Equoid&lt;/a> (spoilers)? There&amp;rsquo;s about a year between the two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I enjoyed the story, it was a neat way to expand the setting. The ending was &amp;hellip; weak. It felt like things just suddenly wrapped up right when they were getting interesting, which is a bit annoying. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spider-Gwen, Vol. 6: The Life of Gwen Stacy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/09/spider-gwen-vol.-6-the-life-of-gwen-stacy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/09/spider-gwen-vol.-6-the-life-of-gwen-stacy/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/spider-gwen-2015-v6-textbundle-77a37a.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Gwens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/spider-gwen-2015-v6-textbundle-252f67.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking for help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/spider-gwen-2015-v6-textbundle-26f3d8.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And all for a secret (even to the Watchers…) cabal of Gwens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man comics sometimes. This is a hit more cosmic than I want right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the next issue is… Spider-Geddon. I’ll come back to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The last with her father though was cute. Just a lot for a single issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: the art dramatically shifted halfway through #33. Always jarring, that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spider-Gwen, Vol. 5: Gwenom</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/08/spider-gwen-vol.-5-gwenom/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/08/spider-gwen-vol.-5-gwenom/</guid><description>&lt;p>And do we have Gwenom. Great name. Interesting new power set. Less interaction with the symbiote than you get sometimes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/spider-gwen-2015-v5-textbundle-b0c691.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>… if that Venom Wolverine? That’s a terrifying idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, Gwenom. Great name, going to be a terrible idea for her. But she’s sort of stuck without many good ones…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/spider-gwen-2015-v5-textbundle-ba9ca6.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah. It’s dark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/spider-gwen-2015-v5-textbundle-310d3e.jpeg" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what else is new?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’re definitely heading to a conclusion here. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exposure</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/05/exposure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/05/exposure/</guid><description>&lt;p>Of course I had to read the sequel!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s another story of Rita Todacheene, but this time getting into the absolute &lt;em>trauma&lt;/em> of the first book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s hard enough (I imagine) being a crime scene photography. Constantly exposed to all that fairly grisly death. But add to that ghosts only you can see screaming at you about solving their murders, but when few enough of your coworkers and bosses believe you&amp;ndash;to the point of thinking you&amp;rsquo;ve lost your mind?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So Rita is done. Heading back home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Except this time&amp;hellip; the ghosts are coming with her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time, rather than backstory the second plot being Rita&amp;rsquo;s past, we have another point of view&amp;ndash;who we quicly learn is a serial killer caught up in his own paranoid worldview and bringing it violently to those around him. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating contrast to the first book and I really liked it. It reminded me a lot of various thrillers I read years and years ago, mostly by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dean-koontz/">Dean Koontz&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid sequel and I so wish the best and better for Rita. Oh I&amp;rsquo;m curious to see if there will be another! Where do you go from here?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shutter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/02/shutter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/02/shutter/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Grandma always said to me that you never do things for people to get something in return. That is the white man’s way of living. You do it because they need you. You do it because if you don’t, no one else will.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a book!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a word, it&amp;rsquo;s an urban fantasy about a Diné (Navajo) forensic photographer that can see ghosts. But it&amp;rsquo;s so much more than that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I love the main character: Rita Todacheene. Someone that can see ghosts and a cop (or cop adjacent) is something I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before, but it being a forensic photographer gave a particular poignancy to the whole thing. And the Diné angle was fascinating&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a bit of it in other urban fantasy books, but they have a particular way of looking at death which really plays interestingly against someone that can see ghosts!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a bit of setting, the attention to detail on the cameras and the craft of photography was a really interesting touch. Rita, growing up poor but from a whole line of photographers. You really get the feeling she knows and loves everything about it which really gives a certain feel to the story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Content warning though: We do get a number of descriptions of what exactly she&amp;rsquo;s photographing. And some of those are &lt;em>grisly&lt;/em>. At least we don&amp;rsquo;t get the pictures? (I don&amp;rsquo;t actually know for sure, I listened to this on audiobook&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Structurally, the book alternates between the present day&amp;ndash;Rita trying to solve crimes and stay mostly sane with ghosts hounding here&amp;ndash;and the past: Rita&amp;rsquo;s time growing up with her grandmother on a reservation, first coming to terms with life, death, and all it means to her specifically. It&amp;rsquo;s a really nice contrast, pulling the two stories together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s not the most complicated of mysteries. You mostly have enough clues to figure out where this is going, but oh the ride to get there. It&amp;rsquo;s still well worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I learned early that no amount of prayer or smoke or love was ever going to change the fact that these lights wanted to talk to me. Even at three years old, I knew it was something that deeply terrified my grandma and our medicine man. It was something that I was going to have to hide from them. As I got older, I taught myself how to look beyond the ghosts and mute their voices.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Furysong</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/31/furysong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/31/furysong/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When a government ceases to protect its people, it becomes necessary to overthrow it.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s how you end a trilogy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Revolution on revolution, coup on coup. Love and hate, betrayal and double/triple/who even knows crossing. And death. Oh the deaths.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, we get a conclusion (for now) of the revolution we were first introduced to in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/30/fireborne/">Fireborne&lt;/a>. And the government in exile of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/flamefall/">Flamefall&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characters are still a large driving factor here, especially (but not only!) Annie and Lee. We finally get an answer to the whole &amp;lsquo;will they / won&amp;rsquo;t they&amp;rsquo; which I expect we all saw coming, but it&amp;rsquo;s all in &lt;em>how&lt;/em> it happened&amp;hellip; and what came next. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of sweet here&amp;ndash;and more than a helpful of bittersweet as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that Griff is a fascinating point here. He got everything he wanted in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/flamefall/">Flamefall&lt;/a> and a few things that he couldn&amp;rsquo;t bear. So for half the book, he&amp;rsquo;s the hero&amp;ndash;and drowning himself in his sorrows. But add in Delo as an actual point of view this time around? A plot well worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the antagonists side, we have Ixion. Oh we love to hate them. Being the last book, they have to fall, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a long painful trip to get there. The (re)introduction of the Bassileans, their princess, and their gargantuan dragon. I think that&amp;rsquo;s a sort of difference in dragon breeds and hints at a larger world that I could do with more of. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to realize that for all the chaos we&amp;rsquo;ve been through with these books, they&amp;rsquo;re only a tiny part of the larger world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then there&amp;rsquo;s Power. He is very much the most complicated character in these books, thoroughly in the morally gray category. Oh Power.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I loved these books. I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to see what else &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/rosaria-munda/">Rosaria Munda&lt;/a> has done! Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I just wanted it to be in writing, somewhere. I wanted it to be in writing that it was you. For me. It&amp;rsquo;s always been you.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Alcatraz Versus the Knights of Crystallia</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/alcatraz-versus-the-knights-of-crystallia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/alcatraz-versus-the-knights-of-crystallia/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Books are not fish sticks.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Now, we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em>really&lt;/em> in the Free Kingdoms. We spent a book learning that there&amp;rsquo;s a hidden world and another mostly underground (in the Library of Alexandria!), so it&amp;rsquo;s nice to get something really &amp;lsquo;hidden world&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man, the Free Kingdoms are strange. But that&amp;rsquo;s probably just the Librarian brainwashing coming through. Castles. Glass pigs. More castles. Kings. Councils. And even more Smedrys!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Farting barf-faced poop!” a voice exclaimed from inside the pig’s butt.&lt;br>
(Sigh. Sorry. At least that’s another great paragraph to try working into a random conversation.)&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Exactly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the hilarious (from our point of view) issues that comes up this book is Alcatraz coming to his &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; moment. A world where he knows next to nothing, but everyone knows who he is. Apparently via the in-universe Alcatraz books, which is an extra level of weirdly meta.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Fame is like a cheeseburger. It might not be the best or most healthy thing to have, but it will still fill you up. You don’t really care how healthy something is when you’ve been without for so long. Like a cheeseburger, fame fills a need, and it tastes so good going down. It isn’t until years later that you realize what it has done to your heart.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There are just so many book/other geeky media references. I love them.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For example, take this story: “Once there was a furry-footed British guy who had to go throw his uncle’s ring into a hole in the ground.” Sounds dumb, doesn’t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Nothing is sacred!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“That’s bad,” Folsom said.&lt;br>
“She Who Cannot Be Named?” I asked. “Why can’t we say her name? Because it might draw the attention of evil powers? Because we’re afraid of her? Because her name has become a curse upon the world?”&lt;br>
“Don’t be silly,” Himalaya said. “We don’t say her name because nobody can pronounce it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Exactly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s more Alcatraz. You have a fun plot, wacky characters, and &lt;em>just&lt;/em> on the edge of too much meta commentary on writing/being a work of &amp;lsquo;fiction&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m still quite enjoying it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this is only halfway.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If a train left Nalhalla traveling at 3.14 miles an hour and a train left Bermuda at 45 MHz, what time does the soup have pancakes?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Where in the world (literally) can they go from here?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Broken Homes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/broken-homes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/broken-homes/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It’s a police mantra that all members of the public are guilty of something, but some members of the public are more guilty than others.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The more things change&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, we have both Peter and Leslie as apprentices at the Folly, learning how to do magic things&amp;ndash;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I’d love to stick some high vestigia material into a mass spectrometer, but first I’d have to get myself a mass spectrometer and then I’d have to learn enough physics to interpret the bloody results.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash;and use those abilities to investigate those &lt;em>stranger&lt;/em> cases in London.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The key is unlikely juxtapositions. Lots of people read books about the occult, but if you find them alongside books by or about Isaac Newton, especially the long boring ones, then hackles are raised, flags hoisted and, more importantly, notes made in my notebook.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;the more they remain the same&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then they find a body sans face.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Attend a peace summit between Rivers/Fae. (I actually really do enjoy how fuzzy and ill defined Fae apparently are in this world. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting and feels somehow more &amp;lsquo;Fae&amp;rsquo; than you often see.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Move into an estate (British for project housing).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Peter,” she said. “When you threaten people it’s usually more effective if they don’t have to spend five minutes working out what you just said first.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a strange book.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;until quite suddenly things &lt;em>aren&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em> the same anymore.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a brutal ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave it at that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And immediately go start the next book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flamefall</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/flamefall/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/flamefall/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Revenge doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to begin with a knife. It can begin with a well-delivered speech.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The cracks were already showing in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/30/fireborne/">Fireborne&lt;/a>. There may have been a Revolution, dealing away with the Dragonlords of old&amp;hellip; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean that whatever comes next is going to be any better. So much so that you start to see those with the feeling that &amp;lsquo;maybe things weren&amp;rsquo;t so bad under the Dragonlords after all&amp;rsquo;. And it just so happens that there&amp;rsquo;s more than one cousin in exile&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really enjoy seeing Annie come into her own in this book, taking her place in charge of the dragon riders after Lee stepped down. And then dealing with all that comes from having to make all those hard decisions at the top. Dealing with Lee and the government and the other riders and her own past. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Lee, actually coming out into the open&amp;ndash;while dealing with the trauma at the end of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/30/fireborne/">Fireborne&lt;/a>. Complicated that. I kept expecting him to snap&amp;ndash;and hoping that he won&amp;rsquo;t, that he &lt;em>will actually be better&lt;/em>. I&amp;rsquo;m rooting for you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then we have newcomer Griff. Another peasant dragon rider from a &lt;em>very&lt;/em> different set of circumstances. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to introduce a new main character in the second book, but I really do think it was done well. Man, the New Pythians are &lt;em>twisted&lt;/em>, almost comically evil. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make them any less dangerous to those in teh story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy there&amp;rsquo;s just so much in this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tonight I&amp;rsquo;m full of confidence, like a dragon riding a gale. I am done letting these tendrils of shame tie me to the ground. No shadow is so great that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t shrink when viewed from the air.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see how it ends from here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Toasting Marshmallows: Camping Poems</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/10/toasting-marshmallows-camping-poems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/10/toasting-marshmallows-camping-poems/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of those &amp;lsquo;read to the children over a few evenings, so I should count it&amp;rsquo; sort of books.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Warm front. Cold back.&lt;br>
    I turn around.&lt;br>
Warm back. Cold front.&lt;br>
    I turn around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I lean against Mom,&lt;br>
my head on her shoulder.&lt;br>
    Warm all over.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And it&amp;rsquo;s actually a really fun book. The feeling of camping&amp;hellip; in poetry form!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Frankenstein: The 1818 Text</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/06/frankenstein-the-1818-text/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/06/frankenstein-the-1818-text/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m really going for that &amp;rsquo;earliest published book&amp;rsquo; for this coming Year in Reviews aren&amp;rsquo;t I?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It is true, we shall be monsters, cut off from all the world; but on that account we shall be more attached to one another.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those stories you expect to know what happens even before you read it. Frankenstein&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> creates LIFE in a form stitched together from dead bodies. But it&amp;rsquo;s super ugly, so he drives his creation off. Said creation isn&amp;rsquo;t a huge fan of this and goes on a murderous rampage. The end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, that&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em>entirely&lt;/em> right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an oddly formatted story to a much more modern reader. It&amp;rsquo;s epistolary (told in letters and journals), which reminds me a lot of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/29/dracula/">Dracula&lt;/a> and nested. We have letters from a sea captain, the account of Victor Frankenstein, and then finally &lt;span class="spoiler">the monster himself&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a neat style, but I think a bit more could have been done with it. And it&amp;rsquo;s never really a great sign when one of the main viewpoints (Frankenstein himself) is just hard to read. He&amp;rsquo;s not likeable and depressed a lot of the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Even broken in spirit as he is, no one can feel more deeply than he does the beauties of nature. The starry sky, the sea, and every sight afforded by these wonderful regions, seems still to have the power of elevating his soul from earth. Such a man has a double existence: he may suffer misery, and be overwhelmed by disappointments; yet, when he has retired into himself, he will be like a celestial spirit that has a halo around him, within whose circle no grief or folly ventures.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Which again, I get it. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make for a thrilling read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s billed as one of the earlier examples of science fiction, but it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;em>really&lt;/em> science fiction. It does deal with the idea of bringing life&amp;ndash;but never really gets into it. It&amp;rsquo;s setting as much as anything, something to set the story in motion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Alternatively, it&amp;rsquo;s also called early modern Horror, but &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s not really horror in either the jump scare or thriller or cosmic senses of the word. There&amp;rsquo;s some sense of inevitability&amp;ndash;the creation is coming!&amp;ndash;but it never really amounts to much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth having read mostly in a completionist sense. And really, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I listened to this one on audiobook&amp;ndash;they have a way of just keeping you going when you might otherwise get stuck and put the book down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>