<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Sopranos on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-sopranos/</link><description>Recent content in The Sopranos on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-sopranos/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos-season-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos-season-6/</guid><description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a lot. In order to finish all of the stories they wanted to tell&amp;ndash;but also not to have to negotiate another season&amp;rsquo;s worth of contracts with the actors, season 6 is really two seasons in one. The first is slightly shorter than the other seasons at 12 (instead of 13), while the second half is only 9. So one big season? Two small? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that much when you&amp;rsquo;re streaming them back to back.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/18/the-sopranos-season-5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/18/the-sopranos-season-5/</guid><description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a season. It&amp;rsquo;s great to see how Christopher has been growing over the series&amp;ndash;man that penultimate episode though. The introduction and arc of Tony B (Buscemi is wonderful) is quite a thing. It just keeps picking up. Crazy to think there&amp;rsquo;s only one more season, even if almost double length.
Mini-reviews per episode:
Two Tonys: The old guard’s the new guard, Christopher and Paulie are (still) butting heads and perhaps they don’t have to whack Carmine after all.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-sopranos-season-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-sopranos-season-4/</guid><description>Man that was another season. Ralphie is a great character to love to hate, Christopher is really having some drug issues, and things really come to a head between Tony and Carmela. A great season and I look forward to the next.
Mini-reviews per episode:
All Debts, Public and Private: Ralphie and Janice now… come on . No-Show: Meadow is moody, Christopher is moving up—that’s going to be trouble.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/28/the-sopranos-season-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/28/the-sopranos-season-3/</guid><description>That&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an odd season. The original plotline had to be thrown out on account of the actress that played Tony's mom dying , so the whole &amp;lsquo;do they have a case against Tony&amp;rsquo; thing falls through. As a result, it&amp;rsquo;s not the most cohesive of seasons, but there are a few gems in here still.
Episode mini reviews:
Mr. Ruggerino’s Neighborhood: All sorts of crazy editing.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/27/the-sopranos-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/27/the-sopranos-season-2/</guid><description>Man this show just keeps going.
They actually lowered the amount of nudity a bit from Season 1 (as HBO tends to do), but the violence is still going strong… It’s fascinating (and solid writing) to see the fall out from the big events of season 1, along with entirely new plotlines with Janice (Tony’s brother), Richard Aprile (who’s got crazy eyes), Christopher really getting into (and out of) writing, and drama with the entire Soprano family/children.</description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/04/the-sopranos-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/04/the-sopranos-season-1/</guid><description>After the crazy violence and nudity of Watchmen, you&amp;rsquo;d think perhaps we&amp;rsquo;d go for something a little more &amp;hellip; safe for next time around.
Nah.
The Sopranos.
It&amp;rsquo;s one of the best rated TV shows of all time (on IMDb, only Breaking Bad (which I watched just before I started reviewing TV series), Avatar: The Last Airbender (it&amp;rsquo;s great), and Game of Thrones (pre Season 8) are rated higher among fiction).</description></item></channel></rss>