<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Robopocalypse on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/robopocalypse/</link><description>Recent content in Robopocalypse on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/robopocalypse/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Robogenesis</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/robogenesis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/robogenesis/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And now the story begins for the last time.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So. That hint that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t all over? That was just the beginning.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We are all expressions of our own minds, projected onto the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The idea that the AI that lead to the end of the world wasn&amp;rsquo;t a unique event&amp;ndash;just one that happened to go particularly sideways is a fascinating one. The story of people trying to rebuild in the ruins&amp;ndash;only for another war to sweep over what&amp;rsquo;s left is terrifying. And the &amp;lsquo;what comes next&amp;rsquo; of animal like machines, augmented humans, and self-aware / free robots is a fascinating basis for a story.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What is a mind, but a pattern? My mind or yours. Man or machine. Simply an arrangement of atoms. Each of us, a unique expression of the mind of the universe.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Honestly, I still think that &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/27/robopocalypse/">Robopocalypse&lt;/a> could stand as it&amp;rsquo;s own&amp;ndash;and was the stronger book. But if it had to have a sequel, this was an interesting one. Now that we have it (and that I&amp;rsquo;ve read it!) I feel like we&amp;rsquo;re going to need at least one more. There are just so many ideas here, we need to go another step further!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>But instead of the end, I’m pretty sure I found myself at the start of something.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Robopocalypse</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/27/robopocalypse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/27/robopocalypse/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I can only give you words. Nothing fancy. But this will have to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you&amp;rsquo;re reading it a year from now or a hundred years from now. By the end of the chronicle you will know that humanity carried the flame of knowledge into the terrible blackness of the unknown, to the very brink of annihilation. And we carried it back.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In the near future, thinking machines are even slightly more everywhere than they are now. Take it one step further along the road to true general AI&amp;hellip; and suddenly you go outright Skynet on the world. Robot Apocalypse. Get it?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The true knowledge is not &lt;em>in&lt;/em> the things, but in finding the connections &lt;em>between&lt;/em> the things.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This &amp;hellip; was perhaps not the best time to read this book, with the ever increasing advances in LLMs and chatbots leading to upheaval in all manner of fields of work, along with the current instability (to put it mildly) in the United States. I think I need more stability in books right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To survive, humans will work together. Accept each other. For a moment, we are all equal. Backs against the wall, human beings are at their finest.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That being said, it was a fascinatingly structured book. From the very first chapter, we know humanity (or what&amp;rsquo;s left of it) eventually wins the war. Each chapter, we have comments like &amp;rsquo;this is the last record of X&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Y had a part to play yet&amp;rsquo; And as we go, the various plots cross and come together, sketching out the end of the world and what comes after.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I will murder you by the billions to give you immortality. I will set fire to your civilization to light your way forward. But know this: My species is not defined by your dying, but by your living.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating book and I think well worth the read&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m curious where exactly the sequel can possibly go next without more of the same.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>