<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Sopranos on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos/</link><description>Recent content in The Sopranos on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos-season-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/19/the-sopranos-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a lot. In order to finish all of the stories they wanted to tell&amp;ndash;but also not to have to negotiate another season&amp;rsquo;s worth of contracts with the actors, season 6 is really two seasons in one. The first is slightly shorter than the other seasons at 12 (instead of 13), while the second half is only 9. So one big season? Two small? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that much when you&amp;rsquo;re streaming them back to back.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/18/the-sopranos-season-5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/18/the-sopranos-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a season. It&amp;rsquo;s great to see how Christopher has been growing over the series&amp;ndash;man that penultimate episode though. The introduction and arc of Tony B (Buscemi is wonderful) is quite a thing. It just keeps picking up. Crazy to think there&amp;rsquo;s only one more season, even if almost double length.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mini-reviews per episode:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Two Tonys&lt;/em>: The old guard’s the new guard, Christopher and Paulie are (still) butting heads and perhaps they don’t have to whack Carmine after all. Unexpected turn with Dr. Melfi too.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Rat Pack&lt;/em>: Hustling air bags… yup. they’re expensive. Wait, this one isn’t called two Tonys? He’s very Buscemi. He just makes everything slightly more… odd. Also wait what… Janice &lt;em>married&lt;/em> Bobby? When? Why?!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Where’s Johnny?&lt;/em>: Old faces make for rather a mess in the leadership. Oh and Uncle Junior is having some issues. Oy an episode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>All Happy Families…&lt;/em> Ooh boy the Sopranos are a mess. And Feech is a mess. AJ is a mess.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Irregular Around the Margins&lt;/em>: Kind of surreal listening to them talk about war in the Middle East… 20 years later. And then… Ade and Tony. I just. Oy. I guess I didn’t expect sobriety to Kay forever, but… Oy. Buscemi is wonderful.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Sentimental Education&lt;/em>: A very strange episode. I… kept expecting things to go sidewise. I guess in the end…&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>In Camelot&lt;/em>: Things worse than drugs, Tony’s father’s old flame (of course not everything was rosy) and Uncle Junior’s a funeral junky. Quite an episode.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Marco Polo&lt;/em>: Mostly a surprise party foot Carmela’s father, but also a bit of redemption perhaps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Unidentified Black Males&lt;/em>: Finn’s in over his head… And Carmela learns the hard way about breaking up with a mob boss. Oy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Cold Cuts&lt;/em>: Oh Janice. Could have done without … any of her plotlines really. I guess she did try. And Tony’s reaction is worth it. But… why don’t they just dump the bodies i. thw water to begin with.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>The Test Dream&lt;/em>: Well… that went quickly weird.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Long Term Parking&lt;/em>: And that was intense. That’s what a penultimate episode should be. Oy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>All Due Respect&lt;/em>: Well. That’s an ending. It’s all about family, but sometimes family has conflicts. No idea where they are going with AJ.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-sopranos-season-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-sopranos-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man that was another season. Ralphie is a great character to love to hate, Christopher is really having some drug issues, and things really come to a head between Tony and Carmela. A great season and I look forward to the next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mini-reviews per episode:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>All Debts, Public and Private: &lt;span class="spoiler">Ralphie and Janice now… come on &lt;/span>
.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No-Show: Meadow is moody, Christopher is moving up—that’s going to be trouble.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Christopher: Columbus versus Native Americans. That’s a complicated issue… not about to be resolved in an episode. Add on another random death &lt;span class="spoiler">poor Bacala :/&lt;/span>
. And Ralphie continues to be an ass. But that’s not new. Weird one.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Weight: The power of a mobster when a slight is felt. Eventually that will (I hope) catch up with Ralphie.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pie-o-My: Adriana, trying to do the right thing in a tricky situation. Carmela, trying to do the right thing in a tricky situation. And… horses. Apparently. Odd sometimes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Everybody Hurts: Oh Christopher. Oh Artie. Oh AJ. Man everything is about to blow one way or another.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Watching Too Much Television: Well Christopher is an ass… The politics of real estate is fascinating. Also Furio feels the same… it doesn’t?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mergers and Acquisitions: Ah. Cancer. And Tony and Ralphie are so going to have to end things one way or another… And Furio. So many things… Looking forward to some endings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whoever Did This: Finally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Strong, Silent Type: Well, that’s a thing. Drugs are one hell of a drug.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Calling All Cars: What is Janice doing… What is AJ doing… man this is screwy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Eloise: Speaking of what are they doing… Furio and Carmela. Oy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whitecaps: And that’s the straw that broke the camels back. On to next season… At least the HUD/Carmine, Uncle Junior, and Christopher on drugs plots are resolved. More or less.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/28/the-sopranos-season-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/28/the-sopranos-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an odd season. The original plotline had to be thrown out on account of &lt;span class="spoiler">the actress that played Tony's mom dying&lt;/span>
, so the whole &amp;lsquo;do they have a case against Tony&amp;rsquo; thing falls through. As a result, it&amp;rsquo;s not the most cohesive of seasons, but there are a few gems in here still.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Episode mini reviews:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mr. Ruggerino’s Neighborhood: All sorts of crazy editing. Bizarre start to the new season. Amusing watching the FBI try to bug Tony and Tony being … surprisingly competent.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proshai Livushka: &lt;span class="spoiler">Tony’s mom dies. What are you going to do? Especially when it’s the actress that died.&lt;/span>
. It would have been fascinating to see the original plot, but they certainly made it work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fortunate Son: All about sons. Christopher, AJ, Jackie Jr. So many things ramping up. Should be an interesting season. Also Janice is set up to be hated. Weird set up.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Employee of the Month: Dr. Melfi and her relationship with Tony is one of the best parts of this show. It’s a hard episode to watch, but oy. Quite the episode. Also I didn’t notice before but that’s Cypher from the Matrix.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Another Toothpick: Dr. Melfi, Tony, … and Carmela? Oy. Also awkward Artie and family troubles. Not quite as intense as the last episode, but that’s a good thing.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>University: Oh Meadow. It’s not a mob plotline, but it’s a fascinating counterpoint. And Ralphie, like Aprile but crazier… And the whole ‘stripper with a heart of gold’ only to be shut down hard. Oh that’s an episode. The number of cuts is pretty bizarre.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Second Opinion: “F*** the orange juice”. Oh the Sopranos have a weird relationship. As do Christopher and Ade. Also also cancer. And bullying Doctors.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>He Is Risen: Man Ralphie is hateable. The look into mafia rules and politics is pretty fascinating though.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Telltale Moozadell: Christopher and Adriana moving up in the world. Jackie Jr is … getting in over his head. Also random AJ plotline at school. Also also I fully expect Gloria to be trouble.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To Save Us All from Satan’s Power: Flashbacks to Pussy, apparently the mob’s Santa? Weird.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pine Barrens: Russians and a frozen night in the woods. How bad could it be?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Amour Fou: Crazy love. Certainly crazy something. Things are so going to explode next episode. Also interesting the conversation about the Clintons.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Army of One: And so ends one problematic plotlines in true Sopranos fashion. Others only amping up. Seems a bit anticlimactic for a season finale. OTOH, Tobin Bell is a treasure (seen him otherwise in Stargate)—maybe AJ’s plot will go somewhere.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The Long Goodbye: Body snatchers again! Of course things go sideways. It&amp;rsquo;s quite an experience.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coup D&amp;rsquo;etat: I never much cared for the human factions in SG-1, but I actually like the Genii as an adversary. I think it&amp;rsquo;s the fact that they&amp;rsquo;re a more alien sort of human.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;span class="spoiler"> No, okay I’m annoyed. We didn’t get anything. Ralphie is still an ass, no one is questioning Jackie’s death, AJ is in limbo, and the while thing ended with… a bizarrely long singing section? &lt;/span></description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/27/the-sopranos-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/27/the-sopranos-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man this show just keeps going.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They actually lowered the amount of nudity a bit from Season 1 (as HBO tends to do), but the violence is still going strong… It’s fascinating (and solid writing) to see the fall out from the big events of season 1, along with entirely new plotlines with Janice (Tony’s brother), Richard Aprile (who’s got crazy eyes), Christopher really getting into (and out of) writing, and drama with the entire Soprano family/children. It’s quite a ride and just keeps getting better.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Sopranos: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/04/the-sopranos-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/04/the-sopranos-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the crazy violence and nudity of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/11/watchmen/">Watchmen&lt;/a>, you&amp;rsquo;d think perhaps we&amp;rsquo;d go for something a little more &amp;hellip; safe for next time around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Sopranos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s one of the best rated TV shows of all time (on IMDb, only Breaking Bad (which I watched just before I started reviewing TV series), Avatar: The Last Airbender (it&amp;rsquo;s great), and Game of Thrones (pre Season 8) are rated higher among fiction). It&amp;rsquo;s a mob story set in late 90s New Jersey produced for HBO and has all the sex, violence, and language you&amp;rsquo;d expect from that combination. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; quite a show. Dealing with family, the moral complexity (at best) of mob life, and mental health issues&amp;hellip; and that&amp;rsquo;s just season 1. Oh it&amp;rsquo;s a show.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>