<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2015 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2015-book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2015 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2015-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2015 Reading List Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/2015-reading-list-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/2015-reading-list-retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;p>I 2015, I set myself an &lt;del>ambitious&lt;/del> &lt;del>slightly&lt;/del> insane reading goal: 100 books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My final count: exactly 100 books (from ~30 different series), totaling 38,048 pages. There were a few short stories in there (Pimpf by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/charles-stross/">Charles Stross&lt;/a> was the shortest at 25 pages) to offset a couple epic fantasies (1,048 pages in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson’s&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/15/words-of-radiance/">Words of Radiance&lt;/a>). Overall, I averaged 388 pages/book, which sounds about right to me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Drowned Wednesday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/drowned-wednesday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/drowned-wednesday/</guid><description>&lt;p>The world of the Keys to the Kingdom continues to get more interesting and weirder all at once. This time around, we have a sort of Multiversal Ocean and the Morrow Day that governs it. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting world all itself, with ships that were once other things, uplifted rats, and a very Nix&amp;rsquo;ian version of the Jonah and Whale story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s neat to finally see one of the Morrow Days that actually wants to help. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing we won&amp;rsquo;t see much of that with the other half.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Grim Tuesday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/grim-tuesday/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/31/grim-tuesday/</guid><description>&lt;p>Of course they&amp;rsquo;re all going to take place over a week (Earth time)&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s really not much different between Mister Monday and Grim Tuesday. Arthur is starting to accept his fate while at the same time learning more about the rules of the House. It interesting to see him change even in just the first two books thus far.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mister Monday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/30/mister-monday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/30/mister-monday/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that Arthur died. He had a massive asthma attack, and, as his oxygen starved brain struggled its last, he hallucinated all of the rest. How else do you describe just how &amp;hellip; odd this book is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, I liked it. It&amp;rsquo;s weird. Garth Nix really does his Proper Nouns. Everything felt like it Meant Something, although we never quite got a perfect idea what Anything was. Most of them were close enough though; so it goes. It&amp;rsquo;s quick and the action picks you up and pulls you right through the story. When it&amp;rsquo;s over, there&amp;rsquo;s something of a feel of getting off a roller coaster, but in a good way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadspawn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/29/deadspawn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/29/deadspawn/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think I&amp;rsquo;m done with the Necroscope series, at least for the time being. And hey, technically this &lt;em>is&lt;/em> the end of the first Necroscope series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the negative side:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadspeak</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/26/deadspeak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/26/deadspeak/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh hey, turns out there is another Ferenczy. Or rather, that&amp;rsquo;s what a lot of this book felt like. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to fill out a few more of the possibilities of what might happen if a vampire spawns a mostly human child who then desperately tries to learn to be a Vampire. But at the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s starting to feel like the same story again, just with different players.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another twist this time, which I at first appreciated was that Harry has lost his powers (stolen from him by Harry Jr). So for a large chunk of the story, he cannot speak to the dead except in dreams&amp;ndash;which he doesn&amp;rsquo;t remember upon waking&amp;ndash;and cannot access the Moebius Continuum at all. Given how often I&amp;rsquo;ve complained about how overpowerful the latter made him, I thought it would be good for him to lose the power, &lt;span class="spoiler">but of course I guessed he would at some point get it back. And just in time for the final battle too, making it feel like an echo of the final battle from Necroscope I&lt;/span>
 . So it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Source</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/23/the-source/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/23/the-source/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Source follows a nuclear accident that manages to blow a hole in between our reality and the homeworld (more accurately home universe, since Harry cannot Moebius his way there) of the Vampires.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting watching this series progress from espionage mixed with urban fantasy and horror in the first book to a more historical urban fantasy (if that makes sense) to this one which veers a bit more into almost science fiction. We have a parallel universe, a tidally locked planet, and some really weird vampire biology. The world building around vampires continues to be the strongest part of this series (which is amusing, given that I find the Moebius Continuum and the various ESP powers to be among the weakest).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vamphyri!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/19/vamphyri/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/19/vamphyri/</guid><description>&lt;p>So that&amp;rsquo;s how the series will continue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, we get a bit more of Harry who is now sharing bodies with his infant son (it&amp;rsquo;s about that weird) and communicating with the now dead main characters from the first book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Necroscope</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/16/necroscope/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/16/necroscope/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read anything in quite this genre before. It&amp;rsquo;s basically urban fantasy, except set during the Cold War (which makes some sense, given this book was released in 1986) and with an extra helping of espionage (ESPionage) thrown in. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting change and the two styles complement one another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ve read many books where the first two chapters go quite so strongly back and forth between this is cool and that&amp;rsquo;s gross. It evened out a bit over the course of the book, but there was still a good amount of each.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zoo City</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/11/zoo-city/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/11/zoo-city/</guid><description>&lt;p>Basically, if you kill someone (is that the only way?) you end up with a literal animal manifestation of your guilt. On the plus side, they come with free magical abilities (like the main character&amp;rsquo;s ability to find lost things). On the down side, people know how you got your animal (your zoo) and discrimination is rampant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a really interesting concept; something that I haven&amp;rsquo;t quite seen anywhere else (The Golden Compass is vaguely similar, at least in the animal companions). And the world is just gritty and dark enough that it felt like a dark echo of what our world could be / have been. Unfortunately, a lot of details are left unclear. What exactly is the Undertow? How do people get which animals? What did the main character actually do to get her Sloth? How different are the animals from their wild brethren?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Golem and the Jinni</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/09/the-golem-and-the-jinni/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/09/the-golem-and-the-jinni/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Golem and the Jinni follows two parallel stories: that of a Golem and a Jinni (of course), each finding their way from fall flung shores to circa 1900 New York City.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a relatively complex narrative structure, jumping from the Golem to the Jinni and even to a few minor characters within the space of a chapter. Even in one viewpoint, there are multiple timelines, showing how events a thousand years apart all fit together. Yet despite all of this, I never got lost, never couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out where I was in the story. It took a while for the story lines to start coming together (for a while, it felt like reading two books), but once they do things just keep pushing towards the conclusion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Autumn Republic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/05/the-autumn-republic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/05/the-autumn-republic/</guid><description>&lt;p>A solid conclusion. Basically, The Autumn Republic builds on the world of the first two books, without really needing to introduce much in the way of new characters (with a few relatively minor exceptions) or new world building, instead taking everything to a final conclusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far as the characters go, I really found myself rooting for the good guys and hoping they would save the day, even when they did some not entirely unobjectionable things. In particular, I&amp;rsquo;m glad that Adamat&amp;rsquo;s story at least didn&amp;rsquo;t get any worse and that he managed to survive (spoilers) all the crap that the Marked and Privileged put him through.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Crimson Campaign</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/02/the-crimson-campaign/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/02/the-crimson-campaign/</guid><description>&lt;p>I think the main reason that I had some problems following all of the different storylines in the first Powder Mage book was that I was reading one chapter per day and discussion as I went. Reading straight through the second book helped keep everything together. It also helps that there are few to no new major characters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, this was very much the second book in a trilogy. It picks up where the first left off and sets up the third. It probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stand particularly well alone, but then again it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much action all of the way through, tying up various plot lines just to ramp things up even more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vortex</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/28/vortex/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/28/vortex/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the strong opening in Spin and the someone meh followup with Axis, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting particularly much from Vortex. Consider me pleasantly surprised.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Getting back to the huge events and big timespans of Spin, Vortex takes place ten thousand years after Axis, after the Temporal Arch discovered towards the end of that book ends its next cycle. Two of Axis&amp;rsquo; main characters (Turn and Isaac) are dumped out / recreated and picked up by a island sized ship that has been floating through arch after arch through the Eight Worlds (apparently the arches connecting Earth to Equatoria connect through several other worlds and finally end at Mars, which is a neat concept).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Axis</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/24/axis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/24/axis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Unfortunately, many of the other reviewers here are on point. In Spin, we followed the lives of a small groups of characters while &lt;em>big ideas&lt;/em> happened around them, spanning either decades or billions of years, depending on your perspective. In Axis, the ideas are not nearly as big, the timespan isn&amp;rsquo;t quite so vast, and the cast of characters has changed to ones I don&amp;rsquo;t find myself caring about as much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a bit of an interesting follow up here to the last chapter of Spin: what&amp;rsquo;s on the other side of the arch and just what &lt;em>are&lt;/em> the Hypotheticals. I think the first could make an interesting story all of itself, just following a series of explorers further and further through the worlds, but that&amp;rsquo;s not what Axis is. And so far as the second&amp;ndash;we don&amp;rsquo;t really learn anything new. There are hints of something bigger (which is saying something, given something on a scale with the entire galaxy) and a few smaller neat ideas, but nothing quite comes together.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spin</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/14/spin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/14/spin/</guid><description>&lt;p>(minor spoilers; although nothing more than used to be on the Goodreads summary)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really enjoy science fiction where they take a really big / weird idea and just run with it. Spin is exactly that sort of book. In a nutshell, one night all of the stars seem to go out. Over the book, the protagonists discover that not the stars didn&amp;rsquo;t actually go out, but rather the Earth was enveloped in a shell that is causing time on Earth to run roughly 100 million times slower, while at the same time preventing any ill effects therefrom.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Girl Who Kicked the Hornet's Nest</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/10/the-girl-who-kicked-the-hornets-nest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/10/the-girl-who-kicked-the-hornets-nest/</guid><description>&lt;p>Given that Hornet&amp;rsquo;s Nest kicks off immediately following the events of Played with Fire, I was hoping that it could keep up the momentum of the previous book and avoid the slow first half / crazy second half that the previous two books had suffered from. Unfortunately, no such luck. If anything, it takes even longer to get moving and the conclusion isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as action packed as the previous novels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, I do feel like this was a solid conclusion to the series. It wrapped up a lot of loose ends that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even realized I was missing and finished character arcs, particularly for Lisbeth. She&amp;rsquo;s still odd, but I&amp;rsquo;m really starting to understand where she comes from. And in the end, she wins. I would have been rather grumpy with the author (even if he is dead) had she not come out all right in the end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Girl Who Played with Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/31/the-girl-who-played-with-fire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/31/the-girl-who-played-with-fire/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo took a while to get into. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until Lisbeth and Blomkvist were finally in the same place perhaps halfway through the book that things really started moving.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Girl Who Played with Fire is much the same.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Promise of Blood</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/30/promise-of-blood/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/30/promise-of-blood/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure what to think about this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, there are several varied magic systems in this book. You have the Privileged, the Marked, and the Knacked.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-girl-with-the-dragon-tattoo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-girl-with-the-dragon-tattoo/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not that often any more that I finish a book in a day. That should tell you something about what I thought about the Girl with the Dragon Tattoo. Especially when it isn&amp;rsquo;t fantasy. It isn&amp;rsquo;t science fiction. It isn&amp;rsquo;t horror (at least not the supernatural sort). Really, it&amp;rsquo;s more of a investigation / thriller. Not a genre that I read that often.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, for the first half of the book, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I was even going to finish it, let alone read the sequels. There were a few different story lines going on that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really see how they fit together. Nothing overly much seemed to be happening. Then, around halfway through (when the main characters finally started to interact more), things really started moving. I read the rest of the book in one sitting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Serpent's Shadow</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-serpents-shadow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-serpents-shadow/</guid><description>&lt;p>A solid ending to the series. Once again the world will end in &lt;em>n&lt;/em> days and it&amp;rsquo;s up to Sadie and Carter to save that day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really, it feels like the second half of The Throne of Fire. We have the same support characters, the same big bad, the same magic, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like that terribly much time has passed. Honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing; it&amp;rsquo;s just a little bit weird.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Throne of Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/19/the-throne-of-fire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/19/the-throne-of-fire/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t really have particularly much to add for Throne of Fire that I didn&amp;rsquo;t already say for The Red Pyramid.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, more of the same. The Kanes have five days to save the world (it&amp;rsquo;s impressive how even something like that can start to get old after a dozen novels&amp;hellip;). They proceed to do so.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Red Pyramid</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/11/the-red-pyramid/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/11/the-red-pyramid/</guid><description>&lt;p>Red Pyramid would be a lot strong if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read Percy Jackson.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. Red Pyramid is still a fine book, although it feels like it&amp;rsquo;s written for an even younger audience than Percy Jackson.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Throne of the Crescent Moon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/04/throne-of-the-crescent-moon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/04/throne-of-the-crescent-moon/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really liked this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throne of the Crescent Moon follows a band of somewhat unlikely heroes as they&amp;rsquo;re off to save the day. You have an old ghul hunter (one of the last of his kind), a whirling dervish (I&amp;rsquo;d never before looked up what that actually meant), an alchemist and her mage of a husband, and a shape shifter who can take the form of a golden lion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blackout</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/blackout/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/30/blackout/</guid><description>&lt;p>A solid ending to a solid series. I think that I liked it more than Deadline, but less than Feed, owing entirely to one thing: George.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yup, she&amp;rsquo;s back. Literally the last thing that happens in Deadline gets fleshed out (heh) in Blackout as we alternate once again between Shaun&amp;rsquo;s and Georgia&amp;rsquo;s viewpoints. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly obvious what&amp;rsquo;s happened (and a neat extension of what we already know about the zombie virus), but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I was still rooting for her nevertheless.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadline</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/25/deadline/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/25/deadline/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was curious to see where Grant would take this, after killing off a small pile of main characters in the first book. It turns out: somewhere right between what I expected and what I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, Shaun is crazy now. He hears George&amp;rsquo;s voice in his head and answers her out loud. Everyone around him of course thinks he&amp;rsquo;s crazy, but they mostly seem to give him space. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what I think about that. Shaun is still probably my least favorite of the main characters from the first book, which is certainly suboptimal, given that he&amp;rsquo;s the only one to survive&amp;hellip; (Also, the Coke fixation is weird.) But why does everyone else keep him around?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Feed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/20/feed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/20/feed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Brains.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the future, zombies are here and bloggers have taken over the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ruins</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/ruins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/16/ruins/</guid><description>&lt;p>A solid ending to a solid series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think Ruins actually managed to pull things together in a way without feeling (too) rushed that none of the other YA series recently have managed to pull off. The previous plotlines (Kira&amp;rsquo;s conflicted nature, the rest of the Trust, the cure(s)) all come to a head in a way that&amp;rsquo;s still driving enough to finish the series but don&amp;rsquo;t feel like the author was just phoning it in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fragments</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/11/fragments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/11/fragments/</guid><description>&lt;p>A good continuation to Partials. In this book, we see Kira start to come to terms with who she is as she sets off with Samm and Heron across what&amp;rsquo;s left of the United States in search of answers&amp;ndash;only to find more than she was looking for. Meanwhile, Marcus is back home, stuck between two warring Partial factions, trying desperately to broker a piece.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a neat continuation. I like watching the world expand, exploring more of what happened in the decade and change since everything fell apart. We&amp;rsquo;re starting to get some answers, which of course lead to more questions. I look forward to Ruins, cautiously hoping that Wells can pull everything together for the finale.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Isolation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/05/isolation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/05/isolation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Quick and to the point, Isolation tells the story of Heron (who we met briefly in Partials) during the Isolation War. It gives a better picture into the Partials: how they are made, how they are trained, and why they might not only want to, but even been the right to, kill us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a good story and I hope to see more of Heron in the second and third books of the Partials Sequence. It&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see how she&amp;rsquo;s grown and changed in the intervening years and how she interacts with the other human (and not) protagonists.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Elantris</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/elantris/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/elantris/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have yet to find a Sanderson novel that I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly like and Elantris is no exception.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, Elantris focuses around the titular city; once a place of wonder and magic which. Ten years ago, all that ended and now it&amp;rsquo;s populated by essentially zombies: those without heartbeats who cannot die and cannot heal. We follow a few different story lines&amp;ndash;a princess from another land engaged to the prince who gets Elantrisified in the very beginning of the story; an attempted religious coup from multiple fronts; and the politics of a kingdom/city trying to heal after massive upheaval.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Partials</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/partials/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/partials/</guid><description>&lt;p>The story of Partials takes place 11 years after humanity lost a terrible war. Basically, we created super soldiers (Partials) to fight for us. Of course, after they won the war they turned on us&amp;hellip; Worse yet, right at the same time, there was a virus which killed 99.96% of humanity&amp;ndash;including any new pregnancies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So that&amp;rsquo;s where we start. Humanity is stuck on Long Island while the Partials are &lt;em>out there&lt;/em> ™. Because no babies can survive the virus, the youngest living people are 14. The main characters are roughly 16. Even stranger, in an effort to figure out how to cure the virus, the Hope Act has been enacted. All women 18 or older must get pregnant as often as possible.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Iron Wyrm Affair</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/01/the-iron-wyrm-affair/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/01/the-iron-wyrm-affair/</guid><description>&lt;p>Disclaimer: I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually finish the story. I stopped at about 80%, although I was skimming before then. The cover looks good and the summary is intriguing, but the book itself I didn&amp;rsquo;t particularly care for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Main problems:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cauldron</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/cauldron/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/27/cauldron/</guid><description>&lt;p>A solid conclusion (for now) to the Academy series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following from Omega, the Academy is basically dead (lack of funding / interest) and humanity is withdrawing from the stars. Then there&amp;rsquo;s a breakthrough in new FTL drive technology orders of magnitude faster than the previous incarnations. Hutch returns as one of the two pilots sent out on a high speed mission to the origin of the Chindi, a world SETI received a transmission came from, a black hole, and the possible origin of the Omegas (finally).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Odyssey</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/26/odyssey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/26/odyssey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Summary: The Academy is running out of money. In the meantime, MacAllister, a senator&amp;rsquo;s daughter, a pilot, and a PR guy from the Academy are on a tour looking for UFOs because reasons. Eventually the find some (ish), the daughter gets contacted by aliens (maybe, no one believes her at first and it&amp;rsquo;s never really explained), and a bunch of people die.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As with a few other books in this series, it takes half the book to get to what feels like the main plot point, with a massive acceleration in the last 15% and a final climax in the last 5%. It&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily a bad thing, it just felt a lot more obvious in this book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Omega</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/23/omega/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/23/omega/</guid><description>&lt;p>Omega continues on in much the same vein as the previous Academy books. Science fiction in a universe where life is remarkably rare and civilization even more so. This time though&amp;hellip; we&amp;rsquo;ve found someone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Omegas (clouds coming in 8000 year waves from the center of the galaxy which have a tendency to seek out and destroy right angles) return in the book, pointing directly to a new civilization. It&amp;rsquo;s thousands of light years away, so there are only a limited number of ships that can possibly get there in time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chindi</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/19/chindi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/19/chindi/</guid><description>&lt;p>Chindi continues the trend of the previous two books in only vaguely being a sequel. It takes place after the previous two with one of the same characters (Hutch) and there are a few references to previous events&amp;hellip; But that&amp;rsquo;s about it. That&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This book starts with the discovery of an alien satellites around a neutron star. Hijinks ensue and people die (I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that in a second). It turns out that the satellites are part of a communication network. The next large chunk of the book follows our characters from world to world chasing after this network. (More people die). They finally end up finding a truly massive alien starship and exploring that (more people die). Then there&amp;rsquo;s the climax where&amp;ndash;just like Deepsix&amp;ndash;our heroes have to attempt a daring / insane rescue mission so as not to leave a man behind.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deepsix</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/12/deepsix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/12/deepsix/</guid><description>&lt;p>I greatly enjoyed Deepsix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Similar to the Engines of God a large chunk of the book is spent on the technology / archaeological aspects and how they interact with the story, but in this case there&amp;rsquo;s also a strong thriller aspect. Things just keep going wrong (although, given that it&amp;rsquo;s a novel, you can almost guess how each thing is going to go) over and over up until the climax.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Engines of God</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/03/the-engines-of-god/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/08/03/the-engines-of-god/</guid><description>&lt;p>I liked it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Engines of God fits into the same rough style of science fiction as Rama, where the story is drive more by events and discovery than particularly by plot or character. In my opinion, this can be a perfectly enjoyable form of story, just so long as you know that&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re getting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Annihilation Score</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/the-annihilation-score/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/28/the-annihilation-score/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Annihilation Score takes a bit of a different take from the previous five books, shifting the viewpoint from the previous hero* Bob to his wife Mo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Previously, Mo had been one of my favorite characters in the series. She&amp;rsquo;s just mysterious enough that she&amp;rsquo;s interesting, coming in to save the day with a truly terrifying violin. Unfortunately, the more I know about her, the less I care.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Rhesus Chart</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/23/the-rhesus-chart/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/23/the-rhesus-chart/</guid><description>&lt;p>Vampires don&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or at least that&amp;rsquo;s what everyone in the Laundry believes. Turns out&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s a good reason for that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Apocalypse Codex</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/17/the-apocalypse-codex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/17/the-apocalypse-codex/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first chunk of this book was a little bit weak, in particularly the introduction of the new character Ms. Hazard. She represents a different style to the magic in this universe, which is interesting, but she just seems too good at her job. In the same manner as Superman, the more powerful someone becomes, the harder it is to make them interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That does get better in the later half of the book, especially in the climax. I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure what to think about the mixed first/third person writing style, but it is interesting to see some of the scenes from two very different points of view. I miss Mo though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Fuller Memorandum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/11/the-fuller-memorandum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/11/the-fuller-memorandum/</guid><description>&lt;p>(Take 2, the internet ate my first review)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is another solid entry in the Laundry Files and perhaps my favorite yet. We&amp;rsquo;re really starting to get into some of the more horrific corners of the world. In particular, we learn a bit more about Mo&amp;rsquo;s violin; we get another glimpse into a far flung world &lt;span class="spoiler">(the Sleeper in the Pyramid, guarded by a wall of the dead on spikes; great/terrible visual; especially when one imagines RAF patrols keeping an eye on eit)&lt;/span>
 ; and more about Angleton than I bet Bob ever wanted to know (and I really is explored more in the next books).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Equoid</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/05/equoid/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/05/equoid/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another short story between the second and third Laundry Files novels, this one goes into detail on exactly how weird unicorns can be in a fantasy universe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out: pretty weird.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Overtime</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/02/overtime/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/07/02/overtime/</guid><description>&lt;p>Heh. Santa Claus is a nasty beastie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overtime is a fun little story about the Horrors of Christmas and builds just a bit more onto the world of the Laundry Files. It&amp;rsquo;s weird how much authority the night watchman has, but it also makes a certain kind of sense.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Jennifer Morgue</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/30/the-jennifer-morgue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/30/the-jennifer-morgue/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is an excellent follow up to The Atrocity Archives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, Stross managed to tone down the technobabble from ridiculous to only mildly over the top. There&amp;rsquo;s still more than enough references to enjoy and enough neat world building on the (non Euclidean) edges between technology and demonology, but it&amp;rsquo;s not quite hitting you over the head like the first one did.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Concrete Jungle</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/23/the-concrete-jungle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/23/the-concrete-jungle/</guid><description>&lt;p>I liked this even better than The Atrocity Archives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea of SCORPION STARE (Medusa, weaponized) is neat and there&amp;rsquo;s some interesting commentary on the potential problems of a surveillance state that fit well with the overall Britishness of the piece.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rama Revealed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama-revealed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/rama-revealed/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my opinion, this was by far the best of the sequels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They start by doing exactly what I wanted out of the middle two books: getting away from the human settlement and into a situation where they are learning and experiencing something strange. In this case, they go to live among the octospiders, an intelligent civilization highly skilled in genetics and biological science who are completely deaf and only speak in color. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating and nicely thought out situation and I did like it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Atrocity Archives</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/the-atrocity-archives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/21/the-atrocity-archives/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;hellip; was intense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To really get the most out of this book, I think you&amp;rsquo;d have to have a certain combination of things in your head: a knowledge of a lot of the more esoteric bits of computer science theory, physics, pop culture, and cosmic horrors. Pretty much right up my alley. Even then, I will admit to having no idea exactly where he was going with a few of those.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Garden of Rama</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/17/the-garden-of-rama/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/06/17/the-garden-of-rama/</guid><description>&lt;p>Like Rama #2, I went back and forth while reading this one on if I was actually enjoying it or if I would finish it at all. In the end, I did finish it and I think I&amp;rsquo;ll even start the last one mostly out of a sense of completionism.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Essentially, there are five sections:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>