<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Memoirs of Lady Trent on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-memoirs-of-lady-trent/</link><description>Recent content in The Memoirs of Lady Trent on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-memoirs-of-lady-trent/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Turning Darkness Into Light</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/07/06/turning-darkness-into-light/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/07/06/turning-darkness-into-light/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Maybe you’re right about the past. But the stories we choose to tell—those matter. It’s important that the Anevrai told a story about harmony, that they went to the effort of writing it on finely made tablets with gold at their heart. Sacred tablets. That says it was an ideal. And even when we fall short of ideals, that doesn’t mean we should give up striving for them.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And so, an extra book! We&amp;rsquo;ve finished the main series that follows the eponymous Lady Trent, so now we get a book from the point of view of her granddaughter. On top of that, we&amp;rsquo;re going full on epistolary format&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s told through diary entries, letters, and the text of in universe books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting style and I think it gives a lot to the book. It&amp;rsquo;s also non-linear, but not egregiously so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I think it&amp;rsquo;s weaker than the first five Lady Trent books, but there&amp;rsquo;s a bit more depth to the Draconean history we didn&amp;rsquo;t quite get to in those books, which I appreciated. If that&amp;rsquo;s something you were left wanting more of, go for it!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Within the Sanctuary of Wings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/06/10/within-the-sanctuary-of-wings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/06/10/within-the-sanctuary-of-wings/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends (sort of).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Much like the previous books, it&amp;rsquo;s an adventure to somewhere new and far off, this time deep into the mountains (once again) of totally-not-the-Himalayas!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In the Labyrinth of Drakes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/18/in-the-labyrinth-of-drakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/18/in-the-labyrinth-of-drakes/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve been to the mountains, a swamp/rainforest, and on the ocean. What&amp;rsquo;s next? To the desert!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s another book much like the first three: a bit of set up and lamenting the not-British society of the time, then off on an adventure! This time, as mentioned, to the deserts of Akhia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The inciting incident this time is that the military is trying to breed dragons&amp;ndash;either to harvest them for bones or train them for war&amp;ndash;is interesting enough and sure to appeal to Isabella. The whole how do dragons breed / how did we get such variety has been a question for a long time now, and I&amp;rsquo;m just as curious as Isabella is to dig into it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a welcome delight to see Suhail again. I do quite enjoy seeing Isabella and Suhail&amp;rsquo;s relationship develop and this book certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t slouch in that regard.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I sometimes imagine there is a clerk behind a desk situated between the brain and the mouth. It is his job to examine utterances on their way out, and stamp them with approval or send them back for reconsideration. If such a clerk exists, mine must be very harried and overworked; and on occasion he puts his head down on the desk in despair, letting things pass without so much as a second glance.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh they&amp;rsquo;re fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will admit, after actually getting Jake at least somewhat in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/07/the-voyage-of-the-basilisk/">The Voyage of the Basilisk&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>weird&lt;/em> that he&amp;rsquo;s just completely ignored again for the most part here.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>(Indeed, a female desert drake makes me look like a doting mother by comparison.)&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re not wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, if you&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed the books up to now, you&amp;rsquo;ll almost certainly enjoy this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(And only one left!)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Voyage of the Basilisk</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/07/the-voyage-of-the-basilisk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/07/the-voyage-of-the-basilisk/</guid><description>&lt;p>The third book of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-memoirs-of-lady-trent/">The Memoirs of Lady Trent&lt;/a>. First she went to studing dragons in rocky mountanious islands&amp;ndash;and almost died. And then she spent some time studying river dragons deep in the jungle&amp;ndash;and almost died.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now she&amp;rsquo;s off on a voyage around the world&amp;ndash;akin to Darwin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voyage%20of%20the%20Beagle">Voyage of the Beagle&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;to study dragons. Only to almost die not once, not twice, but at least three times. Assuming I didn&amp;rsquo;t miss any.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and have all manner of other adventures along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I have never attempted to hide that I have had two husbands in my life. I have, however, neglected to mention that in between them, I had a wife.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In &lt;em>any&lt;/em> case.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“That should be my epitaph when I die: &amp;lsquo;she did not have to do it&amp;rsquo;.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m still loving riding along with the titular Lady Trent on her adventures and learning all about how dragons work in this world right along with her. And this time, she&amp;rsquo;s actually bringing her son along, which gives a whole new dimension to the journeys&amp;ndash;for the most part.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A fun book. I expect if you&amp;rsquo;ll like the first two, you&amp;rsquo;ll continue to enjoy this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Tropic of Serpents</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/23/the-tropic-of-serpents/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/23/the-tropic-of-serpents/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/29/a-natural-history-of-dragons/">A Natural History of Dragons&lt;/a> set out an interesting world. It&amp;rsquo;s more or less our world (although with all the names rewritten, so you&amp;rsquo;re always playing a game so is &amp;lsquo;xxx&amp;rsquo; just like &amp;lsquo;yyy&amp;rsquo;), but &lt;em>with dragons&lt;/em>. And of course the titular Isabela Trent just wants to study them, like any Natural Historian would!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Give me dragons any day; I understand their ways far better than those of my fellow human beings. We make our world much too complicated.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Natural History of Dragons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/29/a-natural-history-of-dragons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/29/a-natural-history-of-dragons/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s not really at all the sort of book I expected, but I ended up quite enjoying it.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I believed myself to be ready then; now, with the hindsight brought by greater age, I see myself for the naive and inexperienced young woman I was. We all begin in such a manner, though. There is no quick route to experience.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a roughly Victorian period piece (feels fairly like Downton Abbey for the rough time period and most recent media I&amp;rsquo;ve experience with) in a secondary world that strongly echoes our own with some new names and one big difference&amp;ndash;dragons!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>