<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hellblazer on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/hellblazer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hellblazer on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/hellblazer/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hellblazer, Vol. 5: Dangerous Habits</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/23/hellblazer-vol.-5-dangerous-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/23/hellblazer-vol.-5-dangerous-habits/</guid>
      <description>Weird, slow, and dark at first but then we get the Deadly Habits storyline. That’s one of the core Constantine storylines so far as I know and for good reason.
The Bogeyman Oh Constantine. What is going on with you. Dark and depressing and little happening. Sets up a story I suppose.
Dead-Boy’s Heart That’s a great issue. Took me a bit to realize it was typing Constantine. So he’s always been … a little different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellblazer, Vol. 4: The Family Man</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/07/hellblazer-vol.-4-the-family-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/07/hellblazer-vol.-4-the-family-man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Better than Volume 3 by a long shot. Starts weird but interesting and gets better from there. I’ll reiterate though that I can’t really imagine buying these by issue, especially in real time. A volume has enough meat to it to sustain a storyline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellblazer, Vol. 3: The Fear Machine</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/01/hellblazer-vol.-3-the-fear-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/01/hellblazer-vol.-3-the-fear-machine/</guid>
      <description>Not terrible, but also not great. It starts very slowly with a hippie commune and takes a few issues to get going and gets downright weird at a few points. But enjoyable enough after that.
Onward!
Issue specific reviews, spoilers:
Touching the Earth Oh boy.
And then it goes all weird hippy commune. Sure? I don’t really get it. Imagine paying for this as a single issue…
Shepherd’s Warning Well, it’s more of the same story, but there’s potential at least!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellblazer, Vol. 2: The Devil You Know</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/hellblazer-vol.-2-the-devil-you-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/hellblazer-vol.-2-the-devil-you-know/</guid>
      <description>Well that’s a ride. The continuation of the Swamp Thing sexy times storyline, some more backstory on how Constantine got to be how he is, Constantine all Arthurian (for some reason), and a straight up horror story.
Weaker than volume 1 but worth continuing to volume 3!
Sex and Death Starts where we left off, with Constantine out of body and the Swamp Thing doing his mating thing… That is not a plot line I care at all about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hellblazer, Vol. 1: Original Sins</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/14/hellblazer-vol.-1-original-sins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/14/hellblazer-vol.-1-original-sins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;18902412&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18902412.hellblazer-vol-1-original-sins&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/hellblazer-vol-1-original-sins.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really do have a thing for urban fantasy specifically dealing with demons and angels, good and evil, especially if it twists it all around. Constantine does that in spades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched the 2005 film well before I knew it was based on a comic (so sue me), so Keanu Reeves is forever going to be stuck in my head as the true Constantine, but I&amp;rsquo;ve also watched just about all of the new wave of DC shows, including the 2014 version of Constantine plus his appearances on Legends of Tomorrow. Not quite the same, but I still loved the character.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
