<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arcane on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/arcane/</link><description>Recent content in Arcane on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/arcane/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arcane: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/21/arcane-season-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/21/arcane-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well then. I absolutely loved [[Arcane: Season 1]]. I still loved Season 2&amp;hellip; but I think they may have reached just a &lt;em>bit&lt;/em> too far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The art style is still amazing. We still have the same main steampunk/magitech/brightly colored visuals (Jink&amp;rsquo;s chaotic spraypunk style in particular), but there are also more scenes this time, with different styles matching the feel. Chaotic black slashes when a monster hunts, childhood crayon feeling drawings for memories, and SPACE for&amp;hellip; well, spoilers. And oh, the glitching. Weird, but quite the style.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characters&amp;hellip; I think at it&amp;rsquo;s heart, this show is about Vi and Jinx and man do they go through a lot in this season. I already felt for Jinx&amp;ndash;even if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure she could ever be redeemed in season 1&amp;ndash;and they just turn it up. On top of that, you have Jayce/Viktor, which&amp;hellip; man that one hurt this season. Plus Vi/Cait (go them!), and Mel/her mother (this one didn&amp;rsquo;t get nearly as much time as it needed), and Ekko (this could have been a whole season&amp;hellip; or left out entirely).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mostly, I think this was the biggest problem with this season. It&amp;rsquo;s only 9 episodes, mostly short of 45 minutes. That is &lt;em>not&lt;/em> enough time to fit everything that they tried to put in this show. I could have easily watched an entire season focussing on any one of those plots above&amp;hellip; and they tried to fit it all in. We get some resolutions&amp;hellip; but so much is left undone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently there won&amp;rsquo;t be an Arcane Season 3; instead, we&amp;rsquo;ll get one or more spinoff shows in the same universe but with other stories/settings/characters. This is absolutely for the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of feel, the first season did a good job of feeling real/grounded. It was a story of class warfare and the introduction of magic into a steampunk world. It all &amp;lsquo;fit&amp;rsquo;. Here, we get quite a bit more of the more &amp;lsquo;cosmic&amp;rsquo; side of what&amp;rsquo;s apparently also kicking around in this world. I liked it, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, but it felt so much bigger and weirder than the first season that they didn&amp;rsquo;t quite fit together&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall? I still quite enjoyed Season 2. It is absolutely worth watching Season 1 and once you have&amp;hellip; well, you have to go on, right? I&amp;rsquo;ll totally check out any spin-offs that we get.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Arcane: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/23/arcane-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/23/arcane-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>That is an absolutely beautiful delight of a show. I love the asthetic/worldbuilding, with a mix of steampunk/magic plus a major cyberpunk visual style. It&amp;rsquo;s something that I really could do with some more of and the animated style &lt;em>really&lt;/em> lends itself nicely to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, there&amp;rsquo;s a mix of a few different plots (family troubles, class war, magic versus tech, corruption in politics / power corrupts) that each work by themselves, but are particularly good when you get crossovers. Class war and politics complicated by magic versus tech. (Found and blood) family troubles through it all. Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the worst part of it all? It ended! And now I have to wait for Season 2!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth a watch.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>