<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2021 Movie Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-movie-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2021 Movie Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 23:59:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-movie-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2021 TV &amp; Movies Retrospective</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-tv-movies-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-tv-movies-retrospective/</guid><description>&lt;p>I do a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-reading-retrospective/">post&lt;/a> each year on books, but this year I also started reviewing movies and TV shows! I have &lt;em>absolutely&lt;/em> no idea how much value people get out of this (and I&amp;rsquo;d love to &lt;a href="mailto:blog@jverkamp.com">hear from you&lt;/a>), but I enjoy doing it, so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to stop any time soon. :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s been a good year for movies and TV!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I watched:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>55 movies&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>25 from the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-cinematic-universe/">Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 Disney Animated Classics + 1 Home Release sequel (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/04/bambi-2-the-great-prince-of-the-forest/">Bambi 2: The Great Prince of the Forest&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>35 on Disney+ (mostly the MCU + kid&amp;rsquo;s movies above)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 on HBOMax (new releases!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 in theaters (oh Covid and having a baby&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>14 TV shows (46 total seasons)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Matrix Resurrections</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/the-matrix-resurrections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/the-matrix-resurrections/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Whoa.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a blast of nostalgia, a bunch of mind-bending meta universe building, some awesome new characters, a few solid action scenes, and overall quite an action movie. I loved it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Far From Home</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/spider-man-far-from-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>As much as I loved &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/">Spider-Man: Homecoming&lt;/a>, Spider-Man: Far From Home takes what made it great and turns it up a few levels &lt;em>even further&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One one level, you have Spider-Man being Spider-Man. He&amp;rsquo;s a good kid, trying to make his way in life, trying to deal with the dual life of being a highschooler and being a superhero&amp;ndash;of saving the world and perhaps getting the girl.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then you layer all the weight of the greater MCU on top of it. This takes place just after &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/">Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a>. So you have the fallout of Iron Man (Spider-Man&amp;rsquo;s mentor/Uncle Ben figure) being gone and Spider-Man having to step into &lt;em>those&lt;/em> shoes, the first big mention of The Blip&amp;ndash;and how you deal with coming back and the world has changed, and all sorts of dealing with a Nick Fury who&amp;rsquo;s lost several of his heaviest hitters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Homecoming</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>That&lt;/em> is a truly delightful Spider-Man movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird seeing him introduced &lt;em>after&lt;/em> the events of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/">Captain America: Civil War&lt;/a>) and completely skipping how he became Spider-Man in the first place&amp;hellip; but it works. I really like the entire plot, dealing with the fallout of the Avengers / super-hero activity and how normal people try to live their lives around it&amp;ndash;and what happens when the powers that be step in and take that away from them. Excellent villain fuel. It&amp;rsquo;s a little silly that &lt;span class="spoiler">the Vulture ends up being Spider-Man's crush's father...&lt;/span>
, but I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s the sort of thing you expect from superhero films. Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid, fun action film.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Greatest Showman</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/21/the-greatest-showman/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/21/the-greatest-showman/</guid><description>&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RW61RQZojMQ?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Now that&amp;rsquo;s music. I can only imagine hearing that on a theater scale sound system. Although my home sound bar certainly tried it&amp;rsquo;s best&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, I know I&amp;rsquo;m behind the times. Better late than never?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid movie that tries to make some big points about everyone having value / sticking it to the people that hate you because you&amp;rsquo;re different and&amp;hellip; mostly hitting the mark? It gets even more complicated when you read up on Barnum&amp;rsquo;s actual history. Very much a serial &amp;lsquo;get rich quick&amp;rsquo;er with some questionable ethics, but there&amp;rsquo;s good parts there as well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VI - Return of the Jedi</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/19/star-wars-episode-vi-return-of-the-jedi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/19/star-wars-episode-vi-return-of-the-jedi/</guid><description>&lt;p>You know, that is a really solid movie. I know a lot of people prefer Empire, but for whatever reason, I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked Return of the Jedi more. That holds true even more, although I have to say that there are a few (possibly nostalgia fueled) particulars that I like more before the special editions changed things.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes Back</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/11/star-wars-episode-v-the-empire-strikes-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/11/star-wars-episode-v-the-empire-strikes-back/</guid><description>&lt;p>Woo! Big icy battles on land in and the sky/space around Hoth, training with a real (short) Jedi Master (and they&amp;rsquo;re all supposed to be dead), meetings between old friends&amp;ndash;who may not be too thrilled about losing in cards all those years ago&amp;ndash;another confrontation between Luke and Vadar, and the big bad reveal. Which&amp;hellip; seriously. His name is literally &lt;span class="spoiler">Dark Father&lt;/span>
.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nutcracker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/11/nutcracker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/11/nutcracker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a truly bizarre adaptation of the Nutcracker. Or I suppose all of the other versions are bizarre, given that this is supposed to be as &amp;lsquo;close as possible&amp;rsquo; to the original Maurice Sendak version.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bambi 2: The Great Prince of the Forest</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/04/bambi-2-the-great-prince-of-the-forest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/04/bambi-2-the-great-prince-of-the-forest/</guid><description>&lt;p>You know, I was actually pleasantly surprised by Bambi II (later retitled). And not only because they got Patrick Stewart of all people to voice Bambi&amp;rsquo;s dad (who now has to step up and be a single father). It&amp;rsquo;s as cute a story as Bambi was&amp;ndash;which the kids&amp;rsquo; appreciated&amp;ndash;but with just a bit more depth&amp;ndash;which I did. It&amp;rsquo;s still certainly not high cinema, but it&amp;rsquo;s not terrible either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Disney Animated&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bambi</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/27/bambi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/27/bambi/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bambi is a surprisingly tricky movie to review, mostly since it relies on who&amp;rsquo;s doing the reviewing. From my perspective, it&amp;rsquo;s cute enough, but there&amp;rsquo;s next to nothing there. It&amp;rsquo;s just a bunch of cute animated animals running around for an hour. From my kids&amp;rsquo; perspectives though&amp;hellip; they loved it. They were laughing out loud at the cartoon antics and cuddled right in during the storm and hunt scenes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun enough movie for kids to watch, but I think next time they request it, I&amp;rsquo;ll find something else to do with my time. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dune (Movie)</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/20/dune-movie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/20/dune-movie/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lady Jessica Atreides: I must not fear. Fear is the mind-killer. Fear is the little death that brings obliteration. I will face my fear and I will permit it to pass over me and through me. And when it has gone past&amp;hellip; I will turn the inner eye to see its path. Where the fear has gone there will be nothing. Only I will remain.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Wow. That&amp;rsquo;s a movie with &lt;em>quite&lt;/em> a sense of scale and granduer. The ships are huge, the worms are huge, the armies are huge, the Duke is honorable, the Fremen are pious, the Baron is gross, everything is spectacular. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a bummer that we&amp;rsquo;re going to have to wait a few years for Part 2, but I think it really did need the space to breath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The worldbuilding and visuals are what really makes this movie. I watched it on HBOMax, rather than in theaters, but I do have a wall sized projected screen and that really does help. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a visually stunning movie. If they re-run Part 1 in theaters, I may have to check it out next time around&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode IV - A New Hope</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/17/star-wars-episode-iv-a-new-hope/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/17/star-wars-episode-iv-a-new-hope/</guid><description>&lt;p>There it is. A New Hope. The Star Wars I grew up on.&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vLgsf8Pei6Q?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a great opening. The scale of the Star Destroyer, dumping us in on the &amp;rsquo;everyman&amp;rsquo; droids, and that Vadar scene. Spectacular.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode III - Revenge of the Sith</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/15/star-wars-episode-iii-revenge-of-the-sith/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/15/star-wars-episode-iii-revenge-of-the-sith/</guid><description>&lt;p>Revenge of the Sith is a somewhat fascinating story. It feels by far the darkest and most &amp;lsquo;adult&amp;rsquo; of the prequel trilogy, probably best matching the feel of A New Hope and Empire Strikes Back, but at the same time, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more humor in the early parts at least, with some truly weird and silly moments with R2 and the Battle Droids. You know&amp;hellip; I just don&amp;rsquo;t understand the droids. I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to that in a bit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/13/the-many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/13/the-many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh is just delightful&amp;ndash;and a blast of nostalgia on top of that. I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to actually watch all of the Disney classic growing up (still haven&amp;rsquo;t), but I definiately watched this one. And now, after reading many of the stories to my children, it&amp;rsquo;s a delight to be able to share the video form with them as well!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really like the style of these stories. It&amp;rsquo;s a mix of animated world with the real storybook characters (Pooh et al), but also obviously in a book, as they hob from page to page. It&amp;rsquo;s not the story of style you&amp;rsquo;d always expect to work, but it really works here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode II - Attack of the Clones</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/07/star-wars-episode-ii-attack-of-the-clones/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/07/star-wars-episode-ii-attack-of-the-clones/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The things that I remember most about Attack of the Clones are the atmosphere of Kamino, the final battle on Genosis (mostly from the game Star Wars Battlefront), and some rather cringey burgeoning relationship dialog from Anakin and Padme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was not disappointed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Luca</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/02/luca/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/02/luca/</guid><description>&lt;p>Luca is something of an odd beast. It&amp;rsquo;s a cute little movie about two young sea monster boys who journey out onto land&amp;ndash;where so long as they don&amp;rsquo;t get wet, they transform to look like humans. Wacky hijinks ensue, there&amp;rsquo;s a meetcute with a young girl, a big race scenes, some quickly resolved drama, and everyone lives happily ever after.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not the most thrilling movie, which isn&amp;rsquo;t really something that you expect to see from Pixar&amp;ndash;if it had come from any other studio it would have been pretty impressive. But at the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid enough movie, it&amp;rsquo;s cute, and there were a few laugh out loud moments, so I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have seen it. I fully expect the children will enjoy this one&amp;ndash;although it&amp;rsquo;s rather odd watching it a week after Finding Nemo&amp;ndash;a much better movie made 20 years earlier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Nightmare Before Christmas</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/the-nightmare-before-christmas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/the-nightmare-before-christmas/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Boys and girls of every age&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you like to see something strange?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Come with us and you will see&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This, our town of Halloween&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Man I love this movie.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One Hundred and One Dalmatians</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/30/one-hundred-and-one-dalmatians/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/30/one-hundred-and-one-dalmatians/</guid><description>&lt;p>60 years ago. Dang. And you know? It holds up. The action is solid and story aren&amp;rsquo;t overly complicated but enjoyable, the animation really works (despite/because of the limitations of the time), and the villains are unambiguous and scary but not overly so. Perhaps best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s the story of an absolute pile of talking dogs. What&amp;rsquo;s not to love?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Episode I - The Phantom Menace</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/29/star-wars-episode-i-the-phantom-menace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/29/star-wars-episode-i-the-phantom-menace/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, that opening score. The title crawl. That&amp;rsquo;s a blast of nostalgia right there. I&amp;rsquo;m too young to have seen the original trilogy in theaters, but I watched the VHS tapes what felt like a million times. When The Phantom Menace came out, that was &lt;em>right&lt;/em> in my wheelhouse. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember how many times I saw that movie in theaters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And you know what? It&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as it&amp;rsquo;s often rated. Granted, if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t leaning so heavily on the rest of the Star Wars franchise, well&amp;hellip; it would probably be about that bad. But I disagree that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t disserve a place in the core &amp;lsquo;Skywalker Saga&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun action movie wrapped around the rise of dark powers and corruption in the guise of&amp;ndash;a trade war and senatorial discourse of all things. It&amp;rsquo;s weird, but I&amp;rsquo;ve grown to accept it at least?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Obi-Wan: You were right about one thing master. The negotiations were short.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s my favorite Star Wars movie so far&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and only a hint of things to come!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Knives Out</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/24/knives-out/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/24/knives-out/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lieutenant Elliott: I&amp;rsquo;m sorry this is an open and shut case of suicide and quite frankly Benny we are getting to the point where I have to ask you what we&amp;rsquo;re doing here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Benoit Blanc: The method? Throat slit? Typical for a suicide?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lieutenant Elliott: Yes, I mean, that&amp;rsquo;s dramatic, but look around. I mean, the guy practical lives in a Clue board.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was a surprising yet great fun movie. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a murder mystery. Heir of the family is found dead&amp;ndash;apparent suicide. But things quickly become more complicated, with a detective (Daniel Craig as Benoit Blanc with a hilarious southern drawl that still somehow works&amp;hellip;) anonymously hired to &amp;lsquo;get to the truth&amp;rsquo;. The family is a nightmare, everyone has a reason to have offed the old man&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Finding Nemo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/finding-nemo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/23/finding-nemo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finding Nemo is a delightful children&amp;rsquo;s movie. It&amp;rsquo;s the story of a worrying dad (Marlin), a son (Nemo) trying to grow into his own self, the trouble that causes, and the lengths family can go through for one another.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shazam!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/shazam/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/21/shazam/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was not really what I expected. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s got the heart of a super hero origin story, with Billy Batson gaining powers, learning to use them (and not lose himself or his friends/family while doing so), and fighting the big bad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Rescuers Down Under</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/the-rescuers-down-under/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/the-rescuers-down-under/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s an absolute blast of childhood nostalgia. We had this movie on VHS when I was little and I remember watching the heck out of it, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t otherwise seen it in decades now. Truth be told, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until recently that I realized it was even a sequel&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case. The Rescuers (Down Under) is the story of a worldwide society of mice that take it upon themselves to rescue human children in need of help. It&amp;rsquo;s a nutty premise, but just go with it. This time around, it&amp;rsquo;s a boy kidnapped in the Australian outback (with a wonderfully over the top poacher as the villain) and somehow the team they send are two mice from&amp;hellip; New York? There&amp;rsquo;s no one else closer? Only two? Anyways, they have to go rescue the boy, there are a few tense moments, a lot of adventure, and in the end the villain is defeated and the boy goes home free. It&amp;rsquo;s got a number of tense moments&amp;ndash;more than I remember truth be told&amp;ndash;and my younger viewers needed a bit of attention through a few points. But I think they enjoyed it well enough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/09/shang-chi-and-the-legend-of-the-ten-rings/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was a surprisingly delightful movie. It takes a character I&amp;rsquo;ve at least barely heard of&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> with a cast pretty much unknown to the western world&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and turns it into a wonderful combination of human drama, Lovecraftian baddies, and awesome action scenes. It&amp;rsquo;s well among my favorite MCU movies to date (only Captain America beats it out among introductions and a few others overall) and well worth the watch. After how big the MCU has gotten recently, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of nice to see a movie that almost completely stands on it&amp;rsquo;s own&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. It&amp;rsquo;s a big world, with parallel/pocket universes and gates to worlds chock full of truly alien baddies, but at the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s a story about family, about legacy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Widow</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/08/black-widow/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first time I&amp;rsquo;ve been to theaters since&amp;hellip; &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/">Avengers: Endgame&lt;/a>. Man it&amp;rsquo;s been a weird few years. Which actually wraps up Black Widow pretty well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly solid action/spy movie. There are a number of spectacular action scenes, a deep dive into Black Widow&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s akin to an origin story, but filling in a character we already knew a decent amount of back rather than introducing someone new, which was nice&amp;ndash;and the introduction of a few new characters I expect we&amp;rsquo;ll see more of. After the absolutely draining intensity of Infinity War/Endgame plus just how dark the followup shows have been, it was nice to have something relatively &amp;rsquo;lighter&amp;rsquo; and smaller in scope.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Palm Springs</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/02/palm-springs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/02/palm-springs/</guid><description>&lt;p>Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t love a good time loop movie/episode? Especially a crude (at times) time loop + romantic comedy.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nyles: I guess you followed me. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those infinite time loop situations you might have heard about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sarah: That I might have heard about?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nyles: Yeah.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I think that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the best part about the movie: there is more than one person trapped in and aware of the loop and Nyles at least is perfectly genre aware. He&amp;rsquo;s seen the time loop movies and knows how screwed up they can be.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Endgame</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/29/avengers-endgame/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s one heck of a climax.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/">Avengers: Infinity War&lt;/a>, Thanos won. He snapped and half of the universe died&amp;ndash;let&amp;rsquo;s ignore the logistics of that. In Endgame, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance&amp;ndash;a very small chance&amp;ndash;that they can fix it all. All they need is a little &amp;ndash;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tony Stark: [discussing the &amp;ldquo;Time Heist&amp;rdquo;] I believe the most likely outcome will be our collective demise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scott Lang: Not if we strictly follow the rules of time travel. That means no talking to our past selves, no betting on sporting events&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/28/captain-marvel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Captain Marvel is a bit of an odd movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a straight up superhero origin story with a bit more of a cosmic twist than many we&amp;rsquo;ve seen (other than Guardians of the Galaxy&amp;hellip; and Thor&amp;hellip;) It&amp;rsquo;s something of a prequel&amp;ndash;in that it&amp;rsquo;s chronologically set before any of the other Marvel movies other than the beginning of Captain America. It&amp;rsquo;s got a hero in Captain Marvel with a grab bag of vaguely defined glowy energy powers with memory issues who has to go on a journey and power up to her final form.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ant-Man and the Wasp</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ant-Man and his daughter are adorable. Especially with Luis&amp;rsquo; help. Luis is wonderful. Everyone playing Luis as he describes everyone. And Paul Rudd playing Janet van Dyne. Add to that the interactions with/introduction of Jimmy Woo.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Scott Lang: Come on, Woo. I&amp;rsquo;ve got three days left. Why would I try to escape?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jimmy Woo: Sorry, Scott, but rules are rules. You trip the perimeter alarm, we search the place. Keel to stern, soup to nuts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Suicide Squad</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-suicide-squad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/24/the-suicide-squad/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, that is a glorious movie. Exactly what an R rated half-satirical superhero movie should be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually seen the first Suicide Squad or Birds of Prey (yet), so it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as strange that they apparently kept some of the characters/actors while ignoring some events and keeping others. Other than that&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s just so enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting right from the opening:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/2021/suicide-squad-1.jpg">
&lt;/figure>

&lt;p>You have the Suicide Squad. Super powered criminals, given the chance to take a few years off their sentence if they&amp;rsquo;ll use their powers to do the jobs that the &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; heroes are either too busy or too &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; to do. It&amp;rsquo;s a crazy yet awesome plot and the cast is amazing. Nathan Fillion as T.D.K&amp;ndash;his arms come off. Jai Courtney back as Boomerang&amp;ndash;he throws&amp;hellip; a boomerang. Flula Borg as Javelin&amp;ndash;likewise, with a javelin. Mayling Ng as Mongal&amp;ndash;she&amp;rsquo;s an alien or something? Pete Davidson as Blackguard&amp;ndash;who knows. And especially Sean Gunn as Weasel&amp;ndash;a humanoid&amp;hellip; weasel. And Michael Rooker as Savant&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure, expert at throwing things? Him and Sean Gunn together was amusing coming off Guardians of the Galaxy. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit I looked that one up; he&amp;rsquo;s in everything! It&amp;rsquo;s not at all the team of heroes you&amp;rsquo;d expect.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Infinity War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>All that. Ten years. 18 movies. Dozens of huge name actors and crossovers, all leading to this. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/">The Avengers&lt;/a> gave us a team up, but Infinity War turned it all up to 11. The battle scenes are insane (especially that final battle in Wakanda, especially especially the return of Thor), the villain&amp;ndash;Josh Brolin as Thanos&amp;ndash;is powerful and &lt;span class="spoiler">ACTUALLY GETS A CHANCE TO WIN&lt;/span>
, and I absolutely love seeing the interplay between all of the characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Panther</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a very solid movie. The casting is top notch, the style is wonderfully afrofuturistic, and the plot/motivation is interesting enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting with the plot/motivation, I think that the choice to have Wakanda separated from the rest of the world, all through centuries of slavery and inequality is certainly an interesting one. And I&amp;rsquo;m not at all alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nakia: I came to support you, and to honor your father. But I can&amp;rsquo;t stay. It&amp;rsquo;s just &amp;hellip; ! found my calling out there. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen too many in need just to turn a blind eye. I can&amp;rsquo;t be happy here knowing that there&amp;rsquo;s people out there who have nothing .&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor: Ragnarok</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ooh, that poster. &lt;em>le kiss&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/">Thor&lt;/a> was &amp;hellip; fine, a weirdly downscale introduction to a kind of strange character early in the MCU. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/">Thor: The Dark World&lt;/a> went the other way, being too bigt and ambitious and suffering somewhat for it. So going into Thor: Ragnarok, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what we were going to get.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An absolute gem of an 80s sci fi/fantasy action superhero comedy that just works. Right from the very intro, you know it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a different sort of movie. They lean hard into the Norse/Asgardian mythos, with Thor in the underworld, chained up (but not concerned) by a giant flaming skeleton who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to signify the end of days. One spectacular Thor&amp;rsquo;ful action scene later and we&amp;rsquo;re back on Asgard, dealing with the missing Odin. Then we&amp;rsquo;re off to Earth, only to bump into Doctor Strange, now fully into his powers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>After the surprisingly awesome &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/">Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/a>, it was really a question of: could they do it again? The answer, a resounding&amp;hellip; sort of?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 has some pretty awesome moments. The opening battle in particular is spectacular (I love the contrast of dancing Baby Groot against a big smack down in the background). And we get all piles of additional humor based around Drax&amp;rsquo;s literalness, Rocket being a racoon, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doctor Strange</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/10/doctor-strange/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/10/doctor-strange/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Wong: While heroes like the Avengers protect the world from physical dangers, we sorcerers safeguard it against more mystical threats.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Man, that is a visually stunning movie. The first battle with building magically twisting all over (a la Inception), the glowing magic rings, the magical doodads. I am ever thankful that superhero movies have gotten popular enough that studios will spend the big bucks on special effects. They really do look great.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain America: Civil War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/03/captain-america-civil-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>Captain America: Civil War isn&amp;rsquo;t really a Captain America movie. While it deals with the Winter Solder to some extent, as much as that it&amp;rsquo;s an Iron Man movie since &lt;span class="spoiler">he killed Stark's parents...&lt;/span>
. But really, it&amp;rsquo;s an Avengers movie. Everyone shows up, takes sides, and eventually ends up a great big superhero fight. And It&amp;hellip; Is&amp;hellip; Spectacular. In my opinion, it&amp;rsquo;s the best MCU movie to this point, beating out any of the solo outings and even the first two Avengers movies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ant-Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/02/ant-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/02/ant-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Continuing in the set of Marvel movies that came out after I stopped going to theaters quite so much / reviewing movies in 2014, we have Ant-Man!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a heist movie/comedy with superheroes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful movie, with a lighter, funnier theme than a lot of the movies. The cast is wonderful. Paul Rudd is hilarious and well cast as Ant-Man, Michael Douglas is a wonderful cranky old man scientist that&amp;rsquo;s been burned as Hank Pym, Corey Stoll is a wonderful crazy (spoilers) bad guy, and Evangeline Lilly is criminally underused. Eventually that will/should get better. But the real standout has to be Michael Peña as Luis. He&amp;rsquo;s hilarious. The &amp;lsquo;he said/she said&amp;rsquo; stories told with all manner of different actors but his voice are a joy to watch. He&amp;rsquo;s just that funny.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Space Jam: A New Legacy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/29/space-jam-a-new-legacy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/29/space-jam-a-new-legacy/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Bugs Bunny: So, you want me, a talking cartoon bunny, to play with you, an NBA superstar, in a high-stakes basketball game?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sounds awfully familiar.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LeBron James: Who are you talking to?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well. That was certainly a thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched the original Space Jam in probably 20 years&amp;hellip; but I remember it fondly enough. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I really want to go back and watch it again. But it still does make me want to give Space Jam: A New Legacy a chance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Age of Ultron</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/14/avengers-age-of-ultron/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Hawkeye: The city is flying and we&amp;rsquo;re fighting an army of robots. And I have a bow and arrow. Nothing makes sense.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Age of Ultron is an odd movie. From the perspective of a summer blockbuster/action movie, it&amp;rsquo;s solid. The opening action scene is wonderfully avengerful, there are all manner of awesome fights (the Hulk versus Iron Man fight and the final battle come to mind), and we get a few new characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/13/guardians-of-the-galaxy/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had forgotten just how &lt;em>fun&lt;/em> Guardians of the Galaxy is. Back when I &lt;a href="#original-2014-review">first reviewed it in 2014&lt;/a>, it surprised me with how different it was and just how much it opened up the Marvel Universe. Well, we&amp;rsquo;ve seen some pretty crazy things since then (Thor Ragnarok springs to mind), but it&amp;rsquo;s still a pretty crazy movie. I mean, come on. It&amp;rsquo;s a man obsessed with classic rock, a badass green woman assassin, an overly literal shirtless wrestler, a cybernetically enhanced racoon, and a speaking tree &lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> &lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Add in the first real hints of the Infinity Stones, Thanos as the continuing &amp;lsquo;bigger bad&amp;rsquo;, and you have a pretty impactful movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then on top of that, you get an absolutely hilarious movie, some wonderful action scenes (the meet up / fight in the square at the beginning is particularly wonderful, but there are several), and a whole range of colorful new characters. When you don&amp;rsquo;t have to even try to stick to what works on Earth&amp;hellip; things get pretty silly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a wonderful movie. I think this time around, I actually rate it higher than the Avengers, although still below Iron Man and Captain America 1 and 2. Well worth a watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the record: the ending scene is still kind of dumb.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Random side note: the idea of a whole fleet of starships linking up (somehow) and literally trying to push a very slow moving enemy spaceship back into space is just bonkers. Among a movie full of crazy scenes, that one came the closest to really pulling me out of the film. But so it goes.&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="original-2014-review">Original 2014 review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Can Marvel do no wrong?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tenet</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/06/tenet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/06/tenet/</guid><description>&lt;p>That &amp;hellip; is a summer blockbuster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an absolutely bonkers plot. In a nutshell, the future is at war with the present (somehow) and there is technology that can &amp;lsquo;invert&amp;rsquo; people and things so that they experience time backwards. How exactly that works and what exactly happens when you mess with the past/future is&amp;hellip; never entirely clear. But it certainly does make for some absolutely crazy action scenes where some things are going forward, some backward, people are in the same scene more than once and&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain America: The Winter Soldier</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/27/captain-america-the-winter-soldier/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/27/captain-america-the-winter-soldier/</guid><description>&lt;p>From &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/">one of the weakest&lt;/a> MCU movies to one of the strongest. I loved the first solo entry of Captain American and the second is even better. Much like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/27/captain-america-the-winter-soldier/">last time&lt;/a>, I very much enjoyed this movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a solid contrast against the first Captain America (blind optimistic patriotism versus a darker world, where even your friends&amp;hellip; might not be). It&amp;rsquo;s made all the better having already seen the future of Sam and Bucky/The Winter Soldier now. Last time through, I was hoping they could pull off all the new characters and now&amp;hellip; I think they did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around (and so far), the top of my list for the year. An excellent movie.&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="original-2014-review">Original 2014 review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Out of all the pre-Avengers / &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Marvel_Cinematic_Universe_films#Phase_One:_Avengers_Assembled">Phase One&lt;/a> Marvel Cinematic Universe movies, it&amp;rsquo;s really a toss up whether Iron Man or Captain American was my favorite. In &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Marvel_Cinematic_Universe_films#Phase_Two">Phase Two&lt;/a>? It&amp;rsquo;s not even a question&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Captain America: The Winter Soldier.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor: The Dark World</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>One problem that comic book universes in general and the MCU in specific have always had is that of scale. How in the world do you have a man in a suit, a literal &amp;lsquo;god&amp;rsquo;, a rage monster, a super soldier, and a couple &amp;hellip; regular people ever interact on the same scale? For the most part, it&amp;rsquo;s hand waved away. Everyone is paired up with an opponent of roughly the same power level and we move on with our lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No where those is this contrast more apparent than in the Universe of Thor. The people of Asgard are supposed to be gods. They live thousands of years. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen them shrug off some pretty crazy weapons. And yet here they are, dying to spears and falling rocks. It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean, there are any number of brilliant CGI shots of the weird world of Asgard, and it at least has a much bigger scope than the first Thor, but it still feels &amp;hellip; hollow. It&amp;rsquo;s a pity, because I enjoy Thor&amp;rsquo;s super powerful fish out of water story well enough in the combined movies, but this is not my favorite of the combined films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s always interesting to re-read my older reviews: &lt;a href="#original-2013-review">see below&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="original-2013-review">Original 2013 review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The first Thor was a bit disappointing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There, I said it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It could certainly have been worse, but it really felt like the entire movie served solely to set up Thor&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> for the Avengers. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t terrible, it just &amp;hellip; was.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iron Man 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/iron-man-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/iron-man-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>For some reason, I Iron Man 3 as a fairly week entry, but looking back to when I last watched it in theaters (&lt;a href="#original-2013-review">see below&lt;/a>)&amp;hellip; I actually liked it about as much then I do now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, I really do still think they absolutely nailed Robert Downey Jr. as Iron man. He can do both funny and broken pretty well and has more than a few chances for each this time around. I know now (and didn&amp;rsquo;t then) that there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be an Iron Man 4, but he still did an amazing job in this last solo outing and in the teams ups yet to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise, I actually really liked Gwyneth Paltrow&amp;rsquo;s as Pepper Potts. It&amp;rsquo;s good seeing her as both a foil for Iron Man and actually being a badass in her own right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ben Kingsley still steal the show, although this time around I&amp;rsquo;m coming to see just how much range there was in Guy Pearce&amp;rsquo;s Aldrich Killian. He pulled down on his luck geek up through brilliant and crazy mirror to Tony Stark all the way to &lt;span class="spoiler">fire breathing baddie&lt;/span>
 pretty darn well so far as action movies go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One that I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention last time around, but made all the more apparent I think having just seen in her in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/godzilla-vs-kong/">Godzilla vs Kong&lt;/a>) was Rebecca Hall&amp;rsquo;s performance as Maya Hansen. She does smart conflicted scientist very well in both films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it was a fascinating way to deal with PTSD, even if does feel a bit sudden (although PTSD can do that) and could really have used a bit deeper dive (not really room for that in a summer blockbuster).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, feel free to give my &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/05/iron-man-3/">previous review&lt;/a> a look. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really changed my opinion much, but it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the two 8 years apart. A lot can change in 8 years&amp;hellip; Both so far as the MCU and in my own life. Some things change, some things stand the tests of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think this time around, I&amp;rsquo;ll slot it in just below the Avengers on both lists. I think Iron Man 3 might actually be the better movie in a lot of ways, but the Avengers I think wins just on sheer spectacle. Feel free to disagree. :) It&amp;rsquo;s all made up numbers anyways.&lt;/p>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>


&lt;div class="ranking">
 &lt;h3 class="title">Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews&lt;/h3>&lt;p>
 Show:
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="current">[current]&lt;/a>
 &lt;a href="#" data-ranked-show="all">[all]&lt;/a>
 &lt;/p>&lt;div class="content">
 &lt;ol>&lt;li>No list available...&lt;/li>&lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="original-2013-review">Original 2013 review:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Go see Iron Man 3. I&amp;rsquo;ll wait.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mortal Kombat</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/03/mortal-kombat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 23:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/03/mortal-kombat/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Shang Tsung: FINISH THEM!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Mortal Kombat is an odd sort of movie. With 2 dozen games, 2 previous live action and 2 animated films, and all manner of other references and media, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of backstory going on. But really, it all comes down to some sort of otherworldly nasties coming to conquer the Earth, but they can only do so if they defeat Earth&amp;rsquo;s champion(s). Other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s really a vehicle for hand to hand combat of the most violent sort.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate: Continuum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-continuum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-continuum/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was a far better movie (in my opinion) than &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/">Stargate: The Ark of Truth&lt;/a>. It basically felt like a slightly higher budget two part episode (although those already tended to be good) of the series and actually gave a chance to say goodbye to a few more people: In particularly Ba&amp;rsquo;al (RIP) and O&amp;rsquo;Neill, who really needed it. Not to mention a callback to the real villains of the show: The Goa&amp;rsquo;uld.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Godzilla vs Kong</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/godzilla-vs-kong/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/godzilla-vs-kong/</guid><description>&lt;p>You know, that was more enjoyable than I think it had any right to be. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of movie that would have been far more spectacular on a big screen, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to the theaters in a while, so I&amp;rsquo;ll take smaller.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All around, it&amp;rsquo;s a visual delight. Transporting Kong is hilarious looking. The Hollow Earth is an insane idea, but it&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful world and all of those big beasties to fight are a lot of fun to see. &lt;spoiler>Mechagodzilla&lt;/spoiler> makes even less sense than a lot of the movie / other human ways to fight the monsters. But once again, it makes for a wonderful visual.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate: The Ark of Truth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stargate: The Ark of Truth is the first of two direct-to-video sequels to SG-1. This one picks up after the SG-1 series finale and concludes the Ori arc and throws in a number of other callbacks along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
Lt. Colonel Cameron Mitchell: It's kind of weird not having a big bad guy to fight anymore.
&lt;p>Lt. Colonel Samantha Carter: Yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s how we felt when we defeated the Goa&amp;rsquo;uld. And The Replicators. The first time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Captain America: The First Avenger</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/31/captain-america-the-first-avenger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/31/captain-america-the-first-avenger/</guid><description>&lt;p>Now that is how you do a super hero movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For anyone that&amp;rsquo;s somehow missed it, Captain America is the story about how a little guy from Brooklyn with a heart of gold and a steadfast determination to serve his country in World War II gets just that chance: taking a super soldier serum to get buff, becomes a showgirl for a while (because of course), fights Nazis, and gets frozen in the ice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 23:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thor is an odd sort of movie for the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marvel%20Cinematic%20Universe">Marvel Cinematic Universe&lt;/a>. On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s our first foray into the more &amp;lsquo;magical&amp;rsquo; side of the universe, with ancient Gods and the like. Although in this universe, we&amp;rsquo;re led to believe that it&amp;rsquo;s really just highly advanced science. On the other hand, despite a worlds spanning plot (literally, 3 of them), it still feels oddly &amp;hellip; small.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s weird. We&amp;rsquo;re supposed to believe that Odin is over a thousand years old and Thor is&amp;hellip; just now coming into his kingship now? How long does it take for them to grow up? And Asgardians at some level can die in battle, but in others handle getting thrown around and hit by cars just fine? It&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip; a little weird. The idea of Thor being a spoiled young man and having to show his worthiness is a solid enough plot (and a common enough Thor origin story); although it all comes together a mite quickly for him. And then the final battle&amp;ndash;while it looks cool enough I guess, it&amp;rsquo;s all feels like they could have used a bit more time and money to fill things in a bit more.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>