<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>King of Scars on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/king-of-scars/</link><description>Recent content in King of Scars on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/king-of-scars/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rule of Wolves</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/27/rule-of-wolves/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/27/rule-of-wolves/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hate it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, not the book, I actually quite liked the book. It&amp;rsquo;s never an easy task to bring together as many different plotlines as you have when you&amp;rsquo;re the second book of the third series set in the same world&amp;ndash;and I think Bardugo did it well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, I hate that one particular death in this book. They did &lt;em>not&lt;/em> have to die.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which I suppose means that it worked? Except&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel like it changed anything, other than to annoy me, the reader. So it goes I suppose.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>King of Scars</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/20/king-of-scars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/20/king-of-scars/</guid><description>&lt;p>All good things must end, it seems. We had our fun with Kaz and crew in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/">Six of Crows&lt;/a>. And now we shift focus once again, back to Ravka.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In some ways, it&amp;rsquo;s a continuation of the storyline of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a>, following the new King Nikolai as he deals with securing his throne in a nation deeply in debt with enemies on all sides. Plus, we get a lot more Zoya (who I did &lt;em>not&lt;/em> expect to like as much as I did) and at least some more of Genya and David (I do love their relationship).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another fascinating aspect of that storyline is that we get to dig much more into the mystical/religious underpinnings of the world. Six of Crows never really went there, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely something that came up in Shadow and Bone. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to feel like you know how magic works in the world&amp;ndash;and then realizing that you know nothing after all&amp;hellip; (both as a reader and as the characters).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will warn though: this part got &lt;em>weird&lt;/em>. All sorts of new and interesting (or I suppose old and interesting) metaphysics and magic we hadn&amp;rsquo;t really dug into before. A bit jarring&amp;ndash;both for the reader and for the characters involved&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a completely different direction, we also have a main storyline with Nina from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/">Six of Crows&lt;/a> (of all the characters, hers isn&amp;rsquo;t the first story I would have chosen to continue, but it is interesting). She&amp;rsquo;s still messed up / something new and now she&amp;rsquo;s off to Fjerda to continue to try to save the world. Newcomer Hanna is a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid book. It&amp;rsquo;s weird how disjoint the two storylines are&amp;ndash;they don&amp;rsquo;t really interact at all, although I see how they&amp;rsquo;ll likely come together in [[todo:Rule of Wolves]]. I kept finding myself annoyed when we switch from one to another.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>