<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>jverkamp.com</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com" /><link rel="self" href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/feed/" /><updated>2015-09-28T00:00:00Z</updated><author><name>JP Verkamp</name></author><id>urn:uuid:8071e9d7-94ed-76dd-cdd5-35e8349c9958</id><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.7: The Market - Johanas</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/28/writing-excuses-10-7-the-market-johanas" /><id>urn:uuid:fceb73f0-c971-e42a-e3c8-a1413d6368e9</id><updated>2015-09-28T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/02/15/writing-excuses-10-7-who-are-all-these-people/">Writing Excuses 10.7</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Pick one of the dead-drop characters from the exercise two weeks ago, and turn them into a secondary character. Now take one of the characters with whom they interacted, and write the same scene again, but from this new character's POV.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>My master is not always the brightest of men.</p>
<p>Not in all regards, not in all things.</p>
<p>But he paid for my mother's transition, when there was no pressing need that he do such a thing. So far as I can tell, he didn't even know what he was paying for.</p>
<p>And for that, I shall be eternally grateful.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/02/15/writing-excuses-10-7-who-are-all-these-people/">Writing Excuses 10.7</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Pick one of the dead-drop characters from the exercise two weeks ago, and turn them into a secondary character. Now take one of the characters with whom they interacted, and write the same scene again, but from this new character's POV.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>My master is not always the brightest of men.</p>
<p>Not in all regards, not in all things.</p>
<p>But he paid for my mother's transition, when there was no pressing need that he do such a thing. So far as I can tell, he didn't even know what he was paying for.</p>
<p>And for that, I shall be eternally grateful.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>For that, I shall protect him from himself.</p>
<p>The package arrived as all do, the sigils of the Parcel's Guild marking the edges. Lord Bronwin did not even seem to recognize them. Granted, it is generally I who answers the door.</p>
<p>In this instance though, Lord Bronwin was walking to the stairs when the package was delivered and as such took an inordinate interest in its contents.</p>
<p>That alone should have been enough to warn me that something was awry. Not in the sense that I recognized the package for what it was--something more subtle. My mother had always said that I had a gift for seeing what truly was.</p>
<p>Yet still, I opened the package. I couldn't very well explain such a feeling to my master. Not without more to go on than just that.</p>
<p>Inside the package, there were three smaller packages and a note. Before I could stop him, Lord Bronwin had snatched the letter from the package and began to read.</p>
<p>My uneasy feeling was confirmed. I could see in his face that it was not good news. And from the sidelong look he spared me, I was involved.</p>
<p>Still, I well knew my place. If my master required it of me, I would do it. No matter the personal cost.</p>
<hr />
<p>Without telling me precisely why, my master bid me prepare his carriage to go to market. While it was common enough for me to go to market--especially on such days when other servants of the hour could not attend to such duties--Lord Bronwin had never, to my knowledge, gone.</p>
<p>Yet an order was an order, and without seeing the letter, I had no particular reason to believe that my master was in any danger whatsoever. So of course, I was going to have to take the letter.</p>
<hr />
<p>My opportunity came just as we were leaving.</p>
<p>In order to step up into the carriage, while still holding on to all three of the individual packages, Lord Bronwin needed both of his hands. Thus he had no room to hold the letter and handed it to me. With only the barest of moments to glance at its contents, I managed to catch only a section:</p>
<p><center> ... your indiscretions shall become common knowledge. Do not send Johanas. ... </center></p>
<p>Then, my master held his waiting hand back out the door, the expectance clear in his stance.</p>
<p>I handed it back, my brain whirling with activity.</p>
<p>I wasn't sure which bothered me more.</p>
<p>The reference to 'indiscretions' or my own name.</p>
<p>At least it explained why he was being particularly short with me.</p>
<p>I would just have to help him without knowing any more. Surely I could do that.</p>
<hr />
<p>At the edge of the market, my master signaled for me to stop the carriage. I made to go to the door to let him out--despite still thinking his plan mad--but he waved me off. Instead, he asked me to find the first two I could find willing to act as couriers. Curious.</p>
<p>It took some short time, but eventually I found a golem and a young boy on the street. The golem seemed to be off duty and more than happy enough to take my--and by extension, Lord Bronwin's--money. Of course, it was hard to read anything on the expressionless, voiceless face, but once a golem agreed to a job, they were incredibly reliable.</p>
<p>The young boy, he at least seemed enthusiastic. And what was more, he didn't seem to have much in the way of bargaining skill. Two silver pennies? A steal.</p>
<p>Then we were off again. It seemed that he wanted to hand deliver one of the three smaller packages. Again, it wasn't my place to question my master, but if he were going to hand deliver one of them himself, then why not deliver all three?</p>
<p>I was still contemplating said thought when a flash of movement just before me drew my attention.</p>
<p>I only had a moment to see a golem walking directly across my path before a terrible screech and the rearing of the metal beasts pulling the carriage required all of my attention.</p>
<p>The horses were strange that way. It wasn't that they were spooked; mechanical beasts as they were, they didn't get spooked. Rather they were trying to avoid damaging either themselves or the golem who had darted in front of them.</p>
<p>At least they succeeded in one.</p>
<p>I saw the golem's head pop off and roll an arm's length away. From what I knew about golems, that wasn't actually fatal--although what does fatal mean to something that is not alive?</p>
<p>I heard my master's voice call up from the carriage. "What's the trouble?"</p>
<p>I debated a second, but only a second. My primary duty was to him, not to these packages. There was a chance that the situation would devolve. The sooner his package was delivered, the sooner we could return to the safety of his mansion.</p>
<p>"Nothing, sir," I said, already directing the steeds to continue on their way.</p>
<hr />
<p>We dropped off the package my master had kept and he had me retreat a safe distance to watch the other two. Or at least, I assume the distance was such that he thought it safe. I wouldn't have minded a few blocks more.</p>
<p>The boy arrived first. He put the package down without even really paying terribly much attention to it. Instead, he was inspecting a metalic object. It took a moment for me to place it.</p>
<p>The golem's head.</p>
<p>I shook my own.</p>
<p>The kid was in for some trouble. The Golemancy Guild was one of the strongest organizations in the city and they didn't take kindly to anyone encroaching on their turf, even unintentionally. I thought to give the boy a bit of advice, but I was sure he wouldn't take it.</p>
<p>A few minutes later, just as I was about to ask Lord Bronwin what exactly he was waiting for, the golem trotted up as well. I admit, I was surprised to see it. It was one thing to know that a golem can lose a head with little to no ill effect; it was quite another to experience it first hand, as it were.</p>
<p>Still, that meant that we had all three packages. That meant we could head home.</p>
<p>We tarried only a moment longer before Lord Bronwin signaled me onward. He seemed to be debating something, although he wouldn't go so far as to tell me.</p>
<p>Halfway home, there was a sharp report. The sound of an explosion, followed closely by two more. I waited, letting the horses trod their inexorable way home, but that was it.</p>
<p>Three.</p>
<p>Three explosions.</p>
<p>Three packages.</p>
<p>It had to be a coincidence.</p>
<p>Didn't it?</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.6: Second Place</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/11/writing-excuses-10-6-second-place" /><id>urn:uuid:713987a1-c620-d6a1-d3fb-52a311aaf8d6</id><updated>2015-09-11T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/02/08/writing-excuses-10-6-the-worldbuilding-revolves-around-me-the-magical-1/">Writing Excuses 10.6</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Think about the last time you lost at a game. What was the process of thought that led to your loss? Now, replicate that moment in the dramatic structure of the story, except the story isn't about games.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>The almost. The not quite. The second place.</p>
<p>All words to describe a feeling. A state of mind. That of not quite making it, when you knew in your heart of hearts that you should.</p>
<p>And what makes it even worse: it <em>should</em> have been me.</p>
<p>I should have been the one to make the run.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/02/08/writing-excuses-10-6-the-worldbuilding-revolves-around-me-the-magical-1/">Writing Excuses 10.6</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Think about the last time you lost at a game. What was the process of thought that led to your loss? Now, replicate that moment in the dramatic structure of the story, except the story isn't about games.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>The almost. The not quite. The second place.</p>
<p>All words to describe a feeling. A state of mind. That of not quite making it, when you knew in your heart of hearts that you should.</p>
<p>And what makes it even worse: it <em>should</em> have been me.</p>
<p>I should have been the one to make the run.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>I should have been the pilot on that fateful trip, the one whose name all of history would remember. Instead, I'm doomed to be the backup, the understudy, the one who gets a footnote--if that.</p>
<p>I should have been the one to say those first words.</p>
<p>Let me tell you. They would have been a far sight better than, "Oh shit."</p>
<p>I'm not kidding. Those were his first words. The first spoken words ever relayed from the orbit of Pluto itself, taking a thousand times longer to return to Earth than the outbound trip had taken in the first place.</p>
<p>"Oh shit."</p>
<p>Don't get me wrong, I get it. After all, after a single trip, the Alcubierre had blown a fuse in the most spectacular way possible. The ring was shattered, very nearly taking the ship itself with it. Without a way home, it was going to be a long trip.</p>
<p>Marshall recovered well enough, acquitting himself well of his training. He went ahead and read the speech that the whole world would one day know had been prepared for him. He even made it sound off the cuff; like he was just making it up on the spot.</p>
<p>But when kids look back on this day, they won't remember the speech. With a half-hidden snicker  at the forbidden (that of course the teacher will see) they'll move on with their lives, forgetting what really mattered about the trip. Forgetting that Marshall opened the stars to them. Forgetting that I even existed at all. All they'll remember is those fateful words.</p>
<p>"Oh shit."</p>
<p>Now it's all up to me. I get to be the one to go to his rescue. The Atlas has been rushed into service, the final weeks' worth of checkups compressed into three days. The powers that be wanted it to be even faster, to prove that even in the face of such adversity we would <em>not</em> back down.</p>
<p>But the scientists and engineers that had built the Atlas put their collective foot down. Three days. Absolute minimum. Any less and they might as well be flying blind.</p>
<p>Truth be told, that would have been all right with me.</p>
<p>Better story that way.</p>
<p>No one remembers second place.</p>
<p>They say they've ironed out the kinks this time. One in a million, this time. One in a million chance that I'll make it out to Pluto and be stuck out there with Marshall. No hope for either us. Not only doomed to die a cold lonely death, but to be second place even then.</p>
<p>Nope, no sir, not going to happen.</p>
<p>I'm going to save the day.</p>
<hr />
<p>As the ion drives took me farther and farther from Lagrange Station, I was struck with a sudden sense of deja vu.</p>
<p>Everything I was doing was something I had already done before. The ion drives, the checklists, the charts. Making sure that the fusion generators were running to the edge of their capacity, charging the capacitors that would eventually feed the Alcubierre ring which made everything possible.</p>
<p>The feeling was so sudden and so strong; for a moment I lost where I was. Of course this mission would succeed, it already had. I didn't need to go and save Marshall, I already had. Everything would proceed as it always had proceeded.</p>
<p>Except if it didn't.</p>
<p>When the rational part of my mind caught up, I realized that I was remembering the hours upon hours that I had spent in the Atlas simulator. In virtual reality, the mission planners had thrown every possible situation they could think of at me--and some they didn't; the computers themselves had at times a sick sense of challenge.</p>
<p>I knew the mission like the back of my hand. Better even. Who actually knew the back of their hand that well anyway?</p>
<p>A blinking light on the control screen in front of me caught my attention. The ion drive had shut off after the preprogrammed interval. So wrapped up in my own thoughts; I hadn't even noticed. Nothing more than a stream of ionized particles, ion drives didn't light a candle to the chemical rockets of the olden days. Far more efficient of course, especially with the fusion generator to power them. But still, wouldn't it have been something to ride an explosion into the night?</p>
<p>Without the ion drive, I was drifting. Even drifting, I was traveling at what would have been a breakneck pace in an atmosphere. In the cold emptiness of space, there was no way to judge just how fast I was going.</p>
<p>And soon, I would be moving much, much faster.</p>
<hr />
<p>The general idea behind the Alcubierre is deceptively simple. Nothing can move faster than the speed of light. Einstein discovered that particular wrinkle centuries ago and it was as true now as it was then.</p>
<p>But there was a catch: nothing can move faster than the speed of light. But you don't have to.</p>
<p>Space itself would.</p>
<p>Short version: space is flexible. It can expand and contract, most often under the influence of gravitational fields. What's more, said expansions can move faster than the speed of light, seeing as, strictly speaking, nothing was moving.</p>
<p>I'll admit, the idea still seemed odd to me when I thought about it too carefully. But essentially, that was the idea. Using physics well beyond my own understanding, the Alcubierre drive created a wave in the fabric of space itself.</p>
<p>That was me. A cosmic surfer. The second human being in history to ride a space bubble to the edge of the solar system.</p>
<hr />
<p>I'm not sure why I imagined that the reality of the Alcubierre drive would be any different from the simulators.</p>
<p>Despite that fact that I was traveling just shy of a hundred times the speed of light, as far as I could tell I might as well have been standing still.</p>
<p>The moment the Alcubierre drive had engaged, the stars had gone out. It was a curious side effect of the Alcubierre field that light tends to slide along the sides of the field, colliding in a faint wake on the far side. I'm told it's for the best: even the light of a star can be blinding when you're colliding with a hundred times as many photons per second.</p>
<p>Still, it's disconcerting.</p>
<p>Now that the drive was engaged, I had only to wait.</p>
<p>162 seconds.</p>
<p>That's it.</p>
<p>5 billion kilometers, and I'd be there in less than three minutes.</p>
<p>Despite the fact that it should have been me out there and Marshall flying to <em>my</em> rescue, I had to admit... That was pretty cool.</p>
<hr />
<p>With fifteen seconds to go, I could feel my heart rate picking up. Based on Marshall's reports and what little long range telemetry mission control had received, this is when the Prometheus' Alcubierre ring had failed. When collapsing the wave and returning space to its normal configuration.</p>
<p>The engineers on the project claimed they had found the issue. An instability in the equations governing the turbulence of quantum foam stirred up by the collapse of an Alcubierre field. Or something like that. It was something that hadn't come up in years of automated testing, so the chances of it happening twice in a row were essentially nil.</p>
<p>At least that was what they said.</p>
<p>They also claimed that they'd tweaked the timing. Collapse the field a fraction of a second more slowly and the turbulence would be directed perpendicular to the ring, rather than directly into.</p>
<p>Personally, I thought that was something they should have thought of before sending the first ship. But what do I know?</p>
<p>Ten seconds. Was this it? Was this the moment when I became the second person in the history of the human race to set eyes directly on Pluto?</p>
<p>Nine.</p>
<p>Eight. A slight vibration echoed through my seat. Something that had never come up in the simulation.</p>
<p>Seven.</p>
<p>Six.</p>
<p>Five. The vibration was back, hard enough up and down that I could hear my own teeth rattling together.</p>
<p>Nothing I could do about it now. If I didn't shut down the Alcubierre drive, there was no telling where I would end up. Two weeks and I could be at Alpha Centauri--if that was the way I was facing.</p>
<p>I wish I'd thought to look that up before I left.</p>
<p>Four.</p>
<p>Three.</p>
<p>Two. I shut my eyes.</p>
<p>One.</p>
<hr />
<p>Gradually, I became aware of a sound.</p>
<p>My eyes were still squeezed shut. I found in that moment that I didn't want to know. I didn't want to know if I was to be the hero who rescued the first Alcubierre test pilot or only its second victim.</p>
<p>But there was a sound in my cockpit, a sound that I recognized.</p>
<p>"Carter? That you?"</p>
<p>Marshall. I'd talked to him less than a week ago, at his going away celebration. It was a bittersweet moment, knowing that--unless something went horribly wrong--he was going to be taking my spot in history. But I had to be happy for him. After all, if something <em>did</em> go horribly wrong, I couldn't be too happy about it. Too suspicious.</p>
<p>Slowly, I opened my eyes. Scanned the control screen.</p>
<p>A few numbers were on the high side, but all well within parameters.</p>
<p>I glanced out the viewports.</p>
<p>The Alcubierre ring. Solid. Unbroken.</p>
<p>I let out a breath I hadn't known I'd been holding.</p>
<p>"Ha," I cried out, "Take that, Einstein."</p>
<p>What can I say? At least it was better than 'oh shit.'</p>
<hr />
<p>It took the better part of six hours to match velocity with the Prometheus and link the two ships.</p>
<p>Marshall was going to have to abandon his ship. For the moment, only the Atlas would be going home. Theoretically, it would be possible to Alcubierre field to move both ships, even linked together as they were now. It wasn't like they were actually moving after all.</p>
<p>But that had been deemed too much a risk by the powers that be. 'Bring him home,' they'd said. There would be other missions. Prove that the technology works and the stars were quite literally the limit.</p>
<p>The ride home was cramped but uneventful. Both the Promethus and the Atlas were designed with a second seat just behind the pilot's for incidents exactly such as this--well, not exactly, but you get the drift. That doesn't mean it's particularly comfortable.</p>
<p>The same as the way back, it only took 160 seconds to return to Earth orbit. Of course, that was after six hours to link, another for the spacewalk, and two more on top of that for the Atlas' computer to calculate the proper trajectory home.</p>
<p>That's one of the problems with moving so fast--if you're off by even a little, you can easily end up thousands of millions from the middle of nowhere.</p>
<p>But we made it, and in the end, that's all that's important. We'd done it. We'd taken an unbreakable law of nature and gone right around it. The stars were open to us, to all of humanity.</p>
<p>And I was part of the story.</p>
<p>Second place.</p>
<p>But hey, I got to be the hero. Perhaps second place isn't so bad after all.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.5: The Market - Noble</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/07/writing-excuses-10-5-the-market-noble" /><id>urn:uuid:a1e87807-71e4-b2f4-9615-71dae2bc7c47</id><updated>2015-09-07T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/25/writing-excuses-10-4-qa-on-ideas/">Writing Excuses 10.5</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Take three different characters and walk them through a scene. Convey their emotional states, their jobs, and their hobbies without directly stating any of those. The scene in question: walking through a marketplace, and they need to do a dead-drop.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>The market is not a place in which I usually find myself.</p>
<p>It is noisy and rife with chaos, the throngs pressing into one another all along the way.</p>
<p>Yet today I find myself in unusual circumstances, descending into those very same masses.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/25/writing-excuses-10-4-qa-on-ideas/">Writing Excuses 10.5</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Take three different characters and walk them through a scene. Convey their emotional states, their jobs, and their hobbies without directly stating any of those. The scene in question: walking through a marketplace, and they need to do a dead-drop.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>The market is not a place in which I usually find myself.</p>
<p>It is noisy and rife with chaos, the throngs pressing into one another all along the way.</p>
<p>Yet today I find myself in unusual circumstances, descending into those very same masses.</p>
<!--more-->
<p><center>* * * * *</center></p>
<p>Night before last, I received a most unusual package, dropped upon my doorstop with nary so much as note or notice. Not even a courier, one whom I could ask from where the package originated.</p>
<p>It was a simple box, as white as new fallen snow, with a thin red line running around the summit of the sides. Neither a style nor material to which I was accustomed.</p>
<p>At my word, my manservant Johanas sliced the box across the top in a single smooth motion, lifting two thick flaps to either side so that I might gaze at the contents therein.</p>
<p>Imagine then my surprise, when inside of the box I found but three smaller packages, each in a more traditional brown wrapping paper, tied with a piece of twine and sealed with wax. Lying on top of the three of them, a piece of thick parchment, waxy to the touch.</p>
<p>Said letter contained only three lines, in a thin spidery hand I had never before seen:</p>
<p><em>Deliver to Temple of Acbris before sunfall, three days hence</em></p>
<p><em>Failure to comply and your indiscretions shall become common knowledge</em></p>
<p><em>Do not send Johanas. Go yourself.</em></p>
<p>It was unsigned, the only identifying mark a curving line, two figures inside of one another, like an arrow in flight.</p>
<p>Imagine, a Lord of the House of Sarane being treated in such a manner.</p>
<p>Yet the mysterious author of the note knew too much. Knowing that dear Johanas would be the one with me when I opened the package; Johanas, who I of course would have been inclined to dispatch in my stead.</p>
<p>And my ... indiscretions.</p>
<p>Yes. I of course would have to send the packages.</p>
<p>But one never said that I would have to carry all three.</p>
<p><center>* * * * *</center></p>
<p>For the first of the three, I hired a child of the street. I saw immediately from the look on his face that he would do his job and return. And all for a pair of silver marks. Pocket change.</p>
<p>The second, I handed to a golem. Dependable lot that. More expensive than the child, but dependable. The letter had been unclear on what would be the outcome were only one or two of the packages delivered.</p>
<p>The last, I took myself.</p>
<p>I had a carriage of course, pulled by a pair of mechanical steeds. Johanas drove, at my insistence. The letter had said that I must go myself, but who else might I trust to this endeavor?</p>
<p>There was only a momentary pause, halfway across the market. A crunching sound and a few quick screams. I called out to Johanas, asking what might be the matter, but he said only not to worry, that he would have me on my way in no time and all. And off we went, true to his word.</p>
<p>At the far end of the market, I for a moment considered handing Johanas the package to place at the foot of the pyre, rather than risking my own person. I had come this far; I would see it through.</p>
<p>And then it was done.</p>
<p>We parked the carriage off down the block, to allow Johanas a vantage point by which to observe the other two deliveries. He claims the boy made it first, placing his package without a second glance.</p>
<p>Then the golem, a few minutes later.</p>
<p>That surprised me somewhat, I must admit, that the young lad could outrun the steady determination of a golem. Johanas assured me though, that both packages were delivered in excellent form, joining my own.</p>
<p>And now I must hope only that the mysterious author of the letter too keeps his word. If not, well... Then perhaps I will ask Johanas to find them. Teach them precisely the meaning of the word indiscretion.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.5: The Market - Orphan</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/05/writing-excuses-10-5-the-market-orphan" /><id>urn:uuid:0e0e90f8-9cb6-aee2-441e-7f72586bd831</id><updated>2015-09-05T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/25/writing-excuses-10-4-qa-on-ideas/">Writing Excuses 10.5</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Take three different characters and walk them through a scene. Convey their emotional states, their jobs, and their hobbies without directly stating any of those. The scene in question: walking through a marketplace, and they need to do a dead-drop.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>The man that gave me the box wasn't a very good man. He was tall and skinny and he smelled. But he gave me a shiny silver penny and said that if I took this box to the other end of the market and came back, he could would give me another.</p>
<p>Two shiny silver pennies?</p>
<p>All for taking a stupid little box across the street.</p>
<p>The market is busy. Busy means pockets and pockets mean pennies and pennies mean dinner.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/25/writing-excuses-10-4-qa-on-ideas/">Writing Excuses 10.5</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Take three different characters and walk them through a scene. Convey their emotional states, their jobs, and their hobbies without directly stating any of those. The scene in question: walking through a marketplace, and they need to do a dead-drop.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>The man that gave me the box wasn't a very good man. He was tall and skinny and he smelled. But he gave me a shiny silver penny and said that if I took this box to the other end of the market and came back, he could would give me another.</p>
<p>Two shiny silver pennies?</p>
<p>All for taking a stupid little box across the street.</p>
<p>The market is busy. Busy means pockets and pockets mean pennies and pennies mean dinner.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>But if I don't hafta steal to get dinner, then that's okay too. People don't come after you if you don't steal so much.</p>
<p>No one looks at me. It's like they don't even see me, even though I'm the tallest of Talitha's crew. Well, except for Talitha herself. But she's old. 20 years at least, that's ancient.</p>
<p>Halfway across the square, there's a ruckus. One of those metal men has fallen down and lost his head.</p>
<p>I stop and laugh, but only for a moment.</p>
<p>It's not polite to laugh at stranger's misfortune. And you have to be polite not to get caught. Talitha says.</p>
<p>But it's funny. The metal men are everywhere now. Not like it used to be. Back when I was still small. Back then, the metal men were only in the rich parts of town.</p>
<p>The metal men are no fun. No pockets. No purses. No pennies.</p>
<p>The metal man isn't interesting though. He just lays there. He has a box too. It looks like my box. But the smelly man didn't say that there would be any other boxes.</p>
<p>Would would a metal man want with a penny anyway?</p>
<p>I start walking again. I really wanted to get the silver penny that the smelly man had already given me out of my pocket. There were things you could only do with the lighter silver pennies.</p>
<p>But then the other boys would see. They might come and take my penny away. Talitha wouldn't be happy then; she said that if I got beat up again, that was it. I was done.</p>
<p>I'm not sure what exactly I would be done with, but it didn't sound good.</p>
<p>I liked my job.</p>
<p>I started again, only to feel a sudden pain in my foot. I'd kicked something.</p>
<p>I looked down and jumped up, all at the same time.</p>
<p>The thing I kicked? It was the metal man's head.</p>
<p>How did that get over here?</p>
<p>It was staring at me with those gemstone eyes. They weren't right though. Normally those eyes never stop moving. The metal men don't have to eat, they don't have to sleep. They cut right into our pickpocketing they did when they started policing the market.</p>
<p>But this one didn't seem much interested in me. All laying there, a head without a body, it didn't seem to be reacting at all.</p>
<p>Was the metal man dead?</p>
<p>I never really thought about that. If they moved around and walked and talked, I guess that meant they were alive. And if they were alive, well then I guess this one could just possibly be dead.</p>
<p>So he won't be needing those eyes.</p>
<p>I took it.</p>
<p>The head I mean.</p>
<p>It was heavier than I expected.</p>
<p>It mean, it was metal, right? But it was heavier than my own head. And the metal men never seemed to mind. And it was shiny.</p>
<p>It wasn't too bad.</p>
<p>I could do this.</p>
<p>Luckily, no one seemed to notice that I'd taken it. In fact, they all seemed to be very careful not to notice anything that was going on.</p>
<p>People don't notice things they don't want to. Talitha always said that.</p>
<p>The rest of the way, there were other metal men. They weren't helping the one that broke. I guess the metal men are just like people after all.</p>
<p>There was a fire at the end of the market. I left the box by the fire.</p>
<p>There was another box, just like mine.</p>
<p>Two shiny silver pennies for them, two shiny silver pennies for me.</p>
<p>They don't have a shiny metal head though.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.5: The Market - Golem</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/writing-excuses-10-5-the-market-golem" /><id>urn:uuid:3e8d76d0-0798-0c9d-638f-9d5e81c17e7e</id><updated>2015-09-04T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn't last nearly as long as I'd hoped with the <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/category/writing/writing-excuses">Writing Excuses</a> prompts. Let's see if I can't catch up...</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/25/writing-excuses-10-4-qa-on-ideas/">Writing Excuses 10.5</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Take three different characters and walk them through a scene. Convey their emotional states, their jobs, and their hobbies without directly stating any of those. The scene in question: walking through a marketplace, and they need to do a dead-drop.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>There are certain advantages that come with being dead. When walking down the street, people tend to give you a wide berth.</p>
<p>People don't want to be reminded of their own mortality.</p>
<p>People don't want to be reminded that death is no longer the end.</p>
<p>My target was on the other end of the marketplace, on the front steps of the temple to Acbris, God of the Sun. Ironic, all things considered.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn't last nearly as long as I'd hoped with the <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/category/writing/writing-excuses">Writing Excuses</a> prompts. Let's see if I can't catch up...</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/25/writing-excuses-10-4-qa-on-ideas/">Writing Excuses 10.5</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Take three different characters and walk them through a scene. Convey their emotional states, their jobs, and their hobbies without directly stating any of those. The scene in question: walking through a marketplace, and they need to do a dead-drop.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>There are certain advantages that come with being dead. When walking down the street, people tend to give you a wide berth.</p>
<p>People don't want to be reminded of their own mortality.</p>
<p>People don't want to be reminded that death is no longer the end.</p>
<p>My target was on the other end of the marketplace, on the front steps of the temple to Acbris, God of the Sun. Ironic, all things considered.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>I was to take my package--a small thing, wrapped in brown paper--and leave it around the massive brazier that was never allowed to go out. To the casual observer, it would seem an offering like any other. Something to be tossed in by the temple priests whenever the fires began to dim even slightly.</p>
<p>At first, I had worried about that. If the package wasn't picked up in time, would it not be thrown into the flames? What good would that do anyone?</p>
<p>But it didn't matter. I was being paid handsomely for no more than a half hour's walk across the market place. The price was more than enough to account for the stares.</p>
<p>Lost in my thoughts, I had no time to respond when the cart came barreling out of an alleyway directly into my path. It was huge, pulled by a team of four mechanical horses, two by two, each snorting and steaming as they reared up in a vain attempt to slow themselves.</p>
<p>The horses smashed into me, the first two knocking me to the ground, and the next two crushing my steel chest. If I had still been alive, that would have killed me. But instead, it didn't even hurt. I could no longer feel pain. Finally, the cart hit me. I felt the impact, although if that was a true response or a memory of what I had once been, I couldn't say.</p>
<p>I saw my chest bending, a long dent running from side to side. I heard a scream of steel as it bent, further and further. Something had to give, and give it did. Unfortunately, the part that gave was my head.</p>
<p>There was a hiss of steam as my head popped off and went rolling across the street. A spray of tiny golden gears spilled out from my neck.</p>
<p>For several long moments, I just lay there.</p>
<p>It had been such a simple job. Just walk across the market and drop off the package. Now I couldn't even tell for sure where the package was, let alone finish the job.</p>
<p>I felt the crystal core, deep in my chest, just as it always was. A miracle of science and magic both, the crystalline structure was exactly how I was able to bind my spirit--all that was left of who I had once been--to the golem's body. I couldn't begin to explain how it worked.</p>
<p>While I lay there, trying to figure out what to do next, a small child walked up to me. In a single quick motion, he bent down and stole my head.</p>
<p>I couldn't believe it. When I first saw the little street rat, I felt bad for him. The city had a problem with orphans, everyone knew that. What circumstances had led him to a life on the street?</p>
<p>When he'd stopped, I sorely wished I still had the ability to speak. But that was one of the conditions of my resurrection. It wasn't that they <em>coudn't</em> give golems a voice--but rather that the guild didn't trust us not to tell anyone exactly what we were. Even with the Geas, they didn't trust us not to go back to our former families and spill their one great secret.</p>
<p>Then he reached down for my head and I thought I wouldn't have to. That he would do the right thing.</p>
<p><em>Just put it back in place,</em> I mentally ordered.</p>
<p>But the little jerk just took it and ran.</p>
<p>I lay there, dumbfounded, for what felt like ages.</p>
<p>I couldn't really blame him. Not really. He was probably starving. Living on the street. I'm sure he didn't have any family or probably even a home to go back to. It was one of the problems that had gotten significantly worse since The Baron had come to power. That and the armies of new golems being pressed into service. I was one of them.</p>
<p>A detail flashed into my mind. In the confusion of losing my head, I missed it at first.</p>
<p>The boy had been carrying a package.</p>
<p>One that looked an awful lot like my own.</p>
<p>I turned within my golem shell, trying to find my own package. It took a moment, but I found it, only a hair away from my outstretched hand.</p>
<p>Well, that was something at least.</p>
<p>With a mental sigh--I no longer possessed either the lungs or the mouth for anything more--I heaved myself to my feet, package in hand. It was an unusual feeling. My body felt off balance and one arm and leg were not quite working correctly. But I could get to my feet and that was enough. If I even hoped to be able to afford a new head, I needed to deliver that package.</p>
<p>One step.</p>
<p>Two.</p>
<p>My left leg was no longer bending at the knee and the right was rattling. When all was said and done, I was going to need more than just a new head.</p>
<p>Three.</p>
<p>Four.</p>
<p>The others in the square gave me an even wider burden. I was no longer merely a shade, but now a headless golem as well. Even if one understood in their mind that a golem did not need a head to function, it was still an unsettling sight.</p>
<p>Five.</p>
<p>Six.</p>
<p>I settled into the new rhythm. Right leg rattles, left leg drags. Right leg rattles...</p>
<p>Before I knew it, I was there.</p>
<p>The fires at the temple to Acbris. And lying just beside the fire, two identical packages to the one I held in one hand.</p>
<p>I watched them for a moment. Not only the boy, but a third courier as well? Someone really wanted this package delivered.</p>
<p>But that was not my concern.</p>
<p>I had done my job. Now I could return to my berth and salvage what I could of my arms and legs. With any luck, this one delivery wouldn't send me even further into debt.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.4: Interviews</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/02/13/writing-excuses-10-4-interviews" /><id>urn:uuid:30e45b30-ea4b-931e-07ba-d9b17029b7f0</id><updated>2015-02-13T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/25/writing-excuses-10-4-qa-on-ideas/">Writing Excuses 10.4: Q&A on Ideas</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Take one of the ideas you're excited about, and then audition five different characters for the lead role in that story. Make sure they're all different from each other.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>"So what brings you all of the way out here?"</p>
<p>The man on the other side of the table blinked. That was all the more reaction he showed, but it was more than I had seen since he'd entered the building.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/25/writing-excuses-10-4-qa-on-ideas/">Writing Excuses 10.4: Q&A on Ideas</a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Take one of the ideas you're excited about, and then audition five different characters for the lead role in that story. Make sure they're all different from each other.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>"So what brings you all of the way out here?"</p>
<p>The man on the other side of the table blinked. That was all the more reaction he showed, but it was more than I had seen since he'd entered the building.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>"The job?"</p>
<p>Mentally, I shook my head. Of course he'd come for the job. That wasn't the point. The entire thing was something of a test.</p>
<p>"It's a bit of a long way to go for work."</p>
<p>Based on his robe and rope belt, I had a sneaking suspicion that he was from some religious order or another. It seemed unlikely that he was looking for a new job, so there had to be something else there.</p>
<p>He just nodded.</p>
<p>Perhaps a different tack.</p>
<p>"You know what the job will entail?"</p>
<p>He nodded again.</p>
<p>I paused a moment, but when he remained silent I prompted, "care to elaborate?"</p>
<p>"I'm here to step through a hole in the end of the world."</p>
<p>It was an oddly poetic answer. But then again, if he actually were a man of the cloth it made some manner of sense. A lifetime devoted to the study of one holy text or another would do that to you.</p>
<p>The next was the most important question of the interview. Given the ... unique situation I found myself in...</p>
<p>"Why?"</p>
<p>He studied me for a long moment before answering. *Good* I thought. That was good.</p>
<p>"Because He is calling to me."</p>
<p>I swear I could hear the capital in his voice. Not entirely sure that I even wanted to know the answer, I asked the obvious question.</p>
<p>"Who?"</p>
<p>"He-Who-Waits" His eyes had grown wide and almost warm, although how such an adjective could be applied to one's eyes, I couldn't quite describe. "He-Who-Lives-Beyond"</p>
<p>"And this 'He-Who-Waits'," I asked, "what will you do if you find him?</p>
<p>A shake of his head and a smile was all the answer I got. No matter how I rephrased the question, he refused to answer.</p>
<p>If it had been up to me, that right there would have been enough to remove him from the pool of applicants, small as it was. Unfortunately though, for me as much as for them, it wasn't up to be.</p>
<p>And the powers that be had been very clear.</p>
<p>Madness was *not* to be considered a deal breaker.</p>
<hr />
<p>The second and third candidates for the position came in together, holding hands in fact.</p>
<p>The first woman was tall and thin, with a veritable name of unruly red hair drawing attention onwards and upwards. I could have sworn I saw twigs tangled throughout and--stranger yet--what appeared to be a potted tree sticking out of one over large pocket.</p>
<p>The second seemed as tied to get machines as the first was to nature. She walked with an odd gate, every second step taking longer than the one before, swinging outwards with a dull thump unlike a footfall had any right to sound.</p>
<p>They took their seats as one, not letting go of one another even as they did, instead scooting the chairs ever closer, just so they could reach without a strain.</p>
<p>"Hi!" the first woman exclaimed. I don't believe I've ever before or since heard a voice better matching the description of sunshine. "I'm Flora."</p>
<p>"Cogs." The other woman's reply wasn't rude, strictly speaking, just on the very edge of curt.</p>
<p>And those names...</p>
<p>Based on the nature of our work--and the position we were attempting to fill in particular--we had suggested, né required that applicants not use their real names. Names have power, and if there's one thing the Others don't need, it's more power over us mere mortals.</p>
<p>Still, they could at least have tried to make up slightly less unusual names.</p>
<p>* * * * *</p>
<p>"Why?" I asked. Despite their nom de choice, the two women were among the best candidates I'd had yet. Truth be told, given how far we were from even the fringes of civilization, it was a miracle that we had choices at all.</p>
<p>To my surprise, Cogs was the first to answer. Up until now, Flora had been taking point, with her friend only chiming in for the few questions with a more mechanical gent.</p>
<p>"They say the rules are different there. Machines don't work. Physics is less rigid. Navigation isn't always reliable."</p>
<p>I nodded to each point. That was often among the more difficult aspect for applicants to wrap their heads around. The rules we'd all grown up with just didn't work on the other side of the portal. To most, it was disorientating, sickening even. To some--like Cogs apparently--it was intriguing.</p>
<p>"And you?" I turned to Flora.</p>
<p>"Isn't it obvious?" Her voice was low, lilting. "I want to be the first to find Otherlife."</p>
<p>I blinked at her. It wasn't the first time I'd heard the idea--the monk had seemed to think there'd be life there at least. But thus far, the other side had been entirely sterile. The only life was what we brought with us, even if it did tend to go... strange, given enough time.</p>
<p>"And if you find it," I asked, "what then?" I was sure my employers wouldn't actually care about that particular question, but I was actually a little curious myself.</p>
<p>She waited a moment before answering, watching me closely. I had the feeling she was weighing me, judging me. As if I were the interviewee, rather than the other way around.</p>
<p>"We've already screwed up this world," she finally said with a nod. "I want to find a world where we can do better. I want to give life a chance."</p>
<p>That sounded like just the right sort of crazy to me. Ultimately it would be up to the powers that were to choose whether or not the lair of them were chosen. I thought they had a chance though.</p>
<hr />
<p>The final interview candidate looked a little bit off even as he walked through the door. It wasn't until he sat down and looked right at me that I could begin to figure out why though.</p>
<p>The first thing that jumped out at me was the eyes. Pale blue, so pale they were almost white. I hadn't seen anyone with eyes that color before. And the pupils. They weren't entirely... Round. Slightly oblong, although without another pair of eyes to compare too, I couldn't say for certain how different they were.</p>
<p>After a sufficiently long pause where I was sure he was beginning to wonder if perhaps he had somehow miraculously come to the wrong place, I finally greeted him. "Good morning."</p>
<p>He smiled.</p>
<p>That was when I got the second surprise--his teeth were ground each to a fine point, overlapping I'm a saw tooth pattern. And it wasn't just that, it couldn't be. To have been ground like that, they couldn't have started out at a normal human size. They had to have been several times that to begin with.</p>
<p>"Good morning," he intoned. Third surprise: his voice was unusually high, edging well into the range of an alto. And neither was a single harmonic, as voices tended towards, but rather a complex layering, a choir all in one.</p>
<p>What <em>was</em> this man?</p>
<p>* * * * *</p>
<p>"So tell me," I asked. "Why do you want the job?" Although the strangeness kept mounting, I still couldn't quite figure out what the man was. I had seen all manner of strange men and women in my travels, but nothing quite like this. It was almost like he didn't quite fit together.</p>
<p>The man answered almost immediately, that layered voice every bit as intriguing as the first I had heard it. I don't think I would ever tire of listening to him. "New parts."</p>
<p>I blinked.</p>
<p>"What?"</p>
<p>He smiled. It wasn't a jovial smile, but rather a predatory one. His eyes glinted, that pale blue catching the light.</p>
<p>He raised his hand, turning it slowly, watching it as he did.</p>
<p>It took me a moment, but eventually I noticed. Running along the back of each finger, right where the tendons would have been was a thin spoke of what looked like bone. I thought at first that he was wearing some sort of glove, but it moved too smoothly, pulling against the skin in too natural a way.</p>
<p>It was part of his hand.</p>
<p>The hand. They eyes. The legs.</p>
<p>This wasn't a single man, this was a patchwork. A mix of who knew how many different organisms.</p>
<p>That predatory glint in his eyes? For all I knew, they were actually a predator's eyes.</p>
<p>This was something I hadn't ever heard of before. Some sort of magic? Whether or not the powers in charge of the expedition wanted him, I was going to have to keep an eye on this one.</p>
<hr />
<p>Why do I want to go? Is that your question?</p>
<p>Well, everyone is looking for something. Be it an alien god or a new set of rules for reality, there's always something.</p>
<p>But me? I study people. That's the reason you hired me in the first place, isn't it? Because I can see how people think, and because it fascinates me to do so.</p>
<p>Well I really want to see what happens to long term explorers in this Otherspace. To date, we've only sent out small trips, a day or two at most.</p>
<p>Even in those, there were changes. Small neurosis, changes so slight you wouldn't even notice them if you weren't watching carefully.</p>
<p>Me, I've been watching carefully.</p>
<p>What will happen if you take a group through for weeks, even months at a time? I don't know. No one does. Well, except maybe He-Who-Waits. You'll have to take that up with the monk though.</p>
<p>But I do know one thing for certain.  I can't wait to find out.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.3: Watching the end of the world</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/02/02/writing-excuses-10-3-watching-the-end-of-the-world" /><id>urn:uuid:baeac256-9b0a-d85d-10c4-89bc5b5ba03b</id><updated>2015-02-02T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/20/writing-excuses-10-3-lovecraftian-horror/">Writing Excuses 10.3 </a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Take a character, and from that character's point of view, describe their reaction to something horrific and awful, but do so without describing the thing itself.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>The old man watched the world end. He knew that he should have been bothered by this, he knew that he should have cared. But he was two wars and uncountable battles beyond caring. When he had been a younger man, something such as this would have mattered, would have gotten a rise out of him. Heck, that was the reason he had gone to battle in the first place wasn't it? The first Great Incursion?</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/20/writing-excuses-10-3-lovecraftian-horror/">Writing Excuses 10.3 </a> writing prompt</strong>: <em>Take a character, and from that character's point of view, describe their reaction to something horrific and awful, but do so without describing the thing itself.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>The old man watched the world end. He knew that he should have been bothered by this, he knew that he should have cared. But he was two wars and uncountable battles beyond caring. When he had been a younger man, something such as this would have mattered, would have gotten a rise out of him. Heck, that was the reason he had gone to battle in the first place wasn't it? The first Great Incursion?</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Even then, the battles had been relatively clean. A thousand fighter jets no more than a swarm of gnats. Megatons of warheads dwarfed to pinpricks of light. A fight that lasted three days, claiming more than half the lives of the worlds most populous nations. But still. Clean. Clean fighting, clean deaths, clean annihilation. He had gone in knowing that there was nothing that he could do. Nothing that any of them could do. Yet he had gone.</p>
<p>And they had done it.</p>
<p>They had won.</p>
<p>The Second Incursion was worse.</p>
<p>Tiny, instead of huge; myriad rather than singular. Appearing in the shadows between two ears of corn, they ate and ate, gorging themselves on what humanity could ill afford to lose. It wasn't fighters and warheads this time, it was chemicals and flames.</p>
<p>Many claimed that they couldn't possibly be related to the First Incursion, they were far too different. The xenogeneticists put that particularly theory to rest, although there were few enough of those left when all was said and done. Few enough of any such lofty ideals in a world on the brink of starvation.</p>
<p>Now <em>it</em> was here. The mother of all things wrong in the universe and he couldn't even bring himself to care. The Third Incursion.</p>
<p>It wasn't clean like the First, nor all consuming like the Second.</p>
<p>Nothing like what he was seeing in front of him now, on a thousand channels, the individuals each with their fifteen minutes, fueled by an Internet just reborn.</p>
<p>Even when he felt the shuddering beneath his feet, the very plates that made up the world beneath him bowing to one far greater than they, he just couldn't bring himself to care.</p>
<hr />
<p>Not sure that I exactly got what the prompt was after, but I think it's close enough to the idea. Horror--especially cosmic horror in the ilk of Lovecraft--is a genre I particularly want to try, for exactly this reason.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.2: Combine and grow</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/21/writing-excuses-10-2-combine-and-grow" /><id>urn:uuid:653c5fed-d432-d0ff-6ca1-7cfbc988cb61</id><updated>2015-01-21T00:05:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[
Inspired by the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/11/writing-excuses-10-2-i-have-an-idea-what-do-i-do-now/">10.2: I Have an Idea; What Do I Do Now?</a>

<strong>Writing Prompt</strong>: Using @crosslink["Writing Excuses exercise: Five story ideas"]{last week's} five story ideas (or five new ones):

<ul>
    <li>Take two of them and combine them into one story</li>
    <li>Take one and change the genre underneath it</li>
    <li>Take one and change the ages and genders of everybody you had in mind for it</li>
    <li>Take the last one and have a character make the opposite choice</li>
</ul>

<!--more-->

<h2>Combine two</h2>

Honestly, this was the last one I decided, just taking the two story ideas that I didn't want to put into one of the other categories. So we'll take the time travel pileup and fae versus robots and combine them:

<em>In the future, war has erupted between the faery realm and advanced robots. In a last ditch effort to preserve themselves, the fae use their most ancient and dangerous magic: time travel. Fighting back, the robots capture several powerful fae and force them to time travel.</em>

<em>As the war grows worse, collisions begin to occur in time, ripples oscillating between the original timeline and the altered versions. As the ripples get worse, more and more time travellers are pulled in, further worsening the problem.</em>

<em>At the core of the worst pile up? Hitler. Why? He was fae. Or a robot. :)</em>

That actually meshed together surprisingly well. It would certainly be an interesting story.

<h2>Genre swap</h2>

For this one, let's take the idea of an outpost in otherspace, waiting far too long for gifts from home. Instead of science fiction / horror, let's make it fantasy / horror!

<em>The borders of reality are fragile. Among some of the most talented mages in the world, there exist those who can take the tears and widen them, opening gateways to other worlds.</em>

<em>This story takes place on the other side of a rift floating in the air, halfway up a cliff, far from the nearest city. Far from support and due to the dangers of crossing the twisting and bending edges of the portal, supplies from home are rare and expensive.</em>

<em>The main characters are a half dozen mages, originally sent by the king to explore and exploit the resources in this other world. But many of them have their own reasons to be there; wanting to study the other world and how the more flexible reality effects their own magic.</em>

I think it works. It's a bit different of a story, but it was already in the softer parts of science fiction anyways.

<h2>Age/gender swap</h2>

For this one, let's swap around the ages/genders in shadows and steam:

<em>In a steampunk world of steam powered clockwork gadgets (including robotlike automatons), death is not the end. What most people don't know, is that the robots are granted life via binding the soul of one recently departed into a 'tired mechanical heart'.</em>

<em>One character is an old man from the kitchens (think a traditional butler look), who dies in the first chapter and becomes one of these automatons, assigned as a frontier solider (a war is brewing with another empire who binds their souls into animals rather than automatons). Another is the very young daughter of the Mayor. When her pranks get out of hand, she gets sent away, apprenticed before the normal age to the Priesthood (the ones who bind the souls to the automatons).</em>

<em>In the end, it's up to the two of them to either save the day... or change their world.</em>

That one didn't actually change that much. It did make me realize that I assigned the genders because of an underlying bias towards women serving in the kitchens and men ruling cities, but I think this makes it even more interesting.

<h2>Opposite day</h2>

For this final one, I have to swap one character's choices. It's a little difficult, since I didn't write much out in the way of choices.

<em>93% of the energy from the sun is stored in the ocean (water has a particularly high <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/specific_heat capacity">specific heat capacity</a>). Far in the future, mankind has used this in order to make a generation ship: a city sealed in the center of a massive sphere of water, hurtling through space.</em>

<em>Over time, the world that was is forgotten and legends grow around operation of the ship. The main character is a young man is offered a position in the Priesthood (mixing <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/MachineWorship">machine worship</a> and <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/CargoCult">cargo cult</a>), but turns them down. When his room starts beeping (old server rooms repurposed), they come looking for him though. No one must know the secrets of the Priesthood.</em>

<em>Before all is said and done, the young man has a lot to learn about the world he thought he knew and about just what is out there in the deep, dark space between the stars.</em>

<hr />

Neat! That was actually a really interesting exercise. I may just have to actually use a couple of these one day.
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[
Inspired by the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/11/writing-excuses-10-2-i-have-an-idea-what-do-i-do-now/">10.2: I Have an Idea; What Do I Do Now?</a>

<strong>Writing Prompt</strong>: Using @crosslink["Writing Excuses exercise: Five story ideas"]{last week's} five story ideas (or five new ones):

<ul>
    <li>Take two of them and combine them into one story</li>
    <li>Take one and change the genre underneath it</li>
    <li>Take one and change the ages and genders of everybody you had in mind for it</li>
    <li>Take the last one and have a character make the opposite choice</li>
</ul>

<!--more-->

<h2>Combine two</h2>

Honestly, this was the last one I decided, just taking the two story ideas that I didn't want to put into one of the other categories. So we'll take the time travel pileup and fae versus robots and combine them:

<em>In the future, war has erupted between the faery realm and advanced robots. In a last ditch effort to preserve themselves, the fae use their most ancient and dangerous magic: time travel. Fighting back, the robots capture several powerful fae and force them to time travel.</em>

<em>As the war grows worse, collisions begin to occur in time, ripples oscillating between the original timeline and the altered versions. As the ripples get worse, more and more time travellers are pulled in, further worsening the problem.</em>

<em>At the core of the worst pile up? Hitler. Why? He was fae. Or a robot. :)</em>

That actually meshed together surprisingly well. It would certainly be an interesting story.

<h2>Genre swap</h2>

For this one, let's take the idea of an outpost in otherspace, waiting far too long for gifts from home. Instead of science fiction / horror, let's make it fantasy / horror!

<em>The borders of reality are fragile. Among some of the most talented mages in the world, there exist those who can take the tears and widen them, opening gateways to other worlds.</em>

<em>This story takes place on the other side of a rift floating in the air, halfway up a cliff, far from the nearest city. Far from support and due to the dangers of crossing the twisting and bending edges of the portal, supplies from home are rare and expensive.</em>

<em>The main characters are a half dozen mages, originally sent by the king to explore and exploit the resources in this other world. But many of them have their own reasons to be there; wanting to study the other world and how the more flexible reality effects their own magic.</em>

I think it works. It's a bit different of a story, but it was already in the softer parts of science fiction anyways.

<h2>Age/gender swap</h2>

For this one, let's swap around the ages/genders in shadows and steam:

<em>In a steampunk world of steam powered clockwork gadgets (including robotlike automatons), death is not the end. What most people don't know, is that the robots are granted life via binding the soul of one recently departed into a 'tired mechanical heart'.</em>

<em>One character is an old man from the kitchens (think a traditional butler look), who dies in the first chapter and becomes one of these automatons, assigned as a frontier solider (a war is brewing with another empire who binds their souls into animals rather than automatons). Another is the very young daughter of the Mayor. When her pranks get out of hand, she gets sent away, apprenticed before the normal age to the Priesthood (the ones who bind the souls to the automatons).</em>

<em>In the end, it's up to the two of them to either save the day... or change their world.</em>

That one didn't actually change that much. It did make me realize that I assigned the genders because of an underlying bias towards women serving in the kitchens and men ruling cities, but I think this makes it even more interesting.

<h2>Opposite day</h2>

For this final one, I have to swap one character's choices. It's a little difficult, since I didn't write much out in the way of choices.

<em>93% of the energy from the sun is stored in the ocean (water has a particularly high <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/specific_heat capacity">specific heat capacity</a>). Far in the future, mankind has used this in order to make a generation ship: a city sealed in the center of a massive sphere of water, hurtling through space.</em>

<em>Over time, the world that was is forgotten and legends grow around operation of the ship. The main character is a young man is offered a position in the Priesthood (mixing <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/MachineWorship">machine worship</a> and <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/CargoCult">cargo cult</a>), but turns them down. When his room starts beeping (old server rooms repurposed), they come looking for him though. No one must know the secrets of the Priesthood.</em>

<em>Before all is said and done, the young man has a lot to learn about the world he thought he knew and about just what is out there in the deep, dark space between the stars.</em>

<hr />

Neat! That was actually a really interesting exercise. I may just have to actually use a couple of these one day.
]]></content></entry><entry><title>Writing Excuses 10.1: Five story ideas</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/14/writing-excuses-10-1-five-story-ideas" /><id>urn:uuid:4f0c7083-c3b9-ae08-7346-06a3ad42ea4c</id><updated>2015-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/04/writing-excuses-10-1-seriously-where-do-you-get-your-ideas/">10.1: Seriously, Where Do You Get Your Ideas?</a></p>
<p><strong>Writing Prompt</strong>: Write down five different story ideas in 150 words or less. Generate these ideas from these five sources.</p>
<ul>
    <li>From an interview or conversation you've had</li>
    <li>From research you've done (reading science news, military history, etc)</li>
    <li>From observation (go for a walk!)</li>
    <li>From a piece of media (watch a movie)</li>
    <li>From a piece of music (with or without lyrics)</li>
</ul>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/04/writing-excuses-10-1-seriously-where-do-you-get-your-ideas/">10.1: Seriously, Where Do You Get Your Ideas?</a></p>
<p><strong>Writing Prompt</strong>: Write down five different story ideas in 150 words or less. Generate these ideas from these five sources.</p>
<ul>
    <li>From an interview or conversation you've had</li>
    <li>From research you've done (reading science news, military history, etc)</li>
    <li>From observation (go for a walk!)</li>
    <li>From a piece of media (watch a movie)</li>
    <li>From a piece of music (with or without lyrics)</li>
</ul>
<!--more-->
<h2>Interview/Conversation</h2>
<p>Humanity has discovered how to find tiny rifts in space, tears in the fabric of reality that can be widened and use to cross from our world into a world with much stranger (and perhaps more mutable) rules. The story takes place on a research station just on the other side of one of these rifts.</p>
<p>Because of the location of the tear in realspace (far out on the edges of the solar system for political reasons) and the danger of the rip (the edges are two dimension, thus sharp), supplies from back home are rare. Throughout the course of the story, stranger and more horrifying things keep happening, making the characters wish more and more for something <em>normal</em>.</p>
<p>All of the characters are Jacks/Jills of All Trades, but specifically scientists. They can't stand that even the basest laws of otherspace aren't so immutable.</p>
<p>Inspiration: <a href="http://space.io9.com/astronauts-get-belated-christmas-presents-mustard-and-1679156026">Astronauts Get Belated Christmas Presents, Mustard, and Clean Undies (io9)</a></p>
<h2>Research</h2>
<p>93% of the energy from the sun is stored in the ocean (water has a particularly high <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/specific_heat capacity">specific heat capacity</a>). Far in the future, mankind has used this in order to make a generation ship: a city sealed in the center of a massive sphere of water, hurtling through space.</p>
<p>Over time, the world that was is forgotten and legends grow around operation of the ship. The main character is a young man being inducted into the Priesthood (mixing <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/MachineWorship">machine worship</a> and <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/CargoCult">cargo cult</a>), but one day the terminal in his bunk (repurposed computer rooms) begins to glow. The ocean is warming, wrecking havoc with the life therein.</p>
<p>Before all is said and done, the young man has a lot to learn about the world he thought he knew and about just what is out there in the deep, dark space between the stars.</p>
<p>Inspiration: <a href="http://www.thenakedscientists.com/HTML/content/interviews/interview/1001076/">Project ARGO - monitoring Earth's oceans (Naked Scientists)</a></p>
<p>Side note: that would be a much better story for the title <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/category/writing/novels/a-sea-of-stars">A Sea of Stars</a>. I may have to repurpose it. <img alt="smile" class="emoji" src="/emoji/smile.svg" /></p>
<h2>Observation</h2>
<p>In the future, time travel is real and common. It's entirely possible to jump back or forward in time, with paradoxes tending to just sort themselves out, as if the universe itself is trying to heal.</p>
<p>The central concept of the story is the idea of a time crash, where two time travelers come directly into conflict and the resulting collision sends out ripples in time and space, with history and reality waving between the original and the two colliding realities. Specifically, there is a time crash pile up, with more and more time travelers arriving, only to be caught in the growing storm.</p>
<p>When? World War II. Why? Hitler.</p>
<p>It's up to the main character: a middle aged, not at all special time cop to untangle the timelines, rescuing some, arresting others, and eventually stumbling on the dark secret at the core of it all: Hitler was a time traveler.</p>
<p>Inspiration:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/qtT_OHIY4jE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/vo4YABHEzuU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>Media</h2>
<p>Just beneath the surface of our world, supernatural beings wage war. Not <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MqT-e44kIM8">werewolves and vampires</a>, nor <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pxOSPfUw3qw">gargoyles and demons</a>. Let's go with the fae and robots (alternatively AIs in general). I'm not sure there are too many books out there mixing those two... <img alt="smile" class="emoji" src="/emoji/smile.svg" /></p>
<p>The main characters will be a young changeling woman rebelling against her family (iron piercings!) and a robot working at a robot factory that fall in love (because of course they do), somewhat mirroring the whole <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romeo_and Juliet">Romeo and Juliet</a> thing.</p>
<p>Also, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skynet(Terminator)">Skynet</a>. <img alt="smile" class="emoji" src="/emoji/smile.svg" /></p>
<p>Inspiration:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/pxOSPfUw3qw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/MqT-e44kIM8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>Music</h2>
<p>In a steampunk world of steam powered clockwork gadgets, death is not the end. The most complicated and powerful of the machines are the automaton, essentially humanoid robots. But what most people don't know, is that it's not technology that grants such machines life, it's magic binding the soul of one recently departed into a 'tired mechanical heart'.</p>
<p>One character is a serving girl from the kitchens, who dies in the first chapter (<em>le twist</em>) and becomes one of these automatons, assigned as a frontier solider (a war is brewing with another empire who binds their souls into animals rather than automatons). Another is the son of the Mayer. When his pranks get out of hand, he gets sent away, apprenticed to the Priesthood (the ones who bind the souls to the automatons).</p>
<p>In the end, it's up to the two of them to either save the day... or change their world.</p>
<p>Inspiration:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/49tpIMDy9BE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Specifically:</p>
<blockquote>Tired mechanical heart<br />
<p>Beats 'til the song disappears<br /> ...<br /> If only the clockwork could speak<br /> I wouldn't be so alone</blockquote></p>
<p>Side note: This is actually the world of two of my previous incomplete novels: Shadows and Steam (NaNoWriMo 2011) and the City on the Lake (<a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/03/06/my-personal-nanowrimo-march-madness">March Madness NaNoWriMo</a>). I really want to write in this world, I just haven't <em>quite</em> managed it.</p>
<hr />
<p>Amusing. I didn't expect to go so heavily into the science fiction. I think that I've subconsciously (or not) been thinking about how much I enjoy science fiction, while at the same time, I've been writing far more fantasy. Perhaps this will be the push I need to remedy that...</p>
<p>Also, if any of these ideas strike your fancy, feel free to steal them. Ideas want to be free and all of that. All I ask is that if you use one of them, let me know. I'd love to see it.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>NaNoWriMo 2014 Winner!</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner" /><id>urn:uuid:7f3cf84a-23c9-507d-b94e-0a28ebc04ae7</id><updated>2014-11-30T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Winner-NaNoWriMo.jpg" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Winner-NaNoWriMo.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Just under the wire this year.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Winner-NaNoWriMo.jpg" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Winner-NaNoWriMo.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Just under the wire this year.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>It took a bit to get going, given that I basically restarted on Day 7:</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Progress-NaNoWriMo.png" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Progress-NaNoWriMo.png" /></a></p>
<p>Basically, I wrote 3000 words each of the first three days and then settled in for 2000 words a day after that. I had one day where I just couldn't make it past 1000. So it goes.</p>
<p>As far as overall progress goes, I'm most of the way through chapter 10 of a planned 19 (there's something to be said for outlining ahead of time after all...), so I should be done around Christmas.</p>
<p>Onwards and upwards!</p>]]></content></entry></feed>