<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>jverkamp.com</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com" /><link rel="self" href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/feed/" /><updated>2015-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated><author><name>JP Verkamp</name></author><id>urn:uuid:8071e9d7-94ed-76dd-cdd5-35e8349c9958</id><entry><title>Writing Excuses exercise: Five story ideas</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/01/14/writing-excuses-exercise-five-story-ideas" /><id>urn:uuid:794c9e5c-9593-20b8-bf6b-31bfaace5985</id><updated>2015-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/04/writing-excuses-10-1-seriously-where-do-you-get-your-ideas/">10.1: Seriously, Where Do You Get Your Ideas?</a></p>
<p><strong>Writing Prompt</strong>: Write down five different story ideas in 150 words or less. Generate these ideas from these five sources.</p>
<ul>
    <li>From an interview or conversation you've had</li>
    <li>From research you've done (reading science news, military history, etc)</li>
    <li>From observation (go for a walk!)</li>
    <li>From a piece of media (watch a movie)</li>
    <li>From a piece of music (with or without lyrics)</li>
</ul>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by the <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/">Writing Excuses</a> podcast <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2015/01/04/writing-excuses-10-1-seriously-where-do-you-get-your-ideas/">10.1: Seriously, Where Do You Get Your Ideas?</a></p>
<p><strong>Writing Prompt</strong>: Write down five different story ideas in 150 words or less. Generate these ideas from these five sources.</p>
<ul>
    <li>From an interview or conversation you've had</li>
    <li>From research you've done (reading science news, military history, etc)</li>
    <li>From observation (go for a walk!)</li>
    <li>From a piece of media (watch a movie)</li>
    <li>From a piece of music (with or without lyrics)</li>
</ul>
<!--more-->
<h2>Interview/Conversation</h2>
<p>Humanity has discovered how to find tiny rifts in space, tears in the fabric of reality that can be widened and use to cross from our world into a world with much stranger (and perhaps more mutable) rules. The story takes place on a research station just on the other side of one of these rifts.</p>
<p>Because of the location of the tear in realspace (far out on the edges of the solar system for political reasons) and the danger of the rip (the edges are two dimension, thus sharp), supplies from back home are rare. Throughout the course of the story, stranger and more horrifying things keep happening, making the characters wish more and more for something <em>normal</em>.</p>
<p>All of the characters are Jacks/Jills of All Trades, but specifically scientists. They can't stand that even the basest laws of otherspace aren't so immutable.</p>
<p>Inspiration: <a href="http://space.io9.com/astronauts-get-belated-christmas-presents-mustard-and-1679156026">Astronauts Get Belated Christmas Presents, Mustard, and Clean Undies (io9)</a></p>
<h2>Research</h2>
<p>93% of the energy from the sun is stored in the ocean (water has a particularly high <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/specific_heat capacity">specific heat capacity</a>). Far in the future, mankind has used this in order to make a generation ship: a city sealed in the center of a massive sphere of water, hurtling through space.</p>
<p>Over time, the world that was is forgotten and legends grow around operation of the ship. The main character is a young man being inducted into the Priesthood (mixing <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/MachineWorship">machine worship</a> and <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/CargoCult">cargo cult</a>), but one day the terminal in his bunk (repurposed computer rooms) begins to glow. The ocean is warming, wrecking havoc with the life therein.</p>
<p>Before all is said and done, the young man has a lot to learn about the world he thought he knew and about just what is out there in the deep, dark space between the stars.</p>
<p>Inspiration: <a href="http://www.thenakedscientists.com/HTML/content/interviews/interview/1001076/">Project ARGO - monitoring Earth's oceans (Naked Scientists)</a></p>
<p>Side note: that would be a much better story for the title <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/category/writing/novels/a-sea-of-stars">A Sea of Stars</a>. I may have to repurpose it. <img alt="smile" class="emoji" src="/emoji/smile.svg" /></p>
<h2>Observation</h2>
<p>In the future, time travel is real and common. It's entirely possible to jump back or forward in time, with paradoxes tending to just sort themselves out, as if the universe itself is trying to heal.</p>
<p>The central concept of the story is the idea of a time crash, where two time travelers come directly into conflict and the resulting collision sends out ripples in time and space, with history and reality waving between the original and the two colliding realities. Specifically, there is a time crash pile up, with more and more time travelers arriving, only to be caught in the growing storm.</p>
<p>When? World War II. Why? Hitler.</p>
<p>It's up to the main character: a middle aged, not at all special time cop to untangle the timelines, rescuing some, arresting others, and eventually stumbling on the dark secret at the core of it all: Hitler was a time traveler.</p>
<p>Inspiration:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/qtT_OHIY4jE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/vo4YABHEzuU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>Media</h2>
<p>Just beneath the surface of our world, supernatural beings wage war. Not <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MqT-e44kIM8">werewolves and vampires</a>, nor <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pxOSPfUw3qw">gargoyles and demons</a>. Let's go with the fae and robots (alternatively AIs in general). I'm not sure there are too many books out there mixing those two... <img alt="smile" class="emoji" src="/emoji/smile.svg" /></p>
<p>The main characters will be a young changeling woman rebelling against her family (iron piercings!) and a robot working at a robot factory that fall in love (because of course they do), somewhat mirroring the whole <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Romeo_and Juliet">Romeo and Juliet</a> thing.</p>
<p>Also, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skynet(Terminator)">Skynet</a>. <img alt="smile" class="emoji" src="/emoji/smile.svg" /></p>
<p>Inspiration:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/pxOSPfUw3qw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/MqT-e44kIM8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2>Music</h2>
<p>In a steampunk world of steam powered clockwork gadgets, death is not the end. The most complicated and powerful of the machines are the automaton, essentially humanoid robots. But what most people don't know, is that it's not technology that grants such machines life, it's magic binding the soul of one recently departed into a 'tired mechanical heart'.</p>
<p>One character is a serving girl from the kitchens, who dies in the first chapter (<em>le twist</em>) and becomes one of these automatons, assigned as a frontier solider (a war is brewing with another empire who binds their souls into animals rather than automatons). Another is the son of the Mayer. When his pranks get out of hand, he gets sent away, apprenticed to the Priesthood (the ones who bind the souls to the automatons).</p>
<p>In the end, it's up to the two of them to either save the day... or change their world.</p>
<p>Inspiration:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/49tpIMDy9BE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Specifically:</p>
<blockquote>Tired mechanical heart<br />
<p>Beats 'til the song disappears<br /> ...<br /> If only the clockwork could speak<br /> I wouldn't be so alone</blockquote></p>
<p>Side note: This is actually the world of two of my previous incomplete novels: Shadows and Steam (NaNoWriMo 2011) and the City on the Lake (<a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/03/06/my-personal-nanowrimo-march-madness">March Madness NaNoWriMo</a>). I really want to write in this world, I just haven't <em>quite</em> managed it.</p>
<hr />
<p>Amusing. I didn't expect to go so heavily into the science fiction. I think that I've subconsciously (or not) been thinking about how much I enjoy science fiction, while at the same time, I've been writing far more fantasy. Perhaps this will be the push I need to remedy that...</p>
<p>Also, if any of these ideas strike your fancy, feel free to steal them. Ideas want to be free and all of that. All I ask is that if you use one of them, let me know. I'd love to see it.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>NaNoWriMo 2014 Winner!</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner" /><id>urn:uuid:7f3cf84a-23c9-507d-b94e-0a28ebc04ae7</id><updated>2014-11-30T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Winner-NaNoWriMo.jpg" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Winner-NaNoWriMo.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Just under the wire this year.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Winner-NaNoWriMo.jpg" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Winner-NaNoWriMo.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Just under the wire this year.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>It took a bit to get going, given that I basically restarted on Day 7:</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Progress-NaNoWriMo.png" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/30/nanowrimo-2014-winner/2014-Progress-NaNoWriMo.png" /></a></p>
<p>Basically, I wrote 3000 words each of the first three days and then settled in for 2000 words a day after that. I had one day where I just couldn't make it past 1000. So it goes.</p>
<p>As far as overall progress goes, I'm most of the way through chapter 10 of a planned 19 (there's something to be said for outlining ahead of time after all...), so I should be done around Christmas.</p>
<p>Onwards and upwards!</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>NaNoWriMo 2014 Update</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/12/nanowrimo-2014-update" /><id>urn:uuid:1c4e4885-4961-9116-19f0-d6c782dc7170</id><updated>2014-11-12T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>They say a picture is worth a thousand words<span class="footnote"><sup><a href="#footnote-1">[1]</a></sup></span>:</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/12/nanowrimo-2014-update/nano.png" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/12/nanowrimo-2014-update/nano.png" /></a></p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>They say a picture is worth a thousand words<span class="footnote"><sup><a href="#footnote-1">[1]</a></sup></span>:</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/12/nanowrimo-2014-update/nano.png" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/12/nanowrimo-2014-update/nano.png" /></a></p>
<!--more-->
<p>Yup, you're reading that right. Five days in and I decided to start over. Not only am I trying to write an entire novel<span class="footnote"><sup><a href="#footnote-2">[2]</a></sup></span> in a month, now I'm trying to do it in 23 days.</p>
<p>Basically, I got a few days in and realized that I was writing the same story I've written before. It had the same core of a story I wrote for The Gates of Heaven (not posted), the core as <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/category/writing/novels/confession">Confession</a>, the same as <a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/category/writing/novels/computational-demonology">Computational Demonology</a>. In all three cases, the main character discovers the supernatural world and becomes a part of it.</p>
<p>Now don't get me wrong. I love that sort of story<span class="footnote"><sup><a href="#footnote-3">[3]</a></sup></span>. But I wanted to try something different. So I tossed out what I'd written, rebuilt the characters to fit the new world, and outlined a new story.</p>
<p><em>*le gasp*</em></p>
<p>Yes, I actually outlined a story. I don't know if I've mentioned it (I'm sure I have), but I'm generally a pants'er. As in fly-by-the-seat-of... But hey, let's try something new.</p>
<p><a href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/12/nanowrimo-2014-update/outline.png" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/12/nanowrimo-2014-update/outline.png" /></a></p>
<p>We have: target word counts, structural arcs, chapter titles (still making these up as I go), locations, times, characters, summaries, and effects. So far, it's actually going pretty well. I'm not great at estimating what is large enough to make a chapter. Live and learn.</p>
<p>At this point, I don't think I'm going to post the story while I'm writing it. If you'd like to read it though, post a comment or <a href="mailto:me@jverkamp.com">email me</a>. I'd love to have <del>beta</del> alpha readers and I can add you to the Google Doc.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>NaNoWriMo 2014</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/11/04/nanowrimo-2014" /><id>urn:uuid:15725cb2-faf4-5f17-7929-11afd884acc7</id><updated>2014-11-04T00:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yup. Even with a new baby around, I'm mad enough to do it.</p>
<p><a href="http://nanowrimo.org/widget/MyMonth/jpverkamp.png" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://nanowrimo.org/widget/MyMonth/jpverkamp.png" /></a></p>
<p>So far I've been keeping up 2000 words per day, but I'm already starting to feel a drag. It just feels like the same sort of story I've written before... We'll see in the next day or two if I try to reboot or just go with it.</p>
<p>I haven't yet decided if I'm going to publish them online this year. It's good motivation and I know at least a few of you out there read it. We'll see. If I do, it won't be daily, but rather after finishing each chapter. So every 2-4 days?</p>
<p>Wish me luck!</p>]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yup. Even with a new baby around, I'm mad enough to do it.</p>
<p><a href="http://nanowrimo.org/widget/MyMonth/jpverkamp.png" data-toggle="lightbox"><img src="http://nanowrimo.org/widget/MyMonth/jpverkamp.png" /></a></p>
<p>So far I've been keeping up 2000 words per day, but I'm already starting to feel a drag. It just feels like the same sort of story I've written before... We'll see in the next day or two if I try to reboot or just go with it.</p>
<p>I haven't yet decided if I'm going to publish them online this year. It's good motivation and I know at least a few of you out there read it. We'll see. If I do, it won't be daily, but rather after finishing each chapter. So every 2-4 days?</p>
<p>Wish me luck!</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Chapter 20 -- The Morning After</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/11/chapter-20-the-morning-after" /><id>urn:uuid:dea149bf-2ddc-828b-841b-179e13a68e3a</id><updated>2014-01-11T14:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Maxwell came to visit Andi in the hospital. </p>
<p>Her and Jenny had been given a shared room. The hospital had plenty of rooms and both of the women luckily had insurance that would have even covered a private room, but neither of them wanted it.</p>
<p>They had just been through too much in the past few weeks to want to be alone. Andi still had that feeling running up and down her spine that Percy couldn't possibly be dead--well, dead again if her suspicions were correct--and that he'd just come after them yet again.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Maxwell came to visit Andi in the hospital. </p>
<p>Her and Jenny had been given a shared room. The hospital had plenty of rooms and both of the women luckily had insurance that would have even covered a private room, but neither of them wanted it.</p>
<p>They had just been through too much in the past few weeks to want to be alone. Andi still had that feeling running up and down her spine that Percy couldn't possibly be dead--well, dead again if her suspicions were correct--and that he'd just come after them yet again.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Although, if he did the both of them were in trouble. Neither one of them could fight. Jenny was actually doing better. Despite having lost rather a lot of blood from the misplaced gunshot, that was fixable easy enough with a few points of O negative.</p>
<p>Andi, on the other hand, needed skin grafts on both of her palms. The doctors couldn't quite decide how she'd done it, the texture of the burn was unlike anything they'd ever seen before. It looked almost as if she'd grabbed onto a live electrical wire and held on fore dear life--but an electrical wire textured like cloth.</p>
<p>Still, after two rounds of surgeries and some lovely pain medication, the general consensus was that she was going to be just fine. All she needed was a few more weeks rest.</p>
<p>Maxwell stood silently at the foot of Andi's bed for several long minutes. After watching time tick by excruciatingly slowly while fighting for her life, waiting patiently just wasn't as hard as it used to be. Finally, he said, "I just wanted to come by and say thank you."</p>
<p>Andi smiled slightly. As if he didn't know that if things had gone differently, he could have been the one that had put them here himself. "You're welcome. For what?"</p>
<p>He shared her smile. He still seemed a bit strange at times and oddly formal, but he was beginning to warm to her it seemed. "For saving my sister."</p>
<p><em>Ah.</em> She hadn't even remembered that. Jenny had said something about her being locked into some sort of sleep that she couldn't wake her from. That had been when she'd taken the shotgun.</p>
<p>"She's fine now. With the help of your book, I managed to figure out exactly what Percy had done to her. I still don't know why he didn't just kill her out right." </p>
<p>Andi froze. He had the book? Had she been wrong all along. </p>
<p>He must have noticed her distress however, for he put a hand up and said, "Don't worry, it's still back in your apartment right where you left it. I hope you don't mind?"</p>
<p>Andi slowly shook her head. Of corse she minded. You didn't just break into someone's house like that, even if it was for an ostensibly good reason. But on the flip side, he had basically saved her life when he gave her that sword. </p>
<p>"I don't think your cat likes me much. I fed him anyways."</p>
<p>Andi smiled at that. Good judge of character, cats. At one point during the past few days,  she'd finally figured out why that infernal cat had acted so strangely when she'd first brought the book home. Cats, as a general rule, could sense demons. They could tell that something not quite natural was invading their space. The book, being a demon, just rubbed her the wrong way. That was likely what had set her off against Maxwell, for that matter. The number of demons the man wore... But if he didn't already know it, she wasn't about to tell him.</p>
<p>Plus, he had fed her. That probably helped to sooth matters somewhat.</p>
<p>After that, neither of them really had much to say. He'd said his part and she still didn't entirely trust him. It wasn't anymore that she thought he was a rogue sorcerer forever on the edge of going bad. Rather, she just didn't think he'd entirely grown up. He still felt like a boy with his toys, and that worried her slightly. His toys had rather much more destructive power than usual. Still, he hadn't <em>actually</em> done anything wrong. That she'd noticed. Yet. </p>
<p>She had one more question though, that she asked him just as he was about to turn and leave. "So what happens now?" Her voice was soft enough that it barely even carried to her own ears. But he heard it. He heard it and turned around.</p>
<p>"What do you mean?"</p>
<p>"All those people on the train. The cops that Percy crushed in the alleyway." She couldn't ask around, not without directing even more suspicion her way, but she wasn't sure that any of them had actually survived their first encounter with... whatever Percy had been. "Our secrets out in the open now..."</p>
<p>He smiled again. More broadly this time. "Oh, that little dust up?" The way he said it made it sounds so <em>small</em> and insignificant. Nowhere near the largest event Andi'd ever had--or suspected might ever have--in her entire lifetime. "People have this way about rationalizing things. I checked in with the police. They're blaming it all on a gas leak just beside the tracks. Blew out the side of the train and knocked a whole bunch of people loopy for a while. Killed a few even."</p>
<p>Andi's voice was flat. "A gas leak?" That was quite possibly the most cliche thing she'd heard in her entire life.</p>
<p>He nodded. "Yup. And it turns out, no one's really looking much more carefully than that. After all, either they didn't seen anything... or they saw entirely too much."</p>
<p>He left her to digest that particular point of view. Right then, she wasn't sure that she ever wanted to see the man again. The way he talked, it was just infuriating. Like he knew so much more and wanted to show it. 'Of course they're wouldn't be any last consequences.' 'People don't <em>want</em> to believe.' 'Peh.'</p>
<p>She had a feeling, she'd come around sooner or later. There was only so much she could learn from the book. And if she'd learned anything from this little adventure, it wasn't that there were people who would abuse power and those that wouldn't. It was that if you had power, you had to learn how to control it--before it took control of you.</p>
<hr>
<p>A few hours later--she wasn't entirely sure, as at some point she had fallen asleep--she received her second visitor. It was Officer Williams, the very same one that had come to them some weeks ago, right after they'd fought the Mrs.-Morris-demon.</p>
<p>He paused awkwardly at the foot of the bed. He wasn't nearly as good at waiting as Maxwell was though, which meant that Andi out waited him easily.</p>
<p>"How are feeling?" he finally asked.</p>
<p>"Fine, thanks. And you?" </p>
<p>Something in her tone--cool but not cold, and completely uncaring about why he was here was what she was shooting for--must have caught him off guard. He answered, "Fine as well. Just trying to tie up a few loose ends on a few cases."</p>
<p>"Oh?" It wouldn't do to remember exactly which case he was talking about. At least not too quickly. That would imply that she'd been thinking about it all this time, which in turn would mean that she was more involved than she'd led him to believe. </p>
<p>"Yeah. Mrs. Morris, you remember her, don't you?"</p>
<p>"Oh yeah," she said, feigning memory slowly coming back. At least he didn't seem to be connecting her to the more recent 'gas leak explosion' on the train line. "Did you ever figure out what happened there?"</p>
<p>He watched her for a bit, but she kept her face smooth, just a little bit of interest showing through. Enough to be polite, that was all. She was glad that Jenny was still sleeping over in her bed...</p>
<p>"No," he finally admitted. "But we've cleared the two of you."</p>
<p>"Oh?" This time she couldn't keep the surprise out of her voice. "That's great. I mean... how?" After tall, they hadn't done it. They hadn't killed the <em>real</em> Mrs. Morris. But that  didn't mean she hadn't been worried about someone coming to the wrong conclusion.</p>
<p>"Yeah," he said. "We found some security footage from just down the street. For the most part, it baks up your version of events. At the very least, it shows that you couldn't possibly have been the ones to kill the old woman. She shows up on the tape too, quite obviously alive, and after you'd already left."</p>
<p>That was interesting. Andi's working theory had been that the demon must have killed her in order to take her form. But that didn't seem to fit with his version of events. Perhaps something had come by after to clean up afterwards? Perhaps something even stranger was going on?</p>
<p>In the end, it didn't really seem to much matter. The cops had apparently found her innocent and were going to leave her alone. What was better, no one had apparently been able to ID her as being on the train. It was a good day all around.</p>
<hr>
<p>Not terribly long after, they were both released from the hospital. Andi's hands had healed well enough that she could at least use them, although the doctors warned her that she was going to have to be careful, possibly for the rest of her life. Jenny walked slowly, making sure not to strain the stitches holding her all together, but that too would pass in time.</p>
<p>They went back to the scene of the final battle. Andi didn't know if it was some sort of penance for the havoc that they'd--indirectly--wrecked on so many people's lives or just a sense of closure. She wanted to see how the city would heal, if it was having any easier a time of it than the two women were having.;</p>
<p>The black patch of demon blood and guts was gone. She'd expected that all along; it had mostly faded already when they'd run. She still didn't know exactly what sort of demon that thing had been and what it's full range of powers were, but it was good that it didn't last long.</p>
<p>The alley where they'd fought Percy was a little worse. There was no evidence of the mist body that Percy had taken, but that was expected. What there was, however, was a memorial on one end of the street for the cops who apparently had been killed, just doing their job in a world that was far stranger and more dangerous than the one they'd signed on for. </p>
<p>She felt terrible about that. It wasn't her fault that they'd died--not really. But the problem was that if she hadn't chosen to confront Percy there, the day would have come eventually. And that could have been in any other just as public a location. It was him that they had to blame, not here.</p>
<p>She still didn't really believe that he was dead. Well, dead again, if her unbelievable theory that he was some sort of ghost of a sorcerer held true. But he'd come back after having his head completely blow apart by a shotgun. What would stop him from coming back yet again after being burnt to a crisp by a fire demon in blanket form?</p>
<p>There was a dark patch marking the ground where he'd finally fallen. She thought that must have been where the blanket sat on the concrete for no more than a few seconds between when his mist form had been completely removed and she'd deactivated it. She couldn't even imagine how hot it had to have gotten to leave that sort of mark. She wondered briefly just how hot it could get if one left it active for hours--or even days.</p>
<p>Then she looked down at her hands.</p>
<p>No, she decided, she really didn't need to know.</p>
<hr>
<p>When Andi got home, the book was waiting for her on her dining room table, right where they'd left it what felt like ages ago. It really didn't look any different. Andi didn't have a particular sane, rational reason whit should have. It was a book after all, even if it was  demon, and hadn't been physically involved in any altercation but the very first. Of course it wouldn't change. </p>
<p>There was a note left, poking out about two thirds through the book. It was in a chapter that she'd never seen before and from the look Jenny gave it, it was new to her as well. She started reading through it, her mood falling even as she did. After a moment, she skipped to the end and read the signature. <em>Of course.</em> Carefully peeling the note out of the book, she sat on the couch, Jenny settling down beside her. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>You were right. </p>
<p>Percival isn't human. Not anymore. I contacted an old friend of mine who did some digging. It's not well known, but apparently it is possible for a human soul to remove after death. It requires arcane rituals I did not even believe were possible and binding a demon to yourself, but it <em>is</em> possible.</p>
<p>What you've done though, you've beaten him for now. My sources say it will likely take him years to reform. But when he does, you can guarantee that he won't be happy. He'll come for you. And then, you have to be ready.</p>
<p>When you decide that it's time, I would like to meet with you once again. You saved my sister, it would be an honor to repay that by teaching you all that I know. Your book almost certainly contains knowledge that I myself do not, but there is no substitute for experience. </p>
<p>It has been a long time since I've had a student, but it's often said that there's no better time than the present. </p>
<p>Maxwell Clerk</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Andi look over at her friend. She had that hungry look in her eyes once again, the same one that had once convinced Andi that she was dangerous, that she was <em>unworthy</em> to be a sorcerer. The thought still stung. Friends should stand beside one another, even when the going got tough. </p>
<p>Especially when the going got tough. </p>
<p>Percy would be back. She knew that for certain now. And Maxwell was right. He'd be furious with them. She'd seen it in his eyes, the first time that he'd come back as the being of the mists. That look in his eyes that just wanted her <em>dead</em>. </p>
<p>They were going to need every bit of help that they could get. And if it took allying with another sorcerer she was only beginning to get the vaguest sense that she could trust? So be it.</p>
<p>Andi wasn't the only one that had to decide though. She turned to Jenny. "So, what do you think?"</p>
<p>"Want to be a sorcerer?"</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Chapter 19 - Final Jeopardy</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/08/chapter-19-final-jeopardy" /><id>urn:uuid:ca9b29a2-e4c1-750b-b5d3-d4d12bdcd310</id><updated>2014-01-08T14:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Somehow, they made it away from the train. They left just as the emergency crews were starting to arrive and cordon off the area. Anyone still there was being checked over by the medical crews first and then the cops after that. With how Andi looked--covered head to foot in a tarry, black paste even after some had begun to dissipate--she was sure they would have had all sorts of questions for her. </p>
<p>Worse yet, Officer Williams was one of the first cops on the scene. She didn't think that she would ever see him again, not if she had anything to say about it. Not after he had stopped by and all but accused them of Ms. Morris' death. It wouldn't be good, not at all, for them to be here, now.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Somehow, they made it away from the train. They left just as the emergency crews were starting to arrive and cordon off the area. Anyone still there was being checked over by the medical crews first and then the cops after that. With how Andi looked--covered head to foot in a tarry, black paste even after some had begun to dissipate--she was sure they would have had all sorts of questions for her. </p>
<p>Worse yet, Officer Williams was one of the first cops on the scene. She didn't think that she would ever see him again, not if she had anything to say about it. Not after he had stopped by and all but accused them of Ms. Morris' death. It wouldn't be good, not at all, for them to be here, now.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The entire area was just swarming with emergency vehicles. Traffic throughout the area was always a little chaotic. Sometimes it was possible to drive from end to end without a single problem, sometimes traffic would just slow to a crawl. Worse yet, it didn't seem to have any rhyme or reason regarding why it would suddenly change. Rush hour was a little bad, but it could be the middle of the day.</p>
<p>This was going to be one of those days.</p>
<p>Andi and Jenny stopped for a breather in an alleyway along the tracks perhaps half a dozen blocks from where the train had stopped. It was still close enough that they could see people rushing either towards or away from the scene, but hopefully far enough that they wouldn't be found. At least not immediately.</p>
<p>"You know, if they look hard enough, they're going to know I was on that train," said Jenny.</p>
<p>"How's that?" </p>
<p>"I paid for the ticket with a credit card."</p>
<p>Andi sighed. She had a monthly pass, which meant that she didn't actually have to tag onto the train more than once a month. But the credit trail might be an issue. What would the cops do when they couldn't find her on the train?</p>
<p>Surely there people had gotten off the train though.</p>
<p>Or perhaps not. The problem was that for most of the fight, everyone else had been frozen by the same effect that had stopped any problems the first time the demon had attacked the train. She didn't know if it was that demon itself or Percy that was actually maintaining the effect, but the mere fact that so many emergency vehicles were there now was evidence enough that the same was no longer working.</p>
<p>Had there been enough time to get away? Andi couldn't say. "Well, there's nothing we can do about that now." She looked down at herself. "What we can do though, is get me somewhere with a shower."</p>
<p>Jenny shook her head. "You don't need a shower, you need a hose."</p>
<p>She might have had a point there; not that it was any easier to procure. Particularly without a car, they were either going to have to walk a good chunk of the way back up the city or find some sort of other transportation that wouldn't just take one look at Andi and turn the other way.</p>
<p>No, they needed to find something a little more local.</p>
<p>"What about one of these businesses here?" Andi asked.</p>
<p>Jenny looked up and down the alley they were standing in, slowly shaking her head the entire time. It wasn't the sort of neighborhood that either of them would normally have taken the opportunity to frequent... but were they really in any position to be picky?</p>
<p>"Or what about a demon?" Andi continued. Jenny perked up slightly at that, but only for a moment. Then her face fell. "What?" </p>
<p>"Believe it or not, but I think I know of just the one."</p>
<p>"So...?"</p>
<p>"So without the book, I can't even begin to say what we'd need to summon it. Let alone how we would get hold of the ingredients."</p>
<p>"Oh." Well that wouldn't work then.</p>
<p>They needed something though. Andi sat down on the curb to think. A moment later Jenny joined her. It was only when she looked over at her friend and caught site of her arm out of the corner of her eye that she realized something particularly strange was going on. </p>
<p>The problem was the demonic sludge. So black it seemed to soak up the light, it would stand out wherever they went. But she'd noticed that it was starting to vanish already back at the bigger pile. This was the first evidence that she'd seen in the smaller case of her own arms. Looking at her arms more closely, she realized that they were actually smoking slightly. The smoke was just thin enough that it was hard to see at any distance, but once you knew what you were looking for--a close cousin to heat waves--it was obvious.</p>
<p>"That's so weird," said Jenny. So she'd noticed as well. "So it's just a matter of time?"</p>
<hr>
<p>No more than ten minutes later, Andi was nearly clean. None of the emergency services had even come anywhere near to them yet and no one seemed to be paying them any attention. They had plenty to deal with down at the train. She really wanted to see what in the world they would say about it in the news. Something like that they couldn't very well keep quiet, but how would they spin it?</p>
<p>Then there was the sound of a door banging open right behind them. </p>
<p>Someone yelled at them in a thick accent. "Hey. What are you doing? You aren't supposed to be back here."</p>
<p>Andi wasn't sure exactly what the man's problem was. They were in a sort of alley way between the tracks and a number of stores, it was true. But they weren't doing anyone any harm.</p>
<p>She stood, intending to apologize to the man and move on. But as soon as she turned, she had just long enough to watch the man's eyes go large and for him to back straight into the wall beside his still hanging open door. He backed into it twice more before recovering enough to shift the six inches necessary to actually make it in, slamming the door behind him.</p>
<p>Andi stared after him for a short while, before turning to her friend and asking, "what in the world was that about?"</p>
<p>Jenny looked to be fighting back a grin. She didn't say anything, just pointed towards Andi's hand. </p>
<p>She looked down. Right. </p>
<p>Andi felt the corners of her lips lifting as well.</p>
<p>She was still covered with just a thin layer now of what looked like oil, holding a three foot long sword in her hand. No wonder the man had backed away. Even for one of the stranger cities in the country, that was probably <em>not</em> what the man had been expecting to see out behind his shop. Poor guy.</p>
<p>At least that was one problem dealt with.</p>
<p>She looked back down at her hands, watching with interest as the last vestiges of demon guts finally faded away. In the last few moments, her skin faded from black, to gray, and finally all of the way back to its normal shade. She checked her legs and chest as well. All clear. It didn't seem to matter particularly much how much she'd gotten on different parts of her--either that or she really had gotten most of it on her hands without realizing. But it was gone now.</p>
<p>Just in time to. Just as the demon blood was seeping away, there was a sudden blare of sirens. Andi and Jenny both spun to it, but it was too late. A cop car skidded to a stop down at the end of the alleyway, followed shortly by a second one.</p>
<p>The two women just looked at each other for a long moment. There just wasn't any way to get out of it. Where could they do?</p>
<p>A moment later, a cop hopped out of each door of each car, those on the near side ducking down behind their doors, those on the far side behind the car itself. From each, a gun appeared, all four pointed right at them.</p>
<p><em>Crap</em></p>
<p>"Freeze," one of the cops yelled. Andi rolled her eyes. As if they would go anywhere... "Drop the ... sword and raise your hands above your heads."</p>
<p><em>Double crap</em></p>
<p>She couldn't believe that she'd forgotten about the stupid sword. It had been awesome when she'd been fighting demons, but she should just have left it there. If not for the fact that she believed Maxwell was actually on their side now, then she would have. This way though, it felt better that she keep it on her person until she could figure out what in the world had happened to him and return it. At least that had been the idea.</p>
<p>Now that there were four cops right in front of her with guns trained in her general direction, she was beginning to rethink that particular line of thought.</p>
<p>Carefully, she bent over. She saw the nearer cops shifting to keep her in view, so she made sure to move slowly and as non-threateningly as she could. As she did, she noticed what she thought was a faint why mist accumulating on the ground between her and the end of the alleyway where the cops were. Fog wasn't an unusual circumstance in the city, not by any means, but it was far later in the day than that normally would have been an issue. Not to mention how quickly it was growing.</p>
<p>The cops hadn't seemed to notice yet thought, thus they were the bigger issue at the moment. Carefully, she laid the blade on the ground, point at a forty five degree angle to the two cops. She wouldn't want them to get the wrong idea. </p>
<p>The mist was growing even faster now, starting to curl around the very tip of the blade and starting to spread down the sides. It was moving oddly, not at all how she'd ever seen fog move before.</p>
<p>"Hey, stop that," one of the cops yelled.</p>
<p>She paused. She'd been straightening back up, once again slowly, but that was all. She froze anyways, even though the position was an awkward one that she couldn't hope to hold for terribly much longer.</p>
<p>The mist grew even thicker, starting to pile up six inches to a foot thick in places. It was dense enough that she was even having problems making out the ground at all in places, although around the edges it was still thankfully at least a little transparent.</p>
<p>"He said, 'stop that'," a different voice said. One of the other cops.</p>
<p>She had to chance it. "Stop what?" Hesitantly, she raised her gaze so that she could at least see the two nearer cops peering through the space between their doors and the interior of their cars. The fog had very nearly reached the further forward one now and she thought that she could make out the barrel of his gun shaking every so slightly even from this distance. </p>
<p>"The fog," the second cop said. "I don't know what you're doing, but <em>stop it</em>."</p>
<p><em>They think <em>I'm</em> doing this?</em> She didn't know how to take that. It was as strange to her as to them, but she couldn't very well say that. They were probably just spooked by the damage to the train car. They wouldn't have had time to go and inspect it themselves, but there'd likely have been radio chatter at least. </p>
<p>At least it wasn't standing up that they objected to. Moving slowly once again, she continued to straighten. She didn't yet respond to their allegations about the fog though. What in the world would she say?</p>
<p>A few seconds later, the mist itself saved her from having to come up with some way to explain it. </p>
<p>With a frightening suddenness, a patch of the mist along the top, slightly nearer to the cops than to Andi solidified. One moment it was rolling white fog, hugging to the ground about a foot she would estimate above the pavement. The next, it had solidified into a tendril, very nearly identical to the one that the black beast had been using to tear apart the train car earlier--only this time white.</p>
<p>Just as quickly as it had formed, the tendril whipped across the space away from Andi, slamming into the nearer of the two open doors on this side of a cop car. It went through the window as if it wasn't even there, the grass shattering with a sharp clapping sound. In the blink of an eye, it had wrapped around the top of the door, right the window. A moment after that, the entire tendril seemed to flex.</p>
<p>Without the sword, Andi only had her ring's reflexes to go on. That was only just barely fast enough to get her head down as the tendril ripped the door completely off the car and tossed it at her. She felt the breeze as it soared over her head. There was a solid sounding thunk from behind her, but she didn't dare turn around.</p>
<p>The cop that had been standing behind the door had dropped his gun a foot or so. His eyes were darting around wildly, surely trying to figure out what in the world he was supposed to be shooting at. </p>
<p>He quickly settled back on Andi.</p>
<p>She saw the moment when he decided. The shaking gun steadied, aiming right at the center of her chest.</p>
<p><em>Crap</em></p>
<p>More tendrils were already forming. She did <em>not</em> have time to talk the cops down, if it were even possible. Making up her mind in a flash, Andi reached down for the sword directly in front of her. </p>
<p>Two things happened nearly simultaneously. The cop without a door fired and the the mists hovering over the gun abruptly coalesced into a pearlescent barrier. Her hand hit the barrier, feeling a strange sort of resistance. it was still mist, and thus most definitely not solid, but the more she pushed against it, the more it pushed back. </p>
<p>The gunshot missed, but only barely. He must have been thrown off by her sudden movement. </p>
<p>She pushed for a moment more, but the fog just wouldn't let her through. It was a demon. It had to be. Which meant that she was in trouble--the cops doubly so. </p>
<p>In just the time since she'd tried to get to her sword, there were already half a dozen tendrils flaring bout. They didn't seem to be particularly directed, especially compared to the malicious focus of the first one, but that didn't mean that they weren't still danger. One of them swiped the door of the other cop car--the one that still had a door--and Andi heard a crunch as it impacted the cop behind limit, sending him sprawling to the ground.</p>
<p>The two behind the cars still seemed fine though, at least for the moment. Shoe was a little surprised honestly that neither of them had opened fire yet. The way they were standing, she couldn't quite make out either. But perhaps it was an issue that they just didn't know where to shoot. Could the, would they shoot at Andi? At the mist?</p>
<p>Truth be told, she would have shot at herself. What exactly do you think a bullet would manage to do to a pile of mist? Then again, she knew what it was. They had to be having a rather abbreviated education right about now.</p>
<p>"I wish he'd told me how to use this thing.</p>
<p>Andi started. She'd completely forgotten that Jenny was standing there right behind her.</p>
<p>She turned.</p>
<p>Jenny had a hand on her side and was looking down at it. Slowly, she brought it away. Her fingers dripped red. </p>
<p>It only took a moment to track back to what must have happened. "Jenny, you got shot!"</p>
<p>"Oh," she said. "Is that what happened/" Her voice was faint and her skin was pale. It didn't look like she'd lost much blood; Andi couldn't even see any of it other than what was on her fingers. But she wasn't sworried about what she could see, it was what she couldn't that had her worried.</p>
<p>Jenny, you need to sit down. She heard a crumpling sound behind her, the grind of metal on metal. She ignored it. She wasn't going to mess this up, not again. "Come on."</p>
<p>She allowed Andi to put her arm around her and help her start moving towards the other end of the alleyway, away from the mists. She had one hand on her lower side, right where Andi presumed the pullet had gone on. </p>
<p>"Just keep pressure on it," Andi said. That was the right thing to do, right? It wasn't like she'ed ever been shot before.</p>
<p>Jenny nodded faintly. Andi couldn't even be completely sure that it was a conscious effort and not just her head bobbing with the effort, but at the moment, and was going o have to take it as trash.</p>
<p>They made it halfway down the block before Jenny stumbled. Her foot just didn't seem to take the next step when Andi did and hehe started to pitch forward. Andi caught her, but only just. It was all she could do to help her slowly to the ground and not drop her. </p>
<p>"<em>YOU</em>"</p>
<p>The voice was so deep and loud it seemed to rattle Andi's very bones. </p>
<p>"<em>COME HERE</em>"</p>
<p>What was worse, she knew that voice.</p>
<p>"<em>I AM NOT THROUGH WITH YOU</em>"</p>
<p>She turned slowly.</p>
<p>Percy.</p>
<p>He had survived.</p>
<p>It made a little sense, but only if you actually thought that he was a ghost. </p>
<p>Now though, he was a living bank of fog.</p>
<p>He still drifted a bit around the edges, but he'd formed most of the mists into a single body for himself. It was larger than he had been in life--or maybe afterlife--easily eight feet tall and proportionally larger all around. His bladed arms had been replaced with tendrils of fog, thick and muscular looking, gleaming faintly.</p>
<p>She caught sight behind him of the cop cars. For a second and only a second, she thought she would have allies this time along. </p>
<p>Then she saw the carnage.</p>
<p>One of the cop cars had been flattened. It was half the height it should have been, nearly the entire cab flattened level with the hood. </p>
<p>There was smoking rising from the hood of the other. A single dent had been lain in that one's hood, from the center of the font back to the windshield. It bent down into a deep V, likely having been forced right into or maybe even through the engine block. That was something she had to give Percy at least. He didn't go to half measures when it came to sheer physical strength. </p>
<p>Of the cops, she saw no sign. She hoped they'd taken the smart route and run. it wouldn't help her out, but at this point, she didn't think they could. Being beheaded by a shotgun blast hadn't even been enough to stop him for more than a few minutes, what could those little popguns they were carrying hope to accomplish.</p>
<p>"<em>SURRENDER. AND I WILL MAKE YOUR DEATH QUICK</em>"</p>
<p><em>Someone really needed to have a talk with him about the definition of 'surrender'</em>, she thought. Aloud she said, "Nope. Don't think so."</p>
<p>Because she'd seen the upside of him taking a human form, even one made of out of mist.</p>
<p>When he'd been a cloud on the ground, he'd kept her from the sword. Upright, it was closer to her than it was to him.</p>
<p>She dove.</p>
<p>He rushed forward at the same time, tendril arms swinging outwards. But this time, it wasn't a matter of speed. He couldn't have gone fast enough--at least not without something like their chronodemon pocket watch. She reached it a moment before he did, immediately ducking and rolling, swinging the sword into an arc over her head. One swift cut and both tendril arms were on the ground. </p>
<p>She continued the roll, coming to her feet well within his range, facing him with sword held high. </p>
<p>The look on his face was pure hatred. His skin was gleaming white, more mist than real flesh and blood. At least it actually looked like she should pass through him now, rather than when he appeared every bit as real as she had. </p>
<p>There was a faint sound from behind her. She glanced over her should and caught sight of Jenny still laying there. Right. She needed to end this. Quickly.</p>
<p>She turned back just in time to catch another tendril whipping towards her face.</p>
<p><em>I could have sworn he only had two,</em> she half muttered to herself even as the sword came up and sliced without her even thinking about it. Another tendril. Another slice.</p>
<p>Even if he suddenly seemed to have a dozen arms all swinging for her at once, at least he wasn't quite so physically strong as the black mass that she'd just fought. This time she could even fight forwards, step after step. Only a matter of time.</p>
<p>Another step and she was face to face with him.</p>
<p>She didn't even think about it. </p>
<p>Slice.</p>
<p>Right through his neck.</p>
<p>His head just seemed to float there. That wasn't right. it was supped to fall down. That was how it had happened before, wasn't it? But he just grinned at her, seemingly completely unconcerned about the inch and change now separating him from himself.</p>
<p>Then the tendrils began to form. Thin, much thinner than his arms, only a thread's width across. But there were more of them. A dozen, two, a hundred or more. Within moments, his neck had reformed, pulling his head back down to where it really belonged. A moment after that, its as as if he'd never even lost it in the first place. </p>
<p>"Well, crap."</p>
<p>This was going to be a problem. </p>
<p>The grin on Percy's face told her he knew <em>exactly</em> what she was thinking. He had just been waiting for the moment. She had the sneaking suspicion that he'd been toying with himself. Now he could begin the attack in earnest.</p>
<p>She cut the first tendril, but now she could see them reforming almost immediately in the same way that his head had. The second blow followed shortly after. Third. Fourth. Fifth. </p>
<p>It was all she could do to keep up. A couple of times, she was just in the nick of time, even catching a bit of the weight before she managed to cut it, turning it into mist for some time. </p>
<p>"<em>YOU CANNOT HOPE TO WIN</em>"</p>
<p>He didn't even sound particularly angry any more. Lazy even. It was like he thought that there was no chance that she could possibly fight him off and that it was only a matter of time.</p>
<p>The problem was, she was becoming more and more sure that he was right. Even with her own ring and Maxwell's sword, it was all she could do to keep up. She needed something else.</p>
<p>She needed something that could fight back the mists.</p>
<p>Her mind jumped ahead; a sudden flash of insight. </p>
<p>She had just the right thing, she just needed enough time to get it to work.</p>
<p>She started to back away, trying to put a bit of room between her and Percy. She would need a bit to get things out of her bag. With any luck, he would taunt her.</p>
<p>"<em>AFRAID, LITTLE GIRL?</em>"</p>
<p>Exactly.</p>
<p>Another step back. She even carefully began slowing her defenses, getting closer and closer to letting him actually strike her. Anything to goad him closer. </p>
<p>He obliged perfectly. She backed up, step by step. He followed, but slower and slower. He wasn't pressing his advantage. He didn't need to press his advantage. He knew that he had her exactly where he wanted her.</p>
<p>Finally, she made it far enough. It would have to be enough.</p>
<p>With a smooth motion, she drove the sword into the ground. It cut into the sidewalk easily, which actually caught her attention longer than it should have. She hadn't been expecting that. She had thought that it would have taken more effort than that.</p>
<p>No matter.</p>
<p>Twisting to the side, she pulled open her bag. It was a miracle that she'd managed to keep it through everything. That was what it was designed for, to stay on, but it was still impressive. Even better, what she was looking for was right on top. </p>
<p>She pulled the blanked out, whipping it out to full width. Bright orange and full of fire. Heat always seemed to burn away the mists in the morning. With any luck, it would work the same way on Percy.</p>
<p>"Znden."</p>
<p>She felt it grow warm in her hands. She wasn't going to have long before it would start burning her. She tried to hold it away from her a little bit, ending up like a matador. She started to advance once again.</p>
<p>Percy just stared at her. He seemed confused. Andi realized after that she'd put the sword down. That must be what he was confused about. He didn't never have to know that it was a demon spelled sword, to know that it was giving her a significant advantage. And now she'd abandoned it, in favor of a bright orange blanket.</p>
<p>Confusion didn't last long though. If she wasn't running, she must still be fighting. So he'd meet that challenge. </p>
<p>The first tendril whipped forward. </p>
<p>Moment of truth.</p>
<p>She tossed the blanked over the tendril. It held. Actually, it froze in place. It was as if he didn't know quite how to deal with the oddly warm blanked now draped over his arm. For sure, he couldn't have been expecting <em>that</em> to be her move.</p>
<p>She waited a moment. Two. Without warning, the blanket fell to the ground. The tendril sheered off as abruptly as if it had been cut with a knife--only this time it didn't immediately begin to reform.</p>
<p>He just stared at his arm, disbelief clouding his features. Andi didn't give him time to react. She bent over, grabbed the blanket and tossed it over Percy's head. It started to slide too far, but just before she lost it entirely, she grabbed hold and held it in place.</p>
<p>He started to struggle, his tendril arm--apparently, there really had been two all along, only they kept reforming over and over again--whipped about, but it did so blindly, seeking for her but never quite managing to find her. The blanket burnt, growing hotter and hotter by the moment, making it increasingly hard for Andi to hold it. But she had to do it, she had to see this through to the conclusion.</p>
<p>She heard a sound, akin to bacon sizzling in the pan. A moment after that, the smell as well. It was only too late that she realized the sizzling was her hands, that se was literally cooking the flesh which held the blanket in place.</p>
<p>But she couldn't stop.</p>
<p>And then it was over. The blanket collapsed into a pile on the ground. Andi immediately dropped it and whispered the word of command that would put it back out, but the damage was done. Her palms were streaked red and black. she couldn't feel a thing, which if anything was worse.</p>
<p>She looked over, to make sure that he really was gone this time. For a few moments, the tendril that had once been a sword and before that been an arm held together, but then it to dissipated, fading first into a more ordinary looking smoke and then blowing away entirely. </p>
<p>And that was that.</p>
<p>He was gone.</p>
<p>She couldn't only pray that this time, he would stay gone...</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Chapter 18 -- Demon in Black</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/04/chapter-18-demon-in-black" /><id>urn:uuid:cf16b58f-8abd-55e1-add9-13f906b9a71c</id><updated>2014-01-04T14:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>She jerked her head up.</p>
<p>Great.</p>
<p>Maxwell stood there, towards the doors on one side--the side without the demon banging at the door. She How had he gotten over there? Hadn't he been thrown out of the train on the opposite side just a little big before? For that matter, hadn't he been <em>thrown out a window</em>? He looked absolutely none the worse for the wear. He could have just stepped onto the car, a normal passenger.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>She jerked her head up.</p>
<p>Great.</p>
<p>Maxwell stood there, towards the doors on one side--the side without the demon banging at the door. She How had he gotten over there? Hadn't he been thrown out of the train on the opposite side just a little big before? For that matter, hadn't he been <em>thrown out a window</em>? He looked absolutely none the worse for the wear. He could have just stepped onto the car, a normal passenger.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Well, normal given the odd sorts that you tended to already see in the city. That much jewelry was a bit unusual even so.</p>
<p>"Should be enough to keep him off our backs for a bit. Your demon's a heck of a fighter for how new you are at all this."</p>
<p>Andi didn't quite know how to take that. Was he trying to complement her or reinforce the fact that he had  a lot more practice than they did.</p>
<p>Either way...</p>
<p>"Thank you." Andi jerked again. Eventually she was going to have to stop doing that. This time it was Jenny's voice. Weak, but very much conscious once again.</p>
<p>"Ah, one of yours then," Maxwell said. He nodded down to her. "Very nice. Unfortunately, i have a feeling that you're about to need another."</p>
<p>"What?" Andi said.</p>
<p>A sickening meaty sound followed by a wet thud from behind answered the question for him. Andi turned yet again, finding herself face to face with... well, Big Red's face. The rest of him still stood, still wedged into place between the seats. He wasn't going to be a distraction for much longer though. Not without a head. </p>
<p>"We should probably get out in the open," Maxwell said. </p>
<p>Andi nodded. It made sense. There was no good way to fight more than one on one in the goth confines of the car and in that situation Percy had all of the advantages. They couldn't even bring Maxwell's demon to bear, not without an even worse reaction than they'd had with Big Red. </p>
<p>There was one potential problem though. "You okay?" she asked Jenny.</p>
<p>She nodded. She seemed to be moving well enough. No obvious signs of a concussion or anything worse. Then again, some of the worse wounds might only show up far too late. </p>
<p>That was just a risk they were going to haves to take.</p>
<p>Maxwell had a hand extended to either of them. Andi considered ignoring it, but what would that gain them? </p>
<p>She reached out. Took his hand.</p>
<p>A feeling like electricity ran up her arm. It was faint, but definitely there. In fact, she could remember only one time she she'd felt something quite like that. Back when she'd first touched the book. That had been closer to falling, but at the very least the two feelings were close cousins. </p>
<p><em>What...</em></p>
<p>Then he had lifted her to her feet. He must have had som sort of strength boosting demon of his own, to lift her straight up off the ground like that. It could have been any one of those rings or necklaces.</p>
<p>To her side, he lifted Jenny as well, with apparently just as little effort. There was barely enough room for the three of them and that only because they were standing in the car entrance. The door was still open where Maxwell must have hit it. One of the doors was hanging at a slight angle, the other wasn't even attached any more at all. </p>
<p>Yup. Definitely a strength boosting demon.</p>
<p>Without another word, he led them out of the car.</p>
<hr>
<p>They had to jump down to the ground. This was the second time that Andi had gotten off of the train not at a station--the second time because of the dssame demon fro that matter--but it still felt strange. Like she was breaking the  rules. Her intuition told her to stop it, to go back on the train, to follow the rules. Luckily, a stronger part of her knew that was an absolutely terrible idea.</p>
<p>A massive thud sounded from the train behind her and she pitched forward off the last step. She barely caught herself as the wild screech of the train settling back onto both sides of wheels sounded behind her. Apparently the tendrilled demon had gotten tired of being cut apart within the car and thought it more amusing to try and knock it over again.</p>
<p>Either that or Percy had commanded it to. She could only imagine the damage that would do if a train car were to land on her....</p>
<p>Luckily, it didn't seem <em>quite</em> strong enough.</p>
<p>Not yet at least.</p>
<p>Another blow.</p>
<p>"So," Maxwell said. "What do you have?" </p>
<p>He sounded too calm. Not at all like someone that had rescued two women from a demonic attack--not that they had needed rescuing, Andi was quick to think.</p>
<p>"What do you mean?" she said.</p>
<p>"Demon-wise. What sort of firepower do you have?"</p>
<p>"Um."</p>
<p>Had Jenny been bluffing after all? Was there really no way to tell what was a demon and what wasn't? Or perhaps it was only sensitive enough to detect if something was a demon or not. Not what we could do.</p>
<p>"Mirror," Jenny said, "let's us walk through walls."</p>
<p>Andi continued for her, holding up her hand. "My ring. General fighting skills. Strength, speeds, the works."</p>
<p>It couldn't hurt to make them sound at least a little better, now could it?</p>
<p>He nodded. "And?"</p>
<p>Andi thought wildly. The pocket watch? No. Jenny had dropped it when it had burned out back on the train. She'd seen it lying on the floor back in there melted and reformed, nearly a third of it closer to puddle than watch. She doubted the demon could have survived that.</p>
<p>Big Red? Not so much. Even a demon couldn't survive a beheading. At least not one in a humanoid form like that. Along with the strengths of a body came the weaknesses, as the book seemed fond of saying.</p>
<p>The fire blanket? She'd folded it up in her bag, but what in the world was she going to do with that? That was really better at getting rid of evidence, it took too long for anything approaching a target that was fighting back. </p>
<p>Maxwell shook his head. "I know you have more than that. There's the big guy, sure. But what about the time dilation? That's one nice chronodemons."</p>
<p>Chronodemon? Was that really a thing? Andi shook her head. "Burnt out."</p>
<p>He eyed them for a moment. "Burnt out?"</p>
<p>Wait, was that not something she was supposed to have said? It couldn't be that uncommon to push a demon that hard. He'd been at this years longer than they had, surely he must have done it before.</p>
<p>Maxwell was looking from one of them to the other now though. "That's it?" He shook his head. "Heck, now I wish I were the bad guy."</p>
<p>Not the sort of thing Andi had been hoping to hear.</p>
<p>"Here," he said. Reaching up to one of his necklaces without looking, he broke the band, pulling it off from around his neck. Seemingly out of nowhere, a sword appeared in his hand. An honest to God sword. The blade was thicker than Andi would have expected and nearly two feet long. There had to have been some real trickery to hide that thing away, in a necklace no less.</p>
<p>He tossed it to Andi. She was so surprised, she nearly didn't catch it. Barely getting one hand around it though, she steadied it.</p>
<p>He said something then in a language Andi couldn't hope to identify. The syllables were too liquid yet somehow too sharp. They didn't sound quite like something that should have been possible to come from a human mouth, but he managed. Somehow, he managed.</p>
<p>The sword grew lighter in her hand. Experimentally, she twirled it. She couldn't say what had gotten into her; she didn't have the slightest idea how to do that... But it worked. The blade moved naturally, curving in a wide arc forward, down, then back up. It was like the sword knew what it wanted and gave her whatever she needed to pull it off. The power of combining that with her own ring was intoxicating.</p>
<p>"Don't get carried away," Maxwell said. She realized that she'd continued to swing the blade in ever increasingly fast arcs. Swish, swish, swish, it cut through the air. "It's not as good as it thinks it is." The blade stopped dead. She would have said that she'd stopped the blade dead in the air, but that wasn't quite right. The blade moved with her, but it wasn't strictly speaking moved <em>by</em> her.</p>
<p>He turned to Jenny. "Unfortunately, chronodemons aren't my speciality. Perhaps some armor plating?" He reached up to another necklace, this one a silvery star hung on a pure black band. Andi wondered what in the world he could have made it out of, it didn't shine at all, but rather seemed to be soaking in the light. "It'll make you heavier as well. Almost impossible for someone to move you, although you'll be able to move just fine."</p>
<p>Jenny smiled slightly, moving her neck as if stretching. "That would be nice." To keep from getting tossed about again, Andi thought. Nice. "Going to need some firepower too though."</p>
<p>"Picky picky," Maxwell said. He started to reach up around his neck to pull down yet another necklace. Just then, a massive black form dropped from the sky, directly on top of him.</p>
<p>Andi was blown backwards from the force of the explosion. She caught sight of Jenny careening in the opposite direction--<em>if only he'd actually activated the thing</em>--then she hit the side of the car and all thought fled.</p>
<p>For a moment, stars danced in front of her eyes and the corners of her vision seemed to retreat. She didn't lose consciousness, but it was a near thing. She watched, half stunned, as the black mass of tendrils expanded outwards, returning to full form.</p>
<p><em>How in the world did you get something like that up in the air?</em> she had time to think. Then a whole mess of said tendrils were coming right for her. </p>
<p>She ducked, avoiding the first pair. The next came in low and she had to jump over them. She'd long ago lost her chair, but the sword Maxwell had given her swung down with a mind of her own as she jumped, slicing a tendril off at what would otherwise have been the shoulder.</p>
<p>Black blood--too thick to be blood, but what else to call it--sprayed. She landed on a sheet of the stuff, almost losing her balance. It was as slick as ice and didn't give a bit. Only the extra balance afforded her by her ring allowed her to keep her feet, but even that was a near thing.</p>
<p>She took a moment to assess the situation.</p>
<p>There was a demon right in front of her. Somewhere under that mass of demon was Maxwell. She could only hope that he was till alive. There wasn't time to look.</p>
<p>And on the other side, Jenny. With an armored demon to her name, but no way to activate it. Not without Maxwell.</p>
<p>That left her with the only firepower.</p>
<p>She was going to have to go on the offensive.</p>
<p>She charged forwards, a wordless roar tearing from her throat. It hadn't been a conscious effort, but it just felt so <em>right</em>. She swung the blade lightly back and forth, around and around. When she hit the demon, it just kept swinging. </p>
<p>Through thick, rubbery black flesh, it kept swinging.</p>
<p>Through a spray of black blood that clung to her and itself with a tenacity not unlike glue, it kept swinging.</p>
<p>Even when the beast turned silently towards her, focusing all of its attention on the annoying gnat that was biting it, it kept swinging.</p>
<p>The thing didn't make a sound as it reacted. That made her think more of the second demon of this form that had attacked them then the first, that hadn't made a sound either. It was creepier that way. She expected the thing to be like a wild beast, roaring and grunting with effort, but it was cunningly efficient. The only sounds that came from it were the almost whistling blur of the tendrils whipping towards and then whipping away, often inches before she cut them off with her blade.</p>
<p>It was hard to get an accurate measure of just how many tendrils the thing had. She could count half a dozen or so at a time, but they kept whipping about. She thought they might be merging or forming as she fought, but she couldn't quite catch it doing it. There were a few that hadn't healed either, which seemed to indicate at least that it wasn't healing them. </p>
<p>Still, half a dozen fresh tendrils all at once were a force to be reckoned with.</p>
<p>She kept swinging.</p>
<p>One.</p>
<p>Two.</p>
<p>Four.</p>
<p>Seven. </p>
<p>After a while, she lost count. There were just too many to deal with. It all started to take on a sort of rhythm. Swing. Miss. Doge. Swing. Hit. Slice. Spray.</p>
<hr>
<p>"Um Andi, I think it's dead."</p>
<p>She turned, breathing hard. </p>
<p>Jenny stood there, a strange expression on her face.</p>
<p>Andi ignored her. She had to keep the demon busy. She was the only one with the ability to...</p>
<p>For the first time in while, she actually looked at what she was doing.</p>
<p>She was standing in front of a pile of what could only be described as black good. There was nothing left of the demon that she'd been fighting, at least nothing that was moving any longer.</p>
<p>The pile was smaller than it seemed like it should have been, barely up past her knees. There was perhaps one or two tendrils that she could still see roughly maintaining their shapes, but neither was moving. The rest had been sliced and diced, mixed with that slick yet somehow gluey blood until they resembled black paste.</p>
<p>It was dead. And had quite obviously been for some time. </p>
<p>"Oh," she said. "Right."</p>
<p>She lowered the sword to one side. A part of her wanted to drop it. Right then and now. The thing had taken her over. It wanted nothing but blood, and it had gotten that in spades. But another part of her knew that that had been exactly what she'd needed at that particular moment. Without the sword, she couldn't have handled the demon.</p>
<p>Then she remembered one of the reasons she'd given in to the demon sword quite so completely in the first place. Why it had been so important to take down the demon, rather than just running to live and fight another day.</p>
<p>With a wordless cry, she dove forward into the black sticky mass. </p>
<hr>
<p>She found Maxwell a few moments later. It took a bit longer to dig him out. The remains of the demon had the consistency of tar, thick and sticky, but it was next to impossible to really get a grip on, sliding out of her hand no matter how she tried to hold onto it. </p>
<p>When she finally got his face clear, she saw that he wasn't breathing. She must have known that would be what she would find--even as she'd diced it, the thing had never moved from its initial position on top of him. But she didn't want to believe it. </p>
<p>She knew what had to be done. She had seen the scene in movies often enough and had even taken the CPR training, although that had been years ago. The only thing holding her back was the black bits of demon that still refused to let loose his face. Well, that and the idea of putting her mouth to another's who until recently she'd been sure had been trying to kill her. She still wasn't entirely sure that <em>wasn't</em> the case.</p>
<p>It had to be done though. She at least had to make an effort.</p>
<p>She leaned in...</p>
<p>And jumped away in pain. She wasn't sure what it was, but it almost felt as if one of the necklaces had bit her. Of course that was impossible.</p>
<p>She looked down at them. Nothing looked particularly out of the ordinary. Except...</p>
<p>One of them was glowing faintly. It was close to a cross, but slightly wrong. Rather than a straight line at the top, it was a loop. She thought it looked familiar, but she couldn't place where she had seen it before.</p>
<p>A whoosh and a thud behind her caught her attention. A deep bass voice sounding out tore it away completely. </p>
<p>"So," the voice said, "it is done." </p>
<p>She turned.</p>
<p>Percy.</p>
<p>Of course it was Percy.</p>
<p>He was standing there, elongated into that inhuman form he favored, almost a living weapon. </p>
<p>"You know, I really wish it didn't have to be this way," he said.</p>
<p>Andi shook her head. "What way?" He wasn't about to...</p>
<p>"If only you had just killed him like you were supposed to. We could have been great, you know."</p>
<p>Andi rolled her lines. She couldn't even think of a less stereotypical line than that. "Let me guess, we could have take over the world together. I could have ruled at your side, queen and king."</p>
<p>He smiled. "Of course not. What do you take me for?" He really didn't want her to answer that question. "No. My hopes for you were much more mundane."</p>
<p>Without any hint for what he was about to do, he swung one of his bladed arms right at Andi's head.</p>
<p>The sword in her hands leaped up before Andi even realized what was happening. It should have been enough to stop the blow... But his arm went right through her sword. She blinked and it went right through her head as well. </p>
<p>"As you can see," he said. "I have bigger problems than ruling the world."</p>
<p>Now she was just confused. Was he toying with her? She'd seen him toss Maxwell through the window. </p>
<p>Maxwell.</p>
<p>She turned back to him. If Percy wasn't going to kill her--or couldn't kill her--then he was a problem that could be put off until later. Maxwell was the more pressing issue.</p>
<p>But he had vanished.</p>
<p>She stared at the spot where he had been.</p>
<p>It wasn't like she didn't have evidence--there was a Maxwell shaped indentation right there as obvious as could be. He just wasn't in it any more.</p>
<p>She shook her head. <em>Impossible.</em> Stupid word that. It just didn't have quite the same effect when time and time again she kept coming right up against things that shouldn't be.</p>
<p>"What is it?"</p>
<p>She turned back to Percy. He actually had a slightly puzzled expression on his face and was craning his neck to look around Andi towards the pile of demon that had sat behind her. Had he not actually known that Maxwell had been under there? Perhaps Andi could use that.</p>
<p>"Nothing," she said.</p>
<p>"See, I know you're lying."</p>
<p>She shook her head. "Really, it's nothing. I was just making sure it was dead."</p>
<p>The corners of his mouth turned up a bit at that. "Oh yes? I wouldn't think that was actually an issue." He gestured from side to side, taking in the entire black mass on the ground. "I'd say you were pretty thorough."</p>
<p>Andi felt sick. It and been a demon, true, but that didn't mean she liked being reminded about having slaughtered it so wantonly. Trying to turn the topic back, she said, "Regardless. What were you saying about me?"</p>
<p>"Right," he said, raising his blade arms again. "I was saying that it's over."</p>
<p>And with that he charged.</p>
<p>Andi almost didn't even bother to block. After all, he'd shown a moment ago that he was essentially impotent. Luckily, Maxwell's sword had other ideas.</p>
<p>Just in time, it jerked her arms upwards, blocking a blow aimed right for her neck.</p>
<p>The impact slid her back nearly six inches. Her breath exploded out in a gasp. "What the hell..." It just wan't fair for her to keep changing the rules on her like that...</p>
<p>"Not quite," Percy said, "but close enough."</p>
<p>Then his attack began in earnest. </p>
<p>It was all Andi could do to keep him off of her. If he would have been able to control his corporeality any better, to switch back and forth, she would have been dead. There was no doubt about it. But for the moment at least, he seemed as solid as her. Even more real than that, truth be told. Those bladed arms had a terrible sort of weight to them, beating her back impact after impact.</p>
<p>She managed to keep her footing even as he forced her across the black remains of her previous conquest, but it was a close thing. He, on the other hand, barely even seemed to notice. He just continued forward, step after step, inexorably towards her.</p>
<p>As he forced her back, she realized that this just wasn't going to work. She had to try something else. </p>
<p>"Why?" she said. It was easier than she was expecting. Shouldn't she be out of breath or something? Or at least distracted? But the sword seemed to be doing that for her as well. It was fighting--she was just along for the ride.</p>
<p>Percy raised an eyebrow at her, as if to say 'why what?' He remained silent though, forcing her ever back.</p>
<p>"What did you really want from me?" There was little question now that he had been the one trying to kill her all along, but then why in the world had he even come to her in the first place. Why couldn't he just have left her alone...</p>
<p>He growled. She didn't believe it at first, even in his most vicious, weapon like stance, he had always seemed to civilized to make a sound such as that. But there was no mistaking it. His tone still rough, he said, "you were supposed to save me."</p>
<p>Andi missed a step and very nearly paid for it with her life. Her sword jerked her arms upwards even as she ducked down, pulling it out of the way. The blow echoed through the sword, shocking her hands to the core. </p>
<p>She couldn't get his words out of her head though. "<em>What?</em> Save you? From what?"</p>
<p>"From myself," he said. His attack didn't slow though. If anything, he redoubled his efforts. "From death."</p>
<p>Andi almost missed another attack. She couldn't keep letting him surprised her like that. </p>
<p>"How do you figure?" She managed, taking advantage of the monetary distraction her words afforded her to push an attack. He still blocked her easily, but it was a momentary breather where to not be pushed back constantly.</p>
<p>"I can't do it myself," he said. "Not as I am. I need another sorcerer."</p>
<p>She shook her head. "And this was the best you could come up with? Attacking me? That's a terrible way to get me over to your point of view."</p>
<p>A part of her wanted him to deny it, even now. It was strange, but even now, even after everything, a part of her still trusted him.</p>
<p>He shook his head. "It wasn't supposed to turn out this way." He shifted in a way that Andi hadn't been expected and landed a scoring blow along her the side of her ribs. She didn't feel it all for a moment, but then she felt a warmth flowing on her side. That couldn't be good--but she couldn't even spare a moment to look down.</p>
<p>"So you admit it?" she said.</p>
<p>Moment of truth.</p>
<p>"Of course I did it. And you know what? I regret nothing. You're not who I thought you would be."</p>
<p>That hurt, more than it should have. "I'm not good enough?"</p>
<p>He actually stumbled. It surprised Andi as much as it did him, but he caught himself quickly enough. He was back on his guard before she could press his advantage. "What? Is that what you think? Nah, you'd be a fine sorcerer. The problem is that you're just too <em>good</em>."</p>
<p>It was Andi's turn to be surprised. <em>Too good?</em> Wasn't that what his whole charade had been enough? That only someone <em>good</em> enough would make a good sorcerer? That everyone else would give in to the power? It seemed though that that was what he'd really wanted all along after all.</p>
<p>It was turning her whole world upside down. Everything she thought she'd known... </p>
<p>Percy wasn't quite done yet though. "Your friend on the other hand. Hmmm, she might just be what I'm looking for. She might just be malleable enough..."</p>
<p>"Think again."</p>
<p>A deafening boom sounded from right behind Percy and his head essentially disintegrated right in Andi's eyes. There wasn't any blood or gore, for which Andi was eternally grateful--that might just have driver her right over the edge--just a faint puff of gray smoke.</p>
<p>The body stood there for a few seconds, completely still, before finally sinking to its knees and the slumping forward. Even as it fell it was growing increasingly fuzzy around the edges. When it actually hit the ground, there was a much larger puff of the same gray smoke and he was gone.</p>
<p>Just like that. Walking, talking, fighting... whatever he was, to dust on the wind in five seconds flat. </p>
<p>Andi looked behind him to see Jenny standing on the steps of the train car, a familiar looking shotgun held in both hands. The barrels were smoking slightly, leaving no doubt in mind at all just who had ended Percy. </p>
<p>"Thanks," Andi said.</p>
<p>She smiled. "Don't mention it." She hoisted the shotgun up onto one shoulder. "We should probably bail though."</p>
<p>Andi cocked her head. </p>
<p>"Can't you hear that?"</p>
<p>Not until she'd mentioned it, she hadn't. Now it was all she could hear. Sirens. All sorts of sirens, coming from every direction at once.</p>
<p>"Crap."</p>
<p>"No kidding. I for one don't want to be the one to have to explain ... " She gestured vaguely towards Andi. It took her a moment to even remember that she was standing in a massive bile of black, tarry demon guts.</p>
<p>"Right. You found Laura?"</p>
<p>Jenny nodded. "Yeah, she's up a few cars. Percy must have gotten to her before we did."</p>
<p>Andi's stomach fell out. "You don't mean..."</p>
<p>"No, no, of course not. She's fine. I think he cast some sort of mojo on her that knocked her out--she was sleeping when I last saw her--but she's fine."</p>
<p>Andi nodded slowly. Some sort of mojo didn't sound particularly good. Not if they'd just dusted the only one that might know for sure how to undo it. </p>
<p>"What about Maxwell?" Jenny said. </p>
<p>Andi spun. She knew there had been something that she'd needed to check back on. </p>
<p>He was still gone though. She could barely even make out the indentation where she'd dug him out of the muck any more. It seemed to flow like tar--slow, but inexorable. Just the brief time they'd had for the fight must have been enough to cover their tracks completely.</p>
<p>Now that she was looking, she noticed something even more strange. The  remains were shrinking. She couldn't be sure of it at first--it wasn't like they were dissipating instantly--but there was definitely less now than there had been before. Perhaps it was soaking into the ground? Or just vanishing? She decided it didn't really matter either way. Just so long as it wasn't there any more when the cops arrived...</p>
<p>"I'm sure he's fine," was all the response she had for Jenny though. "Let's get out of here."</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Chapter 17 -- Showdown</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/01/01/chapter-17-showdown" /><id>urn:uuid:4c5dd2be-37de-20ef-cc6b-75835c4a82d0</id><updated>2014-01-01T14:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The three of them fanned out immediately, forgetting that less than an hour before they'd been doing their best to kill one another. It didn't take long to realize what had happened thought.</p>
<p>Laura's car was gone.</p>
<p>It didn't take long to figure out what must have happened.]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The three of them fanned out immediately, forgetting that less than an hour before they'd been doing their best to kill one another. It didn't take long to realize what had happened thought.</p>
<p>Laura's car was gone.</p>
<p>It didn't take long to figure out what must have happened.<!--more--></p>
<p>The last any of them could remember having seen her was right after Maxwell had dropped his bombshell. Right after he'd revealed that their mother had been killed by some man named Percival--some man that Andi had adamantly insisted never left a certain train network no more than an hour to the south.</p>
<p>Of course, she must have left before they'd actually gotten to the part about him being a potential ghost. Before Andi and Jenny had told Maxwell that he was completely intangible--and thus almost certainly immune to the shotgun Laura had taken with her.</p>
<p>All together, that left Andi and Jenny with two options.</p>
<p>One option was that Maxwell was a master liar and had tricked his sister into working with him and vanishing right at the opportune moment.</p>
<p>The other was that Maxwell was right and Percy was the villain of the piece. In which case Andi and Jenny were in way over their head... Laura wouldn't even have a chance.</p>
<p>They needed to go after her.</p>
<hr />
<p>Maxwell sent them on ahead. He claimed that he had a faster way to get where they were going--but that he wouldn't be able to take them with him. Andi was only too happy to see him go. Even if Andi was being completely honest, that didn't mean she particularly liked him.</p>
<p>Jenny probably broke a dozen traffic laws on their way back into the city. She wasn't talking. Andi wanted to pick her brain, to try to come up with something approaching strategy, but at the same time she <em>really</em> didn't want to crash and die. So she kept quiet.</p>
<p>She did take stock though.</p>
<p>One demonic ring, fully enhanced with all that a few day's experience of a sorcerer could bring to bear. Given all that she'd learned since, it was unimpressive to say the least. Still, it was hers. It had kept her through a number of fights, even if she hadn't always won. It would do for one more.</p>
<p>Then there was the pocket watch. Once, it had been hers, but that moment was gone the moment they had decided to bind a demon to it. Now it was Jenny's as much as the ring was hers. She thought she could deal with that.</p>
<p>Then there was the mirror. A pleasant surprise that, showing that it was entirely possible to mess up demonology and even get things that you didn't plan for. But that wouldn't exactly be the end of the world. In this case, it actually worked out for the best, granted the ability not only to walk through walls but to see what would be on the other side before you did. Crazy.</p>
<p>And what about Big Red? Andi still wasn't sure what to think about that. Although it seemed that it wasn't a particularly strange thing for a sorcerer to do--after all Maxwell had his own demon just like i--but that didn't mean it still didn't freak Andi out. Andi had to wonder exactly how much of that demon was based on Jenny's putting it in and how much was somehow derived from the action figure on which it was based.</p>
<p>And finally, there was that last demon. For some reason, she kept forgetting about it even though it was there in the backseat of the car where it had sat basically forgotten since they'd last used it--the orange blanket that could be used to burn away just about anything.</p>
<p>Andi made a mental not to make sure that she wouldn't forget it this time. Every little bit would help.</p>
<hr />
<p>When they arrived at the northernmost train station, Jenny stopped the car and just stared straight ahead. For a long time, she didn't say anything. They had a few minutes left at least. According to the sign by the tracks, the next train wouldn't be arriving for about a quarter of an hour. Finally though, she couldn't stand it anymore.</p>
<p>"Penny for your thoughts?"</p>
<p>Jenny turned. "Are we doing the right thing?"</p>
<p>Not the question that Andi had been hoping to hear--although not a particularly surprising one. She wasn't sure how to respond.</p>
<p>"I mean, really. How can we believe either of them?"</p>
<p>Andi realized her mouth was hanging open. She'd been so caught up trying to weigh the options one against the other that she'd never even considered that.</p>
<p>But she wasn't done. "What if they're both lying? Even worse yet, what if they're working together?"</p>
<p>Andi shook her head. "That one at least I can't believe."</p>
<p>"Why not?"</p>
<p>"Do you really think that we're a match for <em>either one</em> of them?"</p>
<p><em>knock knock knock</em></p>
<p>Andi spun. Maxwell stood right outside the door, grinning at them. There wasn't another car for a half dozen spots. Not that it would have mattered anyways, he hadn't had one when they'd left either. That would have been a nice trick to learn.</p>
<p>He seemed to be mouthing something. Andi should have been able to hear him at least a little even through the car window, but perhaps he didn't want to chance being misunderstood. Rolling her eyes such that only Jenny could see, she rolled the window.</p>
<p>"Come on out," he said, "time's a wasting."</p>
<p>She briefly considered resisting. What if Jenny were right? But if she were, he could take apart their car just as easily. So it wouldn't make much of a difference either way.</p>
<p>It was time to force a confrontation.</p>
<hr />
<p>The train arrived right on schedule. One of the conductors gave them all a funny look when the boarded--which was unusual in its own right--but they had been riding the train at odd times all along the entire route over the past few rights. It was possible that he would have recognized them, if unlikely. Still, he let them board without issue, not even checking for tickets.</p>
<p>Maxwell took the lead, heading up to the upper decker of the train car without so much as asking leave of the two women. They didn't have much chance to do other than follow, although Andi at least did find it strange. She'd never seen Percy on the upper level of the train, he was always on the bottom. It couldn't matter that much though.</p>
<p>They took seats right behind each other all on the same side on the top level. With the open divider leading down to the bottom, Andi didn't want to take a chance that they'd be separated and apparently Maxwell felt the same way. He didn't seem to mind either sitting in front of them. Either he was confident that they wouldn't betray him... or he didn't think it would be an issue.</p>
<p>Percy didn't show up though.</p>
<p>It surprised her.</p>
<p>It shouldn't have--he had to have some sort of life, didn't he, outside of the train? Even if she'd been the one to suggest it, that didn't mean that she necessarily really believed that he was a <em>ghost</em>!</p>
<p>Unfortunately though, with Percy not being her, she didn't have anything in the way of closure. All she had was an awkward silence.</p>
<p>She realized then just how complete the silence was.</p>
<p>They had the car completely to themselves. She glanced around to confirm her suspicions, but there really was nothing. Just the three of them on the top floor and no one down below.</p>
<p>More strangely, there were no more conductors. That in itself was normal enough--they tended to move from car to car--but the fact that they'd seen one on the way in...</p>
<p>And the announcements. Normally, someone was on the intercom nearly continuously, announcing the next station.</p>
<p>Thinking back, Andi couldn't really remember the last time she'd heard it. She was pretty sure she'd hear one when she'd gotten on... but after that, it was all sort of a blur.</p>
<p>It wasn't completely silent thought. There were still the sounds of the train and the outside world passing them by. Just nothing inside.</p>
<p>"Do you notice that?" she said. Her voice almost seemed to echo in the emptiness.</p>
<p>Jenny looked over and Maxwell turned back in his seat. "What?" Jenny asked. "I didn't hear anything."</p>
<p>"Exactly," Andi said.</p>
<p>She watched the expressions on Jenny's face as she went through the same thought process that Andi herself had not long before. Gradually, she looked first surprised and then a bit worried. Something strange was going on.</p>
<p>Of course it was.</p>
<p>Something strange was always going on.</p>
<hr />
<p>Percy appeared at the next stop.</p>
<p>It was the same as it had been the other times. One moment he wasn't there, the next he was. This time, he appeared in the seat in front of Jenny, two in front of Andi. By some miracle, he didn't seem to have even noticed Maxwell yet.</p>
<p>"And to what do I own..."</p>
<p>He was cut off midsentence by an inhuman roar from the opposite side of the car. In a blur of motion, Maxwell threw himself out of his seat and across the metal shelves that divided the two sections. Before Andi could react, he'd slid across right at Percy.</p>
<p>Of course, he slid right through him. No matter what else had changed, Percy was still as intangible as he had ever been.</p>
<p>For several long moments, everyone was still. Andi and Jenny stared at Maxwell and Percy, the latter sitting still calmly in his seat, looking down at the former who now lay head first almost completely upside down in the seat.</p>
<p>"Well," Percy said, "that was unexpected."</p>
<p>With a flowing, casual series of motions, he stood in the narrow aisle and reached down to the back of Maxwell's neck. Andi nearly tried to stop him--of course it wouldn't work, he couldn't touch things--but then Percy latched on.</p>
<p>With apparently no more effort than it would have taken for Andi to life her cat, Percy hoisted Maxwell up off of the seat and as close to upright as could be managed in the relatively narrow standing room.</p>
<p>Then, without a moment's pause, he tossed him through the window.</p>
<p>The world seemed to be coming apart at the seams as an unholy crashing sound ran up and down the entire car. It wasn't only the window that Maxwell went through the exploded, but every single window on that side of the car, top and bottom. In between one breath and the next, hundreds of shards of glass took to the air, propelled by the wind whipping by the train as it continued on its merry way.</p>
<p>Most were propelled outward by the force of the impact, but some small percentage at least were blown inward instead. And a small percentage of a whole heck of a lot of glass shards... was still rather a lot of glass.</p>
<p>There was no time to do anything but stare at the thousands of projectiles careening towards her.</p>
<p>Time itself seemed to slow, those selfsame shards taking longer and longer to cover the distance between her.</p>
<p>"Come on," Jenny hissed at her.</p>
<p>Andi shook herself. That wasn't right. Shouldn't she sound slower? Time wasn't working quite right, but she still sounded perfectly normal.</p>
<p>"We have to get out of here," she continued.</p>
<p>Andi looked around the seat in front of her at her friend. It was surprisingly easy. There was no drag at all, nothing to impeded her from moving, although the glass shards soaring through the air were moving as if through molasses. Now that she took a moment to look, the scenery outside the car was moving more slowly as well.</p>
<p>As was Maxwell.</p>
<p>She had to stop and stare at that one in particular. She had just seen intangible Percy, ghost Percy, Percy that shouldn't have been able to touch anything, take poor Maxwell and heave him effortlessly through the window. Now, he just hung there. It seemed like gravity should have taken its hold by now--but the law of gravity appeared to have been repealed. He just hung there.</p>
<p>Andi felt a hand move on her arm and nearly shrieked. It was only turning to see her friend standing there, pocket watch in hand, that she calmed even slightly. It looked different than Andi remembered, a little more red rather than gold... and was that a whisp of smoke.</p>
<p>"Come on," Jenny said. Her voice seemed strained somehow. "I don't know how much longer we have."</p>
<p>Andi looked from her friend's face to the pocket watch--now definitely smoking. She didn't know <em>how</em> her friend had done it, but somehow she'd extended the pocket watch's range to include the both of them. While undoubtedly cool, Jenny had a point.</p>
<p>Still...</p>
<p>Andi shook her head. "I'm not going."</p>
<p>"What?" Jenny said flatly.</p>
<p>"We're here for a reason," she said.</p>
<p>Jenny nodded. "Right. That reason just went right out the window." She glanced out the window, but Andi didn't need the hint.</p>
<p>"Right, and that's pretty good evidence right there that Percy's been lying to us."</p>
<p>Jenny shook her head and shifted the watch from one hand to another. Andi followed worriedly with her gaze. Was it heating up?</p>
<p>"Right," Jenny said, "but you saw what he just did. What are <em>we</em> supposed to do?"</p>
<p>"Fight back!" Andi didn't have much detail beyond that, but this seemed like the perfect opportunity. Jenny had bent the rules--or at least the ones that Andi had thought she'd known--giving them the perfect opening.</p>
<p>"How?" Jenny said. Andi opened her mouth to reply, but Jenny forestalled her. "Perhaps you don't remember, but we can't actually touch him."</p>
<p>"What if attacking Maxwell..."</p>
<p>Jenny shook her head. "We can't chance it. Plus..." she waved her hand. Andi realized then that the glass hadn't been stopped at all, it was still moving. Just much more slowly. But even now, it was starting to speed up. Either that... or the power of the pocket watch was starting to fade.</p>
<p>And when it failed entirely, they were going to have rather a lot of problems to attend to. Sharp ones at that. Perhaps retreating was the better plan after all.</p>
<p>She started to get up, to pull away from Jenny's continued contact on her arm.</p>
<p>Jenny suddenly blinked. "Don't. Do. That." she breathed. She sounded out of breath. Like she'd just been punched in the gut.</p>
<p>Andi shook her head. "What?"</p>
<p>"Let. Go of me." she continued. "It has to be direct contact."</p>
<p>One of these days, Andi was really going to have to catch up on that book. That was definitely on the list of things that would have been really helpful to know. Perhaps they could use it to their advantage somehow?</p>
<p>Then Andi caught sight once again of the pocket watch. It was clearly smoking now, there was no question of it. Jenny could no longer even hold it directly in her hand. She had it by the chain, yet even with just that little bit of metal touching her skin, Andi thought she could hear a faint sizzling sound. That would be her imagination. It had to be her imagination.</p>
<p>"Together then," she said, rising carefully, so as not to dislodge Jenny's grasp on her arm.</p>
<p>It was awkward, navigating around the tight space, but they made it. Just in time too. About halfway down the stairs, it felt like the entire world suddenly lurched. Andi pitched forward, finally losing touch with Jenny completely, but it didn't much matter. There was a tremendous clattering from above and Andi felt tiny pinpricks of something landing slowly on the back of her neck.</p>
<p>Luckily, between the various walls in the spiral stairway, the glass slowed down enough that it didn't even break her skin.</p>
<p>It was <em>loud</em> though.</p>
<p>Andi turned at the bottom of the stairs, looking up the gap between the upper aisles. Percy was standing there with his back to him. The strange thing about him, the thing that she'd always found strange, was that he didn't <em>look</em> particularly transparent. He looked just as solid as her or Jenny. But up until just a few moments ago, he hadn't felt the same.</p>
<p>The breeze blowing in the broken windows was intense. They weren't moving that quickly--far more slowly than a car would have been, although quicker at least than walking speed. The bigger problem was how the car was vibrating. It had never been designed to deal with one window blowing out but not the other, the balance between the two windows was causing issues.</p>
<p>Not as much trouble as Percy though.</p>
<p>He finally turned.</p>
<p>"You have no idea what you've done."</p>
<p>He looked right at them. He didn't even have to track. It was as if he'd known exactly where they were the entire time.</p>
<p>His voice was calm. Eerily so. For all that feat of sheer strength, he wasn't even breathing hard.</p>
<p>Andi wanted to just ignore him, but that point was long past. Not with him staring at them like that.</p>
<p>"Why did you have to bring him here? You were supposed to kill him."</p>
<p>For someone that hadn't even sounded particularly sure that Maxwell was their target, he might at least have mentioned that fact. Of course, he probably knew them well enough for that at least. If he had explicitly <em>told</em> them to kill him, they wouldn't have gone for it...</p>
<p>She was saved having to come up with a response by Jenny. "What is <em>with</em> you two."</p>
<p>As if Maxwell hadn't told them the entire story.</p>
<p>Percy shook his head, chuckling slightly. He still hadn't moved from his original position on the second floor. "I'm sure he told you." He seemed to be half talking to himself at this point. "What else could have convinced you? I should have seen that one coming. Next time. Next time..."</p>
<p><em>Next time?</em> Andi thought. Was he really already moving on to planning ahead? What exactly was he planning on doing with the two of them then?</p>
<p>A thud against the side of the car cut off that train of thought. She spun towards the blown out windows, catching sight of something large and black, keeping up with the train.</p>
<p>She hadn't noticed before--keeping track of Percy was doing that to her--but the train had slowed. It was slight enough that she hadn't felt it, but they were almost stopped now.</p>
<p>That made it easy for the black tentacled beasty to keep pace with the car. Easy to give it enough time to bat against the train car with what would have passed for a shoulder. If it had shoulders. If it even had arms, rather than tentacles.</p>
<p>It was the same demon that had attacked the train before.</p>
<p>This couldn't be a coincidence.</p>
<p>The biggest problem was that it <em>still</em> wasn't enough evidence to condemn either Maxwell or Percy. One of the two of them had attacked them with the demon, but it could have been either.</p>
<p>Percy could have been telling the truth and Maxwell was after the book. He knew that Andi had it and was trying to take her out of the picture.</p>
<p>Just as easily though, it could have been Percy. The demon had shown up at the perfect time, right when Andi had needed convincing. He had fought it off, but what did that really mean? Andi had run, leaving Percy to fend off the demon. If he'd summoned it in the first place...</p>
<p><em>thud</em></p>
<p>The demon hit the side of the train again. For a moment, it tilted up on two wheels completely losing touch with the ground. It slammed back down, tilting slightly back the other way with a terrible screech of metal on metal.</p>
<p>Perhaps who had summoned it <em>wasn't</em> their biggest problem at the moment.</p>
<p><em>thud</em></p>
<p>Finally the train came to a stop. Whether because it had been slowing down the entire time or if the demon had had something to do with it, Andi neither knew nor particularly needed to know.</p>
<p>Percy didn't seem to be paying the demon any mind. He was still focused on the two women on the lower deck. That was damning evidence in itself, wasn't it?</p>
<p>The demon hit the side of the car again, drawing Andi's attention back down. At least it didn't seem to have realized that there wasn't a window to hold it back any more. It was large enough that it could never have fit through the gap, but those tentacles likely could have.</p>
<p>Now that she could see it up close, she could confirm a suspicion she'd had before, but couldn't quite get out of her her head. It was the same type as the one that had dropped out of the sky at them, tentacles and all. It seemed bigger somehow, and hadn't they dealt with that one? But it at least supported the idea that whoever had sent one of them had sent the other. Which really didn't tell them anything...</p>
<p>Then it figured out who to get into the car. As it whipped through the air, Andi only had time to respond because she was facing the correct direction. Jenny, previously facing her, wasn't so lucky. Andi didn't even have time to warn her. Andi ducked down and Jenny was knocked over her head, colliding with her back in mid flight. She hit one of the corners of the doors out of the car and lay still.</p>
<p>Andi didn't have time to worry, not with more tendrils seeking weaknesses in the broken window. One, two, four, half a dozen. Things were going to get ugly in her really quickly.</p>
<p>"Strken." She didn't see anything obviously a weapon nearby, so without thinking about about how mad an idea it was, she reached down to one of the seat right beside her and yanked. It didn't give at first, but pulling more and more strength from the ring, she finally wrenched it up. It came away, the metal itself tearing with a loud grinding noise.</p>
<p>Another tendril whipped passed and she beat it with the chair.</p>
<p>It wasn't anything like the metal bars she was starting to get used to fighting with, but it worked well enough. The tendril paused, beaten back and slithered directly back out the window.</p>
<p>"Jenny," Andi called out, not daring to look down at her friend to confirm her worst suspicions. She didn't have time. If she looked down, she would be clobbered by one of the tendrils.</p>
<p>No response. Another tendril swung by. Andi ducked, hitting it as it passed her. It withdrew, but there were another three where that came from. She wasn't doing any good right here.</p>
<p>As the next tendril whipped by, she dropped face down on the floor. She'd aimed so that she was facing Jenny. Her heart froze for a moment, until she noticed the faint rise and fall of her breathing. At least she hadn't hit <em>that</em> hard. It still couldn't be good if she didn't seem to be rising yet. If there was one thing that the internet had taught her, it was that a head wound that kept you knocked out for any significant amount of time was far worse in real life than the movies.</p>
<p>"Jenny," she shook her arm. That was another thing--you weren't supped to move someone with potential head damage--but they had bigger problems now.</p>
<p>She shifted slightly, making a sound that could have been anything. At least she seemed close to conscious. That was something. "Come on, Jenny, wake up. We have to get out of here."</p>
<p>Glancing up to make sure the tendrils were still whipping above her head and hadn't decided to come down any closer yet, she started inching forward. Interesting, the ring actually made this a much more easy process than she would have expected. it took a lot of effort to crawl, but the ring let her scoot along almost as quickly as she could have walked. It helped her keep her balance so that even when she tgot a hand under Jenny's cooler and started to pull her, it wasn't impossible to get her to move along with her.</p>
<p>She whimpered slightly as she started to slide, her eyelids fluttering. Was that a good sign? A bad one?</p>
<p>There was a solid sounding thud--something organic hitting metal--right behind her. Definitely a bad sign.</p>
<p>She glanced over her shoulder.</p>
<p>Percy was standing there. His arms had elongated into blades. He looked like a fighting machine.</p>
<p>Moment of truth. Had he come to help them? Or to hunt them?</p>
<p>He didn't say a word. A single swing of his blade-arm, cutting only inches from Andi's leg, passing through the floor of the car like butter answered that question. It also meant that he was corporeal again.</p>
<p>"Crap." She started to slide faster. It wasn't going to be enough though.</p>
<p>Jenny was muttering something. Andi couldn't quite make it out. She leaned closer, keenly aware that she was taking time they likely didn't have. But if she were making the effort...</p>
<p>"Aw... gin..." It sounded like she was saying. That didn't make terribly much sense though.</p>
<p>"Augen?" Andi repeated. She could have sworn that she saw Jenny smile.</p>
<p>Then, several things started happening very quickly, too quickly to completely distinguish between one another.</p>
<p>There was a crashing thud from the other direction, right behind her towards the door of the car. She didn't even glance back, but she thought i might have been the doors to the car. Something big had just hit them.</p>
<p>At the same time, one of the tendrils whipped forward right towards Percy. With a smooth motion, he brought up one of his arms and neatly bisected it. One bit whipped back out, spraying a thunk, inky, black fluid as it went. The other smashed into one of the seats and started to wiggle all over of its own accord.</p>
<p>Lovely.</p>
<p>And finally, something made a deep growling sound from somewhere roughly beneath her. She felt it growing beneath her, whatever it was. Rolling out of the way--of whatever was behind her, or beneath her, or the bladed arm behind her she didn't know.</p>
<p>A large dark form, already the size of a reasonably sized dog and growing rapidly appeared where she had been sitting. It took her a moment to recognize it. It was only when it spoke, that pleasant tenor voice belying the rapidly growing bulk, that she determined what in the world was going on.</p>
<p>"I appreciate your moving miss, but why have you summoned me and not the master?"</p>
<p><em>The master?</em> Jenny was going to have a talking to, should they get out of this alive. either that or she was going to come back and haunt the woman.</p>
<p>"We need a distraction," she said.</p>
<p>"From?" He was already larger than she was now and half laying on her arm. Thinking back to how large he was at full size, she began to wonder if perhaps this hadn't been so great an idea. Not that she actually remembered the command word that was necessary to reduce him in size. She could have started spouting relevant phrases in German easily enough, but based on the one activation word that she knew, that wouldn't do terribly much good.</p>
<p>She was saved having to answer by a blade flying through the air right to her face. She didn't have time to react... but didn't need to. Big Red had all the time he needed.</p>
<p>He threw up two big beefy arms--now nearly each as wide around as Andi--up, catching the blade in midair. Andi caught sight of Percy's face behind the blade, a mask of rage disrupting the otherwise normal calm.</p>
<p>He didn't seem at all happy to see an autonomous demon there like that.</p>
<p>It was just the distraction Andi needed though. At the very least, Big Red was now big enough that she wasn't sure Percy even <em>could</em> get around her. So that at least would buy them some time.</p>
<p>"Nice thinking."</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Chapter 16 -- Counterpoint</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/28/chapter-16-counterpoint" /><id>urn:uuid:0f29d408-ee6f-86ae-e08a-a16330980d64</id><updated>2013-12-28T14:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>"One might imagine that the two of you have a good reason for being here?" Maxwell's voice was smooth and disturbingly calm. He didn't seem at all perturbed by the forces arrayed against him.</p>
<p>Of course, his demon <em>was</em> bigger after all.</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>"One might imagine that the two of you have a good reason for being here?" Maxwell's voice was smooth and disturbingly calm. He didn't seem at all perturbed by the forces arrayed against him.</p>
<p>Of course, his demon <em>was</em> bigger after all.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Andi and Jenny shared a glance, but neither spoke. Andi at lest was glad enough for a chance to breath.</p>
<p>"And you, dear sister." He didn't move, he didn't have to, but Andi spun towards where he was looking. Laura stood there, as she'd been expecting. A little less expected was the shotgun in her hands. "I must say, I'm not surprised."</p>
<p>Andi didn't know the first thing about shotguns, but from the way she was holding it Andi thought that perhaps Laura did. She wasn't yet pointing it at anyone in particular, but she was far enough back that it wouldn't take much to swing it to either to Andi and Jenny or to her brother and his demons.</p>
<p>"At least it's not drugs," Laura muttered. She'd clearly spoken loudly enough for all of them to hear, but not to anyone in specific. </p>
<p>Maxwell smiled. "Is that what you thought all of this was about?"</p>
<p>Laura raised the barrel of her shotgun a few inches. Still carefully not pointed at anyone in particular, but now it was closer to Maxwell than it was the women.</p>
<p>Andi took a chance, taking a step forward. "All I want to know is, 'why?'" Anything to keep him talking for a while longer.</p>
<p>Maxwell tilted his head to one side. "Why? Why what?" The behavior was oddly birdlike. </p>
<p>"Why you've been attacking us." The book, obviously. But it would be nice to have a bit of confirmation. </p>
<p>His head tilted further. Any more and it would be pushing unnatural. "Me? You're the ones that broke into my lair." Andi felt her eyes widening. Forget the denial, wasn't his usage of the word <em>lair</em> enough all on its own? Who talked like that? "How about you explain that one first."</p>
<p>"How about not." Laura's shotgun was definitely aimed at Maxwell now. Or at least at the massive chest of his demon. "How about <em>all</em> of you explain to me what in the <em>hell</em> is going on?"</p>
<p>It was far too late now, but Andi was regretting not telling her a bit more. It didn't put them in any better of a situation than Maxwell's. </p>
<p>"I'm a sorcerer. Someone who summons demons." Maxwell said. "This is a demon. As is that." He gestured towards Big Red. Perhaps it wouldn't have been the end of the world to tell her. She seemed to be taking it well so far.</p>
<p>"I'm guessing there are a few less... obvious ones on your two friends there," he continued. "Oh, they're sorcerers as well."</p>
<p>The shotgun wavered, angling slightly towards Big Red and Andi. Jenny remained further to the side. </p>
<p>Perhaps just telling her might not have been such a great idea. </p>
<p>"Okay, you sound crazy," Laura said. But she kept glancing from Big Red to the demon with the silver hammer and back. It was a bit harder to call something crazy when a larger than life example was standing right there in front of me. She started to lower the shotgun. "But then again, maybe I'm the crazy one."</p>
<p>Maxwell's smile grew. "Oh now, dear sister. You're not mad. Not at all. The universe is just a bit stranger than you've been previously led to believe." </p>
<p>He turned his attention back towards Andi. "You on the other hand, I'm not so sure about. Perhaps <em>you</em> are the crazy ones."</p>
<p>Andi shook her head. A good 'no you' would have been her first thought, but she wasn't planning on sinking to that level. "We didn't start this. Maybe here, now. But you're the one that attacked me on the train. You're the one that sent the Morris-demon after us in the bookstore. You're the one that attacked us in the street."</p>
<p>She was on such a roll, it seemed such a pity to abandon it. But one look at Maxwell's expression caught her dead in her tracks. He didn't look the least bit guilty or triumphant. Honestly, he just looked confused. </p>
<p>"What in the world are you going on about?"</p>
<p>"Demon attacks. We have it on good information that you were the one behind them."</p>
<p>"Good information?" </p>
<p>She just nodded. </p>
<p>"Well you might want to consider firing your informant. Why in the world would I be after <em>you</em>?"</p>
<p>The sheer condescension in his voice stopped Andi before she could so much as think up a response. Even after the two times that they'd fought with his demons--at least theoretically giving him an idea of their abilities--he appeared to think they were <em>beneath</em> him. </p>
<p>It was true enough that they'd only been at their craft for a few weeks... But that didn't mean they were completely without merit. After all, they'd at least been able to hold their own, hadn't they.</p>
<p>He was looking right at her now though, a serious expression on his face. "Percival. That's your informant, isn't it?"</p>
<p>Andi froze. </p>
<p>How in the world...</p>
<p>"Thought so. This is about that damn book again, isn't it?"</p>
<p>She didn't even have to say anything. Her silence was apparently confirmation enough for him.</p>
<p>His previously calm demeanor shattered as he swore up a storm. Or at least Andi had to assume that was what he was doing, just from the tone--she couldn't quite place the language. It had a vaguely Germanic flavor to it. Strangely, perhaps one word in ten sounded familiar, although none that she could particularly pick out. </p>
<p>His sister was staring at him, as if seeing him for the first time. The gun had dropped completely now, pointed back at the ground. If it had been up to Andi, she would have had it right back at Maxwell after that storm... but it wasn't up to her. </p>
<p>Then, just as quickly as it had started, he stopped. From one moment to the next, he ceased cursing and smoothed his face out. It took a few moments more to completely calm his face and for his color to return more to normal, but it was still an impressive transformation.</p>
<p>"I'm sorry," he said, back in the same perfectly calm English he'd affected when he'd first appeared. "I shouldn't have done that."</p>
<p>Andi was just having problems all around bringing words to mind. That hadn't been at all how she'd expected him to react.</p>
<p>Luckily, Jenny wasn't similar afflicted. "I take it the two of you know each other, then?"</p>
<p>Maxwell nodded slowly. "You might say that."</p>
<p>"How?"</p>
<p>He smiled. It was disconcerting how quickly he'd shifted. So angry, so calm. "You know, that's one heck of a story. How about we all sit down and discuss it."</p>
<p>Andi was really having a problem figuring out how to deal with him. But this at least was something that she could latch on to... "Are you crazy?"</p>
<p>He popped his head to one side yet again. Back in bird mode. "I don't think so." He really sounded like he was giving the idea some serious consideration. "But then again, that's exactly what I would say either way, isn't it."</p>
<p>Andi shook her head, more in disbelief than denial.</p>
<p>"But seriously. I don't want to fight you. I can't speak for you, but I would hope that you'll at least do me the favor of hearing what I have to say."</p>
<p>"I for one, would love to hear you <em>all</em> explain a bit of this," Laura said. She still had her shotgun ready for the slightest provocation, but she wasn't pointing it at anyone any more at least. So that was something. </p>
<p>"There are going to be a few conditions," Jenny said. </p>
<p>Andi jerked her head towards her friend. Was she seriously considering listening to the man? She was still dealing with the whole idea of someone who seriously used the word 'lair'. </p>
<p>Still, perhaps she had a point. At the very least, it would be interesting to how he responded to whatever the conditions were. </p>
<p>"First condition," Jenny started. "No demons." That certainly got Andi's attention. "That includes both demon tools and the ... large one." He was already nodding, even before Jenny finished with, "We'll of course do the same. I trust you also have a way of verifying this?"</p>
<p><em>Wait, what?</em> Jenny had a way of telling if there were any demons nearby? She hadn't mentioned anything like that... Nor could Andi recall the book saying anything of the sort. That would have been extremely helpful to know a little while ago. If they could have proven that Maxwell was indeed a sorcerer without even going into his lair... Great, now she was thinking it too. </p>
<p>Still, Maxwell was nodding. So either such a way actually existed or he was willing to let Jenny go along with her bluff. </p>
<p>"Second, your sister will mediate." Maxwell looked over at his sister, considering. "And she will keep that shotgun of hers."</p>
<p>His eyebrows certainly shot up at that one. In that at least, Andi could totally see where he was coming from. Perhaps Jenny was betting that Laura would come down on their side in any arguments that might ensue? She had seemed pretty keen on getting them in to investigate in the first place... but he was family.</p>
<p>Still...</p>
<p>"Fine," Maxwell said. "Anything else?"</p>
<p>"You have to guarantee that we can safely leave here at any point."</p>
<p>That was one that Andi could get behind. It might be a problem in that if he decided that he didn't want to deal and would rather attack them then what was to say that he couldn't just <em>disagree</em> with this condition as well. Still, something told Andi that he would stick to his word. She had absolutely nothing more to go on than that and a gut feeling of course, but that was better than nothing. </p>
<p>He smiled. It was more sharky than pleasant, but at least he agreed. "Deal. Shall we?" he asked, gesturing vaguely at the demons.</p>
<p>At first Andi wasn't entirely sure what he meant. Luckily Jenny picked up at it more quickly. "Attenuo," she said. Big Red gave her a look... Was that disapproval? From a demon? But he was already shrinking. In a few minutes, he would be back in action figure form.</p>
<p>If Maxwell deactivated any of his demons, he didn't do it with command words. He looked like he was concentrating on something but that was about it. His demon--they'd never gotten a name for it--didn't shrink. It just outright disappeared, dropping the hammer to the ground. It didn't disappear, even after a few minutes just lying there on the ground. That at least supported the idea that they were two different demons.</p>
<p>Then he started taking off his jewelry.</p>
<p>It was worse even than Andi had suspected. She'd seen the rings and earrings, but he had at least two belts along with all manner of smaller pieces in his pockets, similar to the pocket watch that they'd made earlier. She couldn't help but stare. Either he was trying to bluff and show that he'd made more demons than he'd actually made--or they were <em>seriously</em> out matched here. </p>
<p>She briefly considered keep her ring. After all, they couldn't really be able to detect if she was still carrying a demon, could they?</p>
<p>But no. She couldn't chance it.</p>
<p>She muttered the activation under her breath. She walked over to where Big Red's still form--much smaller now--lay on the ground and picked up.</p>
<p>She turned back to Jenny, who was holding the pocket watch and mirror in her hands. "Want me to take them to the car?" She made sure to stand between her and Maxwell, just to try to keep some semblance of parity between their two collections. Not that there was much of a chance of that any more...</p>
<p>Jenny nodded and handed over her demons. Andi watched her almost slump as she handed them over. It was strange, but she knew exactly what her friend was feeling. She hadn't handed her ring over yet, but even with it off of her finger she felt somehow... naked. Vulnerable. Still, it was all for the best.</p>
<p>She just had to keep telling herself that...</p>
<hr />
<p>Their meeting took place in the cafe. It gave Maxwell the potential home field advantage, but Andi couldn't think of a better option. </p>
<p>For that matter, Andi couldn't quite figure out Laura was thinking about the entire situation. If it were her, she wouldn't be keen about her brother's situation. But it wasn't her. She seemed entirely too calm about the whole situation, but that could change in a flash... Either way.</p>
<p>The were just going to have to make the most of it.</p>
<p>They sat across from each other one of the four seat tables. Andi and Jenny were on one side, Maxwell was on the other. Laura sat off to one side on a barstool, cradling her shotgun. She was just far enough away that she could shoot any one of them before they could get to her--should it come to that.</p>
<p>"So. Spill." Jenny's directness was refreshing. "How about you start with why in the world we should trust you."</p>
<p>Maxwell half grinned. "Hey, you're the ones who invaded my personal space--without provocation, I might add."</p>
<p>"Let's start with that," Andi said. "You say that we attacked without provocation. We say that you attacked us several times. At least three."</p>
<p>"Or so you've said. And I assume you have some sort of evidence..."</p>
<p>Andi and Jenny shared a quick look. "You're a sorcerer," Andi finally managed. "And judging from your ... collection, you've had a fair bit of practice at this." He inclined his head slightly. "So far as we know, you're the only sorcerer around that could do it."</p>
<p>He nodded. "True enough. I'll admit; I know nothing about the attacks you mention. But if they're anything like what you expect, yes. They would have been well within my power..."</p>
<p>"See!" Jenny burst out, half rising out of her chair.</p>
<p>He raised an eyebrow. That was all, but Jenny sat back down. "I would like to think that if I really wanted you dead, I would have succeeded." He said it so matter of factly, it took a moment for the threat to actually sink in. </p>
<p>"What if you didn't want us dead?" Andi said softly. "What if you just wanted something from us?"</p>
<p>He considered her for a moment. Finally he said, "so do have it." It wasn't a question. It didn't need to be.</p>
<p>Andi flushed. She hadn't been <em>that</em> obvious, had she? "What do you mean?"</p>
<p>He shook his head. "Too late to back down now. You might as well have told me right out. You have <strong>Computational Demonology</strong>."</p>
<p>There was a cough from Laura direction. As if on cue, all three at the table turned to look at her. She lowered her gaze slightly. "Sorry. It's just... I mean... Seriously? <strong>Computational Demonology</strong>? That's got to be the most ridiculous..."</p>
<p>Andi smiled slightly at that at least. It was pretty crazy when you thought about it. She still hadn't quite worked out why the title was as it was. It wasn't like demons were computers in any particular sense of the word. Beings of pure Mind, they were close at least. They would follow orders without question, even to their own detriment. </p>
<p>But in one area at least, they far surpassed any computer she'd ever worked with--they were smart. They could make their own tactical decisions, making the best of their orders--to whatever point <em>best</em> could even be defined. </p>
<p>Still. It was amusing.</p>
<p>"That's actually a pretty neat story," Maxwell said, pulling their attention back to him like a magnet. "How the book got its name. Perhaps I'll tell you one day." </p>
<p>So subtle. That crack about how much longer he'd been doing this than them. Smooth.</p>
<p>"In any case," he continued. "That changes everything."</p>
<p>"It really doesn't," Andi cut in. "We already knew you were after the book."</p>
<p>He paused for a moment. "<em>I'm</em> after the book? Let me guess, Percival again?"</p>
<p>Andi considered, but was there really anything to gain from hiding it? She nodded.</p>
<p>"Thought so. And obviously you would believe him. Why?"</p>
<p>For the first time, Andi really thought about it. Unfortunately, she wasn't particularly thrilled with what she found. "Because he sent me the book."</p>
<p>"You don't sound so sure about that."</p>
<p>She had to admit, it was a bit of a circular argument. She'd trusted Percy because he'd known a lot about the book and everything he'd said seemed to make sense. And he claimed at least to have sent the book her way--but what proof did she really have about that? It had appeared just after she'd first seen him on the train...</p>
<p>"No."</p>
<p>"No?"</p>
<p>"No, I can't believe that. It all fits. You can't just come in and say that it wasn't him that sent the book into my life."</p>
<p>He smiled. "Fair enough. What if I have an alternate theory for you?"</p>
<p>She shrugged. "Sure."</p>
<p>"What if the book came to you of its own accord."</p>
<p>She shook her head. "That's what Percy already said. He said that the book chooses who to teach next--and that sometimes it gets it wrong." She couldn't help the edge her voice took by the end of that. </p>
<p>Unfortunately, that just made him even smile even more. "He really got you good, didn't he?"</p>
<p>Andi couldn't say anything. The words just wouldn't come. </p>
<p>"The book doesn't care about good or evil. It's a book. What's more, it's a demon. Ask your friend there, a demon alone doesn't distinguish. They can be used for evil, sure, but a demon <em>isn't</em> evil."</p>
<p>Jenny nodded slowly. The problem was, she and Andi had had that conversation already. They knew that demons--especially the baser ones--were tools. But that didn't really change anything, did it? The book could very well have been <em>designed</em> to search out good people. Couldn't it?</p>
<p>"I know what you're thinking," he said. Andi's head jerked up. How could he? "Let me assure you. The book would love to choose good people--if it could. Good people are just easier to work with in the long term." </p>
<p>She started to agree, but he stopped her with a single raised finger.  "The book cares about power. It's as simple as that. It will work with you in order to make you a more powerful sorcerer. The only reason that it would tend to choose more stable, good people is that they tend to survive longer."</p>
<p>Andi blinked. "What?"</p>
<p>"Sorcerers have real power. Power that few other human beings will ever have. If you're going to use that power in what you might consider an evil way, sooner or later someone is going to hunt you down. What does that do to all of the effort the book put in then?"</p>
<p>She had to admit, he had a point. She didn't like it, but it made at least as much sense as Percy's explanation. The problem though, was that the two just weren't compatible.</p>
<p>"Okay, say you're telling the truth. Why would Percy send me the book then?"</p>
<p>Maxwell shook his head slowly. "I don't think he did."</p>
<p>"What do you mean?" </p>
<p>"In all likelihood, the book sent itself."</p>
<p>"Huh..."</p>
<p>"It's a demon. You haven't even begun to scratch the surface with all that it's capable of."</p>
<p>Andi wasn't quite sure what to say to that. This was all getting a little off topic though. "Still, that doesn't prove anything. You say you weren't the one who attacked us--attacked me. Can you prove it?"</p>
<p>He considered for a while. Finally, he said, "No."</p>
<p>"I knew it!" Jenny shouted.</p>
<p>"No, you don't get it. How could I possibly prove it? It's not like I could give an alibi for where I was, that's the advantage of demons. You can send them anywhere. You can send them to do anything. And you don't even have to be there."</p>
<p>"There has to be a way though," said Andi. "Can't you track a demon? Figure out who summoned them in the first place."</p>
<p>"Sure," he said, "but what if I didn't summon them? What if I got someone else to summon them for me?"</p>
<p>"You're not helping your case," Andi said.</p>
<p>He shook his head. "Just trying to be honest."</p>
<p>It would have been a lot easier to hate the guy if he didn't seem so very much like Andi herself. She had to admire the directness, even if it was making the whole thing a lot more difficult.</p>
<p>"Okay then," she said. "So what is it between you and Percy then? You keep hinting at something and its obvious that you don't like him..."</p>
<p>He stood smoothly, not meeting the women's eyes. In a few steps, he was across the room. Laura followed him with her eyes, but she seemed as undecided about the whole situation as Andi. It was a little weird that she was taking it as well as she was, but Andi guessed that having a few demons quite <em>that</em> obvious would go a long way towards overcoming disbelief.</p>
<p>Standing with his back to all of them, Maxwell said, "You know, I was a lot like you once. Innocent. Just getting into demons. Young. Idealistic."</p>
<p>Andi couldn't quite think of what to say to that. She didn't think of herself that way. But then again, she wouldn't, would she?</p>
<p>"That all changed when I met Percival." His voice was rough. "He gave me the book. Told me I could do great things in the world; all I needed was a little more training."</p>
<p>"Wait," Andi cut in, taking a few steps over to stand by him. "You didn't start with the book?"</p>
<p>He shook his head. "No. Originally, my training was a little closer to home." He turned all of the way then, but not towards Andi. He was looking at his sister. "My mother was a sorcerer."</p>
<p>Laura's face was frozen. There was obviously something there... Andi just didn't know what. But Maxwell didn't stop there.</p>
<p>"He killed her."</p>
<p>Complete silence.</p>
<p>No one so much as moved a muscle.</p>
<p>This wasn't at all what Andi had been expecting. The way that Maxwell had talked about Percy... It had been clear that there'd been something between the two of them, but this? This was far worse than anything she'd thought.</p>
<p>Maxwell finally broke the silence. "Now perhaps you see why I'm not particularly thrilled with the idea of Percy sending you against me. He must be finally trying to finish what he started, all of those years ago."</p>
<p>Andi found her voice. "But why? Why now? Why at all?"</p>
<p>Maxwell shook his head. "I don't know why. I never asked him why he did it, I just ran. I ran and ran and never looked back."</p>
<p>"That's why you left," Laura said. Her voice was quiet. "And here all this time, I thought you just fell in with the wrong crowd. I thought you were just trying to lose yourself..."</p>
<p>He smiled slightly, but it was a bitter expression. "Oh, you're not wrong. I was trying to lose myself. Did a pretty good job too. Made it as far as New York. It took a while before I even dared to dream that Percival would have moved on. I still had contacts though, back on the coast. Eventually, he went quiet. It took me years to believe that he was really gone."</p>
<p>Andi cut in. "Wait, gone? How could he be gone? He can't leave the trains..."</p>
<p>He turned that bitter expression on her. "Oh yeah? Who told you that?"</p>
<p>Andi started to reply, but she didn't need to. They all full well knew the answer to that particular question. </p>
<p>"Oh he can leave the trains all right. He just has a thing for them though. That's where we met, most of the time, back when... Anyways."</p>
<p>"So what is he anyways?"</p>
<p>It was Maxwell's turn to look surprised. At least it was preferable to bitterness. "What do you mean? He's a sorcerer."</p>
<p>Andi shook her head. "That's not possible. He's something else entirely..."</p>
<p>"I promise you, he's as human as you or I."</p>
<p>Andi wasn't about to argue the merits of humanity with him. Not when something so definitely wasn't adding up. </p>
<p>"Then why can I walk right through him."</p>
<p>That one comment was enough to strike him dumb. He just stared at Andi. "That's not possible."</p>
<p>Andi shook her head. Apparently no matter how far you made it as sorcerer, some things never changed.</p>
<p>"Yeah," Jenny jumped in. "I did it to." Everyone turned to her and seemed to shrink slightly into herself. "I mean, I put my hand right through him as well."</p>
<p>"He's human, I'd swear to it."</p>
<p>Andi shook her head. "Maybe he was when you knew him. Surely that book has something about overcoming that particular ailment?"</p>
<p>Jenny raised an eyebrow at her, while Maxwell said, "Ailment? Humanity?"</p>
<p>"It was a joke," said Andi. "But the point stands. Surely there's some way that you can go from human to... something else."</p>
<p>But as she looked from Maxwell to Jenny, she could tell that neither of them had any ideas in particular. Based on her own limited knowledge, it would have been possible to augment one's form with a demon--even to turn yourself temporarily intangible. But permanently? That was something else entirely. </p>
<p>Perhaps he was just messing with them. The more Andi thought about it the more she thought that perhaps Maxwell may have had a point about Percy. One or the other of them was lying. They had to be. If she could force the two of them into a confrontation...</p>
<p>Andi had a sudden flash of insight. "What if he's a ghost?" It was such a ridiculous idea. Completely impossible of course. Except... "Is that even possible?"</p>
<p>Jenny was shaking her head, but Maxwell didn't look quite so sure.</p>
<p>"Maxwell?" Andi asked.</p>
<p>"I don't know," he finally said. "It shouldn't be..."</p>
<p>"No," Jenny cut in. "It can't be. A human being is Body, Mind, and Soul. All in one. You just can't have one without the other two."</p>
<p>Andi hadn't read quite <em>that</em> far in the book. It was actually a bit disheartening to hear. She went to church regularly enough, but she was never entirely sure about the whole idea of an afterlife. It sounded like a nice enough idea in theory, but if there was really such a thing, surely someone would have had some sort of proof by now...</p>
<p>But now Jenny was saying that it didn't exist at all?</p>
<p>She was still talking though, "There was a whole chapter on it in the book. When you die, the bonds break down. The Body--our material form--breaks down. It didn't say what happens to the Mind or Soul, but it was quite clear that they can't stay here."</p>
<p>That was something at least. "But if he doesn't have a Body any more, then he'd fade, wouldn't he?" Andi asked. "Just like a demon?" </p>
<p>Jenny nodded at her. The look on her face was a little more like a mother approving of her daughter's schoolwork than Andi would have liked, but at least she'd gotten the theory down.</p>
<p>Her mind was still whirring though. "But what if he did have an anchor?" Andi asked. "Just like our demons?"</p>
<p>Maxwell nodded slowly. "I guess it's possible. You really think he's a ghost? All of you?" He looked from Andi to Jenny, then over Jenny's shoulder... And froze.</p>
<p>Andi turned to follow his gaze. It took her a moment to realize what he was looking at. Or rather what he <em>wasn't</em> looking at.</p>
<p>Laura was gone.</p>]]></content></entry><entry><title>Chapter 15 - Revelation</title><link href="http://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/12/25/chapter-15-revelation" /><id>urn:uuid:a9363f22-d7d0-2cd2-4fa3-8b51c8ced6ce</id><updated>2013-12-25T14:00:00Z</updated><summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Andi blinked. "Break into..." she said under her breath.</p>
<p>"I wasn't sure you were coming back," Laura said, speaking right over her. </p>
<p>"We did come back," Andi said slowly.</p>
<p>Laura nodded. "I see that."</p>
<p>"No. Earlier. We were already here."</p>
]]></summary><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Andi blinked. "Break into..." she said under her breath.</p>
<p>"I wasn't sure you were coming back," Laura said, speaking right over her. </p>
<p>"We did come back," Andi said slowly.</p>
<p>Laura nodded. "I see that."</p>
<p>"No. Earlier. We were already here."</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Laura's smile shuddered for a moment, but didn't quite fade. "Yeah, yesterday. You said you were going to pick up a few supplies."</p>
<p>Jenny stepped up beside Andi and put an arm on her shoulder. "That's right. And we did."</p>
<p>Andi opened her mouth, but didn't say anything. </p>
<p>Laura looked between one and the other. Her smile wasn't doing quite so well anymore, but she seemed determined to keep it up. "How about we go inside and talk." She gestured towards the winery. </p>
<p>Andi immediately bristled. Her trap sense was tingling all sorts now. If they went into the building, they would be more constrained--and if Maxwell really was setting a trap it would be the perfect location for it. </p>
<p>Unfortunately, they didn't really have a reason <em>not</em> to go with her. For the time being at least, Jenny seemed willing to go along with Laura's pretense that she hadn't seen them this morning. </p>
<p>It didn't stop Andi from feeling the ring on her finger though. She didn't need to specifically touch it to activate it, but it was comforting in a way.</p>
<p>Inside the shop, they were alone. Whoever the other woman they had seen the very first time they'd come to visit was gone. Just the two of them and Laura.</p>
<p>She gestured to one of the tables and took the seat across from them. "So, what do you have in mind?" she asked.</p>
<p>Andi and Jenny shared a glance. "You don't remember anything, do you?" Jenny said. So much for pretending that they didn't know anything.</p>
<p>She looked from one of them to the other. Her expression continued to fall. "I don't know what you're talking about."</p>
<p>"I think you do," Jenny said.</p>
<p>She just shook her head.</p>
<p>"Please," Andi said, reaching out to put a hand on Laura's arm. "Where were you this morning?" Ultimately, the hand on the arm was serving two purposes. First, she was hoping to comfort her a little bit at least; getting her guard up wasn't likely to help anyone. But second, she had a sneaking suspicion.</p>
<p>All for naught though. If her arm had passed right through Laura's arm, she would have had reason to worry. But she skin was every bit as solid as Andi's, albeit slightly cool to the touch. That could easily have been explained by her waiting outside for them though.</p>
<p>"I..." She paused, obviously considering. "I was as here all morning." Something in the way she said it...</p>
<p>"What is it?" Andi prompted.</p>
<p>"I... don't remember."</p>
<p>Andi and Jenny shared a glance. Just like when Andi had gone to meet Percy. Right at the same time that there was a bit of a difference between what Laura thought she had done and Andi and Jenny knew she had. It was perhaps the best evidence so far that Maxwell was behind everything so far.</p>
<p>Evidence that he was a sorcerer and a nasty piece of work at that... Fairly obvious. But this was a much more direct link.</p>
<p>"We came back this morning," Jenny said. "We already went with this."</p>
<p>Laura shook her head. "That... can't be right. I haven't seen you since yesterday."</p>
<p>"We went to the shack," Jenny said. "Had a bit of a fun time. Turns out your brother is a ..."</p>
<p>"Piece of work," Andi cut in. If Laura didn't remember the events of the morning, it was possible she was still innocent when it came to the realms of demonology. For better or for worse, Andi wanted to try to preserve that innocence, at least for a little while.</p>
<p>Again, Laura considered the both of them. Perhaps she wasn't quite so slow as Andi had thought. A fair point. She seemed though to come down on the side of giving them another chance. "If you went to the shack, then you can tell me what's inside."</p>
<p>Neither Andi nor Jenny said anything at first. It wasn't that they didn't have an answer, but rather that neither was sure how the other would react. Unfortunately, both took the initiative at the same time. </p>
<p>"Yes," Andi said, right on top of Jenny's "No."</p>
<p>The two looked at each other. "I guess..." Jenny said, right on top of Andi's "Well, not really..."</p>
<p>In other words, operation 'don't make the sister of a potentially dangerous sorcerer suspicious' was a bust.</p>
<p>"So what really happened?" Laura finally asked.</p>
<p>Andi took the lead before Jenny could say a word. "It looks a lot like a fancy bachelor pad. Projector, nice couch, the works."</p>
<p>Laura nodded her head. "That sounds about right."</p>
<p>"And then there's the basement..." Jenny said. Andi tried to hide a smile. She didn't think she would have chosen to be quite so direct, but it worked out. </p>
<p>Laura's response was slow. "What basement?"</p>
<p>"There's a nice elevator; goes down to a nice complex completely underground." Laura was shaking her head slowly. "Probably a few floors. Bigger than this place at least."</p>
<p>"That makes sense."</p>
<p>It was Andi's and Jenny's turn to share a look of surprise. "It does?" Jenny finally asked.</p>
<p>"Yeah. He renovated the place a few years back. It never quite made sense how many trucks of dirt they took out of the place."</p>
<p>That made sense enough. Of course, there was one wrinkle... "Then why didn't you say anything last time?" Andi asked. </p>
<p>Laura blinked. "Last time?"</p>
<p>"Right," Jenny said. "You don't remember."</p>
<p>Laura shook her head. Suddenly, she was standing. "Either you're outright lying to me... Or something really strange is going on."</p>
<p>Andi stood with her. To her surprise, she found that she was barely suppressing a smile. <em>Strange</em> was something that Andi was becoming increasingly used to. </p>
<p>"It's easy enough to prove though," Laura continued. "All we have to do is break into my brother's shed."</p>
<p>"Again..." Jenny muttered under her breath.</p>
<p>Not quietly enough though apparently. Laura said with a smile, "again then."</p>
<hr />
<p>Just in the short time it took to walk to the shed, Andi was already half convinced that the entire morning's activities must have been a dream. She just couldn't very well reconcile the Laura of the morning who'd gone the elevator and disappeared while fighting a demon with the Laura who apparently had no idea regarding any of that. </p>
<p>Still, when they got to the shed, it looked pretty much the same as it had in the morning. Then again, it hadn't changed when they'd gotten into it. </p>
<p>The three of them stopped a fair bit away and looked up at it. After a while, Laura said, "It doesn't look like much from out here."</p>
<p>"It's bigger on the inside," Jenny said with a smirk. Turning to Andi, she said, "How about we just cut to the chase?"</p>
<p>Andi turned to her. "No more lies?"</p>
<p>"Well," she said. "Not many anyways." She pulled out the mirror and held it out for Andi. "Care to do the honors?"</p>
<p>Laura's expression couldn't have been any more perfect. </p>
<p>"Don't mind if I do," Andi said. "Geister."</p>
<p>Without looking back, she held the mirror out and walked right towards the shed. She thought she heard a gasp from Laura when she didn't slow, but then she was through.</p>
<p>The experience was a strange one. Previously, when she'd used the mirror to walk through the bathroom door back in her apartment, she hadn't felt anything. This time, there was a slight tingle and a feel of resistance. It felt vaguely like pressing through a sheet of staticky plastic. </p>
<p>For just a moment, she felt a jolt of sheer terror run through her. Had Maxwell expected their return? Of course he had. Of course he'd known...</p>
<p>Then she was through.</p>
<p>Strange. </p>
<p>Still, she was inside. The interior of the shed looked exactly the same as it had during the morning. Quickly scanning to make sure no one was hiding in wait, Andi turned back to the door. There was a control panel on the back of the door with obvious controls for opening the door. </p>
<p>A touch of a button and the door slid open.</p>
<p>Laura and Jenny were standing right on the other side. Jenny had a slight smirk on her face; while Laura was standing there with her mouth hanging open. Even if she had seen the events of the morning, that still had to have been surprising--to see someone walk right through the door like that.</p>
<p>"How..."</p>
<p>"Like I said," Jenny said with a smile. "Magic."</p>
<p>Andi rolled her eyes and headed over to the couch. She wanted to find that remote again. </p>
<p>"So you're saying, there's an entire underground complex down there," she heard Laura saying. "And that I went down there with you this morning."</p>
<p>"Exactly," Jenny said."</p>
<p>"So... what happened then?"</p>
<p>Andi still couldn't quite guarantee that she wasn't just a good liar--really good--but she was at least starting to believe.</p>
<p>"We had a... bit of trouble," Andi said. She paused, midway through lifting a pillow looking for the remote. "Um. Jenny? What's the point again?"</p>
<p>Jenny opened her mouth to speak, but no words came out. She closed it again without saying a word. </p>
<p>"After all," Andi continued. "We came back to rescue Laura..."</p>
<p>"Wait, what?" Laura said. "<em>Rescue</em> me? From what?"</p>
<p><em>Oops.</em> For the moment, Andi elected to ignore the question. "But if she's here now, we don't have to go down again just now. We have time to prepare."</p>
<p>Jenny was nodding slowly. "We could use a few more..."</p>
<p>Andi mentally finished her sentence. <em>Demons.</em> "Still, with a bit more time."</p>
<p>Laura refused to back down. Taking a step forward to place herself directly between Andi and Jenny, she turned to the former with her hands on her hips. "What did you <em>mean</em>, rescue me?"</p>
<p>"Well..." Back to hesitating. </p>
<p>Hesitations suddenly cut short by a solid thud, shaking the entire room and nearly knocking Andi off of her feet.</p>
<p>"What in the..." It could have been any of them that spoke, the thought was so universal. </p>
<p>Another thud, followed shortly by three ringing bells one after another. Then they knew all too well what the sound had been.</p>
<p>The top of the elevator shaft was rising out of the floor. It was almost certain that the elevator itself would be shortly behind.</p>
<p>Andi turned to Jenny, both of them backing away. "You don't think..."</p>
<p>"It couldn't fit..."</p>
<p>Laura was backing away too. Even if she wasn't lying and hadn't actually been with them this morning, there was only so many ways to react to people backing away the way they were. "What in the world is going on?"</p>
<p>And smiled at her, albeit halfway between a grin and a grimace. "Trouble," was all she said. Another bell--if she remembered the previous events correctly, this meant the elevator was here now. "Run!"</p>
<p>She didn't even wait to see if the other two were following. She just ran. </p>
<p>Through the door and out into the yard, she ran. She heard at least one pair of footsteps following her and had to assume that both of them were. There were far more solid sounds even further behind that. Something large was back there... It didn't take much to imagine what that might be. </p>
<p>A fair distance form the shed, Andi turned back. She was right in one at least. Both Laura and Jenny were right behind her, running to catch up. She was a little surprised that she'd kept such distance from the both of them. Still, that surprise turned to naught when she caught site of what was following them.</p>
<p>"Um... Jenny?"</p>
<p>Jenny slowed, looking up to catch Andi's gaze. She must have seen something, as she stopped almost dead in her tracks and spun to look behind her.</p>
<p>Andi heard her swear--she completely understood the feeling. </p>
<p>Between the two of them, Laura finally came to slow as well. She turned and stopped dead. "What in the hell..."</p>
<p>And knew that feeling. She knew that feeling all too well.</p>
<p>Interestingly enough, the thing following them wasn't the demon they'd fought during the morning. Nor was it the tentacled beasty that Andi had run from by herself back on that train. This one was something entirely different.</p>
<p>This one looked an awful lot like the woman they'd come back to rescue. But of course it couldn't be. The other Laura--Andi was already thinking of her as 'their' Laura--had been with them the entire time. What was more, the new comer had something that quite clearly identified her as something not altogether natural. </p>
<p>She had the demon's silver hammer. </p>
<p>"Are you seeing what I'm seeing?" Andi asked no one in particular.</p>
<p>"Yeah, but I'm not sure I'm believing it," Jenny said.</p>
<p>Laura--their Laura--said nothing. Andi would have given rather a lot to figure out what she was thinking. </p>
<p>"That's... not possible." She finally said.</p>
<p>"Welcome to our world," Jenny said.</p>
<p>The other Laura stopped. She was a few yards on the other side of their Laura, then Jenny and finally Andi a few yards back from there. The four of them stood, all staring at one another.</p>
<p>Other-Laura had the silver hammer held lightly, almost idly in one hand. </p>
<p>That more than anything was setting Andi's sense on edge. </p>
<p>She had felt the impacts of that hammer against the walls down beneath their feet. She had felt the air waver as it passed by.</p>
<p>A normal human being couldn't possibly be holding that hammer so lightly. Even with the ring, she wouldn't have been surprised if she could even lift it at all.</p>
<p>"Hey Laura..." Andi called out.</p>
<p>She wasn't sure exactly what outcome she expected, but it still sent a chill up her spine when both Lauras answers simultaneously. "Yes?"</p>
<p>Andi elected to ignore the further Laura and direct her question to the nearer one. "Just checking. You don't have a twin do you?"</p>
<p>Laura half turned, but not enough so that she would lose sight of said twin. She shook her head slightly, saying "Well, at least I didn't think I did."</p>
<p>"Of course not," the other Laura said. "She's clearly an impostor."</p>
<p>It was such a classic situation that Andi could have laughed. It was only that she didn't think either Laura would take kindly to that. </p>
<p>A pair of twins where there couldn't possibly be twins, each claiming that the other was the fake. In this case though, the decision was easy. </p>
<p>One Laura had been with them the entire afternoon. The other had come from the sorcerer's den, so to speak. </p>
<p>One was holding a silver hammer that shouldn't have been humanly possible. The other had nothing in her hands, which now that Andi was watching were shaking ever so slightly.</p>
<p>On of them seemed genuinely concerned with her brother's well being and those two strangers that had come to help him. The other had a cold hint to her voice, barely noticeable at first, but obvious given a moment's thought.</p>
<p>Andi made a snap decision, hardly a decision at all. Stepping forward, she took up position side by side with Laura, facing the silver-hammer-Laura down. She had a hand on her ring. Not necessary to activate it... but much more so to keep a positive state of mind.</p>
<p>A moment later, Jenny joined them. Now it was the three of them, facing off against the one and her hammer. Not exactly a fair fight--if fight it came to.</p>
<p>Other-Jenny smiled.</p>
<p>It was a wicked grin, devoid of any real mirth. </p>
<p>With a simple shrug of her should, she set the hammer to swinging. In a single effortless motion, she had the hammer spun it to catch her other hand. A few tapping motions that would have looked significantly less threatening had Andi not known just how heavy that hammer was--and how lightly other Laura was tossing it around.</p>
<p>It was looking like they were in for a fight--and not a pleasant one.</p>
<p>"Strken," Andi said, her voice steadier than she expected. A moment later, she heard Jenny activating the pocket watch. They were going to need a bit more than that though... "Big Red?" she asked.</p>
<p>Laura was looking from one of them to the other, but nothing so far had been physically impossible--other than the mere existence of the other Laura. The hammer was close, but it could have been lighter than it looked, rather than heavier. </p>
<p>Big Red though; that would be something else entirely. That would be a line that once crossed they wouldn't very well be able to recover from.</p>
<p>"Fine," she said. She reached around to her purse--Andi had been wondering where she'd been hiding it--and pulled out the foot tall red action figure.</p>
<p>"Um, guys?" Laura said. "What's going on?"</p>
<p>Neither answered. They didn't have to. Instead, Jenny calmly tossed the figure into the air and said a single word: "Augeo."</p>
<p>Big Red immediately began to grow. It took only a matter of moments until he stood, full height, just as big and red as he had been the night before. </p>
<p>Laura's eyes grew big as well. Too late to take it back now...</p>
<p>Unfortunately, the other Laura took Big Red's appearance as a sign to make a few changes of its own. Completely silently, she began to grow. By the time Big Red's transformation was complete, the other demon's--there was no doubt about it now--was only just beginning. </p>
<p>It began with the muscles. The effect was strange, something like a series of balloons inflating one after another from one arm to the other and then down the legs. She looked strange unbalanced while the changes were going on, skin stretching to nearly the breaking point on one side and the other completely human.</p>
<p>After that, she grew. It was almost a direct scaling, everything growing at once, expanding in all directions.</p>
<p>As she grew, she darkened, skin deepening to first red and then nearly black. It was definitely the same demon they'd seen this morning. </p>
<p>"Well, that answers that question," Jenny said. </p>
<p>Andi knew exactly what she was getting at--she'd been wondering exactly how Laura could have disappeared this morning and not remembered a thing in the afternoon.</p>
<p>It all made a lot more sense if they'd not actually talked with Laura in the morning. If she <em>hadn't</em> been taken by the demon, but rather <em>was</em> the demon. </p>
<p>Of course that didn't help the current situation.</p>
<p>The first time, they'd barely made it away with their lives. This time, they had a real innocent to protect.</p>
<p>They may have had Big Red, but given the sheer size and scope of the thing in front of them--Big Red didn't look quite so <em>big</em> anymore. </p>
<p>With a roar, the newly transformed demon lifted its hammer and charged.</p>
<p>Big Red let loose a roar of his own and ran forward to meet the other demon. He may have been a few feet shorter and a fair bit less muscular, but with a single swift motion, he'd caught the hammer and held it in place.</p>
<p>For a second, two, three, the demons held steady, both pushing as hard as their unnatural forms would allow. Then, ever so slowly, demon-Laura started to gain the upper hand. Inch by inch, the silver hammer was forced downwards.</p>
<p>"A little help here..." It took Andi a moment to realize that it was Big Red speaking. That pleasant tenor was still entirely too nice to be coming from such an ugly form. </p>
<p><em>Right. They had more than one demon at their disposal.</em></p>
<p>With a cry of her own, Andi ran forward to join the fray.</p>
<p>Big Red managed to keep the hammer under control just long enough to give Andi and Jenny an opening. The hammer was touching his nose when Andi landed her first punch.</p>
<p>She couldn't reach much higher than the beast's waist, so instead she went for the back of the knee. With a blow that should have been enough to cripple an elephant, she hit the demon.</p>
<p>Her hand bounced. </p>
<p>It felt like a steel sheet covered in a thin layer of rubber. Just enough give to keep her from breaking her hand, but nowhere near something that she was going to be able to punch through. </p>
<p>Unfortunately, it didn't appear that either Jenny or Big Red was having much better luck. That morning, Jenny had been using a steel cable or something of the sort along with her amazing speed to rip through the demon's flesh, but she had no such weapon this time. Andi couldn't actually tell what she was doing this time--seeing nothing more than a blur--but whatever it was, it wasn't working</p>
<p>Big Red on the other hand, at least had a chance. He couldn't quite match the other's raw strength, but he at least seemed to be marginally quicker. He could keep the worst of the blows from landing on either Andi or Jenny, at the cost of a few solid blows to himself. He was bleeding from a number of wounds, but was grinning all the while. If Andi didn't know any better, she was would have said that he was enjoying herself.</p>
<p>It would all be for naught though, if none of them could actually land a blow.</p>
<p>"You don't by any chance have your gun?" Andi asked the air. </p>
<p>Jenny stopped for a moment, suddenly seeming to appear right to her side. She took a big breath--she had to have been running hard even with the speed boost--and shook her head. No such luck it seemed. </p>
<p>Not that she was sure a gun would have worked in the first place. Still, it would have been nice.</p>
<p>They still needed a weapon. She turned around, scanning the surroundings. Grape bushes? Too hard to get hold of, even harder to use as a weapon. Their car? Too far away, the demons would just get out of the way. The fence?</p>
<p>That might just work.</p>
<p>Best yet, it made a certain sort of sentimental sense. </p>
<p>Crossing the ground in a few steps, she reached into the full power of the ring and ripped a chunk of the fence cleanly out of the ground.</p>
<p>She heard a gasp from behind her--Laura most likely. She would just have to get over it though. Save her life first, worry about property damage... later.</p>
<p>She took a few minutes to tear off what was left of the fence, leaving only the main pole itself. It wasn't quite as simple a metal bar as she'd used twice before, there were still a few jagged edges along the top part. With any luck, that would make it even more viscous of a weapon. </p>
<p>"Andi, duck!"</p>
<p>For once, she didn't even think. She ducked.</p>
<p>A blur of silver swished through the air right where her head had been a moment before. </p>
<p>She swung her new weapon from her back, landing a raking blow along the black rubbery flesh. It wasn't perfect, but for the first time, she at least managed to break the skin. A thin spray of dark blood covered the ground.</p>
<p>The demon roared.</p>
<p>Standing over her the way it was, with her flat on her back on the ground, it looked even bigger. It seemed as big as an elephant. An elephant that seemed dead set on ending her life.</p>
<p>A crack split the air and a vicious looking wound appeared in the demon's side. It was twice as long and much deeper long than the blow Andi had landed. Andi hadn't seen her coming in, but she caught a glimpse of a blur moving away.</p>
<p>It was enough though, to distract the demon. Rolling as quickly as she could, she put some distance between herself and it. Bounding to her feet, she took stock of the situation.</p>
<p>Big Red wasn't looking too good. Dark bruises--even darker than his deep red flesh--dotted his skin and one arm hung at an unnatural angle. Then again, his limbs had never quite seemed natural to begin with.</p>
<p>Jenny, Andi couldn't quite see. She kept flitting from place to place, never even taking a moment to slow down and catch her breath. At least not that Andi could see. Although at the speeds she was moving, she could rest several hundred times as quickly as well. She could be taking a minute's breather in the blink of an eye. That really was a neat ability.</p>
<p>Laura--the real Laura--was gone.</p>
<p>Andi felt a rush of deja vu. It was just like the first time. Laura was gone again. And the first time, that had apparently been because she was the demon... Andi didn't think she could deal with it if that were the case yet again.</p>
<p>Speaking of their demonic <em>friend</em>, they were actually starting to do some damage. They'd landed nothing more than a fair collection of cuts and scrapes, but even that was beginning to take its toll. It seemed a little slower and it wasn't quite throwing that hammer around with quite the same reckless abandon.</p>
<p>They might actually be able to do this. </p>
<p>Of course that was right when things went from bad to worse.</p>
<p>"Stop!"</p>
<p>The voice was a new one and came from far off to the side, back from the direction of the shed. It was a man's voice, which at the moment left really one option.</p>
<p>All four of them turned. The two demons stopping beating on each other for a moment. Jenny slowed. She was still jittering, which meant she was still accelerated. She was just standing in one place. It had to be maddening, watching everyone creep along so slowly, knowing that if you slowed down you'd lose your one biggest advantage. </p>
<p>Maxwell--it had to be Maxwell--was surprisingly average. After everything, Andi had built up a mental picture of him that was somewhat... bigger. More impressive. He just looked normal. Mid twenties, a touch below average height and thin. He had the same darker complexion and hair that his sister did, albeit cropped short.</p>
<p>The most interesting thing about him was a surprising collection of jewelry. Andi thought herself relatively progressive, but it still stuck out. A half dozen earrings in each ear, three or four necklaces, and enough bangles and belts to furnish a small army--although what a small army would do with such armaments was anyone's guess.</p>
<p>Andi felt a sinking feeling. That was one thing that the book had made clear enough, the more solid a physical form you could give a demon, the longer it would last. Metals tended to work better; jewelry had the advantage of not looking out of place when you went out among the general populace.</p>
<p>Well, until you were wearing <em>quite</em> so many all at the same time.</p>
<p>She had no way of telling how many of them housed demons and how many were just a distraction. Best case? He had many times as many demons as Andi and Jenny had between the two of them. Worst case? Every single one was a demon...</p>
<p>And he'd just stopped all of them with a single word.</p>
<p>"Come here," he said again.</p>
<p>Andi and Jenny shared a glance, but of course he was talking to his demon. The not-Laura. Step after rumbling step, the demon covered the ground back to its master. It was swinging the hammer slowly front to back. Even that revealed a terrifying strength in those massive arms. </p>
<p>Andi took the opportunity to move nearer to Big Red and Jenny. She was ready to square off against the others, even if it was mad. They had barely been able to hold their own against Maxwell's demon, now they had not only the demon but its master as well? With a dozen or more additional demons on his side?</p>]]></content></entry></feed>