<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Neil Gaiman on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/30/neil-gaiman/</link><description>Recent content in Neil Gaiman on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/30/neil-gaiman/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stardust</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/30/stardust/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/30/stardust/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For every nine years, the fold from Beyond the Wall and over the hill set up their stalls, and for a day and a night the meadow played host to the Faerie market; and there was, for one day and one night in nine years, commerce between the nations.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I do love Neil Gaiman&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. He does weird/creepy/dark perfectly well. Stardust is a great example of &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a dark fairy tale, a la the Brothers Grimm. A city on the border between Victorian England and Fairie. The contrast of worlds. An adventure full of princes and witches, woodland animals, magic, and of course: fairy tale love.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“So, having found a lady, could you not have come to her aid, or left her alone? Why drag her into your foolishness?&amp;quot;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Love,&amp;rdquo; he explained.&lt;br>
She looked at him with eyes the blue of the sky. &amp;ldquo;I hope you choke on it,&amp;rdquo; she said, flatly.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a great listen. A bit weird, since apparently it was also originally published in graphic novel format and is also supposed to be a great movie. Looks like I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to go through it a few more times.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Good Omens: The Nice and Accurate Prophecies of Agnes Nutter, Witch</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/good-omens-the-nice-and-accurate-prophecies-of-agnes-nutter-witch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/good-omens-the-nice-and-accurate-prophecies-of-agnes-nutter-witch/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Well,” said Crowley, who’d been thinking about this until his head ached, “haven’t you ever wondered about it all? You know—your people and my people, Heaven and Hell, good and evil, all that sort of thing? I mean, why?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“As I recall,” said the angel, stiffly, “there was the rebellion and—”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Ah, yes. And why did it happen, eh? I mean, it didn’t have to, did it?” said Crowley, a manic look in his eye.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Anyone who could build a universe in six days isn’t going to let a little thing like that happen. Unless they want it to, of course.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Oh, come on. Be sensible,” said Aziraphale, doubtfully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“That’s not good advice,” said Crowley. “That’s not good advice at all. If you sit down and think about it sensibly, you come up with some very funny ideas. Like: why make people inquisitive, and then put some forbidden fruit where they can see it with a big neon finger flashing on and off saying THIS IS IT!?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The ANTICHRIST is born. ARMAGEDDON is coming! And all that stands in the way (for better /and/ for worse) is an angel/demon best friend combo who happen to /like/ living here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh it&amp;rsquo;s so good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve read quite a bit of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/24/terry-pratchett/">Terry Pratchett&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/30/neil-gaiman/">Neil Gaiman&lt;/a>, so reading a co-lab between them. Plus, I actually watched the &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Good-Omens-Season-1/dp/B089XW1Z6Y" target="_blank" rel="noopener">show on Amazon&lt;/a> a while back, well before reading this book. From that order at least, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the particularly faithful and well done adaptations. Both being rather enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really can&amp;rsquo;t get Michael Sheet and David Tennant out of my head though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which is not a bad thing. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun ride, political/religious in exactly that fun somewhat blasphemous irreverent sort of way. I enjoy watching the ever increasing highjinks, as more plots get involved. The hundreds of years descendent of the one truly accurate prophetess. The Witch Finder Army&amp;ndash;somewhat reduced in manpower. The Four Horsemen&amp;ndash;and the dedicated deliveryman who sets them on their way. Plus the Other Four. And of course, the Antichrist himself. All these powers&amp;ndash;and no one ever taught him how to use them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun ride. You could do far worse than giving it a go!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Marvel 1602</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/17/marvel-1602/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/17/marvel-1602/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sir Nicholas Fury, with his servant Peter Parquagh. Stephen Strange, master of medicines. A blind man jumping around in the night. Sister Wanda, with her red habit. Witchbreed. So many new takes on old friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh. And dinosaurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/marvel-1602-8f5230.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As things escalate, it turns out there may very well be a reason everything is out of time… as there always had to be in a comic book. It’s neat when you get there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read. It’s certainly an interesting ride.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Wake</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/11/the-wake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 14:19:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/11/the-wake/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so as all things must end, so too do the Endless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After uncountable years, Dream of the Endless has died. Another Dream has risen to take up the mantle (as must be), but before, it&amp;rsquo;s time to say goodbye to the Dream we&amp;rsquo;ve all come to know over the last 10 volumes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Kindly Ones</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/09/the-kindly-ones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/09/the-kindly-ones/</guid><description>&lt;p>More than ever before, we&amp;rsquo;re seeing things from the past Sandman stories come back to haunt Dream. We have Lyta Hall and her baby (from way back in the beginning), Nuala of the Fae, and the Corinthian (man he&amp;rsquo;s creepy) all back and ready to wreck havoc (in wildly varied ways). And that ending&amp;hellip; knowing there&amp;rsquo;s only one more book makes me really look forward to finishing this series, as weird as that sounds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/sandman-9-01.jpg" alt="Sandman-9-01">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Worlds' End</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/08/worlds-end/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/08/worlds-end/</guid><description>&lt;p>A Tavern at the World&amp;rsquo;s End. Travellers from all manner of realities, thrown together. Stories around the fire.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/sandman-8-01.png" alt="Sandman-8-01">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brief Lives</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/05/brief-lives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/05/brief-lives/</guid><description>&lt;p>Destruction of the Endless is missing (and has been missing for a very long time). Delerium&amp;ndash;the strangest by far&amp;ndash;seeks him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh it&amp;rsquo;s quite a story. I think this is the most we&amp;rsquo;ve seen about the other Endless yet, and it&amp;rsquo;s truely bizarre. I think that Delerium being a core point of view helps that along nicely.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fables &amp; Reflections</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/02/fables-reflections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/02/fables-reflections/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Death was a little older than Dream. Things had the potential to die before
they had the potential to dream.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Endless are so fascinating. As it this story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Game of You</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/31/a-game-of-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/31/a-game-of-you/</guid><description>&lt;p>This time around, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll just start with the summary from Goodreads:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Take an apartment house, mix in a drag queen, a lesbian couple, some talking
animals, a talking severed head, a confused heroine, and the deadly Cuckoo.
Stir vigorously with a hurricane and Morpheus himself and you get this fifth
installment of the Sandman series.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Season of Mists</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/30/season-of-mists/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/30/season-of-mists/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To reign is worth ambition though in Hell: Better to reign in Hell, then
serve in Heav&amp;rsquo;n.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Wherein Lucifer (yes that Lucifer) is, after thousands of years, &lt;em>done&lt;/em> with his job (yes that job) and decides to leave his keys to Dream to figure out what the Hell (heh) to do with.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dream Country</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/25/dream-country/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/25/dream-country/</guid><description>&lt;p>A bit of an odd one. Despite the series being named for Dream, herein we have a handful of mostly disconnected stories with Dream as only a minor character. They&amp;rsquo;re still absolutely fascinating and do give us a much deeper look at the world (both the analogue to our own world and the Dream). The second is especially funny, Dream as a cat. Sure. :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Doll's House</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/25/the-dolls-house/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/25/the-dolls-house/</guid><description>&lt;p>Herein we get a bit more worldbuilding, seeing how Dream is taking back his world after decades of capture. For the most part, we deal with the fallout around a family of one of the women from Sandman 1 (the one who found herself pregnant), but there&amp;rsquo;s also a very well told story of a man granted immortality&amp;ndash;on the condition that he checks up with Dream once every hundred years at the same old pub. Also a &amp;lsquo;Cereal&amp;rsquo; convention (that took me longer than it should have). Of course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s well written, beautifully (in the creepy sort of way at times) illustrated, and well worth the read. Onwards!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preludes &amp; Nocturnes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/16/preludes-nocturnes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/16/preludes-nocturnes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sandman is often considered one of the best of the best when it comes to graphic novels and&amp;hellip; for good reason. It&amp;rsquo;s very very good. It&amp;rsquo;s got immortal &amp;lsquo;anthropomorphic personifications&amp;rsquo; (Dream is the main character, but we also get a bit of Death), a crazy deep/complicate mythos, dark and creepy imagery, and a wacky awesome storyline. Pretty much right up my alley. There&amp;rsquo;s little I could do better than the blurb on Goodreads:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In PRELUDES &amp;amp; NOCTURNES, an occultist attempting to capture Death to bargain
for eternal life traps her younger brother Dream instead. After his 70 year
imprisonment and eventual escape, Dream, also known as Morpheus, goes on a
quest for his lost objects of power. On his arduous journey, Morpheus
encounters Lucifer, John Constantine, and an all-powerful madman.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Neverwhere</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/27/neverwhere/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/27/neverwhere/</guid><description>&lt;p>Neverwhere is an excellent example of the &amp;lsquo;hidden world&amp;rsquo; sort of urban fantasy &amp;ndash;where someone, often from our own world stumbles upon a door or falls through the cracks and finds themselves in another world, just off the beaten track from our own. Harry Potter. Narnia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a lot of amusing uses of language, particularly in taking the London Underground stops literally. Earl&amp;rsquo;s Court is literally the Court of an (the?) Earl of London Underground. Blackfriars houses the Monastery of the Black Friars. It&amp;rsquo;s a really neat way to tie the real world into something alltogether more fantastical.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Coraline</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/31/coraline/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/31/coraline/</guid><description>&lt;p>Before I ever read Coraline, I watched the movie and read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/05/26/american-gods/">American Gods&lt;/a>. I quite enjoyed the former, while the latter was&amp;hellip; not exactly my favorite. So I was cautiously optimistic that I would like Coraline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, consider the optimism well founded. I&amp;rsquo;ll never know if I enjoyed the book more because of the film or if I would have liked it as much had I read it first. So it goes. As it stands, I got a nice mix of the book&amp;rsquo;s / Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s way with words combined with the wonderfully bizarre visuals from the film. It made for quite the experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>American Gods</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/05/26/american-gods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/05/26/american-gods/</guid><description>&lt;p>American Gods falls on the unfortunately long list of books that I wish were better. It won (or was at least nominated) for a whole pile of awards[1]. It&amp;rsquo;s by an author who&amp;rsquo;s works in other genres I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed (e.g. the movie Corline or his episodes on Doctor Who) and who seems like a solid person in real life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t get into it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>