<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michael Schur on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/michael-schur/</link><description>Recent content in Michael Schur on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/michael-schur/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Man on the Inside</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/05/a-man-on-the-inside/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/05/a-man-on-the-inside/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was a fun show. Created by the Michael Schur (who also did the Good Place, check it out!) and with many overlapping cast members from the Good Place, I had high hopes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I learned that it was about a man learning to live in an assisted living center, I &amp;hellip; wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure. Was there a supernatural element?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then when it dropped (in the first episode and all the promotional materials, so I don&amp;rsquo;t see it as a spoiler) that he&amp;rsquo;s going in to assisted living as a SPY! Well, I&amp;rsquo;m intriuged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun show, hilarious at times (especially with just how &lt;em>bad&lt;/em> Charles is at all this) and sad at others (it&amp;rsquo;s about old folks. Death, loneliness, and memory loss are just part of it). But it&amp;rsquo;s quite the ride all the way through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do love the cast, Ted Danson as Charles is amazing. I enjoyed Mary Elizabeth Ellis
as his daughter Emily, even if her family troubles were a weird B plot. Lilah Richcreek Estrada as Julie did &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to solve this problem whatever it takes&amp;rsquo; wonderfully, and it was fascinating to see Stephanie Beatriz as head of staff Didi. I really need to watch Brooklyn Nine-Nine at some point&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then all of the old folks inhabiting those halls&amp;hellip; Man those were some performances. I honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize any of them from other roles but I expect there are some well known names in there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful show and goes by quick. Well worth the watch!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>