<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2023 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2023/</link><description>Recent content in 2023 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2023/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Oppenheimer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/">Barbenheimer&lt;/a>!&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Oppenheimer: Albert? When I came to you with those calculations, we thought we might start a chain reaction that would destroy the entire world&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
Einstein: I remember it well. What of it?&lt;br>
Oppenheimer: I believe we did.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That is a long, dense film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s complicated and there are &lt;em>long&lt;/em> stretches with little going on by talking and setting. But&amp;hellip; man, is it thematic talking and setting?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s all about the story of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J.%20Robert%20Oppenheimer">J. Robert Oppenheimer&lt;/a>, the so called &amp;lsquo;father of the atomic bomb&amp;rsquo; and&amp;hellip; well, how he earned that title. I knew bits and pieces of the story, but having watched this, bits and pieces were apparently all I knew. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of amazing how many of the names I recognize from physics classes were involved in either the project or Oppenheimer&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was at times difficult to follow, there are a ton of jumps (mostly stylistically) and it makes me wander just how much of that was actually problems in Oppenheimer&amp;rsquo;s mind and how much was style. That&amp;rsquo;s not really clear, even by the end of the movie. I certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised though if he was having issues like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Einstein: When they&amp;rsquo;ve punished you enough, they&amp;rsquo;ll serve you salmon and potato salad, make speeches, give you a medal, and pat you in the back telling all is forgiven. Just remember, it won&amp;rsquo;t be for you&amp;hellip; it would be for them.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I think the cast was another impressive part of this film. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t speak to just how perfectly accurate it was, but I think Cillian Murphy was an excellent casting for Oppenheimer. He&amp;rsquo;s got just the right amount of strange charisma to really pull you into the film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matt Damon and Robert Downey Jr. were solid roles, enough to actually remind me why they&amp;rsquo;re considered solid actors&amp;ndash;and not just playing themselves as some do. Alden Ehrenreich I thought looked familiar, but had to look up where I&amp;rsquo;d seen him recently (Solo and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2013/02/17/beautiful-creatures/">Beautiful Creatures&lt;/a> (that&amp;rsquo;s been a while)). There are just a bunch of people I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in other things before&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, quite the solid movie. I think I learned something and enjoyed the process of doing something, which is something always worth saying. It&amp;rsquo;s long, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth a watch!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Personally, I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s any reason to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/">Barbenheimer&lt;/a> it though, although it is amusing.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Last note:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Oppenheimer: Now I am become Death, the destroyer of worlds.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The first time he says it&amp;hellip; was surprising and kind of weird. I expect they were going with &amp;rsquo;everyone is waiting for him to say the line&amp;hellip; psyche!&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave it at that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Barbie</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/11/barbie/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/">Barbenheimer&lt;/a>!&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Barbie is quite a movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An entire world populated entirely by every single variant of Barbie and Ken&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. All named Barbie and Ken, all living their lives in the most &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo;re sort of toys and sort of real&amp;rsquo; way possible. Drinking your morning coffee? Tip the empty cup to your mouth. Need to get out of the second floor? Just jump down! And of course&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ken: I thought I might stay over tonight.&lt;br>
Barbie: Why?&lt;br>
Ken: Because we&amp;rsquo;re girfriend and boyfriend.&lt;br>
Barbie: To do what?&lt;br>
[pause]&lt;br>
Ken: I&amp;rsquo;m actually not sure.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh this movie is weirdly(ly on point) at times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we get the &amp;rsquo;toy in the real world and DOESN&amp;rsquo;T UNDERSTAND THINGS&amp;rsquo; scenes. I feel like a lot of those were dialed up &lt;em>just&lt;/em> to the edge of over-parody, but really, it somehow just works? Barbie is so out of sorts and just doesn&amp;rsquo;t realize it&amp;hellip; until she does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things go wrong&amp;hellip; and suddenly the movie isn&amp;rsquo;t just the Barbie movie anymore. Now, it&amp;rsquo;s all about Ken. And the PATRIARCHY.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ken: To be honest, when I found out the patriarchy wasn&amp;rsquo;t just about horses, I lost interest.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I knew that we were going to have some major conflict there, in a world (almost) entirely populated by Barbies and Kens&amp;hellip; who else is there? But it&amp;rsquo;s kind of weird. I feel like Ken honestly has more of a story arc for a lot of the movie does than Barbie. Which&amp;hellip; feels kind of against the entire point of the movie?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It works though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course, we have the big Mattel in the room. Of &lt;em>course&lt;/em> we have to have a dig about companies making toys for girls run by powerful men. But man, did they dial that one up to 11 on a rediculous scale. A bicycle built for&amp;hellip; a boardroom. That is all. Will Ferrell is a delight as the CEO. After Lord Business in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/02/15/the-lego-movie/">The Lego Movie&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; this is a weird role to be typecast as, but it really works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of casting, I did love Margot Robbie as Barbie&lt;sup id="fnref:5">&lt;a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Barbie: [in tears] I&amp;rsquo;m not pretty anymore!&lt;br>
Gloria: What? You&amp;rsquo;re so pretty!&lt;br>
Barbie: I&amp;rsquo;m not stereotypical Barbie pretty!&lt;br>
Narrator: Note to the filmmakers: Margot Robbie is the wrong person to cast if you want to make this point.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>She just &amp;hellip; epitomizes Barbieness in the movie? I don&amp;rsquo;t know who esle could possibly have carried that role quite as well. Kate McKinnon as Weird Barbie was great as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Ryan Gosling as Ken&lt;sup id="fnref:6">&lt;a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. This one I think could have been differently cast with less issue, but he still did a wonderful job.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that stood out was how at times uncomfortably on point Barbie managed to be on various social commentary issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sasha: You&amp;rsquo;re a fascist!&lt;br>
Barbie: How can I be a fascist?&lt;br>
[through tears]&lt;br>
Barbie: I don&amp;rsquo;t control the railways or the flow of commerce&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
[cries]&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh this movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it was a movie better than it had any right to be and far better than I expected, even with generally positive reviews going on. Worth watching. Not sure it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/12/oppenheimer/">Barbenheimer&lt;/a> it though&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>For All Mankind: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/11/for-all-mankind-season-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/11/for-all-mankind-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>On MARS! And all caught up!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The 4th and last (as of my watching) final season of For All Mankind sees humanity not only surviving, but THRIVING on Mars, beginning to reach out into other smaller bodies for resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s kind of awesome and kind of depressing, to see where the writers think humanity could have been. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a bit wishful, but still. If only&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, things are, of course, not at all rosy. We have some major issues with class divisions, yet more tensions between the US and (still surviving) USSR, and the mess that is the North Koreans landing first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite a lot of drama and a world I love to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to season 5 if (hopefully when) we get it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Across the Spider-Verse</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/30/spider-man-across-the-spider-verse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/05/30/spider-man-across-the-spider-verse/</guid><description>&lt;p>I still think the first one was the better movie, but man I still enjoyed this one. Biggest negative: I&amp;rsquo;d totally forgotten this is a part one / to be continued. That was&amp;hellip; not fun to find out right at the end with no current release date for the next sequel!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a great film. I love seeing more of Miles and Gwen, especially a couple of years later. I love the introduction to even more Spider-People (and not-people even, oh Peter Parkedcar) and the introduction of even more multiverse concepts that brings to mind. And the idea that there are fixed points in each Spider&amp;rsquo;s story that makes them who they are is great fuel, both for this and I hope the eventual sequel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Visually, this story once again shines. I love seeing all the different styles, especially when you have more than one on screen at once.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now, on seeing this, I learn that Marvel 2099 with more Miguel O&amp;rsquo;Hara is a thing. I should read that next!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward! (And hopefully not too long to a sequel.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Honor Among Thieves</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/08/dungeons-dragons-honor-among-thieves/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/08/dungeons-dragons-honor-among-thieves/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Edgin: We must never stop failing, because the minute we do, we&amp;rsquo;ve failed.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s such a fun movie. It takes the delightful chaos of an idolized Dungeons and Dragons session, leans hard into the worldbuilding of the Forgotten Realms (without strictly requiring you know anything about it); and cranks up the visuals up to 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s gobs of humor, some pretty crazy action scenes, and a big &amp;rsquo;evil skybeam&amp;rsquo; action scene that every movie nowdays seems to have. Really, there are just so many great individual scenes. The initial view of the prison&amp;ndash;and the prison break. Fighting a certain dragon. Asking exactly five questions of the dead (it goes exactly as you&amp;rsquo;d expect).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characters and casting were really quite fun too. Chris Pine&amp;rsquo;s Edgin the bard really sells teh movie, but I loved the over the top paladin feel of Regé-Jean Page&amp;rsquo;s Xenk and Daisy Head&amp;rsquo;s bonkers Sofina. Michelle Rodriguez as a barbarian? Yes please. Hugh Grant as Hugh Grant? A delightful surprise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s great. Give it a watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Xenk: You may have forsworn your oath, but your oath hasn&amp;rsquo;t forsworn you.&lt;br>
&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
Edgin: Just because that sentence is symmetrical, it doesn’t make it not nonsense.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Secret Invasion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/secret-invasion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/secret-invasion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s fine. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see some spy stories in the MCU, even if they&amp;rsquo;re light on the spy stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have Fury again, even if (in hindsight) I was perfectly fine without knowing more about Fury&amp;rsquo;s backstory. And the introduction of Super Skrulls? Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really need that in the MCU. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fan of it in either of the previous story lines I&amp;rsquo;ve read them in (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/13/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-6-frightful/">Ultimate Fantastic Four&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/03/04/runaways-vol.-8-dead-end-kids/">Runaways&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you know what I really think bothers me about the Skrull? All through the Infinity Saga, we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to believe they&amp;rsquo;ve been here, working with Fury. And we never heard even a hint about them. I get it. They’re shapeshifters. The perfect secret agents. Still weird to add something like this after 15 years&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If it had been something tied into each movie and show, leading up to an event (like the Infinity Saga), it could have worked. As it is, it really feels like the concept of an MCU is working against them here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/05/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol.-3/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Rocket: Someday I&amp;rsquo;m gonna make great machines that fly. And me and my friends are gonna go flying together, into the forever and beautiful sky.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was fun. If you liked the previous two Guardians of the Galaxy entries (or especially the Holiday Special), I expect you&amp;rsquo;ll love this. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t care for them, there&amp;rsquo;s a chance!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ant-Man and the Wasp: Quantumania</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/21/ant-man-and-the-wasp-quantumania/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/21/ant-man-and-the-wasp-quantumania/</guid><description>&lt;p>Upside: It&amp;rsquo;s visually super colorful and weird and it&amp;rsquo;s got a lot of potential for the new MCU Phase 5!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Downside: It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; weird and chaotic and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really fit with anything else we particularly know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; fine? I enjoyed watching it, but it&amp;rsquo;s in the category of MCU films that I doubt I&amp;rsquo;d watch again unless I&amp;rsquo;m doing a full rewatch (which is getting to be quite the endeavor).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>