<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2008 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2008/</link><description>Recent content in 2008 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2008/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Doctor Who: 2008 Specials</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/30/doctor-who-2008-specials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/30/doctor-who-2008-specials/</guid><description>&lt;p>The 2008-2010 specials!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-next-doctor">The Next Doctor&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Where the Doctor meets&amp;hellip; the Doctor?!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p> Jackson Lake: There she is. My transport through time and space. The TARDIS!&lt;br>
 The Doctor: You&amp;rsquo;ve got a balloon.&lt;br>
 Jackson Lake: TARDIS. T - A - R - D - I - S. It stands for Tethered Aerial Release Developed in Style! Do you see?&lt;br>
 The Doctor: Well, I do now. I like it. Good TARDIS.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And you know? Dervla Kirwan as Miss Hartigan gets a bit of flack, but if you ignore for a moment the history of the &lt;span class="spoiler">Cybermen&lt;/span>
, she&amp;rsquo;s quite the fun row. Plus, an absolutely giant robot in old fashioned london down. What&amp;rsquo;s not to love?&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="planet-of-the-dead">Planet of the Dead&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Doctor, sent through a portal to a desert planet, where he has to depend on a temporary companion in jewel thief Lady Christina to get back home.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Christina: It&amp;rsquo;s Christina Da Souza. To be precise it&amp;rsquo;s Lady Christina Da Souza.&lt;br>
The Doctor: Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s handy because I&amp;rsquo;m a lord.&lt;br>
Christina: Seriously, lord of where?&lt;br>
The Doctor: It&amp;rsquo;s quite a big estate.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s yet another case (Voyage of the Damned was another one) where a companion for a special would have been &lt;em>fascinating&lt;/em> to keep around. So it goes though.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-waters-of-mars">The Waters of Mars&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Fixed points in time don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>really&lt;/em> make sense for the Doctor. Especially given how it turns out in the end. But still, a giant marsbase and soggy zombies? What&amp;rsquo;s not to love?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it&amp;rsquo;s yet another one of those episodes that digs just into how broken and&amp;ndash;at some level&amp;ndash;insane the Doctor is, after all those years and triumphs. And failures.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Adelaide: But you said we die. For the future. For the human race!&lt;br>
The Doctor: Yes, because there are laws. There are laws of time. Once upon a time there were people in charge of those laws but they died. They all died. Do you know who that leaves? &lt;em>Me!&lt;/em> It&amp;rsquo;s taken me all these years to realize that the laws of time are &lt;em>mine&lt;/em> and they will obey me!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Quite the set up for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-end-of-time-parts-one-and-two">The End of Time (Parts One and Two)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Tennats finale is coming&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Doctor: Even if I change it still feels like dying. Everything I am dies. Some new man goes sauntering away&amp;hellip; and I&amp;rsquo;m dead.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But on the way, we have Wilfred Mott as the Doctor&amp;rsquo;s companion? Yes please.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Doctor: I&amp;rsquo;m going to die.&lt;br>
Wilfred Mott: Well, so am I one day.&lt;br>
The Doctor: Don&amp;rsquo;t you dare!&lt;br>
Wilfred Mott: Alright, I&amp;rsquo;ll try not to.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And add to that, the Master (back from he dead) and perhaps&amp;hellip; something even worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh that&amp;rsquo;s an intense pair of episodes. Even if it&amp;rsquo;s more than a &lt;em>touch&lt;/em> overdone at times (as all of ennats finales seem to be).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this time around, we get a victory lap of sorts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so Ten ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Doctor: I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On to Eleven!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doctor Who: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/21/doctor-who-season-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/21/doctor-who-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh Doctor Who.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This such a wonderful season (and I do say that about a lot of the seasons).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First off, we have Donna back as the companion. I do love that she&amp;rsquo;s not pining after the Doctor as others have been want to do. And she&amp;rsquo;s just so delightfully snarkily&amp;ndash;human. They really do play off each other well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, we have &lt;em>The Fires of Pompeii&lt;/em>, with both a future Doctor and a future companion (in other rolls), &lt;em>Planet of the Ood&lt;/em> (delightfully creepy), &lt;em>The Doctor&amp;rsquo;s Daughter&lt;/em> (actually his wife&amp;hellip;), &lt;em>Silence in the Library&lt;/em> (well, okay maybe she is), and &lt;em>Midnight&lt;/em> (for such a limited set it&amp;rsquo;s so intense).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are just so many solid episodes this season!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward, to the 2008-2010 specials! Man those can be a pain to find/categorize. I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure why they weren&amp;rsquo;t just considered season 4.5 or even season 5.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lost: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/17/lost-season-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/17/lost-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Survival. Mysteries. The Others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now, just possibly&amp;hellip; rescue?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But, as they said in the end of the previous season, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>not Penny&amp;rsquo;s boat&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So who&amp;rsquo;s is it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really enjoy this season. We get a chance to have some new characters (from the freighter come to rescue them), a bit of a shake up in terms of who&amp;rsquo;s on which side on th island, and a whole pile of &amp;lsquo;what is even going on&amp;rsquo;, split a bit between Desmond and newcomer Daniel Faraday&amp;ndash;I do enjoy his character.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, we really are starting to get into the point where you question &amp;lsquo;so&amp;hellip; were they planning that all along? do even the &lt;em>writers&lt;/em> know what&amp;rsquo;s going on?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the answer is no? That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s a bad season though!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And, because of the 2008 writer&amp;rsquo;s strike, it&amp;rsquo;s a shorter season as well&amp;gt; Ramps of the tension that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Favorite episodes this season?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first flashes off the island&amp;ndash;with their own level of *you did &lt;strong>what&lt;/strong> now. &lt;em>The Constant&lt;/em>, with timey-whimey shenanigans and &lt;em>There&amp;rsquo;s No Place Like Home&lt;/em>, with everything coming to a tense, sometimes magical, and always chaotic end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing Lost straddle the line between science fiction and more supernatural/fantasy. I tend to like the former, but a lot of times, it&amp;rsquo;s the contrast that really does the best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only two seasons left!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/">Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade&lt;/a> was such a good movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then they made another one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as I remembered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harrison Jones isn&amp;rsquo;t getting younger&amp;hellip; but he still really makes Indiana Jones. Full stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I bet they were expecting this film (and especially Shia LeBeouf&amp;rsquo;s Mutt) to go better and possibly pass the torch. It was an echo of the same dynamic as Indy and his father in The Last Crusade. Just not quite done as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was kind of fun to see the Soviets be the bad guys this time around and it more or less fits this new, older Indy.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Dean Charles Stanforth: I barely recognize this country anymore. The government&amp;rsquo;s got us seeing Communists in our soup. When the hysteria reaches academia, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to call it a career.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On top of that, seeing Karen Allen&amp;rsquo;s Marion Ravenwood again after all these years? And with the obvious fallout of that? That was more fun than I expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man. Cate Blanchett act the heck out of that role. But still, she just wasn&amp;rsquo;t as much a villain as previous films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;ndash;the action scenes. A bit more over the top than previous movies? Do you even &lt;em>remember&lt;/em> the roller coaster mine cart of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/">Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom&lt;/a>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed the opening in the warehouse. The nuclear bomb-fridge scene has been talked about to death. The motorcycle chase (through the library!) was a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Indiana Jones: You want to be a good archaeologist&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
[Mutt drives them out of the building on his motorcycle]&lt;br>
Indiana Jones: &amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ve got to get out of the library!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The jungle fight between the jeeps was pretty cool&amp;ndash;but the Tarzan bits? a bit much&amp;hellip; The temple was technically neat, even if it didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense. And the &lt;span class="spoiler">alien&lt;/span>
 finale wasn&amp;rsquo;t really that much weirder than centuries old knights and Nazi face melting artifacts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I think I&amp;rsquo;d place it above Temple of Doom, but below Raiders and the Last Crusade. A fun action flick and&amp;ndash;not as bad as I initially thought.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ponyo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/04/ponyo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/04/ponyo/</guid><description>&lt;p>That is a strange movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s slower movie, with a magical style to the animation that&amp;rsquo;s both truly beautiful and surprisingly terrifying at times. The plot is somewhere between simple and mostly absent and the characters are mostly&amp;ndash;there?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it was fascinating to catch in theaters as part of the &lt;a href="https://gkids.com/ghiblifest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Studio Ghibli Fest 2024&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; but not really something I&amp;rsquo;d ever choose to watch again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such is life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate: Continuum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-continuum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-continuum/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was a far better movie (in my opinion) than &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/">Stargate: The Ark of Truth&lt;/a>. It basically felt like a slightly higher budget two part episode (although those already tended to be good) of the series and actually gave a chance to say goodbye to a few more people: In particularly Ba&amp;rsquo;al (RIP) and O&amp;rsquo;Neill, who really needed it. Not to mention a callback to the real villains of the show: The Goa&amp;rsquo;uld.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Incredible Hulk</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/20/the-incredible-hulk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/20/the-incredible-hulk/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Bruce Banner: [in a poor Portuguese] Don&amp;rsquo;t make me hungry. You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like me when I&amp;rsquo;m hungry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tough Guy Leader: [in Portuguese] What the hell he is talking about?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of bummer that The Incredible Hulk is stuck in sort of a legal loophole and isn&amp;rsquo;t available with all the rest of the MCU on Disney+ (A̸̜̓L̶̬̽L̷̗̋ ̵̦̂Ĥ̴̖A̵͓͋I̴̝̓L̵̺̓ ̶͖̄T̶̿͜H̶̬̊È̷̡ ̸̜̋M̸̮̔O̷̜͒U̶͇̓S̵̺̏Ë̵̝́). On top of that, it&amp;rsquo;s the only main MCU superhero that they&amp;rsquo;ve recast (so far). Conversely though, it&amp;rsquo;s actually (surprisingly) a good movie.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iron Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/iron-man/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/iron-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Way back in 2008, I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone had the slightest idea how far the Marvel Cinematic Universe would go. Taking a less well known superhero (face it, before this few knew who Iron Man was), attaching him to a talented but troubled actor (Robert Downy Jr was an amazing cast) and make a fairly stock standard action movie and&amp;hellip; build a media empire that would span more than 12 years and 20 films (so far&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>