<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2008 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2008/</link><description>Recent content in 2008 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2008/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/25/indiana-jones-and-the-kingdom-of-the-crystal-skull/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/19/indiana-jones-and-the-last-crusade/">Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade&lt;/a> was such a good movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then they made another one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as I remembered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Harrison Jones isn&amp;rsquo;t getting younger&amp;hellip; but he still really makes Indiana Jones. Full stop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I bet they were expecting this film (and especially Shia LeBeouf&amp;rsquo;s Mutt) to go better and possibly pass the torch. It was an echo of the same dynamic as Indy and his father in The Last Crusade. Just not quite done as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was kind of fun to see the Soviets be the bad guys this time around and it more or less fits this new, older Indy.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Dean Charles Stanforth: I barely recognize this country anymore. The government&amp;rsquo;s got us seeing Communists in our soup. When the hysteria reaches academia, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s time to call it a career.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>On top of that, seeing Karen Allen&amp;rsquo;s Marion Ravenwood again after all these years? And with the obvious fallout of that? That was more fun than I expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man. Cate Blanchett act the heck out of that role. But still, she just wasn&amp;rsquo;t as much a villain as previous films.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;ndash;the action scenes. A bit more over the top than previous movies? Do you even &lt;em>remember&lt;/em> the roller coaster mine cart of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/04/indiana-jones-and-the-temple-of-doom/">Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom&lt;/a>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed the opening in the warehouse. The nuclear bomb-fridge scene has been talked about to death. The motorcycle chase (through the library!) was a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Indiana Jones: You want to be a good archaeologist&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
[Mutt drives them out of the building on his motorcycle]&lt;br>
Indiana Jones: &amp;hellip; you&amp;rsquo;ve got to get out of the library!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The jungle fight between the jeeps was pretty cool&amp;ndash;but the Tarzan bits? a bit much&amp;hellip; The temple was technically neat, even if it didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense. And the &lt;span class="spoiler">alien&lt;/span>
 finale wasn&amp;rsquo;t really that much weirder than centuries old knights and Nazi face melting artifacts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I think I&amp;rsquo;d place it above Temple of Doom, but below Raiders and the Last Crusade. A fun action flick and&amp;ndash;not as bad as I initially thought.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ponyo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/04/ponyo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/04/ponyo/</guid><description>&lt;p>That is a strange movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s slower movie, with a magical style to the animation that&amp;rsquo;s both truly beautiful and surprisingly terrifying at times. The plot is somewhere between simple and mostly absent and the characters are mostly&amp;ndash;there?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it was fascinating to catch in theaters as part of the &lt;a href="https://gkids.com/ghiblifest/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Studio Ghibli Fest 2024&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; but not really something I&amp;rsquo;d ever choose to watch again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such is life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stargate: Continuum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-continuum/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 23:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/22/stargate-continuum/</guid><description>&lt;p>That was a far better movie (in my opinion) than &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/21/stargate-the-ark-of-truth/">Stargate: The Ark of Truth&lt;/a>. It basically felt like a slightly higher budget two part episode (although those already tended to be good) of the series and actually gave a chance to say goodbye to a few more people: In particularly Ba&amp;rsquo;al (RIP) and O&amp;rsquo;Neill, who really needed it. Not to mention a callback to the real villains of the show: The Goa&amp;rsquo;uld.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Incredible Hulk</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/20/the-incredible-hulk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/20/the-incredible-hulk/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Bruce Banner: [in a poor Portuguese] Don&amp;rsquo;t make me hungry. You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like me when I&amp;rsquo;m hungry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tough Guy Leader: [in Portuguese] What the hell he is talking about?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of bummer that The Incredible Hulk is stuck in sort of a legal loophole and isn&amp;rsquo;t available with all the rest of the MCU on Disney+ (A̸̜̓L̶̬̽L̷̗̋ ̵̦̂Ĥ̴̖A̵͓͋I̴̝̓L̵̺̓ ̶͖̄T̶̿͜H̶̬̊È̷̡ ̸̜̋M̸̮̔O̷̜͒U̶͇̓S̵̺̏Ë̵̝́). On top of that, it&amp;rsquo;s the only main MCU superhero that they&amp;rsquo;ve recast (so far). Conversely though, it&amp;rsquo;s actually (surprisingly) a good movie.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iron Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/iron-man/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/03/iron-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Way back in 2008, I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone had the slightest idea how far the Marvel Cinematic Universe would go. Taking a less well known superhero (face it, before this few knew who Iron Man was), attaching him to a talented but troubled actor (Robert Downy Jr was an amazing cast) and make a fairly stock standard action movie and&amp;hellip; build a media empire that would span more than 12 years and 20 films (so far&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>