<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sea of Trolls on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/sea-of-trolls/</link><description>Recent content in Sea of Trolls on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/sea-of-trolls/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Sea of Trolls</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/01/the-sea-of-trolls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/01/the-sea-of-trolls/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a surprisingly fun book!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The year is A.D. 793; Jack and his sister have been kidnapped by Vikings and taken to the court of Ivar the Boneless and his terrifying half-troll wife; but things get even worse when Jack finds himself on a dangerous quest to find the magical Mimir&amp;rsquo;s Well in a far-off land, with his sister&amp;rsquo;s life forfeit if he fails.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I started out reading this since it&amp;rsquo;s a great (and rare) fit for the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/bingo/2024-book-bingo/">2024 Book Bingo&lt;/a> &amp;lsquo;Bard&amp;rsquo; square, since both Jack and his mentor are explicitly called &amp;lsquo;Bards&amp;rsquo; (even if, interestingly music is a relatively small part of their training), but it ends up being so much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s got Vikings&amp;ndash;including digging into what makes them who they are and how they think differently from the people Jack grew up with.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Just say no to pillaging.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s got monsters&amp;ndash;the Vikings for one, along with Trolls (sometimes more human that anyone), dragons, ravens, and giant spiders.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Norns keep the tree Yggdrassil alive. Without them, nothing would exist… They show up when you&amp;rsquo;re born and decide what kind of life you&amp;rsquo;re going to have.&amp;quot;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;I guess they were in a rotten mood when I came along,&amp;rdquo; Jack said. He loaded up the water bag and supplies.&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Me too,&amp;rdquo; Thorgil said gravely.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Look around you&amp;hellip;Feel the wind, smell the air. Listen to the birds and watch the sky. Tell me what&amp;rsquo;s happening in the wide world.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s got magic. Bardic magic. Shapeshifting. Talking to animals. Calling up / banishing storms. Norse mythology. Norns. Yggdrasil.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“It&amp;rsquo;s my fault,&amp;quot; said Rune. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s untrained and likely to overdo things.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Like turning the queen bald. That was a good trick, though.&amp;rdquo; Olaf smiled.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve absolutely no idea if it&amp;rsquo;s particularly historically accurate (barring the above of course :)), but it&amp;rsquo;s a fun read and I greatly enjoyed it. Now I really want to know what happens next!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: Great fun for an audiobook, lightly accented. Just enough to get into the feel of the book all the more!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>