<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Disney Animated Home Releases on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/disney-animated-home-releases/</link><description>Recent content in Disney Animated Home Releases on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/disney-animated-home-releases/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bambi 2: The Great Prince of the Forest</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/04/bambi-2-the-great-prince-of-the-forest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/04/bambi-2-the-great-prince-of-the-forest/</guid><description>You know, I was actually pleasantly surprised by Bambi II (later retitled). And not only because they got Patrick Stewart of all people to voice Bambi&amp;rsquo;s dad (who now has to step up and be a single father). It&amp;rsquo;s as cute a story as Bambi was&amp;ndash;which the kids&amp;rsquo; appreciated&amp;ndash;but with just a bit more depth&amp;ndash;which I did. It&amp;rsquo;s still certainly not high cinema, but it&amp;rsquo;s not terrible either.
Onward!
Ranked: Disney Animated MoanaEncantoPocahontasOne Hundred and One DalmatiansThe Rescuers Down UnderThe Many Adventures of Winnie the PoohBambi Ranked: 2021 Movie Reviews The Nightmare Before ChristmasAvengers: EndgameAvengers: Infinity WarThe Matrix ResurrectionsCaptain America: Civil WarCaptain America: The Winter SoldierSpider-Man: Far From HomeThor: RagnarokCaptain America: The First AvengerSpider-Man: HomecomingShang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten RingsThe Suicide SquadMoanaBlack PantherIron ManGuardians of the GalaxyFinding NemoAnt-ManStar Wars: Episode VI - Return of the JediStar Wars: Episode V - The Empire Strikes BackThe Greatest ShowmanCaptain MarvelAnt-Man and the WaspDoctor StrangeBlack WidowStar Wars: Episode IV - A New HopeOne Hundred and One DalmatiansLucaPalm SpringsKnives OutShazam!</description></item></channel></rss>