<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brandon Sanderson on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/</link><description>Recent content in Brandon Sanderson on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bastille vs. the Evil Librarians</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/11/bastille-vs.-the-evil-librarians/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/05/11/bastille-vs.-the-evil-librarians/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends. Again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the events of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/23/the-dark-talent/">The Dark Talent&lt;/a>, Alcatraz isn&amp;rsquo;t doing so well&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, the Talents are still gone, several Smedrys are dead&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, and the world is about to end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So of course we have one last adventure. Chock full of impossible situations, anti-gravity sharks, a Gak, &lt;em>so&lt;/em> many straw puns&lt;sup id="fnref:4">&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, and an army of kittens&lt;sup id="fnref:5">&lt;a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, romance&lt;sup id="fnref:6">&lt;a href="#fn:6" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">6&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, and a big battle on top of a giant glass spire in the middle of the ocean!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that was kind of odd to me (having read &lt;em>almost&lt;/em> all of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s works at this point) is how the fine details of the magic system never quite came together&amp;ndash;and now they probably never will. The talents are a lot of fun, magic glass is neat&lt;sup id="fnref:7">&lt;a href="#fn:7" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">7&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;sup id="fnref:8">&lt;a href="#fn:8" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">8&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, and somehow they are related&amp;hellip; but how does it all work? Is Alcatraz right? Where did it come from?! I know it&amp;rsquo;s not a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-cosmere/">Cosmere&lt;/a> novel, so it gets a bit of a bye for that, but I wanted more. So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, compared to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/23/the-dark-talent/">The Dark Talent&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s actually an ending, which I greatly appreciate. Other than that, I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s a weaker entry into the series. Still a lot of fun to read and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have finally gotten to them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;sup id="fnref:9">&lt;a href="#fn:9" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">9&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Dark Talent</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/23/the-dark-talent/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/03/23/the-dark-talent/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Some of you have been waiting for years to read this, the final volume of my autobiography.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I cannot really imagine that being the last book. Or at least the last one that would be published for another 6 years! Now, in hindsight, it&amp;rsquo;s obvious (and my kids&amp;rsquo; totally already knew), but man. That&amp;rsquo;s NOT AN ENDING.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Fine,” Grandpa said. “You fetch your evil Librarian mother from the jail. I’ll go warm up the giant penguin!”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Ahem.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Well, that was fun,” Grandpa said as he climbed to his feet. “Anyone dead?”&lt;br>
“Does my pride count?” Draulin asked, dusting herself off.&lt;br>
“I don’t think so,” Grandpa said. “I killed that years ago. Dif, I appreciate your enthusiasm, but shoving my grandson out of planes is usually my job. So next time, kindly refrain until I give the word.”&lt;br>
“Sorry, sir,” Dif said, looking abashed.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Dark Talent sees Alcatraz. Sans Dark Talent, off on a mission to save the world &amp;hellip; and to save the girl. Just don&amp;rsquo;t let Bastille hear you say that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a lot like the rest of the series. New Smedrys (oh Dif), new worldbuilding (the HIBRARY! Beneath Washington DC!), new schenanigans (that is &lt;em>quite&lt;/em> a library; also, rocket powered penguins), and a big new battle at the end (leading up to that oft forementioned SACRIFICE UPON AN ALTAR OF ENCYCLOPEDIAS).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it&amp;rsquo;s not the ending. And the ending can more than tell you that, which&amp;hellip; is honestly getting kind of old.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s doubly painful since not only did it end quickly, but it also ended painfully. In a series where guns put people in comas and main characters have magic powers seemingly purposely designed (hmm) to get them out of trouble&amp;hellip; well, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a shock.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of fun and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to where in the &lt;em>world&lt;/em> the series will &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> end&amp;hellip; For real this time? Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alcatraz Versus the Shattered Lens</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/26/alcatraz-versus-the-shattered-lens/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/26/alcatraz-versus-the-shattered-lens/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Impossible things are really rough to do, you know.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And man, Alcatraz does all manner of impossible things this time around. There&amp;rsquo;s wacky tech (like Teddy bear grenades and giant flying bats (not made of glass)), wacky situations (Alcatraz getting a major (temporary) promotion (of sorts)), and powers (a Talent for Being Bad at Math). Pretty much exactly what you&amp;rsquo;d expect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And all along, we&amp;rsquo;re getting more about the world building, one thing that I always enjoy in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s books. There definitely seems to be a connection between it all&amp;ndash;but exactly how it all works together and how that can make things go wrong&amp;hellip; well, that&amp;rsquo;s the story, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Structurally, my kids were absolutely thrilled by the chapter numbering. The books are terribly meta, referring to chapters that don&amp;rsquo;t exist (because of skipping numbers) and with notes and comments going back and forth. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to read and honestly kind of impressive that we&amp;rsquo;ve gone this far&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Boys, welcome to the wonderful world of talking to women about their feelings. As a handy primer, here are a few things you should know:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Women have feelings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You will spend the next seventy years or so trying to guess what they&amp;rsquo;re feeling and why.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You will be wrong most of the time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I like French Fries.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Alcatraz continues to fall for Bastille.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>She was absolutely beautiful. She had long blonde hair, kind of the shade of a bowl of mac and cheese. She was smiling a wide, genuine smile—which was rather the shape of a macaroni and cheese noodle. She seemed to radiate light, much like a bowl of mac and cheese might if you stuffed a lightbulb into it. Her skin was soft and squishy, like— Okay. Maybe I’m too hungry to be writing right now.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In a very Alcatraz sort of way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun book and quite an ending. Of all the things to Break&amp;hellip; Here we go, one more book from Alcatraz&amp;rsquo;s perspective / in the original series. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to see where it can possible go from here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alcatraz Versus the Knights of Crystallia</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/alcatraz-versus-the-knights-of-crystallia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/01/25/alcatraz-versus-the-knights-of-crystallia/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Books are not fish sticks.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Now, we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em>really&lt;/em> in the Free Kingdoms. We spent a book learning that there&amp;rsquo;s a hidden world and another mostly underground (in the Library of Alexandria!), so it&amp;rsquo;s nice to get something really &amp;lsquo;hidden world&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And man, the Free Kingdoms are strange. But that&amp;rsquo;s probably just the Librarian brainwashing coming through. Castles. Glass pigs. More castles. Kings. Councils. And even more Smedrys!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Farting barf-faced poop!” a voice exclaimed from inside the pig’s butt.&lt;br>
(Sigh. Sorry. At least that’s another great paragraph to try working into a random conversation.)&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Exactly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the hilarious (from our point of view) issues that comes up this book is Alcatraz coming to his &amp;lsquo;Harry Potter&amp;rsquo; moment. A world where he knows next to nothing, but everyone knows who he is. Apparently via the in-universe Alcatraz books, which is an extra level of weirdly meta.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Fame is like a cheeseburger. It might not be the best or most healthy thing to have, but it will still fill you up. You don’t really care how healthy something is when you’ve been without for so long. Like a cheeseburger, fame fills a need, and it tastes so good going down. It isn’t until years later that you realize what it has done to your heart.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There are just so many book/other geeky media references. I love them.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For example, take this story: “Once there was a furry-footed British guy who had to go throw his uncle’s ring into a hole in the ground.” Sounds dumb, doesn’t it?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Nothing is sacred!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“That’s bad,” Folsom said.&lt;br>
“She Who Cannot Be Named?” I asked. “Why can’t we say her name? Because it might draw the attention of evil powers? Because we’re afraid of her? Because her name has become a curse upon the world?”&lt;br>
“Don’t be silly,” Himalaya said. “We don’t say her name because nobody can pronounce it.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Exactly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s more Alcatraz. You have a fun plot, wacky characters, and &lt;em>just&lt;/em> on the edge of too much meta commentary on writing/being a work of &amp;lsquo;fiction&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m still quite enjoying it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this is only halfway.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If a train left Nalhalla traveling at 3.14 miles an hour and a train left Bermuda at 45 MHz, what time does the soup have pancakes?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Where in the world (literally) can they go from here?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Alcatraz Versus the Scrivener's Bones</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/20/alcatraz-versus-the-scriveners-bones/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/20/alcatraz-versus-the-scriveners-bones/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Once there was a bunny. This bunny had a birthday party. It was the bestest birthday party ever. Because that was the day the bunny got a bazooka.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bunny loved his bazooka. He blew up all sorts of things on the farm. He blew up the stable of Henrietta the Horse. He blew up the pen of Pugsly the Pig. He blew up the coop of Chuck the Chicken.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I have the bestest bazooka ever,&amp;rdquo; the bunny said. Then the farm friends proceeded to beat him senseless and steal his bazooka. It was the happiest day of his life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Epilogue: Pugsly the Pig, now without a pen, was quite annoyed. When none of the others were looking, he stole the bazooka. He tied a bandana on his head and swore vengeance for what had been done to him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;From this day on,&amp;rdquo; he whispered, raising the bazooka, &amp;ldquo;I shall be known as Hambo.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/10/alcatraz-versus-the-evil-librarians/">Alcatraz Versus the Evil Librarians&lt;/a> introduced us to the world, now in Alcatraz Versus the Scrivener&amp;rsquo;s Bones we actually get to live in it! A bit. Sort of.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>(Hushlanders, it might be noted, aren’t very imaginative with their idioms. Personally, I say, “Out of the frying pan and into the deadly pit filled with sharks who are wielding chainsaws with killer kittens stapled to them.” However, that one’s having a rough time catching on.)&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Essentially, the entire book is an adventure where Alcatraz and co (Bastille, but also newcomers Australia&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and Kaz) are on a mission to mention a recently missing Grandpa Smedry. One thing leads to another, they end up in the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library%20of%20Alexandria">Library of Alexandria&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;which got totally Tardis&amp;rsquo;ed&amp;ndash;and discover all sorts of spooky ghosts, ancient scrolls, hidden messages, &amp;hellip; and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Not all librarians are evil cultists. Some librarians are instead vengeful undead who want to suck your soul.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Alcatraz Versus the Evil Librarians</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/10/alcatraz-versus-the-evil-librarians/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/10/alcatraz-versus-the-evil-librarians/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve read pretty much all of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/brandon-sanderson/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s works&amp;hellip; yet somehow I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to completely miss &lt;em>Alcatraz vs. the Evil Librarians&lt;/em>. Let&amp;rsquo;s remedy that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short version: Alcatraz reminds me a decent bit of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/27/the-frugal-wizards-handbook-for-surviving-medieval-england/">Frugal Wizard&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;which was actually my least favorite of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/year-of-sanderson/">Year of Sanderson&lt;/a> secret projects. But so far at least, I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying this series quite a bit more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Slightly longer version:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In the Hushlands—those Librarian-controlled nations such as the United States, Canada, and England—this book will be published as a work of fantasy. Do not be fooled! This is no work of fiction, nor is my name really Brandon Sanderson. Both are guises to hide the book from Librarian agents. Unfortunately, even with these precautions, I suspect that the Librarians will discover the book and ban it. In that case, our Free Kingdom Agents will have to sneak into libraries and bookstores to put it on shelves. Count yourself lucky if you’ve found one of these secret copies.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a (non-&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-cosmere/">Cosmere&lt;/a>) YA novel &amp;lsquo;written by&amp;rsquo; our titular Alcatraz as he learns that the world he&amp;rsquo;s always known is full of lies (perpetrated by a cabal of EVIL LIBRARIANS) who are now, of course, out to capture and/or kill him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As one does.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>impressively&lt;/em> meta, with almost constant comments from Alcatraz as narrator, talking about writers, writing, fiction, and just about anything else.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Authors also create lovable, friendly characters, then proceed to do terrible things to them, like throw them in unsightly librarian-controlled dungeons. This makes readers feel hurt and worried for the characters. The simple truth is that authors like making people squirm. If this weren&amp;rsquo;t the case, all novels would be filled completely with cute bunnies having birthday parties.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Which, from my perspective as both a reader and writer myself, is amusing, but feels like it might be a bit weirder / too meta for a much younger reader?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If you don&amp;rsquo;t believe what I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, then ask yourself this: would any decent, kind-hearted individual become a writer? Of course not.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well, so far my children are enjoying it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I suppose we&amp;rsquo;ll see where we go from here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, we haven&amp;rsquo;t learned &lt;em>that&lt;/em> much about how &amp;lsquo;magic&amp;rsquo; works in this world (we already have technology based almost entirely on glass along with &amp;lsquo;Talents&amp;rsquo;, which seem somewhat chaotic). That&amp;rsquo;s kind of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>thing&lt;/em>, so I expect a lot more there. The world is chaotic and strains believability when it comes to &amp;lsquo;could you &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> have a hidden world like this&amp;rsquo; but&amp;hellip; suspend disbelief and GO WITH IT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not actually sure how &lt;em>much&lt;/em> I like Alcatraz. So far, I like supporting cast Grandpa Smedry and Bastille quite a bit more. I expect that&amp;rsquo;s kind of the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, enjoyed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Sunlit Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/23/the-sunlit-man/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/23/the-sunlit-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so ends the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/year-of-sanderson/">Year of Sanderson&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/">Tress&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/yumi-and-the-nightmare-painter/">Yumi&lt;/a> already hinted at new and interesting worlds in the far future of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-cosmere/">The Cosmere&lt;/a>, but the connections were (relatively) small parts of the story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Sunlit man is a bit more tied in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still in the far future. And oh, the hints we get at where the Cosmere is going&amp;hellip; but this time, we have a protagonist we&amp;rsquo;ve met before, chock full of references to stories we&amp;rsquo;ve seen&amp;ndash;and a few that haven&amp;rsquo;t happened yet. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into who it is&amp;ndash;spoilers!&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s a neat surprise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid story as all the Cosmere secret projects have been. I think I prefer Tress and Yumi over Sunlit Man, but it&amp;rsquo;s by absolutely no means a bad book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think my only real negative is&amp;hellip; I want more! More of protagonist. More of the Night Brigade. More of this weird offshoot society. More worldbuilding and magic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I&amp;rsquo;m worried we won&amp;rsquo;t see more/any of this for at the very least a very long time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still very worth the read.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Yumi and the Nightmare Painter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/yumi-and-the-nightmare-painter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/14/yumi-and-the-nightmare-painter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh Sanderson. How &lt;em>do&lt;/em> you do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Three of the four novels in the &amp;ldquo;Year of Sanderson&amp;rdquo;. Tress was amazing and if anything&amp;hellip; Yumi is even better. (Frugal Wizard was fine. &amp;#x1f604;)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Frugal Wizard’s Handbook for Surviving Medieval England</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/27/the-frugal-wizards-handbook-for-surviving-medieval-england/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/27/the-frugal-wizards-handbook-for-surviving-medieval-england/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>What products did one use in Anglo-Saxon England? Beaver snot? A grudging four stars.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, I feel like “a grudging four stars” is about where this book ends up for me. Not bad, but given how much I&amp;rsquo;ve loved just about everything else Sanderson, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit lower.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tress of the Emerald Sea</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take one part Princess Bride (a modern fairly tale for a grown up audience), one part Hoid as the narrator (even more Wit-like than in Stormlight), and add in weird world&amp;ndash;Sanderson style. It&amp;rsquo;s funny. It&amp;rsquo;s touching. And it&amp;rsquo;s a delight to read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Voilá. Tress of the Emerald Sea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a really good book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Evershore</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/25/evershore/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/25/evershore/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Like the Saint says, if you don’t have anything to say, you might scare your flightleader into thinking you’re dead.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The one with Jerkface and the Kitsen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like all of the Starsight novellas, we have a focus on what else has been going on while Spena has been doing her &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/cytonic/">Cytonic&lt;/a> things. This time&amp;ndash;as you might guess&amp;ndash;with Jerkface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s actually really great to see his point of view and especially to see just how much he&amp;rsquo;s grown throughout the books. He was always a leader, but he&amp;rsquo;s really coming into it now&amp;ndash;and really realizing that sometimes, just maybe, the books might be &lt;em>wrong&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do also love seeing more of the Kitsen. They&amp;rsquo;re really building up a regular anti-Superiority alliance there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the biggest bummer now is having to wait for Defiant to come out this November&amp;hellip; Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cytonic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/cytonic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/19/cytonic/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Stories say something. About us, and about where we came from. They’re a reminder that we have a past, a history. And a future.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was certainly a thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/skyward/">Skyward&lt;/a> introduced us to some far future humans trapped on a planet by terrifying aliens. Spensa learns how to fight, teachers her friends and allies how to be awesome, and saves the day from the aliens!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/">Starsight&lt;/a>, we get off world. We&amp;rsquo;re introduced us to some of those same aliens. Turns out they&amp;rsquo;re people, more or less just like us. So Spensa learns how to spy, teachers her new friends and allies how to be awesome, and saves the day from the Eldrich Horrors From Beyond Space!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So of course in Cytonic&amp;hellip; Spensa goes Beyond Space. She adventures through all manners of weird environments, meets a bunch of Pirates From Beyond Space&amp;hellip; And learns to fight, teachers her friends and allies how to be awesome, and saves the universe?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m starting to sense a pattern here.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>All people must accept that we have the potential to do terrible things. It is part of seeing our place in the universe, our heritage, and our natures. But in that acceptance we gain strength, for potential can be refused. Any hero who could have been a monster is more heroic for the choices he or she made to walk another road.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>ReDawn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/redawn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/04/redawn/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A prisoner could be convinced that they lived in a paradise, if the prison was pretty enough.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>ReDawn is a lot like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/">Sunreach&lt;/a> in that it&amp;rsquo;s a cousin to the main Skyward books, really expanding the universe and letting us know what the rest of Skyward flight (and others) were getting up to while Spensa was&amp;hellip; otherwise occupied.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around&amp;hellip; the point of view is Alanik, the near human alien that crashed into Detritus right at the beginning of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/">Starsight&lt;/a>, enabling the events of that book.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I didn’t know enough about human politics to know who was correct, but I did know enough about politics in general to guess that everyone would interpret the law in the way that best suited themselves.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s facinating to have a point of view from someone who grew up in this universe on an alien world (bubbles of air around giant trees!) with an alien culture&amp;ndash;that in this case is actually tied to humanity throughout the past. It gives us a way to dig more into the relationships (especially the &amp;lsquo;relationships&amp;rsquo;) between the humans all the more, which I enjoyed a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;hellip; learning more about the Taynix / slugs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty fun story, well worth it&amp;rsquo;s place as a Skyward sidestory novella!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sunreach</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/29/sunreach/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s cute. Part teenage romance, part &amp;lsquo;how in the world do we take care of these random alien slugs anyways&amp;rsquo;. Well worth a piece of the Skyward universe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Starsight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/26/starsight/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“A hero does not choose her trials. She steps into the darkness, then she faces what comes next.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If you are the sort to want absolutely zero spoilers going into a book &lt;em>stop reading now&lt;/em>. Go read the book (it&amp;rsquo;s really good, that&amp;rsquo;s not a spoiler :spoiler:) and then come back. You have been warned.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, now that that&amp;rsquo;s out of the way. It&amp;rsquo;s been &amp;hellip; three years since I first read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/skyward/">Skyward&lt;/a>. WheN I read it, the sequels weren&amp;rsquo;t even out yet&amp;hellip; when Starsight first came out, I just didn&amp;rsquo;t get around to it. I&amp;rsquo;m somewhat lamenting that lack now. &amp;#x1f604; But as they say, the second best time to plant a tree is today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, Starsight takes place where Skyward left off. Spensa has some crazy new powers she doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand, M-Bot is out in the open&amp;ndash;and really the star of the book&amp;ndash;, and humanity is ready to take back the stars&amp;hellip; More or less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Spoilers. For real, albeit minor.&lt;/em>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Defending Elysium</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/07/defending-elysium/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/07/defending-elysium/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You must understand that he knew the risks of living in an undeveloped civilization. Creatures of lesser intelligence cannot be held responsible for their acts of barbarity. You have not yet learned a better way.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve only read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/skyward/">Skyward&lt;/a> before of that series, so on re-reading, I noticed that Defending Elysium is sort of a prequel? It&amp;rsquo;s unclear to me exactly how much. It feels like the same world, but set well before and with none of the same characters? Especially since I haven&amp;rsquo;t read past Skyward before&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s a bit more worldbuilding and background than I&amp;rsquo;d otherwise be aware of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short, but worth a read in my opinion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Lost Metal</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/27/the-lost-metal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/11/27/the-lost-metal/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Mate, it ain&amp;rsquo;t violence if it&amp;rsquo;s religion.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And so it ends. The second era of one of the more ambitious ideas in fantasy: take a fantasy world with a hard/scientific magic system (or three), tell a crazy story in that world, and then advance a few hundred years so that the first story becomes the myths and religions of the world. Not only that, but (specifically in the Lost Metal), take that same idea and expand it across a shared universe of fantasy worlds, each with their own feel and magic and start really bringing things in from other worlds, mashing them together and seeing just what sort of madness pops out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>White Sand, Volume 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/white-sand-volume-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/21/white-sand-volume-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Onward and conclusionward! All the political machinations to save the Sand Masters (and himself) are coming to a head. It&amp;rsquo;s a fine enough central plot, even if the random assassinations / friend that doesn&amp;rsquo;t get along well with his father / scientist from the other side of the world / bodyguard that hates you and you have to win over subplots really do get to be a bit random and disorientating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s really a problem with the whole set of graphic novels though and&amp;ndash;if I remember correctly&amp;ndash;I had the same problem with the prose version years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s not a deal breaker, but I feel like the whole thing could be cleaned up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>White Sand, Volume 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/18/white-sand-volume-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/18/white-sand-volume-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the things that I feared most about getting into these stories is the big &amp;lsquo;art style change&amp;rsquo;. I see it. It&amp;rsquo;s definately different. But having read all manner of graphic novels over the last year&amp;ndash;some change &lt;em>far&lt;/em> more dramatically than this. They&amp;rsquo;re similar enough that I barely even noticed for the most part.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it still is quite beautful:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>White Sand, Volume 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/16/white-sand-volume-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/02/16/white-sand-volume-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>White Sand has something of an odd story. It&amp;rsquo;s the first novel Sanderson finished (and also the 7th, a complete rewrite), but in prose form was never published. You can get it if you ask him (I think signing up for the newsletter? It&amp;rsquo;s been a few years) and I read it back in 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now though, the same story has been actually published as a three volume set of graphic novels. Having gotten rather more into graphic novels over the last year, of course I had to give it a try, so here we go!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rhythm of War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/21/rhythm-of-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/21/rhythm-of-war/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Heroism is a myth you tell idealistic young people—specifically when you
want them to go bleed for you. It got one of my sons killed and another
taken from me. You can keep your heroism and return to me the lives of those
wasted on foolish conflicts.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well dang. After the absolutely bonkersiosity of the first three Stormlight Archive books, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t the slightest idea how Sanderson was going to pull off yet another (and another and another coming down the pipeline). And yet here we are.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dawnshard</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/28/dawnshard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/12/28/dawnshard/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was unexpectedly wonderful. I was all set to dive into the behemoth that is &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/01/21/rhythm-of-war/">Rhythm of War&lt;/a> and then I noticed that there&amp;rsquo;s a 50k word &amp;lsquo;short&amp;rsquo; to read before it. I loved &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/11/25/edgedancer/">Edgedancer&lt;/a>, so let&amp;rsquo;s give this a try!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end, this I do not regret at all. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/11/25/edgedancer/">Edgedancer&lt;/a> is a story that could was too long to be an interlude and too different to be in the main storyline, but having read it is a story that every much needed to be told.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Edgedancer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/11/25/edgedancer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/11/25/edgedancer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Edgedancer is a short story set in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s Cosmere, specifically on Roshar of the Stormlight Archive. It features Lift, a young girl who was first featured in one of the interludes of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/15/words-of-radiance/">Words of Radiance&lt;/a> interludes and now has a story all to her own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In short, Lift is a lot of fun. She&amp;rsquo;s a surgebinder who can make herself &amp;lsquo;awesome&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;her term for it&amp;ndash;and basically ignore friction. She seems an overall good person with a somewhat odd sense of morals and has a way of talking and acting that will just leave you smiling.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lies of the Beholder</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/13/lies-of-the-beholder/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/13/lies-of-the-beholder/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Who cares?” I said. “Yes, it’s all in my head. But pain is ‘all in my head’ too. Love is ‘all in my head.’ All the things that matter in life are the things you can’t measure! The things our brains make up! Being made-up doesn’t make them unimportant.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a few years since I last read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/legion/">Legion&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/21/skin-deep/">Skin Deep&lt;/a>, so when I saw a there was a new (and apparently last) part out, I had to give it a try. This time around, I listened to all three on audiobook and that, I can highly recommend. It&amp;rsquo;s a solid production and each aspect having their own voice helps that little bit more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Children of the Nameless</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/10/children-of-the-nameless/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/04/10/children-of-the-nameless/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey, it&amp;rsquo;s Sanderson. I&amp;rsquo;ll give it a chance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Taking place in the greater Magic the Gathering universe, there&amp;rsquo;s a feel for a huge world we&amp;rsquo;re only seeing a corner of. Names That Matter left and right and nowhere near enough time to learn what they all mean&amp;hellip; but if you just go with it, you&amp;rsquo;ll figure out enough for this particular story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skyward</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/28/skyward/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/28/skyward/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I imagined those broken rocks as the broken bodies of my enemies, their bones shattered, their trembling arms reaching upward in a useless gesture of total and complete defeat. I was a very odd little girl.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Spensa (Spin) is an odd girl in an odd world. Humanity is trapped on an alien planet for reasons (initially) unknown. The sky is filled with rubble and debris that occasionally rains down on them and from time to time aliens come down and try to kill them. Spin&amp;rsquo;s father is a pilot, trying to protect them, but he dies early in the book (before a timeskip), called a coward&amp;ndash;seemingly one of the worst things you can call someone in this world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Oathbringer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/02/oathbringer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/02/oathbringer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hooooly crap. The first three quarters of Oathbringer are fairly slow. They&amp;rsquo;re still fascinating, building up more and more of the world of The Stormlight Archive, answering some questions while raising even more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then crap really hits the fan. I read the final several hundred pages in one session and wow a lot of things happen. Epic. Just epic. Read the book just for that and don&amp;rsquo;t put it down early.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Words of Radiance</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/15/words-of-radiance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/15/words-of-radiance/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I am offend!” Shallan yelled. “You have offended Her Highness again!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Very offend!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“You’d better apologize.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“No apologize!” Shallan declared. “Boots!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kal leaned back, looking between the two of them, trying to parse what had just been said. “Boots?” he asked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Yes,” Shallan said. “I am liking your boots. You will apology with boots.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“You . . . want my boots?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Did you not hear Her Highness?” Tyn asked, arms folded. “Are soldiers of this Dalinar Kholin’s army so disrespectful?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“I’m not disrespectful,” Kal said. “But I’m not giving her my boots.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“You insult!” Shallan declared, stepping forward, pointing at him. Stormfather, those horses were enormous! “I will tell all who are to listen! When arriving, I will say, ‘Kholin is stealer of boots and taker of women’s virtue!’”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kal sputtered. “Virtue!”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“Yes,” Shallan said; then she glanced over to Tyn. “Virtue? No, wrong word. Virture . . . No . . . Vesture. Vesture! Taker of woman’s vesture! That is word I wanted.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The soldier glanced to his companions, looking confused. Drat, Shallan thought. Good puns are lost on men with poor vocabulary.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Arcanum Unbounded</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/25/arcanum-unbounded/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/25/arcanum-unbounded/</guid><description>&lt;p>Arcanum Unbounded collects a small pile of short stories all set in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s shared universe (the Cosmere) and glues them together with some extra information about each world and about how the Cosmere itself works. While each of the stories is good by itself, they really shine collected together, where you get a sense of just how big and diverse this universe that Sanderson is building is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Individual reviews:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shadows for Silence in the Forests of Hell</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/24/shadows-for-silence-in-the-forests-of-hell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/24/shadows-for-silence-in-the-forests-of-hell/</guid><description>&lt;p>Shadows for Silence in the Forests of Hell is a fascinating Sanderson story set in an out of the way corner of his shared universe&amp;ndash;the cosmere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a creepy short (for Sanderson) that follows an older woman (probably middle aged). She&amp;rsquo;s a mother, an inn-keeper, and a bounty hunter. She&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful character and really does do a lot to sell the story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sixth of the Dusk</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/24/sixth-of-the-dusk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/24/sixth-of-the-dusk/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve previously listened about this story on the &lt;a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Writing Excuses&lt;/a> podcast and read it in the &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21844946-shadows-beneath?from_search=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Shadows Beneath&lt;/a> anthology, but it&amp;rsquo;s just as weird/good now as it was then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, the idea of an ocean culture that travels between terrifying islands (with just as terrifying beasties in the water) is fascinating. Sentient birds ( &lt;span class="spoiler">/ worms&lt;/span>
 ) that people can tame and carry with them to grant them special powers? Yes please.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Secret History</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/23/secret-history/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/23/secret-history/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Oh, hell,” Kelsier said. “There’s actually a God?” “Yes.” Kelsier decked him.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;ve read the Mistborn series, read Secret History. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t, read the Mistborn series, then read Secret History. It&amp;rsquo;s worth the read just for for the the crazy intertwined universe-building that Sanderson has been pulling off for years now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Allomancer Jak and the Pits of Eltania</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/21/allomancer-jak-and-the-pits-of-eltania/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/21/allomancer-jak-and-the-pits-of-eltania/</guid><description>&lt;p>Allomancer Jak is a hilarious, pulpy, over the top adventure story set on the Mistborn universe (specifically the Alloy of Law time period).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It adds a bit of world building&amp;ndash;specifically explaining how the Koloss have changed since the first era of the Final Empire&amp;ndash;but mostly it&amp;rsquo;s just fun to read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Eleventh Metal</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/19/the-eleventh-metal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/19/the-eleventh-metal/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Eleventh Metal is a short story originally written for the Mistborn Adventure Game (an RPG) that takes place before the events of the first Mistborn book. It gives us a bit more backstory about Kelsier and actually shows his own training, which is interesting enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s not bad. It&amp;rsquo;s just very short and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really add anything in particular to the rest of the Mistborn stories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hope of Elantris</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/18/the-hope-of-elantris/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/18/the-hope-of-elantris/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a cute little side story set during the climactic final scenes of the main Elantris storyline. Basically, it&amp;rsquo;s a story that Sanderson had originally in mind for Elantris but cut due to pacing or other issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, it follows Matisse, an Elantrian who is charged with watching after the children and ends up saving them all with the help of Ashe the Seon.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Emperor's Soul</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/11/the-emperors-soul/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/11/the-emperors-soul/</guid><description>&lt;p>If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been told, at first I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t realize that The Emperor&amp;rsquo;s Soul takes place in a far away corner of the same world as Elantris. But as the story wears on, and the details of the magic system are revealed, it becomes more obvious that the worlds are one and the same. I really do love how Sanderson does magic systems. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen anything quite like it, especially not at the same scale. Every system seems new, yet there&amp;rsquo;s a shared core to all of them. I love it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, I did like the character of Shai. There&amp;rsquo;s something about an artist who works entirely to know that she did it, rather than for public acclaim that I enjoy. Sneaky and subtle. Excellent. I could see a few of the twists coming (that she wouldn&amp;rsquo;t escape until the last moment; the changes she made), but that didn&amp;rsquo;t make it any less enjoyable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Snapshot</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/03/10/snapshot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/03/10/snapshot/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Mustard?” Chaz replied. “Who puts mustard on a burrito?”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Sanderson recently posted the first two chapters of Snapshot online (&lt;a href="http://brandonsanderson.com/snapshot-chapter-one/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">1&lt;/a> / &lt;a href="http://brandonsanderson.com/snapshot-chapter-two/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2&lt;/a>). CLIFFHANGER! Bought the whole thing. (It&amp;rsquo;s $3&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Calamity</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/10/calamity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/10/calamity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reading some of the other reviews on Goodreads, I was afraid that Calamity wouldn&amp;rsquo;t live up to the expectation of the previous two Reckoners books. Luckily, at least so far as I&amp;rsquo;m concerned, it not only met the expectations I had for it, it exceeded them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So far as the world building / settings go, each of the Reckoners books takes an ordinary city in the former United States and weirds it. First, we had Chicago made of steel. Then New York, mostly underwater and covered with glowing spray paint. This time around? The city of Atlanta, made of salt and on the move. It&amp;rsquo;s just such a bizarre visual that it could carry a decent bit of the story just on that alone. All the little details that entails (sweat breaks down the salt, buildings crumble) just make it all the more interesting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Firefight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/08/firefight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/08/firefight/</guid><description>&lt;p>Firefight is a an excellent followup to Steelheart, taking everything I liked about the first book&amp;ndash;the variety of the Epics&amp;rsquo; powers and the ruined world they&amp;rsquo;ve left behind&amp;ndash;and making it better while at the same point smoothing out my one real complaint&amp;ndash;the &amp;lsquo;bad analogies&amp;rsquo;. They&amp;rsquo;re still there, but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t mention them every page or two, so they actually feel funny this time around, rather than so forced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the upside, the new setting is just as crazy and cool this time around. Last time&amp;ndash;Chicago turned to steel. This time, New York City flooded to the point only the tops of skyscrapers stick out of the water, where fruit trees grow freely in buildings and spray paint glows in the night. It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful image and an interesting contrast to the relentlessly gritty steel of Newcago.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Steelheart</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/10/steelheart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/10/10/steelheart/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Reckoners is everything that I love in a Sanderson book, with the main exception being that it&amp;rsquo;s not set in the otherwise shared universe of the Cosmere. It makes sense though, given that Steelheart is set in our universe (more or less).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, a bunch of people gained superpowers. In Sanderson fashion, their powers are varied and interesting and the &amp;lsquo;rules&amp;rsquo; are fairly solid. Powers range from illusions and fire to turning an entire city into metal. On top of that, every Epic (the word &amp;lsquo;Superhero&amp;rsquo; having some legal oddities around it) also has a weakness, thus fulfilling &lt;a href="http://coppermind.net/wiki/Sanderson%27s_Laws_of_Magic" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s Second Law&lt;/a>. Also, they&amp;rsquo;re all pretty much evil. It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty neat world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skin Deep</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/21/skin-deep/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/21/skin-deep/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stephen Leeds returns!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, the &amp;lsquo;big idea&amp;rsquo; plot that sort of fades into the background is the idea of encoding research into DNA. It&amp;rsquo;s something that&amp;rsquo;s actually happening now, although (so far as we know) not actually being used to store anything in a person&amp;rsquo;s genetic code. But it&amp;rsquo;s certainly not out of the realm of possibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Legion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/19/legion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/08/19/legion/</guid><description>&lt;p>After reading so may of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s cosmere novels, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit odd to read one that isn&amp;rsquo;t. There&amp;rsquo;s still a &amp;lsquo;Sanderson feel&amp;rsquo; to it, both in how the characters think and interact and also in this novel&amp;rsquo;s version of a magic system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basic premise: the main character&amp;ndash;Stephen Leeds&amp;ndash;has manifest many &amp;lsquo;aspects&amp;rsquo; that only he can see. Each is a specialist in a specific field that Leeds needed to solve a particular problem. It&amp;rsquo;s left vague if the aspects are actually real (in the sense of being conscious entities, separate from Leeds himself), which makes the story all the more interesting. So far as Leeds is concerned, they are, and his mind will jump through some pretty crazy hoops to keep that illusion going.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bands of Mourning</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/12/the-bands-of-mourning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/07/12/the-bands-of-mourning/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sanderson has this tendency to completely change the world in ways that you&amp;rsquo;d never think could possibly work&amp;hellip; and yet pull them off. He did it between the first and second Mistborn books and he just did it again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuilding-wise, so many things have changed. Yet he hasn&amp;rsquo;t really broken the rules that he set down in the previous books, just expanded them, exploring areas that we&amp;rsquo;ve never seen before. We learn about people that live far from the Lord Ruler&amp;rsquo;s rule. We learn about new and fascinating ways that the Metallic Arts can be used&amp;ndash;Feruchemy in particular. And we start to see just how magic and technology can be combined.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shadows of Self</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/25/shadows-of-self/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/25/shadows-of-self/</guid><description>&lt;p>Shadows of Self takes place in the same timeline and with mostly the same characters as Alloy of Law. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard, this is supposed to be the actual first book of the second trilogy, with Alloy of Law being essentially a happy accident.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wax and Wayne are back, in all their awesome glory. I still greatly enjoy what Sanderson did both with their Allomantic/Feruchemic abilities (they&amp;rsquo;re more interesting / real feeling that the full Mistborn of the original trilogy) along with their great personalities. Wayne is the best sort of crazy and Wax is just as driven as ever. Marasi also gets a chance to shine as well, becoming a constable in her own right and putting her sharp mind, passion, and years of schooling to good use.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Alloy of Law</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/11/the-alloy-of-law/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/11/the-alloy-of-law/</guid><description>&lt;p>In Alloy of Law, Sanderson demonstrates not one, but two things that he&amp;rsquo;s done which I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen another author pull off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For one, he has a massive shared universe in the Cosmere. Each world has its own unique magic system (Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s strength) with just enough relation to the others to hint that they might just be part of a bigger universe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hero of Ages</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/05/the-hero-of-ages/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/06/05/the-hero-of-ages/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever since the Lord Ruler was killed in the first Mistborn book, things have been getting worse. It all comes to a head in The Hero of Ages. The world is quite literally ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s strength continues to be his world building. We get a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> more details this time around. We learn of a few more Allomantic metals. We learn all about the third metallic art (only previously hinted at): Hemalurgy. On top of that, we expand on what exactly the Koloss and Kandra are, what abilities they have, and how they came to be. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy awesome how it all fits together and would be well worth the read just got that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Well of Ascension</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/16/the-well-of-ascension/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/16/the-well-of-ascension/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since last I read this book, I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten just how much happens in this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since the Lord Ruler was killed in The Final Empire, some things have gotten better&amp;hellip; some have gotten much much worse.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Warbreaker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/08/warbreaker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/08/warbreaker/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wish it hadn&amp;rsquo;t taken quite so long to get to Warbreaker. It&amp;rsquo;s really quite a good book, right up there with pretty much all of the rest of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a neat magic system (as there always is)&amp;ndash;although this time around it felt a bit less detailed than Sanderson usually is. Usually even when as a reader doesn&amp;rsquo;t know all of the rules, you get the idea that there &lt;em>are&lt;/em> rules. This time, it just felt a bit more vague. I&amp;rsquo;m still unsure what exactly the color has to do with it, although the idea of magical automatons powered by souls (Breaths, whatever) is neat, if not quite as original as Sanderson often is. (It doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that I&amp;rsquo;m also reading Mistborn at the moment.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Final Empire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/01/the-final-empire/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/05/01/the-final-empire/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Final Empire is a great read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love the worldbuilding. It&amp;rsquo;s a weird world, with strange nightly mists and a near constant fall of ash that gets on everything. Even stranger, it&amp;rsquo;s hinted that the world was once much more like our own. On top of that, you have a quasi-Feudal society ruled by a powerful, potentially immortal being. All of which leads to some pretty obvious seeds for some crazy stuff to go on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Elantris</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/elantris/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/09/04/elantris/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have yet to find a Sanderson novel that I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly like and Elantris is no exception.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, Elantris focuses around the titular city; once a place of wonder and magic which. Ten years ago, all that ended and now it&amp;rsquo;s populated by essentially zombies: those without heartbeats who cannot die and cannot heal. We follow a few different story lines&amp;ndash;a princess from another land engaged to the prince who gets Elantrisified in the very beginning of the story; an attempted religious coup from multiple fronts; and the politics of a kingdom/city trying to heal after massive upheaval.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>