<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shirley Jackson on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/shirley-jackson/</link><description>Recent content in Shirley Jackson on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/shirley-jackson/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Haunting of Hill House</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/11/the-haunting-of-hill-house/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/11/the-haunting-of-hill-house/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No live organism can continue for long to exist sanely under conditions of absolute reality; even larks and katydids are supposed, by some, to dream. Hill House, not sane, stood by itself against its hills, holding darkness within; it had stood so for eighty years and might stand for eighty more. Within, walls continued upright, bricks met neatly, floors were firm, and doors were sensibly shut; silence lay steadily against the wood and stone of Hill House, and whatever walked there, walked alone.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A haunted house? Let&amp;rsquo;s do SCIENCE!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, that&amp;rsquo;s the claim. Mostly, it&amp;rsquo;s a vehicle to get all our main characters in one place, plus a bit of conflict later on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, we have character introductions. They&amp;rsquo;re some weird folks&amp;ndash;the best kind for these stories. And then the house as character. It&amp;rsquo;s impressive how you can get such a feel for a place with only minimal (initial) description. And then the caretakers of the house. Quite the characters those two are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then&amp;hellip; things get creepy. There&amp;rsquo;s little jumping out of the page to scare you. It&amp;rsquo;s not that sort of story. But it&amp;rsquo;s creepy nevertheless. Perfecting that evermounting sense of dread. And at that, it&amp;rsquo;s quite well done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that I enjoyed this book more having listened to the audiobook. It&amp;rsquo;s a slow burn and&amp;hellip; hard to describe just why it&amp;rsquo;s so intriguing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a try.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Journeys end in lovers meeting; I have spent an all but sleepless night, I have told lies and made a fool of myself, and the very air tastes like wine. I have been frightened half out of my foolish wits, but I have somehow earned this joy; I have been waiting for it for so long.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>