<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The 5th Wave on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/the-5th-wave/</link><description>Recent content in The 5th Wave on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/the-5th-wave/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Last Star</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/the-last-star/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/the-last-star/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s always been this way&amp;hellip; We bear the unbearable. We endure the unendurable. We do what must be done until we ourselves are undone.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Whelp. That&amp;rsquo;s where &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/the-5th-wave/">The 5th Wave&lt;/a> ends. Honestly, the first book was really quite good. The second was fine. And the third was &amp;hellip; marginally better?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But really, the ending kind of came out of left field, we got too much and not enough of the alien invaders all at the same time, and &amp;hellip; other than (mostly) Ringer, I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly care about what happens next to any of the protagonists.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Infinite Sea</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/the-infinite-sea/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/14/the-infinite-sea/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>That’s the cost. That’s the price. Get ready, because when you crush the humanity out of humans, you’re left with humans with no humanity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other words, you get what you pay for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/17/the-5th-wave/">The 5th Wave&lt;/a> had an interesting premise with a lot of potential: alien spaceship shows up; 4 waves of death and destruction kill 99.99% of humanity. This is the story of all that unfolding, plus what happens next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Infinite Sea takes that&amp;hellip; and continues it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The 5th Wave</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/10/the-5th-wave/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/10/the-5th-wave/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>After the 1st wave, only darkness remains.&lt;br>
After the 2nd, only the lucky escape.&lt;br>
And after the 3rd, only the unlucky survive.&lt;br>
After the 4th wave, only one rule applies: trust no one.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the world (as we know it). The aliens came and killed off most of humanity&amp;ndash;in some actually fairly interesting ways. This is the story of what comes next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first, it&amp;rsquo;s the story of Cassie after the end of the world. How she survives each wave (not told in order), how things keep getting worse, and then finally how she starts to find some &lt;em>other&lt;/em> survivors.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I would kill for a cheeseburger. Honestly. If I stumbled across someone eating a cheeseburger, I would kill them for it.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But then we start getting a few more points of view. More survivors and their own stories of death. Child soldiers. Human* survivors every bit as bad as the aliens. A possible look into what comes next.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>How do you rid the Earth of humans? Rid the humans of their humanity.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>