<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Grishaverse on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/grishaverse/</link><description>Recent content in Grishaverse on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/grishaverse/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rule of Wolves</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/27/rule-of-wolves/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/27/rule-of-wolves/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hate it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, not the book, I actually quite liked the book. It&amp;rsquo;s never an easy task to bring together as many different plotlines as you have when you&amp;rsquo;re the second book of the third series set in the same world&amp;ndash;and I think Bardugo did it well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No, I hate that one particular death in this book. They did &lt;em>not&lt;/em> have to die.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which I suppose means that it worked? Except&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel like it changed anything, other than to annoy me, the reader. So it goes I suppose.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>King of Scars</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/20/king-of-scars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/20/king-of-scars/</guid><description>&lt;p>All good things must end, it seems. We had our fun with Kaz and crew in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/">Six of Crows&lt;/a>. And now we shift focus once again, back to Ravka.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In some ways, it&amp;rsquo;s a continuation of the storyline of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a>, following the new King Nikolai as he deals with securing his throne in a nation deeply in debt with enemies on all sides. Plus, we get a lot more Zoya (who I did &lt;em>not&lt;/em> expect to like as much as I did) and at least some more of Genya and David (I do love their relationship).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another fascinating aspect of that storyline is that we get to dig much more into the mystical/religious underpinnings of the world. Six of Crows never really went there, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely something that came up in Shadow and Bone. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to feel like you know how magic works in the world&amp;ndash;and then realizing that you know nothing after all&amp;hellip; (both as a reader and as the characters).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will warn though: this part got &lt;em>weird&lt;/em>. All sorts of new and interesting (or I suppose old and interesting) metaphysics and magic we hadn&amp;rsquo;t really dug into before. A bit jarring&amp;ndash;both for the reader and for the characters involved&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a completely different direction, we also have a main storyline with Nina from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/">Six of Crows&lt;/a> (of all the characters, hers isn&amp;rsquo;t the first story I would have chosen to continue, but it is interesting). She&amp;rsquo;s still messed up / something new and now she&amp;rsquo;s off to Fjerda to continue to try to save the world. Newcomer Hanna is a lot of fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid book. It&amp;rsquo;s weird how disjoint the two storylines are&amp;ndash;they don&amp;rsquo;t really interact at all, although I see how they&amp;rsquo;ll likely come together in [[todo:Rule of Wolves]]. I kept finding myself annoyed when we switch from one to another.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crooked Kingdom</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/02/crooked-kingdom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/02/crooked-kingdom/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Crows remember human faces. They remember the people who feed them, who are kind to them. And the people who wrong them too. They don’t forget. They tell each other who to look after and who to watch out for.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/">Six of Crows&lt;/a> took the world of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> and instead gave us one heck of a heist book. Really, it all circled around one big, impossible heist. Plan everything, get in, plans fall apart, make new plans, and pull off the impossible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s one heck of an impressive book and I really enjoyed it, but it left an awful lot of plot thread hanging open&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which makes Crooked Kingdom all the more cathartic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Six of Crows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No mourners.&lt;br>
No funerals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among them, it passed for &amp;lsquo;good luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s such a good book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It takes the world of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> and completely ignores the at times overly YA political and religions machinations of that particular trilogy in favor of a somewhat darker and grittier heist novel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the most part, you really don&amp;rsquo;t need to have read Shadow and Bone first. There are a few references to the &amp;lsquo;Ravkan Civil War&amp;rsquo; and even to Sankta Alina, but other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s a new world. There are still Grisha, but they&amp;rsquo;re far less &amp;lsquo;miliary&amp;rsquo;, instead using (and hiding) their powers in all manner of interesting ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And while the heist elements were &lt;em>strong&lt;/em> (an impossible job, planning going absolutely sideways, and double triple crossing left and right) we also get all sorts of interesting backstory. Each of the main characters has chapters in their voice, but in the action going now, and explaining how they got into this mess in the first place. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot, but in a good way!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One gotcha is that, while the main heist plot is more than adequately contained in the book, it very much is the first half of a duology. It managed to just make me want to read the second&amp;hellip; but don&amp;rsquo;t go into this looking for a stand alone novel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what really shines are the characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ruin and Rising</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/24/ruin-and-rising/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/24/ruin-and-rising/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that&amp;rsquo;s quite an ending. After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> set the stage and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/19/siege-and-storm/">Siege and Storm&lt;/a> raised the stakes, Ruin and Rising really brings everything home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have the increasing religious fever of Alina as Saint&amp;ndash;whether or not that&amp;rsquo;s what she wants.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have what&amp;rsquo;s left of Alina&amp;rsquo;s friends and allies trying desperately to hold off the ever more powerful&amp;ndash;and ever more unhinged&amp;ndash;Darkling.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We finally get some real history, digging deeper into where the Darkling came from&amp;hellip; and perhaps how Alina fits into it all as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have more adventures; a desperate bid to find the third Amplifier that may well save the day&amp;ndash;or doom them all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And finally&amp;ndash;obvious seeing as it&amp;rsquo;s the final novel in the trilogy&amp;ndash;we have victory. But at what cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s by a decent margin my favorite of the three. A solid conclusion, in my opinion. Now I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the other series in the same world. Six of Crows especially to see where those threads in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/25/shadow-and-bone-season-1/">the show&lt;/a> came from and King of Scars for a &amp;lsquo;what comes next&amp;rsquo;. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Siege and Storm</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/19/siege-and-storm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/19/siege-and-storm/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When people say impossible, they usually mean improbable.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> had quite the ending. The Darkling showing his true allegiance, death and destruction, Alina and Mal on the run&amp;hellip; So of course in Siege and Storm they get captured by pirates (&lt;em>cough&lt;/em> I mean &lt;em>privateers&lt;/em>), the Darkling shows up again, they go meet the royal family, the Darkling shows up again, and in the end&amp;hellip; things just keep ending up getting worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s really a solid step up from Shadow and Bone. It&amp;rsquo;s still got a YA core, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely edging on the darker end of it all&amp;ndash;which I really enjoy. I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely looking forward to where this goes next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shadow and Bone</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/</guid><description>&lt;p>Browsing through Netflix last fall, I came upon &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/25/shadow-and-bone-season-1/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a>. Watched it. Quite enjoyed it. Figured I should read the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s not bad, but I enjoyed the show more. For one, it pulls in Kaz and co, which don&amp;rsquo;t appear in this novel at all (they&amp;rsquo;re originally from the related Six of Crows books), which is a bummer. For two, the additional dynamic of Alina as half-Shu in addition to being an orphan added rather a lot to her character.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>