<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rosaria Munda on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/rosaria-munda/</link><description>Recent content in Rosaria Munda on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/rosaria-munda/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fireborne</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/30/fireborne/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/30/fireborne/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dragons!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;are actually probably the weakest part of the book. We&amp;rsquo;ll get back to that.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>They watch us kneel, they see the back of our heads, and they think we&amp;rsquo;ve given in. They don&amp;rsquo;t realize you can think from your knees just as well as from your feet.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What we have here is an epic fantasy world, full of the aforementioned dragons and strife and war&amp;hellip; but for a change, this world is set in the near aftermath of the collapse of the old regime and the rise of the good guys. In theory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everyone gets a chance at education. Even commoners&amp;ndash;even orphans of the revolution&amp;ndash;can apply to be trained as dragon riders.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From there, we get the first half of the book&amp;ndash;a straight up magic school style training montage. It feels awfully YA, in the genre of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/03/30/the-hunger-games/">The Hunger Games&lt;/a> / &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/03/29/divergent/">Divergent&lt;/a> / &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/harry-potter/">Harry Potter&lt;/a>, up to and including a school tournament to decide the &amp;lsquo;best dragonrider&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What really makes the book shine to me is that initial setting&amp;ndash;the idea that we&amp;rsquo;re shortly after a revolution, building something new. And the entirely too real chance that the anything new&amp;hellip; might be just as bad as what came before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now&amp;hellip; the dragons. Despite the fact that all of our main characters have a dragon and they&amp;rsquo;re present throughout the series&amp;ndash;they never seem to really have any personality or presence of their own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even now, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I could honestly tell you more than the subspecies of each dragon, and even then only barely. I like intelligent dragons (a la &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/temeraire/">Temeraire&lt;/a>) and &lt;em>love&lt;/em> books with more &lt;em>alien&lt;/em> dragons (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/the-rage-of-dragons/">The Rage of Dragons&lt;/a> shines here). These are almost more like cars or fighter jets than anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s really a bummer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I enjoyed the series. And the way things go towards the latter part of the book + the ending really make me curious where in the world it&amp;rsquo;s going from here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>