<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ralph Wright on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/ralph-wright/</link><description>Recent content in Ralph Wright on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/ralph-wright/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lady and the Tramp</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/07/lady-and-the-tramp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/07/lady-and-the-tramp/</guid><description>That&amp;rsquo;s a cute little movie. I think if you&amp;rsquo;re going to do the dog thing, I would strongly prefer {{crosslink &amp;ldquo;One Hundred and One Dalmatians&amp;rdquo;}}. Better music, decent story. Could be that I watched the latter far more.
But characterwise, I did enjoy the contrast between the titular Lady and the Tramp and it&amp;rsquo;s a nice enough story. Stylistically, I enjoy the city and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to not really see the human characters (it&amp;rsquo;s a dog movie after all.</description></item><item><title>Bambi</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/27/bambi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/27/bambi/</guid><description>Bambi is a surprisingly tricky movie to review, mostly since it relies on who&amp;rsquo;s doing the reviewing. From my perspective, it&amp;rsquo;s cute enough, but there&amp;rsquo;s next to nothing there. It&amp;rsquo;s just a bunch of cute animated animals running around for an hour. From my kids&amp;rsquo; perspectives though&amp;hellip; they loved it. They were laughing out loud at the cartoon antics and cuddled right in during the storm and hunt scenes.
Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a fun enough movie for kids to watch, but I think next time they request it, I&amp;rsquo;ll find something else to do with my time.</description></item><item><title>The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/13/the-many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/13/the-many-adventures-of-winnie-the-pooh/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh is just delightful&amp;ndash;and a blast of nostalgia on top of that. I didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to actually watch all of the Disney classic growing up (still haven&amp;rsquo;t), but I definiately watched this one. And now, after reading many of the stories to my children, it&amp;rsquo;s a delight to be able to share the video form with them as well!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really like the style of these stories. It&amp;rsquo;s a mix of animated world with the real storybook characters (Pooh et al), but also obviously in a book, as they hob from page to page. It&amp;rsquo;s not the story of style you&amp;rsquo;d always expect to work, but it really works here.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maleficent</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/06/14/maleficent/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2014/06/14/maleficent/</guid><description>&lt;p>Maleficient was magnificent.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>