<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lilly Wachowski on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/directors/lilly-wachowski/</link><description>Recent content in Lilly Wachowski on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/directors/lilly-wachowski/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Matrix Revolutions</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/14/the-matrix-revolutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/14/the-matrix-revolutions/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh the Matrix Revolutions. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/the-matrix-reloaded/">The Matrix Reloaded&lt;/a>: Part 2. We cut in right as that one ended, with Neo out for the count, robots descending on Zion, and Smith doing&amp;hellip; whatever Smith is doing. I particularly appreciate the idea of humans, programs, and machines perhaps finding common ground (which &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/30/the-matrix-resurrections/">The Matrix Resurrections&lt;/a> really got into).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Neo: I just have never&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rama-Kandra: &amp;hellip;heard a program speak of love?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neo: It&amp;rsquo;s a&amp;hellip; human emotion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rama-Kandra: No, it is a word. What matters is the connection the word implies. I see that you are in love. Can you tell me what you would give to hold on to that connection?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neo: Anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rama-Kandra: Then perhaps the reason you&amp;rsquo;re here is not so different from the reason I&amp;rsquo;m here.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Matrix Reloaded</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/the-matrix-reloaded/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/11/the-matrix-reloaded/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Morpheus: [Morpheus addresses the people of Zion] Zion, hear me! It is true, what many of you have heard. The machines have gathered an army and as I speak, that army is drawing nearer to our home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[the Zion crowd becomes louder]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Morpheus: Believe me when I say we have a difficult time ahead of us. But if we are to be prepared for it, we must first shed our fear of it. I stand here, before you now, truthfully unafraid. Why? Because I believe something you do not? No, I stand here without fear because I remember. I remember that I am here not because of the path that lies before me but because of the path that lies behind me. I remember that for 100 years we have fought these machines. I remember that for 100 years they have sent their armies to destroy us, and after a century of war I remember that which matters most&amp;hellip; We are still here! Today, let us send a message to that army. Tonight, let us shake this cave. Tonight, let us tremble these halls of earth, steel, and stone, let us be heard from red core to black sky. Tonight, let us make them remember, THIS IS ZION AND WE ARE NOT AFRAID!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>More Matrix! I love it!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Matrix</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/the-matrix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/the-matrix/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh the Matrix. This movie came out at just the perfect time for me&amp;ndash;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t into the counter culture as much, but even then I was messing around with computers and hacking&amp;ndash;and I absolutely love every minute of it. It stands up even today, with a retrofuturistic sort of vibe that really still works even though it&amp;rsquo;s been twenty years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloud Atlas</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/06/cloud-atlas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 04:00:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/11/06/cloud-atlas/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wanted to make sure that I caught Cloud Atlas while it was in theaters, so that meant that I pretty much had to go this week. Between the 23 local screens, only 1 is still showing it and that only for three showings per day. I give it until the end of the week, maybe next week at tops before it&amp;rsquo;s gone.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>