<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rita Todacheene on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/rita-todacheene/</link><description>Recent content in Rita Todacheene on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/rita-todacheene/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exposure</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/05/exposure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/05/exposure/</guid><description>&lt;p>Of course I had to read the sequel!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s another story of Rita Todacheene, but this time getting into the absolute &lt;em>trauma&lt;/em> of the first book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s hard enough (I imagine) being a crime scene photography. Constantly exposed to all that fairly grisly death. But add to that ghosts only you can see screaming at you about solving their murders, but when few enough of your coworkers and bosses believe you&amp;ndash;to the point of thinking you&amp;rsquo;ve lost your mind?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So Rita is done. Heading back home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Except this time&amp;hellip; the ghosts are coming with her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time, rather than backstory the second plot being Rita&amp;rsquo;s past, we have another point of view&amp;ndash;who we quicly learn is a serial killer caught up in his own paranoid worldview and bringing it violently to those around him. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating contrast to the first book and I really liked it. It reminded me a lot of various thrillers I read years and years ago, mostly by &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/dean-koontz/">Dean Koontz&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid sequel and I so wish the best and better for Rita. Oh I&amp;rsquo;m curious to see if there will be another! Where do you go from here?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shutter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/02/shutter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/02/shutter/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Grandma always said to me that you never do things for people to get something in return. That is the white man’s way of living. You do it because they need you. You do it because if you don’t, no one else will.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s quite a book!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a word, it&amp;rsquo;s an urban fantasy about a Diné (Navajo) forensic photographer that can see ghosts. But it&amp;rsquo;s so much more than that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I love the main character: Rita Todacheene. Someone that can see ghosts and a cop (or cop adjacent) is something I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before, but it being a forensic photographer gave a particular poignancy to the whole thing. And the Diné angle was fascinating&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a bit of it in other urban fantasy books, but they have a particular way of looking at death which really plays interestingly against someone that can see ghosts!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a bit of setting, the attention to detail on the cameras and the craft of photography was a really interesting touch. Rita, growing up poor but from a whole line of photographers. You really get the feeling she knows and loves everything about it which really gives a certain feel to the story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Content warning though: We do get a number of descriptions of what exactly she&amp;rsquo;s photographing. And some of those are &lt;em>grisly&lt;/em>. At least we don&amp;rsquo;t get the pictures? (I don&amp;rsquo;t actually know for sure, I listened to this on audiobook&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Structurally, the book alternates between the present day&amp;ndash;Rita trying to solve crimes and stay mostly sane with ghosts hounding here&amp;ndash;and the past: Rita&amp;rsquo;s time growing up with her grandmother on a reservation, first coming to terms with life, death, and all it means to her specifically. It&amp;rsquo;s a really nice contrast, pulling the two stories together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s not the most complicated of mysteries. You mostly have enough clues to figure out where this is going, but oh the ride to get there. It&amp;rsquo;s still well worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I learned early that no amount of prayer or smoke or love was ever going to change the fact that these lights wanted to talk to me. Even at three years old, I knew it was something that deeply terrified my grandma and our medicine man. It was something that I was going to have to hide from them. As I got older, I taught myself how to look beyond the ghosts and mute their voices.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>