<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philip Reeve on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/philip-reeve/</link><description>Recent content in Philip Reeve on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/philip-reeve/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Darkling Plain</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/31/a-darkling-plain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/31/a-darkling-plain/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends. I&amp;rsquo;ve had some issues with this series (mostly with some of the relationship drama present throughout), but I&amp;rsquo;m glad I finished it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I liked what happened to either Tom or Hester. Tom is entirely too naive. Pennyroyal literally shot him&amp;ndash;and this is likely to kill him one day. He enslaved Tom&amp;rsquo;s daughter. And he doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to care. He&amp;rsquo;s good to a fault and it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem real. Hester&amp;hellip; is crazy and violent and full of a desire for vengeance and it&amp;rsquo;s only worse this time around. This time it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel unreal&amp;ndash;what does that say about me?&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s still sad that she ended up this way. Wren and Theo I liked a lot more. I wish they would have spent less time separated nearly missing one another again and again, but it works out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Predator's Gold</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/09/predators-gold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/12/09/predators-gold/</guid><description>&lt;p>On one hand, Predator&amp;rsquo;s Gold does a solid job of expanding on what was the best part of Mortal Engines: the world building all around mobile cities that eat one another. We get to see a few more cities&amp;ndash;both predators and trading cities&amp;ndash;along with more details on airships in this world. But the real worldbuilding gold&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> is in the parasites that can attach themselves to cities and steal from them. It really makes the cities feel like gigantic living organisms as much as anything, which I&amp;rsquo;m sure is Reeve&amp;rsquo;s intention.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, I very nearly put Predator&amp;rsquo;s Gold down several times during the first half of the book. There&amp;rsquo;s a rather blatant love triangle between Tom, Hester, and Freya (princess of Anchorage&amp;ndash;roving city of the north nearly destroyed by a plague in the recent past). It really doesn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense given Tom and Hester&amp;rsquo;s relationship at the end of the first book and drags on way too long. Perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s what some people read the book for&amp;hellip; but it&amp;rsquo;s really not for me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mortal Engines</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/25/mortal-engines/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/07/25/mortal-engines/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It was a dark, blustery afternoon in spring, and the city of London was chasing a small mining town across the dried-out bed of the old North Sea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon the city was lumbering in pursuit, a moving mountain of metal that rose in seven tiers like the layers of a wedding cake, the lower levels wreathed in engine smoke, the villas of the rich gleaming white on the higher decks, and above it all the cross on top of St. Paul’s Cathedral glinting gold, two thousand feet above the ruined earth.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>