<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Millennium on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/10/millennium/</link><description>Recent content in Millennium on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/10/millennium/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Girl Who Kicked the Hornet's Nest</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/10/the-girl-who-kicked-the-hornets-nest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/11/10/the-girl-who-kicked-the-hornets-nest/</guid><description>&lt;p>Given that Hornet&amp;rsquo;s Nest kicks off immediately following the events of Played with Fire, I was hoping that it could keep up the momentum of the previous book and avoid the slow first half / crazy second half that the previous two books had suffered from. Unfortunately, no such luck. If anything, it takes even longer to get moving and the conclusion isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as action packed as the previous novels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, I do feel like this was a solid conclusion to the series. It wrapped up a lot of loose ends that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t even realized I was missing and finished character arcs, particularly for Lisbeth. She&amp;rsquo;s still odd, but I&amp;rsquo;m really starting to understand where she comes from. And in the end, she wins. I would have been rather grumpy with the author (even if he is dead) had she not come out all right in the end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Girl Who Played with Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/31/the-girl-who-played-with-fire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/31/the-girl-who-played-with-fire/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo took a while to get into. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until Lisbeth and Blomkvist were finally in the same place perhaps halfway through the book that things really started moving.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Girl Who Played with Fire is much the same.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-girl-with-the-dragon-tattoo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/10/23/the-girl-with-the-dragon-tattoo/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not that often any more that I finish a book in a day. That should tell you something about what I thought about the Girl with the Dragon Tattoo. Especially when it isn&amp;rsquo;t fantasy. It isn&amp;rsquo;t science fiction. It isn&amp;rsquo;t horror (at least not the supernatural sort). Really, it&amp;rsquo;s more of a investigation / thriller. Not a genre that I read that often.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Honestly, for the first half of the book, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure that I was even going to finish it, let alone read the sequels. There were a few different story lines going on that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really see how they fit together. Nothing overly much seemed to be happening. Then, around halfway through (when the main characters finally started to interact more), things really started moving. I read the rest of the book in one sitting.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>