<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andrew Verkamp on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/andrew-verkamp/</link><description>Recent content in Andrew Verkamp on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/andrew-verkamp/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kyana Woodstock: One More Day of Peace and Music</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/15/kyana-woodstock-one-more-day-of-peace-and-music/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/15/kyana-woodstock-one-more-day-of-peace-and-music/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose the proverbial &amp;ldquo;greatest book of all time&amp;rdquo; is The Bible (and/or the Quran?). These collections contain a series of sometimes random, rambling stories, yet they all reinforce a key overarching theme. Debates continue as to whether The Bible is pure fact—a series of &amp;ldquo;memoirs&amp;rdquo; documenting events around that central theme—or fictionalized to reinforce the same message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry Potter, by many accounts, comes in second as one of the greatest books ever written. There’s no debate about this one; it was crafted purely as a work of fiction. But again, it’s a series of stories that follow close friends as they navigate their life journeys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That &amp;hellip; is quite a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a memior of Andrew Verkamp&amp;ndash;a boy who &lt;del&gt;grew&lt;/del&gt; threw up in rural southern Indiana. And to read it, it&amp;rsquo;s honestly a bit of a surprise he made it this far. From a runaway chainsaw to a cabin in the woods, from childhood drinking to biting a head off a turkey. And that&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many of these stories will translate well if you didn&amp;rsquo;t grow up in that particular time and place, but at the very least it&amp;rsquo;s just like a train crash&amp;ndash;in all the best ways. You know, for some reason, that you perhaps shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be enjoying this quite so much&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to look away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDITOR&amp;rsquo;S NOTE: I assume any legal implications from that evening have long since exceeded the statute of limitations, and this public confession has no legal basis. If it does, just forget I said anything. It was a snowy night, and obviously, I was safe at home cuddled up in bed that night (just ask Mom and Dad). That&amp;rsquo;s the story, and I am sticking to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other, it&amp;rsquo;s the story of Kyana Woodstock&amp;ndash;25 years of a local mirror of that famous concert now itself more than half a century gone. Growing from a TV in the backyard to a 30&amp;rsquo;+ screen, hundreds of guests, live music, and entirely too many fireworks to a professional venue with licensing fees, insurance worries, and seats for 1500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s structurally a strange book, taking half the time to even get to the title&amp;rsquo;s point. It&amp;rsquo;s a touch &amp;lsquo;stream of consciousness&amp;rsquo; at times and you&amp;rsquo;re never quite sure where (or when) the next story is going to take you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t your average blah, blah, blah book. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s a random &amp;ldquo;kamikaze&amp;rdquo; style of seemingly unrelated &amp;ldquo;pukes&amp;rdquo; of brain thoughts, all weaving into a &amp;lsquo;sorta&amp;rsquo; seamless collection of recollections. Four books in one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But oh, is it a ride alone the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: You might be able to guess from author&amp;rsquo;s name (and the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;in the book&lt;/em&gt;) that this is my father. I also helped a bit to edit the book and read an earlier version before this one. Heck, I even wrote one of the chapters (apparently). So take this all with a &lt;del&gt;grain&lt;/del&gt; heaping spoonful of salt. But like I said&amp;ndash;once you get start, it&amp;rsquo;s a hard book to put down.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>