<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Animorphs Chronicles on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/animorphs-chronicles/</link><description>Recent content in Animorphs Chronicles on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/animorphs-chronicles/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VISSER</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/28/visser/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/28/visser/</guid><description>&lt;p>Told from the point of view of Visser One (former and, for the moment, current). On trial, in front of the Council of Thirteen themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I spoke to the holographic representation of the Council. Thirteen Yeerks in various host bodies: Nine Hork-Bajir, two Taxxons, and two whose host bodies were so concealed that I could not guess at their form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They were dressed in dark red robes, so dark that they were almost black. They stood, motionless, held in place, suspended by gravity-neutral fields, fed by a continuous refined current of Kandrona rays.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Hork-Bajir-Controllers wore a lightweight mesh beneath their robes to keep the wrist and arm blades from slicing through the robe&amp;rsquo;s fabric.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The two Taxxon-Controllers were bloated, monstrously inflated versions of the great centipedes. Both were attended by Gedds, ready with freshly killed meat to feed the eternal hunger that not even a Yeerk inside that feverish brain can control. Their ceremonial robes were as large as sails, wrapped around the raised front third of their bodies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They were light-years away, of course. They would see me, my host face and body in three dimensions. They could also watch my vital signs, translated into universal equivalents. Blood pressure, heart rate, hormone production, all reduced to digital readouts a billion miles away. And they could, with a thought, call up whatever data had been compiled on specific events or locations or individuals.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I really do enjoy the worldbuilding here and I&amp;rsquo;m a bit sad that this is about as much as we&amp;rsquo;re going to get about the Council.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, it&amp;rsquo;s yet another interesting point of view. Especially when you add in Visser One&amp;rsquo;s testimony&amp;ndash;the backstory of how the Yeerk invasion of Earth actually began.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tentatively I reached toward the far side of the brain. I touched it. Made contact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fascinating!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was incredible. This second half of the brain was an almost mirror image, but not. It could have functioned all on its own, if necessary, and yet it was in some ways radically different in its memories, its sensory interpretation, even its will. Two almost entirely functional brains in one skull, communicating across a channel of nerves. Not a fully redundant system, almost a second, different brain!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s more interesting to think that humans are weird like that (and that is weird) or that seemingly no other species is!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoy all of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/animorphs-chronicles/">Animorphs Chronicles&lt;/a>. This is no exception.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hork-Bajir Chronicles</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/10/the-hork-bajir-chronicles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/10/the-hork-bajir-chronicles/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, I do enjoy the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/animorphs-chronicles/">Animorphs Chronicles&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/">The Andalite Chronicles&lt;/a> were good, but if anything, The Hork-Bajir Chronicles are even better! If nothing else, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot less time travel. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this one, we get not only the story of the Hork-Bajir, but to a large extent the story of how the Yeerks came to be as well:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Alloran turned all four of his eyes on my father. &amp;lt;Prince Seerow, you are relieved of duty.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;You can&amp;rsquo;t relieve me!&amp;gt; my father cried.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;When a commander has become incapacitated due to injury or mental defect, his subordinates may relieve him,&amp;gt; Alloran quoted from the regulations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;What mental defect?&amp;gt; my father demanded.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Stupidity,&amp;gt; Alloran said harshly. &amp;lt;The stupidity of kindness. Charity to potential enemies. You&amp;rsquo;re a fool, Seerow. A soft, sentimental, well-meaning fool. And now my men are dead and the Yeerks are loose in the galaxy. How many will die before we can bring this contagion under control? How many will die for Seerow&amp;rsquo;s kindness?&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s Alloran and his family (especially his daughter) sent to the Hork-Bajir world&amp;ndash;and them that end up directly participating in the terrible mess that we all knew had to be coming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But up until then, I love the worldbuilding in this one. The Hork-Bajir world is &lt;em>weird&lt;/em>. I love the idea of a shattered world and giant (kilometers tall) trees keeping it barely habitable. I love the (minor spoilers) reasons &lt;em>why&lt;/em> the world and the Hork-Bajir are the way they are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then eventually, I love the conflict. Andalite versus Hork-Bajir, not fighting, but morally and ethically. And the Yeerks in all their soon to be overwhelming numbers. It&amp;rsquo;s an invasion rather unlike that of Earth&amp;ndash;far more out in the open.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an added bonus, our first point of view of how the Yeerks do their thing:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My sonar found the head quite easily, of course. And I&amp;rsquo;d been taught how to pinpoint the opening into the head by extending two palps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was quite a small entryway. I had to squeeze myself down and work my way slowly inside the ear canal. From there on, it was all by feel. My sonar didn&amp;rsquo;t work, of course. And the smells encountered were unfamiliar, useless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But then, after what seemed far too long a time, my palps encountered a surface alive with electricity!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The brain. I could feel the activity, the snapping neurons, the arcs of microvoltage between synapses. I had to flatten myself all the way. My palps sought for trenches, gaps, openings around the brain. And I found them. I pushed my body down inside each wrinkle of the brain. Just as I&amp;rsquo;d been taught to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And slowly at first, then faster and faster, I began to make contact! I felt the neurons connecting to me!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Still&amp;hellip; a bit weird. But it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see for once.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I mentioned, one of my favorites, at least up until we get to The Ellimist Chronicles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Andalite Chronicles</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something new! (If you not on a reread :))&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rather than the shared points of view of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/12/the-andalites-gift/">The Andalite&amp;#39;s Gift&lt;/a>, we now have the first [[Animorphs Chronicles|chronicle]] book: a book written from a completely alien (heh) point of view to fill in some other part of the universe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this case Elfangor-Sirinial-Shamtul. The one who in a lot of ways started this whole mess. And after reading this book&amp;ndash;apparently in more ways than we could believe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, we get a lot of fascinating world building. Learning more about Andelite culture directly, as opposed to via our normal human filters. Learning about Yeerks. Visser Three (before he was Three!). And Taxxons. And Skrit Na.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Skrit Na ship was round, with tapered sides. It looked like a fat disc. You could hardly even see where the engines were, and the Skrit Na had blinking colored lights all around it. I guess they find that attractive or something.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>(it&amp;rsquo;s a typical saucer shaped UFO)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand (minor spoilers, but it becomes obvious fairly early), time travel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve done that already&amp;ndash;and not that long ago (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/21/the-forgotten/">The Forgotten&lt;/a>). And&amp;hellip; while it&amp;rsquo;s got some interesting points here, it makes things a bit too messy and convenient, at least in my opinion.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>