<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Asteroid Wars on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/17/the-asteroid-wars/</link><description>Recent content in The Asteroid Wars on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/17/the-asteroid-wars/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Aftermath</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/17/the-aftermath/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/17/the-aftermath/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a standalone story, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/17/the-aftermath/">The Aftermath&lt;/a> would have been pretty good. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting story from a sci-fi take: a family on a space ship out in the belt, hauling ore. They&amp;rsquo;re attacked. One member escapes back to the belt and the rest are sent out on a long orbit with a broken ship, years before they&amp;rsquo;ll return to civilization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting story, showing just how big space is and how dangerous a frontier it can be in a science fiction story can be in the near future solar system, where they don&amp;rsquo;t have magical engines that can go through the system in days (well, they do, but not on a cargo ship like this). And if you don&amp;rsquo;t have an antenna and can&amp;rsquo;t aim a laser, then you can&amp;rsquo;t very well talk to anyone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Silent War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/07/the-silent-war/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/07/the-silent-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/07/the-silent-war/">The Silent War&lt;/a> feels like a conclusion to the Asteroid Wars ( &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/14/the-precipice/">The Precipice&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/01/the-rock-rats/">The Rock Rats&lt;/a> ), with the war continuing to escalate to father and father atrocities with even more sides to the conflict than before ( &lt;span class="spoiler">Yamagata is back! If a bit weirdly.&lt;/span>
 ). It&amp;rsquo;s a bit strange to see what feels like such a conclusion with one book left, but I guess that&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/17/the-aftermath/">The Aftermath&lt;/a> ? We&amp;rsquo;ll just have to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, The Silent War is a satisfying enough conclusion to the Asteroid Wars (as a war and as a subseries) building up both the overall conflict and one within the book itself. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to actually see everything come to a head and I think the conclusion is workable, if a little ridiculous. It really feeds into the idea that behind every powerful corporation is a handful (or one) of powerful men and women really driving things forward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Rock Rats</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/01/the-rock-rats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/01/the-rock-rats/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/07/01/the-rock-rats/">The Rock Rats&lt;/a> continues the story of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/14/the-precipice/">The Precipice&lt;/a>, following the story of humanity&amp;rsquo;s expansion into the Asteroid Belt and all the atrocities that entails.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, this book is all over the place. Pancho is great fun, but we don&amp;rsquo;t see nearly enough of her. Lars is &amp;hellip; kind of crazy and revenge driven, a long descent from liking him well enough in The Precipice. Amanda is pretty great, but only when she&amp;rsquo;s away from either Lars or Humpries. Of all the marriages in the series thus far, why does this have to be the one to stick beyond a single book? They really don&amp;rsquo;t make much sense together&amp;hellip; Trite as the saying may be, she could do better.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Precipice</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/14/the-precipice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/14/the-precipice/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/06/14/the-precipice/">The Precipice&lt;/a> does two things rather well: it introduces technology that will change the Grand Tour universe and it makes me actually &amp;hellip; kind of like Dan Randolph.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the former, we finally have one possible solution to the fundamental problem of near future science fiction:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>