<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Disrupted Magic on jverkamp.com</title>
    <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/disrupted-magic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Disrupted Magic on jverkamp.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/disrupted-magic/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow Hunt</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/25/shadow-hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/25/shadow-hunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;36225306&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36225306.shadow-hunt&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/shadow-hunt.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was bad enough that Americans insisted on driving themselves everywhere, but Los Angeles in particular seemed to depend on individual cars the way other, more intelligent cities depended on public transportation. And their reward for this individualism was to spend hours of every day in gridlock. Petra thought it was a perfect example of American “independence”—selfish, lazy, and with a complete lack of foresight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not entirely wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blood Gamble</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/19/blood-gamble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/19/blood-gamble/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;34181876&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34181876.blood-gamble&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/blood-gamble.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is how I ended up being the only one who could help. As a null, I don’t have any particular magic powers—just the opposite, really. I negate all the magic within a certain radius around me, creating a magic-free bubble that has me as its center. In theory, if Marko stayed within that area, I could keep him human for a short time, and he and his wife could make a baby the old-fashioned way. Assuming, of course, we could all get past the extreme awkwardness that would be involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was weird, but it was far from the weirdest thing I’d done lately. The leaders of the Los Angeles vampires, werewolves, and witches all paid me a retainer to clean up supernatural problems that arose in the city. When things were quiet, as they’d been for the past couple of months, I was free to pick up freelance work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time this involved shepherding vampires around during daylight activities, but two weeks earlier, I had been paid to attend a witch’s beach volleyball tournament so I could make sure her opponent wasn’t using magic to cheat. A few days before that, I’d accompanied a crowd-shy werewolf to a taping of his favorite sitcom, to help him stay calm in the midst of all that teeming humanity. I might have actually enjoyed that outing, except the sitcom was one of those “fat slovenly husband vs. shrill anorexic wife” crapfests. Freelance work could be kind of a gamble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midnight Curse</title>
      <link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/18/midnight-curse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/18/midnight-curse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;cover-image&#34;&gt;
                &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;31352753&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/31352753.midnight-curse&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/midnight-curse.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finished &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;24369122&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24369122.boundary-crossed&#34;&gt;Boundary Crossed&lt;/a&gt; and the sequels in 2017, I enjoyed them enough to put &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;author&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;6536659&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/6536659.melissa-f-olson&#34;&gt;Melissa F. Olson&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s other books on my ever expanding to-read list. &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/01/2019-reading-list/&#34;&gt;Last year&lt;/a&gt;, I randomly choose &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;31352753&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/31352753.midnight-curse&#34;&gt;Midnight Curse&lt;/a&gt; to read and finally got to it this year&amp;ndash;not realizing that it&amp;rsquo;s actually the &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; Scarlett Bernard series. &lt;a data-goodreads-type=&#34;book&#34; data-goodreads-id=&#34;16037696&#34; href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16037696.dead-spots&#34;&gt;Dead Spots&lt;/a&gt; is the first (even before Boundary Crossed actually).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually matter that much, at least so far, but there are a number of references to previous events that I expect I would already know about. So it goes. It&amp;rsquo;s actually kind of nice not to go through Scarlett first finding out about the Old World and getting acclimated and just start out in the middle of everything. Plus, having the protagonist that basically cleans up messes and neutralizes anyone else in the Old World is pretty cool. Also, she&amp;rsquo;s wonderfully snarky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>