<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Temeraire on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/temeraire/</link><description>Recent content in Temeraire on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/temeraire/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Black Powder War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/29/black-powder-war/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/29/black-powder-war/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“One man can go where a group cannot, and manage on very little, particularly a rough adventurer such as he. More the point, he risks only himself when he goes: you much consider that in your charge is an inexpressibly valuable dragon, whose loss must be of greater importance than even this mission.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Oh, pray, let us be gone at once,&amp;rdquo; said the inexpressibly valuable dragon, when Laurence had carried the question, still unresolved, back to him. &amp;ldquo;It sounds very exciting to me.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/15/his-majestys-dragon/">His Majesty's Dragon&lt;/a> started strong, with dragons fighting great battles in the Napoleonic wars. In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/">Throne of Jade&lt;/a>, we took almost an entire book to get to get to (and then some of that to) experience China. So now in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/29/black-powder-war/">Black Powder War&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; we get to come home?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More seriously, it&amp;rsquo;s actually quite a story. Laurence and Temeraire get a super important message (tm) that there are dragon eggs that need picked up in Istanbul. There isn&amp;rsquo;t time to book a ship&amp;hellip; so they&amp;rsquo;re about to travel the Old Silk Road across a huge chunk of land.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Throne of Jade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Those men want to take Laurence from me, and put him in prison, and execute him, and I will not let them, ever, and I do not care if Laurence tells me not to squash you,&amp;quot; he added, fiercely, to Lord Barham.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Laurence and the British Government may think that Temeraire was won fairly under the articles of war&amp;hellip; but the Chinese aren&amp;rsquo;t so sure. In an effort to appease them, off Temeraire and Laurence go, halfway around the world to see if they can&amp;rsquo;t convince them otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a number of parts to really like about this book: Getting to travel the world is neat. The difference of Chinese culture, especially around dragons is fun. I like the idea of basically a Napoleonic era aircraft carrier for dragons. There are other related big beasties in the world as well!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The discussions about slavery, the differences in culture between the British and Chinese, and what that might mean for dragons were fascinating. Especially having read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/23/a-declaration-of-the-rights-of-magicians/">A Declaration of the Rights of Magicians&lt;/a> not &lt;em>that&lt;/em> long ago, it was interesting to see another take on the same period&amp;ndash;especially when we randomly get news that Pitt has died.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course, the aforequoted relationship between Temeraire and Laurence. That&amp;rsquo;s really a great part of the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a downside, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit less action packed than the first book. We get a couple of big fights, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, but it&amp;rsquo;s got a low slower pace. A bit jarring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>His Majesty's Dragon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/15/his-majestys-dragon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/15/his-majestys-dragon/</guid><description>&lt;p>TLDR: Well that&amp;rsquo;s unexpected. Originally (8 years ago), I wasn&amp;rsquo;t thrilled. Enough to DNF the series (although not the book). On a reread (+relisten?), I loved it and am looking forward to more!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>8 years ago, I first read Temeraire. I thought the idea was fascinating. An alternate history set around the time of Napoleon, tied fairly closely to our own world. Only: Dragons! Cool, no? And turns out&amp;hellip; it is pretty cool!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet somehow, I managed to find myself annoyed by the mechanics of dragons, their intelligence, and&amp;ndash;for some reason&amp;ndash;the idea that there was a &amp;lsquo;chosen one&amp;rsquo; trope going on? I feel like I must have mellowed out somewhat in age. Or decided that I like almost everything now. Or read enough &lt;em>really&lt;/em> good Naomi Novik that I wanted to give it another try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that one big difference this time was listening to the audiobook. Some books just work better that way&amp;ndash;something about the book picking you up and carrying you along, where it&amp;rsquo;s easier to just keep listening rather than having to work at it. This is definitely one of them.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>