<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Temeraire on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/temeraire/</link><description>Recent content in Temeraire on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/temeraire/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blood of Tyrants</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/29/blood-of-tyrants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/29/blood-of-tyrants/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first half or so of the book follows Laurence in Japan (cool!) and back to China (cool!) who&amp;hellip; lost all memories of the last eight years (oy!). I don&amp;rsquo;t know if there&amp;rsquo;s a series that&amp;rsquo;s had a serious amnesia storyline I actually liked and this wasn&amp;rsquo;t the exception. A third of the entire reason of the series is Temeraire and Laurence and their relationship. To lose all of that&amp;ndash;even if it gives a chance to rebuild and explore it again? Not shiny.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crucible of Gold</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/25/crucible-of-gold/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/25/crucible-of-gold/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“They are ours,” he said, “although not properly the sailors: they are only along because we would not leave them to drown, and ought to be more grateful for it than they are. Laurence,” he said, turning, “this is Palta, and that man is called Taruca: Iskierka snatched him, and I cannot find she asked him in the least.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s an interesting one. On one hand, I&amp;rsquo;m glad they&amp;rsquo;re out of Australia. Instead, they&amp;rsquo;re off across the Pacific&amp;hellip; to Brazil and the Portuguese royal family. Of course things don&amp;rsquo;t go as expected. Crossing the Pacific is one mess and meeting up with the Inca and how they deal with dragons was pretty fascinating&amp;ndash;they&amp;rsquo;re still a power to be reckoned with in this world, mostly on the backs of their local dragons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still not up to the strengths of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/13/victory-of-eagles/">Victory of Eagles&lt;/a>, mostly because the travels and exploration was never the original draw of the series&amp;ndash;the Napoleon but &lt;em>dragons&lt;/em> was, and we&amp;rsquo;ve scant little of that. This time around&amp;hellip; we do at least get the war, which is pretty cool. So it&amp;rsquo;s a decent book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tongues of Serpents</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/21/tongues-of-serpents/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/21/tongues-of-serpents/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It seems to me after a fellow has been mutinied against three or four times, there is something to it besides bad luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Convicted of Treason in Napoleonic Era Britain? Where else to go next but&amp;hellip; Australia!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s another travelog of a book, showing off yet another continent, although this time without much in the way of native dragons at all. We get a lot of very minor politics, a very long chase sequence across much of the continent following a stolen egg, a few interesting newly hatched dragons (probably the highlight of the book honestly). I do miss a lot of the old crew, but it&amp;rsquo;s something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notice anything missing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s painfully little in the way of big Napoleonic battles (with dragons!). Slightly more exploration of Chinese dragons and that end of the world, but not that much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In theory, it&amp;rsquo;s a way for Laurence to deal with his actions in previous books&amp;hellip; but we&amp;rsquo;ve already done a chunk of that in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/13/victory-of-eagles/">Victory of Eagles&lt;/a> and we really don&amp;rsquo;t get much of it here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem quite like something we need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward. Fingers crossed.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I am sick of the quarrels of nations and kings, and I would not give a ha&amp;rsquo;pence for any empire other than our valley, if that can content your ambition.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Victory of Eagles</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/13/victory-of-eagles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/13/victory-of-eagles/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If they cannot be woken to a natural affection for their country, such as we feel, it is our fault and not theirs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Where Laurence is condemned for Treason for trying to prevent war crimes and Temeraire is on his own&amp;ndash;and ends up starting a sort of soft revolution among the dragons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite a story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laurence having to go against loyalty, against king and country was a Big Thing last book, so seeing the fallout of that goes about as expected. It&amp;rsquo;s dark. And we&amp;rsquo;re still not done with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And seeing Temeraire come into his own, basically take over the breeding grounds, and speak for dragonkind in Britain? Love it. Plus, a whole bunch of Temeraire point of view! Couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it any other way and the voices are as distinct as I expected. But it&amp;rsquo;s lovely to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite a book and well worth the read in the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward to see what happens next!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Maximus] put his head down and said in a conspiratorial whisper, “Tell Temeraire that Lily and I have not forgotten our promise; we will not let them hang you at all.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laurence stared up at the immense Regal Copper. All his crew looked deeply distressed, as well they might, the outlaw remark being perfectly audible several clearings over.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It continues being delightful to read about the largest dragons trying to be sneaky.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Empire of Ivory</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/08/empire-of-ivory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/08/empire-of-ivory/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/">There&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/29/black-powder-war/">back again&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; and now everydragon left behind in Britain is deathly ill! So of course it&amp;rsquo;s up to Laurence and Temeraire to save the day!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As it seems to be the case in each of these books past the first, we&amp;rsquo;re off on an adventure! Novik really does like showing off the world as it was in that time period. This time around, to the Cape of Africa (and eventually across the interior). We get to meet new and interesting friends, enemies, and dragons along the way; along with all sorts of fun* moral problems of the era (and in general).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another solid entry in the series and worth the read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward! And who even knows whereto next?!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Powder War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/29/black-powder-war/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/29/black-powder-war/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“One man can go where a group cannot, and manage on very little, particularly a rough adventurer such as he. More the point, he risks only himself when he goes: you much consider that in your charge is an inexpressibly valuable dragon, whose loss must be of greater importance than even this mission.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Oh, pray, let us be gone at once,&amp;rdquo; said the inexpressibly valuable dragon, when Laurence had carried the question, still unresolved, back to him. &amp;ldquo;It sounds very exciting to me.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/15/his-majestys-dragon/">His Majesty's Dragon&lt;/a> started strong, with dragons fighting great battles in the Napoleonic wars. In &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/">Throne of Jade&lt;/a>, we took almost an entire book to get to get to (and then some of that to) experience China. So now in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/29/black-powder-war/">Black Powder War&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; we get to come home?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More seriously, it&amp;rsquo;s actually quite a story. Laurence and Temeraire get a super important message (tm) that there are dragon eggs that need picked up in Istanbul. There isn&amp;rsquo;t time to book a ship&amp;hellip; so they&amp;rsquo;re about to travel the Old Silk Road across a huge chunk of land.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Throne of Jade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Those men want to take Laurence from me, and put him in prison, and execute him, and I will not let them, ever, and I do not care if Laurence tells me not to squash you,&amp;quot; he added, fiercely, to Lord Barham.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Laurence and the British Government may think that Temeraire was won fairly under the articles of war&amp;hellip; but the Chinese aren&amp;rsquo;t so sure. In an effort to appease them, off Temeraire and Laurence go, halfway around the world to see if they can&amp;rsquo;t convince them otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a number of parts to really like about this book: Getting to travel the world is neat. The difference of Chinese culture, especially around dragons is fun. I like the idea of basically a Napoleonic era aircraft carrier for dragons. There are other related big beasties in the world as well!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The discussions about slavery, the differences in culture between the British and Chinese, and what that might mean for dragons were fascinating. Especially having read &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/23/a-declaration-of-the-rights-of-magicians/">A Declaration of the Rights of Magicians&lt;/a> not &lt;em>that&lt;/em> long ago, it was interesting to see another take on the same period&amp;ndash;especially when we randomly get news that Pitt has died.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course, the aforequoted relationship between Temeraire and Laurence. That&amp;rsquo;s really a great part of the book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a downside, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit less action packed than the first book. We get a couple of big fights, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, but it&amp;rsquo;s got a low slower pace. A bit jarring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>His Majesty's Dragon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/15/his-majestys-dragon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/15/his-majestys-dragon/</guid><description>&lt;p>TLDR: Well that&amp;rsquo;s unexpected. Originally (8 years ago), I wasn&amp;rsquo;t thrilled. Enough to DNF the series (although not the book). On a reread (+relisten?), I loved it and am looking forward to more!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>8 years ago, I first read Temeraire. I thought the idea was fascinating. An alternate history set around the time of Napoleon, tied fairly closely to our own world. Only: Dragons! Cool, no? And turns out&amp;hellip; it is pretty cool!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet somehow, I managed to find myself annoyed by the mechanics of dragons, their intelligence, and&amp;ndash;for some reason&amp;ndash;the idea that there was a &amp;lsquo;chosen one&amp;rsquo; trope going on? I feel like I must have mellowed out somewhat in age. Or decided that I like almost everything now. Or read enough &lt;em>really&lt;/em> good Naomi Novik that I wanted to give it another try.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think that one big difference this time was listening to the audiobook. Some books just work better that way&amp;ndash;something about the book picking you up and carrying you along, where it&amp;rsquo;s easier to just keep listening rather than having to work at it. This is definitely one of them.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>