<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Magic Ex Libris on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/08/magic-ex-libris/</link><description>Recent content in Magic Ex Libris on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/08/magic-ex-libris/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Revisionary</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/08/revisionary/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/08/revisionary/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For security reasons, no books will be permitted in the chamber during your testimony.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Revisionary is a fascinating work. It takes the world building of the first three [Magic Ex Libris](&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/67567-magic-ex-" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.goodreads.com/series/67567-magic-ex-&lt;/a> libris) books and explores what happens when magic comes out in the modern world. It&amp;rsquo;s probably the best example I&amp;rsquo;ve seen of this, right up there with the [Mercy Thompson books](&lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/series/40932-mercy-" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.goodreads.com/series/40932-mercy-&lt;/a> thompson) (and honestly does a better job of showing the changes from the point of view of humans dragged into a new world).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unbound</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/11/11/unbound/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/11/11/unbound/</guid><description>&lt;p>And we&amp;rsquo;re back. This time around, things are getting really serious with Meridiana, the queen of the Ghost Army wrecking havoc in the modern world. It&amp;rsquo;s an excellent story, much tighter than the previous two. It&amp;rsquo;s also rather more serious in tone, although there are still piles of jokes and references to other books to go around.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>As was often the case, magic just chuckled and kicked physics in the balls, leaving it groaning and wondering what just happened.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Codex Born</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/10/21/codex-born/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/10/21/codex-born/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“My name is Isaac Vainio,” I said. “You smashed my library. Prepare to die.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This time around, the stakes are higher. We learn a bit more about the history of magic in the world and Libriomancy in particular, including a way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require Gutenberg&amp;rsquo;s presses to come into being, which isn&amp;rsquo;t something I had even considered. On top of that, we get some technomancy, more looks at the big nasties that live in books, and a big magical showdown.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Libriomancer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/09/07/libriomancer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/09/07/libriomancer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Libriomancer has a lovely premise. Basically, books are magical. The more people you&amp;rsquo;ve had that have read the same edition of a given book, the more possible it is to magically pull various objections out of said book. Gutenberg took this principal with his first Bibles and founded an organization of Libriomancers that have existed up to the present day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love how many different ways Hines finds to use objects from various books (many I&amp;rsquo;ve read or at least heard of):&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>