<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Daevabad Trilogy on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/31/the-daevabad-trilogy/</link><description>Recent content in The Daevabad Trilogy on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/31/the-daevabad-trilogy/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Empire of Gold</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/31/the-empire-of-gold/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/31/the-empire-of-gold/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Luck is a fairy tale we use to make people feel better about the world being unfair as shit.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Man this book has come a ways since &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/07/05/the-city-of-brass/">The City of Brass&lt;/a>. At first we had a fairly straight forward portal fantasy: normal human girl goes through a portal (ish) to another world, discovers magic, and has adventures (again; ish). Then things escalate. Political intrigue. Old enemies. Revolution. War.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now&amp;hellip; Daevabad has fallen. Nahri and Ali are on the run, trying desperately first to survive and then&amp;hellip; maybe, to come back and save the day. And perhaps learn all those dirty little secrets those (formerly) in power tried hard to hide all these years.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I do not believe ambitious men who say the only route to peace and prosperity lies in giving them more power—particularly when they do it with lands and people who are not theirs.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I love the characters. Especially Dara, but the whole Nahri and Ali journey was great to read. And I even foundmyself rooting for Muntadhir, which after the previous books&amp;hellip; I did not expect). Manizheh&amp;hellip; I think Ghassan was a better villain overall, and it&amp;rsquo;s interesting that she made it as far as she did, but so it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I still love the worldbuilding&amp;ndash;even if I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em>still after 3 books&lt;/em> not 100% sure what is a subset of what and who is a when. But I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s the point. Reality is messy. But it&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating world and I&amp;rsquo;m sad to be leaving it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall it&amp;rsquo;s a solid conclusion to a great series. I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to read more in this world, but I&amp;rsquo;m always glad to see a series actually get it&amp;rsquo;s own small end, rather than just fading out as many do.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Find your happiness, little thief. Steal it and do not ever let it go.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Kingdom of Copper</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/13/the-kingdom-of-copper/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/10/13/the-kingdom-of-copper/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Because a lost little girl from Cairo thought she was living in some sort of fairy tale. And because for all her supposed cleverness, she couldn’t see that the dashing hero who saved her was its monster.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/07/05/the-city-of-brass/">The City of Brass&lt;/a> set us off on an adventure; The Kingdom of Copper vastly expands the world&amp;ndash;and the stakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The city of &lt;em>Daevabad&lt;/em> is a mess. Nahri&amp;rsquo;s life is a mess. Ali&amp;rsquo;s exile is a mess. Dara is dead&amp;ndash;but what else is new?&amp;ndash;and also a mess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a book about war and violence and family squabbles writ kingdom large. We&amp;rsquo;re truly in the magical world now, and oh there&amp;rsquo;s far more depths to that world that we knew.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of all the middle books of a trilogy out there, few do quite so well as this one. It&amp;rsquo;s still got some middle book issues&amp;ndash;it doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>really&lt;/em> stand alone&amp;ndash;but for what it is, I&amp;rsquo;m quite impressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m so looking forward to finishing this one. I fully expect even more and worse messes before (if) everything is wrapped up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“No, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t afraid. I was tired.&amp;quot; Ali&amp;rsquo;s voice broke on the word. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m tired of everyone in this city feeding on vengeance. I&amp;rsquo;m tired of teaching our children to hate and fear other children because their parents are our enemies. And I&amp;rsquo;m sick and tired of acting like the only way to save our people is to cut down all who might oppose us, as if our enemies won&amp;rsquo;t return the favor the instant power shifts.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The City of Brass</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/07/05/the-city-of-brass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/07/05/the-city-of-brass/</guid><description>&lt;p>18th Century Cairo. Street living, mixed with all manner of quasi magical cons (palm readings, faking healings). And then &amp;hellip; one accidental summoning later and you&amp;rsquo;re off swept into the magical world of childhood stories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world building is really interesting. You get a touch of the Arabic world mixed with a straight up Arabic inspired fantasy world full of djinn in all manner of shapes and sizes&amp;hellip; even at the end of the story, I&amp;rsquo;m not actually 100% sure what all the differences are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I ever quite got around to liking Nahri. I was rooting for her before she took off, but I&amp;rsquo;m not thrilled where she ended up.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You&amp;rsquo;re some kind of thief, then?&amp;quot;&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;That a very narrow-minded way of looking at it. I prefer to think of myself as a merchant of delicate tasks.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Ali and Dara though, I quite like the both of them&amp;ndash;surprisingly for roughly the same reasons. They are trying to do the &amp;lsquo;right thing&amp;rsquo;, just with rather opposing ways of going about that.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“To keep walking a path between loyalty to your family and loyalty to what you know is right. One of these days, you’re going to have to make a choice.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the second book. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>