<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Animorphs on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/animorphs/</link><description>Recent content in Animorphs on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/animorphs/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Beginning</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/09/the-beginning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/09/the-beginning/</guid><description>&lt;p>And it ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And a new day begins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This isn&amp;rsquo;t really a book with much action (although there is some). It&amp;rsquo;s really more of an epilogue. How things wrap up and what happens next. It&amp;rsquo;s not always something you get in a series and I appreciate it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The end of the end? Weird. Undoes a bit of the closure. But in a way, it fits?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Animorphs were an amazing read when I guest found them years (decades?) ago now. This is my third time reading them. They may be dated at times, but oh, they hold up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A story of teenagers growing up far too fast. Fighting a war. Saving the world. And paying for it all in blood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ellimist Chronicles</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/09/the-ellimist-chronicles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/09/the-ellimist-chronicles/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My full name is Azure Level, Seven Spar, Extension Two, Down-Messenger, Forty-one. My chosen name is Toomin. I like the sound of the word, which is all the reason you need for a chosen name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My &amp;ldquo;game&amp;rdquo; name is Ellimist. Like Toomin, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean anything in particular. I just thought it sounded breezy. Never occurred to me when I chose the name that it would follow me for so long, and so far.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A world of flying crystals. Searchers, flying to the stars. A living moon. And all along, games. Games at an unimaginable scale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps my favorite book of the whole series&amp;ndash;although it&amp;rsquo;s for the most part completely inconsequential to any of the other books. It explains a few things (that were acceptable not to explain) and builds more worlds (perhaps connecting things too much). Still, I quite enjoy this one. And it&amp;rsquo;s at a good point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beginning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Answer</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/09/the-answer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/09/the-answer/</guid><description>&lt;p>My name is Jake.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My name is Jake Berenson. The days of secrecy, of lurking in the shadows are over. The Yeerks know my name. They know my height, weight, eye color, Social Security number, and favorite foods. At long last they know the word Animorph, Marco&amp;rsquo;s word for us.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve fought them for more than three years. I was just thirteen when I started. I&amp;rsquo;m sixteen now, though that fact, like so many facts, has been deliberately obscured in the secret accounts we&amp;rsquo;ve kept.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a sixteen-year-old kid named Jake Berenson, and I am the leader of the Animorphs.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>More battles, bigger than ever before. Characters we&amp;rsquo;ve met long ago, back where we&amp;rsquo;d never expect them. And choices. Choices that could charge the whole galaxy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It all comes back to the power to morph.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the choices the Animorphs will all have to make. And live with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or die by.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One more book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Sacrifice</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/09/the-sacrifice/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/09/the-sacrifice/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Yeerks are in the open now. Rounding up people by gunpoint and sending them by subway to the Yeerk Pool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Animorphs need to do something about it&amp;hellip; but at what cost?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Add on to that, it finally comes out. Cassie stopped Jake from killing Tom&amp;ndash;and that&amp;rsquo;s why the Yeerks can morph now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ax&amp;rsquo;s reaction is&amp;hellip; interesting. We often get fairly alien beliefs from him and other Andalites. But this one, this is interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But really, it all comes down to this:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>None of us are adults. The others are now of the age to be attending what humans call &amp;ldquo;high school.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Man. They&amp;rsquo;re so young.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Absolute</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/08/the-absolute/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/08/the-absolute/</guid><description>&lt;p>The National Guard is mobilizing! It&amp;rsquo;s time&amp;hellip; to kidnap the governor?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything escalated &lt;em>so fast&lt;/em> in these last few books.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimate</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/08/the-ultimate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/08/the-ultimate/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Animorphs tried adding to their number &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-discovery/">once before&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It went poorly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But nothing is going well any more. So now, perhaps, it&amp;rsquo;s time for some reinforcements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The only reinforcements the Animorphs can universally assume not to be Controllers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite the idea&amp;ndash;and quite the risk, both for the Animorphs and for Applegate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But as Jake said, it&amp;rsquo;s our planet. &lt;em>All&lt;/em> of our planet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Diversion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/08/the-diversion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/08/the-diversion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another step further.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;No, Rachel. We retreat,&amp;rdquo; Jake answered. &amp;ldquo;A tactical retreat. Save the army. Live to fight another day. But a toothbrush would be good. And extra deodorant. We&amp;rsquo;ll be out there a while.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s like a series of heists. Barely planned, absolute chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Almost all successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And still things escalate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Return</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/06/the-return/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/06/the-return/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nightmares within nightmares.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among all the Animorphs, they&amp;rsquo;d all say that there&amp;rsquo;s only one who might be truly sad if the war ended tomorrow: Rachel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But even the most gung ho fighter is eventually going to burn out. Perhaps &lt;em>especially&lt;/em> them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An intense book with all the surreal uncertainty of the worst nightmares.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Resistance</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/06/the-resistance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/06/the-resistance/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things continue to escalate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The free Hork-Bajir under attack, willing to die to defend their homes. With some Animorph help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And two hundred years ago, but not all that different, Union soldiers under attack, willing to die to defend their homes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With some freed slaves willing to help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end, it&amp;rsquo;s the same battle, time and again. And the same people&amp;ndash;black, white, and Hork-Bajir alike&amp;ndash;willing to step up to fight&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a neat structure, interweaving the two battles. A solid read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Deception</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/06/the-deception/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:00:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/06/the-deception/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things continue to escalate&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Finally, Jake spoke. His eyes were dull but his voice was firm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Things are different,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;From now on, we take what we need. We do what we have to do. No matter what the consequences.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Jake . . .&amp;rdquo; Cassie began.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s only one morph that will get us thousands of miles out to sea in the time we have left,&amp;rdquo; he added. &amp;ldquo;Human.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s kind of amazing how out in the open/direct thins things are getting. We have less than ten books left, but still. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An intense book. And more to come.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Revelation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/05/the-revelation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/05/the-revelation/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What are you calling your discovery?&amp;rdquo; I heard Nora ask.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t really know,&amp;rdquo; Dad said tentatively. &amp;ldquo;What can you call something that is nothing at all?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything on TV. An old Star Trek. A new Star Trek. My life was plenty sci-fi. How about some Real World?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What could you call it?&amp;rdquo; Dad continued. &amp;ldquo;Zero, I suppose. Zero-space.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Uh oh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so we&amp;rsquo;re really in the endgame now. Things are falling apart. The Yeerks have all the power. And the Animorphs&amp;hellip; well, they have that they&amp;rsquo;ve always had.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hope.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unexpected</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/05/the-unexpected/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/05/the-unexpected/</guid><description>&lt;p>I feel like Unexpected could really be the title to about half of these books. Maybe more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing leads to another, everything goes wrong, and Cassie is off to SYD-South Something Dakota. Right? Right&amp;hellip;?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But hey, kangaroo morph!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s basically no impact on the greater Animorph&amp;rsquo;s story, but sometimes that&amp;rsquo;s all right. And it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to get a fairly straight forward Cassie story with the existential dread.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No worries.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Test</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/05/the-test/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/05/the-test/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man, Tobias doesn&amp;rsquo;t get a break.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Civil war is coming, Andalite,&amp;rdquo; she began. &amp;ldquo;Yeerk versus Yeerk. We&amp;rsquo;ve had enough of the petty Visser fights, the favoritism, the punishments . . . the Council makes us sick.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And all that from a rather unexpected source.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;No,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s wrong. I won&amp;rsquo;t. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to judge you guys, but you&amp;rsquo;re talking about strategy and risk like this is some computer game. Like there aren&amp;rsquo;t others involved. Have you forgotten that we&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be in this to save lives?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Now it makes sense. Totally a trick. But how? When? Why?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Journey</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/04/the-journey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/04/the-journey/</guid><description>&lt;p>And&amp;hellip; Helmacrons. Again. We just saw them in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/01/the-hidden/">The Hidden&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still not &lt;em>nearly&lt;/em> my favorite alien species in these books. At least this time, they get to go all Magic School Bus!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Familiar</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/02/the-familiar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/02/the-familiar/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I fingered the suit, and then it hit me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I knew what was going on here. It had finally happened.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I knew it was only a matter of time, what with the pressures of leadership, the violent battle, the endless fights against a strengthening enemy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d finally been driven to a complete psychotic breakdown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d gone crazy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this was my padded cell.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Not &amp;hellip; exactly?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a very weird book. A what if sort of future and even at the end, it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely clear what&amp;rsquo;s happening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially back to back with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/02/back-to-before/">Back to Before&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve done this sort of thing before, but usually with at least some small amount of closure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not my favorite.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Back to Before</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/02/back-to-before/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/02/back-to-before/</guid><description>&lt;p>What if&amp;ndash;instead of walking through that fateful construction site&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Ellimist and Crayak/the Drode are at it again. Giving Jake a chance at a normal life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But all is not as it seems&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Oh, I see it now, I see it now,&amp;rdquo; the Drode said, ignoring Marco, ignoring all of us. &amp;ldquo;Subtle as always, Ellimist. Your meddling came before, didn&amp;rsquo;t it? How could we not have seen it? Elfangor&amp;rsquo;s brother? His time-shifted son? This anomalous girl here? And the son of Visser One&amp;rsquo;s host body? A group of six supposedly random humans that contains those four! You stacked the deck!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Did I?&amp;rdquo; The Ellimist laughed. &amp;ldquo;That would have been very clever of me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>You know? So far as justifications for the coincidences that make stories just work&amp;ndash;that&amp;rsquo;s actually a sneakily good one. The Animorphs are talented and more than a little lucky. But all along, someone (something?) has been stacking the deck to help them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like it. More than I expected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Other</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/02/the-other/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/02/the-other/</guid><description>&lt;p>An Andalite on TV! Almost right on the heels of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/01/the-arrival/">The Arrival&lt;/a>. Bit weird that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting look into Andalite preconceptions though:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;No. The Yeerks would have no use for his body. He is completely useless as a host.&amp;gt; Ax waved his frail hand in a dismissing motion. &lt;Without a tail blade he cannot fight. And it is obvious this vecol is incapable of morphing or he would have restored his tail from his own healthy DNA.>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And&amp;hellip; is directly contrary to the idea that your original body doesn&amp;rsquo;t heal (mostly recently in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/01/the-hidden/">The Hidden&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; how does the DNA know your age? Or current haircut? Or if you got a tattoo? Or the progress of a genetic disease&amp;ndash;even if the disease is in your DNA, why is the damage has already caused.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s an interesting look into another portion of Andalite society.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, we get:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tobias glared. &amp;lt;Okay, I&amp;rsquo;m getting a complex over here. I&amp;rsquo;m a nothlit. A freak. Whatever. My best friend is an alien with blue fur. My girlfriend is human - when she isn&amp;rsquo;t in morph. How about we don&amp;rsquo;t talk about &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; anymore. Or &amp;ldquo;average&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;natural.&amp;rdquo; Please.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hidden</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/01/the-hidden/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/01/the-hidden/</guid><description>&lt;p>Helmacrons. Not my favorite when they showed up in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/12/the-suspicion/">The Suspicion&lt;/a>, not much better now. At least it&amp;rsquo;s only their tech though&amp;ndash;the ability to track morphing energy&amp;hellip; and the blue box.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interesting enough plot, but there&amp;rsquo;s a spoilery twist (see below) that &amp;hellip; I just didn&amp;rsquo;t think worked. it didn&amp;rsquo;t quite work with the established world building and I doubt will be used again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Arrival</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/01/the-arrival/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/01/the-arrival/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Andalites have arrived!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sort of.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things go well.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Rachel whirled around. Her face red with anger. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m through taking orders from you,&amp;rdquo; she said through clenched teeth. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m through with Marco and his stupid jokes. I&amp;rsquo;m through with Cassie&amp;rsquo;s hypocrisy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cassie took a broom from the corner and began to sweep up the glass. &amp;ldquo;Count me out, too,&amp;rdquo; she said softly. &amp;ldquo;If this war is unwinnable, how do we justify killing Hork-Bajir? Basically, they&amp;rsquo;re prisoners of war. Innocent victims.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marco thrusts his hands into his pockets. &amp;ldquo;Guess I&amp;rsquo;m out, too. I&amp;rsquo;m going to enjoy what time I&amp;rsquo;ve got left. Acquire a surfer dude chick magnet. Hang out.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It would be nice to meet some fine upstanding examples of Andalite society.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today&amp;hellip; is not that day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a solid story. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice contrast to Ax&amp;rsquo;s earlier conflict between his people&amp;hellip; and his people.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Weakness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/29/the-weakness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/29/the-weakness/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oof. Two in a row I don&amp;rsquo;t overly care for.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, we have Jake out of town&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;A vote,&amp;gt; Tobias said. &amp;lt;It&amp;rsquo;s the only way.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marco snorted. &amp;ldquo;Beautiful. Let&amp;rsquo;s see. We&amp;rsquo;ve got Rachel&amp;rsquo;s best friend and her bird-friend and Ax isn&amp;rsquo;t voting . . . forget it, man. I&amp;rsquo;m out.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marco turned to me and bowed. &amp;ldquo;Congratulations, your highness. Your wish is my command.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And for some reason Rachel steps up. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean to agree with Marco too strongly here&amp;hellip; but this is a bad idea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hit and run, almost get killed, learn a lesson.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And away we go!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mutation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/28/the-mutation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/28/the-mutation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, just &lt;em>how many&lt;/em> alien (and otherwise) species &lt;em>are&lt;/em> there on the Earth?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, at lesat one more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At some point, it seems we have to do every possible historical weirdness. Which this time involves Atlantis. And it&amp;rsquo;s every bit as weird and fishy as you might expect &amp;rsquo;the Animorphs do Atlantis&amp;rsquo; would be&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Look, I don&amp;rsquo;t know about anyone else, but I believe in listening to my instincts. And my instincts are saying, &amp;lsquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve done enough, Marco. Go home. Play with the stupid poodle. Do some homework.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I get the same feeling, Marco,&amp;rdquo; I said. &amp;ldquo;But we almost got killed trying to take out the Sea Blade. I don&amp;rsquo;t want a rematch. I want it sunk. I want to know it&amp;rsquo;s sunk.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; not my favorite. Weird worldbuilding that should have a lot more impact and/or repercussions than it does. Could have been skipped.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>VISSER</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/28/visser/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/28/visser/</guid><description>&lt;p>Told from the point of view of Visser One (former and, for the moment, current). On trial, in front of the Council of Thirteen themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I spoke to the holographic representation of the Council. Thirteen Yeerks in various host bodies: Nine Hork-Bajir, two Taxxons, and two whose host bodies were so concealed that I could not guess at their form.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They were dressed in dark red robes, so dark that they were almost black. They stood, motionless, held in place, suspended by gravity-neutral fields, fed by a continuous refined current of Kandrona rays.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Hork-Bajir-Controllers wore a lightweight mesh beneath their robes to keep the wrist and arm blades from slicing through the robe&amp;rsquo;s fabric.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The two Taxxon-Controllers were bloated, monstrously inflated versions of the great centipedes. Both were attended by Gedds, ready with freshly killed meat to feed the eternal hunger that not even a Yeerk inside that feverish brain can control. Their ceremonial robes were as large as sails, wrapped around the raised front third of their bodies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They were light-years away, of course. They would see me, my host face and body in three dimensions. They could also watch my vital signs, translated into universal equivalents. Blood pressure, heart rate, hormone production, all reduced to digital readouts a billion miles away. And they could, with a thought, call up whatever data had been compiled on specific events or locations or individuals.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I really do enjoy the worldbuilding here and I&amp;rsquo;m a bit sad that this is about as much as we&amp;rsquo;re going to get about the Council.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, it&amp;rsquo;s yet another interesting point of view. Especially when you add in Visser One&amp;rsquo;s testimony&amp;ndash;the backstory of how the Yeerk invasion of Earth actually began.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tentatively I reached toward the far side of the brain. I touched it. Made contact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fascinating!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was incredible. This second half of the brain was an almost mirror image, but not. It could have functioned all on its own, if necessary, and yet it was in some ways radically different in its memories, its sensory interpretation, even its will. Two almost entirely functional brains in one skull, communicating across a channel of nerves. Not a fully redundant system, almost a second, different brain!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s more interesting to think that humans are weird like that (and that is weird) or that seemingly no other species is!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoy all of the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/animorphs-chronicles/">Animorphs Chronicles&lt;/a>. This is no exception.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Proposal</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/27/the-proposal/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/27/the-proposal/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My name is Marco.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you can call me &amp;ldquo;Marco the Mighty.&amp;rdquo; Or &amp;ldquo;Most Exalted Destroyer of My Pride.&amp;rdquo; You can cower before my mighty thumbs and beg for mercy, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be crushed just the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For I am the lord of the PlayStation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pick a game. Any game. Tekken. Duke Nukem. NFL Blitz. Whatever. Practice all you want. I&amp;rsquo;ll still beat you. I&amp;rsquo;ll crush you like Doc Martens crush ants.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A bit dated, but not terribly so. I do like Marco&amp;rsquo;s points of view.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, then things go wrong (otherwise there wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be much of a book, now would there?):&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My arms! They weren&amp;rsquo;t becoming wings! What was happening? I felt them stretching out in front of me. The skin on my hands turning brittle, like armor. Fingers merging, becoming two barbed claws.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something was wrong!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My face . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A pinprick on each cheek! Two long whisker-like hairs sprouted outward. Instinctively, I swept them in front of me, gauging the wind, the temperature, sensing my surroundings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Antennae? Birds don&amp;rsquo;t have antennae!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Dim eyes. Pincers. Antennae.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lobster?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was half-osprey, half-lobster?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A useless combination of mismatched parts.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a standard &amp;lsquo;discover a high powered Yeerk that&amp;rsquo;s going to ruin everyone&amp;rsquo;s day, so let&amp;rsquo;s take him down&amp;rsquo; sort of plot. This time with more TV personalities. And a secondary plot of Macro&amp;rsquo;s dad moving on, which&amp;ndash;given the storyline of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/25/the-conspiracy/">The Conspiracy&lt;/a> and the upcoming &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/28/visser/">VISSER&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;is complicated at best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Ooookay,&amp;gt; Jake replied. &amp;lt;That could have gone better. Guess it&amp;rsquo;s time for Plan B.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Someday when this is all over people will ask us about the war against the Yeerks,&amp;gt; Tobias said. &amp;lt;Let&amp;rsquo;s leave this part out&amp;gt;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another good one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Especially with&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Marco, if you&amp;rsquo;re there, pick up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My mother.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be continued in . . . &lt;em>Visser&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Prophecy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/27/the-prophecy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/27/the-prophecy/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;An Arn, on Earth? Here? Why? That&amp;rsquo;s the question. What&amp;rsquo;s he up to?&amp;gt; Rachel wondered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;He had to come. Star Wars: The Phantom Menace isn&amp;rsquo;t coming out on DVD there for, like, two years. He buys up a bunch of copies here, takes &amp;rsquo;em home, makes a fortune.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Good grief, Marco, you live science fiction, why do you want to watch science fiction?&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be dissing TPM,&amp;gt; Marco said. &lt;Cool is cool.>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; the Arn. Like I said &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/10/the-hork-bajir-chronicles/">The Hork-Bajir Chronicles&lt;/a> was among my favorites of these books, so following up on that storyline is pretty cool. Especially the the Animorphs getting a chance to go offworld entirely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And hey, let&amp;rsquo;s bring back the memory implant of Aldrea (the Andalite from the Hork-Bajir Chronicles, Seerow&amp;rsquo;s daughter) for good measure. Of course bringing back the dead to the source of some of their worst possible memories (although best too I suppose) can&amp;rsquo;t possibly go wrong&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a neat book. Bit weird, but I liked it. I hope something comes of it, but if it does, I don&amp;rsquo;t remember from last time I read these books. We shall have to see!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Illusion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/26/the-illusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/26/the-illusion/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tobias just doesn&amp;rsquo;t get a break. (I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m saying that a lot recently).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, the Yeerks are working on an anti-morphing ray. And the Animorphs &lt;em>really&lt;/em> don&amp;rsquo;t want them to think &lt;em>that&lt;/em> works (despite the fact that&amp;hellip; they would really want to try it more than once. Or, despite the danger&amp;hellip; on Visser Three).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But there&amp;rsquo;s an obvious answer. Who&amp;rsquo;s morph could they shine just about anything on and never get them to &amp;lsquo;de&amp;rsquo;morph?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tobias.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s actually kind of brilliant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Makes up a bit for the tone of the rest of the book. Man there are evil even by Yeerk standards in this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Separation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/26/the-separation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/26/the-separation/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; a really strange story. And hard to talk about without spoiling the main conceit, which they at least seem to want to keep semi-hidden.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Conspiracy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/25/the-conspiracy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/25/the-conspiracy/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an odd one to pair with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/24/the-reunion/">The Reunion&lt;/a>. In both cases, we have an Animorph with a family member controller. In both cases, it&amp;rsquo;s too close to home. But Marco made the call&amp;ndash;even if it&amp;rsquo;s going to tear him up later to do it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now it&amp;rsquo;s Jake&amp;rsquo;s turn.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You know what Marco and I used to talk about? Whether Batman could beat Spiderman. Whether Sega was better than Nintendo. Whether some girl would rather go out with him or me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now . . .&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What are we, anymore, Marco? What has happened to us?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He didn&amp;rsquo;t answer. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect him to. We both knew what had happened.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Man these books get dark.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s one reason I like them. They don&amp;rsquo;t get into everything, but they really do get into enough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Reunion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/24/the-reunion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/24/the-reunion/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Interesting,&amp;gt; Ax observed. &amp;lt;Bearded, white-coated creatures with hooves. And horns. Grazers. I would point out the similarities between the mountain goat and Andalites, except for my extremely disappointing experience with the cow.&amp;gt; (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/17/the-experiment/">The Experiment&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And so Marco&amp;rsquo;s mom is back&amp;ndash;and after the mess of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/04/the-decision/">The Decision&lt;/a>, she&amp;rsquo;s not Visser One anymore. But if anything, that means that she hates Visser Three all the more&amp;hellip; and would stop at nothing to get back at him. Even if that means allying herself with the &amp;lsquo;Andalite Bandits&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marco of course deals with this in a perfectly reasonable and level headed manner.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;What do you do when you have to make a decision, and each choice is horrible? What would you do, Rachel? If it was your mom or dad or sisters. What would you do, Xena?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rachel came back and sat beside me on the bed. She didn&amp;rsquo;t hug me. Rachel&amp;rsquo;s not a hugger. But she sat there with me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;One battle at a time, Marco. One battle at a time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an intense book and man I feel for Marco. Tobias and Ax are really going through some stuff, but they&amp;rsquo;re only sort of human any more. Of the remaining Animorphs&amp;ndash;well, I think that it&amp;rsquo;s Marco that&amp;rsquo;s gone through the most. And this book certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t go easy on him.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Elfangor's Secret</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/22/elfangors-secret/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/22/elfangors-secret/</guid><description>&lt;p>Am I some kind of hideous freak of nature, a twisted concoction of mismatched parts? Or am I something new and wonderful?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Depends on the day. Depends on whether I&amp;rsquo;m with Melissa, wanting to make her happy, wanting her to hold my hand, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Way to bury the lede there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s another time travel story. Another Time Matrix story. Another Ellimist / Cyarak story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The slightly more interesting bit this time is that time is wrong. Someone has been messing around in history and it&amp;rsquo;s up to the Animorphs to put things right.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Sickness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/21/the-sickness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/21/the-sickness/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You ever notice how many different ways there are to say &amp;rsquo;throwing up&amp;rsquo;?&amp;rdquo; Marco asked as we passed Dunkin&amp;rsquo; Donuts, the first in the row of fast food places dotting the main street running through town. &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s vomiting, of course. Hurling. Tossing your cookies. Puking, a classic. Ralphing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was glad Marco was filling up the silence. Even though I thought he could have come up with a better topic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s cascading. But I prefer the terms that are more real. Like blowing chunks. Spewing your guts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marco took a deep breath and kept on talking as we made our way past Taco Bell. &amp;ldquo;Tangoing with the toilet. That&amp;rsquo;s a good one,&amp;rdquo; he said reflectively. &amp;ldquo;Technicolor yawn.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The one where everyone gets sick (Ax deathly so) and Cassie has to go on a solo rescue mission to the Yeerk pool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quite a story and quite a bit more Cassie than we often get. Being the action hero no less!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A solid one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Experiment</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/17/the-experiment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/17/the-experiment/</guid><description>&lt;p>The one where Ax watches entirely too much TV.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Look, Tobias! Victor and Nikki are doing that thing again!&amp;gt; I pointed at the screen. &lt;They do this very often.>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Uh-huh.&amp;gt; His hawk eyes were trained on the little screen as Victor tightened his arms around Nikki. &amp;lt;It&amp;rsquo;s called kissing, Ax-man. Just like yesterday. And the day before. Kissing. Everyone does it. Of course, you need lips.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;I know what it is called. And the role of lips is self-evident. I simply do not know why it is performed.>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Ah. Well . . .&amp;gt; Tobias rearranged his wings noisily. &amp;lt;It&amp;rsquo;s definitely got a purpose. By the way, Marco&amp;rsquo;s heading this way.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Way too much.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Marco sighed. &amp;ldquo;Whatever you call it, it basically reeks, you know. I think it&amp;rsquo;s time I introduced you to some better programming, Ax. Buffy. Party of Five, maybe. Cops. South Park. Something, anything better than this. Although she is hot.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Yes, she is hot. This is why she often wears less artificial skin.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Yeah, well, I think you may have your cause and effect turned around there. Hey, you know what you need? A TV Guide.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Entirely&lt;/em> too much.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Nothing but lame sitcom reruns this week,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re not missing anything.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;There are always These Messages,&amp;gt; I pointed out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;These what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;The shorter shows that are displayed between longer shows. These Messages. They are often my favorites. &amp;ldquo;Zestfully clean! Zestfully clean! You&amp;rsquo;re not fully clean unless you&amp;rsquo;re Zestfully clean!&amp;rdquo; So much information condensed into so brief a format. So much emotional intensity.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re starting to scare me, Ax.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes. The entire book is like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, there&amp;rsquo;s also something about a machine to remove free will, which seems to fall into the &amp;lsquo;duh, that&amp;rsquo;s not possible category&amp;rsquo;:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I wanted to tell him. I wanted to say, Look, it can&amp;rsquo;t be done. You don&amp;rsquo;t understand! There&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as a human being without a free will. It&amp;rsquo;s . . . it&amp;rsquo;s . . . idiotic! But he&amp;rsquo;s no scientist, much less a philosopher. You can&amp;rsquo;t separate a sentient creature from free will. They are free will. Yeerk, Hork-Bajir, human, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. A sentient species has free will like an object has mass. You can&amp;rsquo;t separate them! But Visser Three doesn&amp;rsquo;t listen.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Which&amp;hellip; annoyed me more than it probably should have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We don&amp;rsquo;t know what free will is. But you &lt;em>very much&lt;/em> can seemingly take away people&amp;rsquo;s free will. That&amp;rsquo;s what whole classes of drugs are designed to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Exposed</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/16/the-exposed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/16/the-exposed/</guid><description>&lt;p>Erek&amp;rsquo;s glitching.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which&amp;ndash;if the Yeerks find out there have been highly advanced androids infiltrating them for years&amp;ndash;could be bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;How about his face? A mask?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jake ran to snatch up some full-head masks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I have Clinton, Gingrich, and a Teletubby. Dipsy, I think.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s not Dipsy,&amp;rdquo; Cassie corrected. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s Tinky Winky. Dipsy&amp;rsquo;s green and has the straight up thing. Tinky Winky&amp;rsquo;s the one with the triangle.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Who&amp;rsquo;s the little red one?&amp;gt; Marco wondered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Po,&amp;rdquo; Cassie said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Oh, yeah.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;No offense,&amp;rdquo; Erek said, &amp;ldquo;but how on Earth have you people managed to avoid getting caught for this long?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I mean, he has a point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So now the Animorphs have to go somewhere they&amp;rsquo;ve never gone before&amp;ndash;deep, &lt;em>deep&lt;/em> in the ocean. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/05/the-message/">The Message&lt;/a> was nothing compared to this. They&amp;rsquo;re going to need all new morphs this time around.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Calamari,&amp;rdquo; she said with a grin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Snails?&amp;rdquo; I said, frowning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;I am not in favor of snails,&amp;gt; Ax said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Wait, that&amp;rsquo;s not-&amp;rdquo; Cassie said loudly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;I had the misfortune to inadvertently eat one while feeding,&amp;gt; Ax continued. &lt;I did not see it in time. I stepped on it and digested it.>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You ate a snail through your hoof?&amp;rdquo; I asked. That picture temporarily replaced the image of me being squashed to the size of a Barbie doll on the ocean floor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Yes, and the meat portion was fine. However, once the snail&amp;rsquo;s body had been digested, the shell was very difficult to-&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Ooookay, I think that&amp;rsquo;s probably enough about snails,&amp;rdquo; Jake said.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>(Calamari isn&amp;rsquo;t snail anyways, as Cassie yells shortly after this section).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting premise and some really weird and wonderful (ymmv) new morphs and a fun (pun intended) look into Pemalite technology and culture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Attack</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/14/the-attack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/14/the-attack/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whelp, it seems &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/13/the-extreme/">The Extreme&lt;/a> wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>extreme&lt;/em> enough. Forget the Arctic, now the Animorphs are going to a world far, &lt;em>far&lt;/em> away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a(nother) precursor to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/09/the-ellimist-chronicles/">The Ellimist Chronicles&lt;/a>, detailing that long, &lt;em>long&lt;/em> battle between the Ellimist and Crayak.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t to be that simple. Approximately a hundred million Earth years ago, we became aware of a new force in the galaxy. Not a species, an individual. He was a fugitive from another galaxy, chased out of that galaxy by a power even greater than he. Greater than me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;We knew then, Crayak and I, that we could never make war again. Not open war, at least. The conflict would have to be carried on by different means. No longer a savage battle. Now it must be a chess game. There would be rules. Limits.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This time around, it&amp;rsquo;s a contest of champions: the Animorphs (plus Erek the Chee) versus Howlers (they killed the Chee&amp;rsquo;s creators, thus Erek).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>quite&lt;/em> the weird world. And quite the battle(s). And of course&amp;hellip; quite the solution out of left field. Turns out even strengths can be turned into a weakness if you&amp;rsquo;re &amp;hellip; human enough?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interesting story, if a little weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Extreme</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/13/the-extreme/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/13/the-extreme/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been hurled sixty million years into the past, and been trapped on alien planets, but I&amp;rsquo;d never felt so far from home.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Animorphs go to the Arctic&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Yeerks have decided enough is enough. They&amp;rsquo;re sick of those &amp;lsquo;Andalite bandits&amp;rsquo; always ruining everything, so for their new secret project&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;re going to build at the North Pole.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Took long enough&amp;hellip; Even if they don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;re humans, the Yeerks have the numbers. Spread out and there&amp;rsquo;s no way that a half dozen guerilla fighters could deal with you any more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s quite the adventure&amp;ndash;and establishes that the Animorphs have a way to handle extended away missions now:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Erek&amp;rsquo;s solution had been to have himself and three of his Chee friends program their holograms to look like each of us. Little did my dad know that he&amp;rsquo;d be sharing his cornflakes with an android who&amp;rsquo;d been on Earth since before the first flake was created.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;hellip; works. And gives a bit more flexibility in what stories they can tell. Man. They&amp;rsquo;re children. And having to deal with even this now&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A solid story&amp;ndash;and more evidence&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note: This is the first &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/jeffrey-zeuhlke/">ghostwritten&lt;/a> Animorphs book. I&amp;rsquo;ll be putting the ghostwriters in the author section as well. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting practice. Not sure what to think about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Suspicion</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/12/the-suspicion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/12/the-suspicion/</guid><description>&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; the one with the Helmacrons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re small. And very angry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s kind of weird just how many aliens there are/have been wondering about the Earth. And this is no exception.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus, the idea of tiny aliens is (for the most part) played for laughs, rather than really digging into how in &lt;em>the world&lt;/em> that would work. How does anything work at that scale?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not one of my favorites.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Pretender</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/11/the-pretender/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/11/the-pretender/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so after &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-solution/">the David Trilogy&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/10/the-hork-bajir-chronicles/">The Hork-Bajir Chronicles&lt;/a>, we were about due for something lighter, yes?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How about&amp;hellip; Tobias getting a letter from a long lost relative (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/">hmm&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course it all goes well.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;How long do we have till your birthday, Tobias?&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Um . . . three days?&amp;gt; I asked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Today&amp;rsquo;s the twenty-third. When&amp;rsquo;s your birthday?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;The twenty-fifth. I think. Twenty-sixth?&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marco laughed, then I guess he realized I wasn&amp;rsquo;t kidding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;I don&amp;rsquo;t . . . I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly remember. Not for sure. But I think it&amp;rsquo;s in three days.&amp;gt; I forced a laugh. &amp;lt;Just don&amp;rsquo;t ask me how old I am in bird years.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I really like Tobias. He&amp;rsquo;s quite often my favorite Animorph (Marco is a good one too). He&amp;rsquo;s just got such a &lt;em>fascinating&lt;/em> story and does &lt;em>not&lt;/em> give up. No matter how absolutely &lt;em>terrible&lt;/em> of a life hand he&amp;rsquo;s been dealt. And perhaps&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>For a long while neither of us spoke. Then Rachel, in a whisper, said, &amp;ldquo;What am I supposed to do, Tobias? I&amp;rsquo;m a girl. You&amp;rsquo;re a bird. This is way past Romeo and Juliet, Montagues and Capulets. This isn&amp;rsquo;t Kate Winslet and Leo DiCaprio coming from different social groups or whatever. It&amp;rsquo;s not like you&amp;rsquo;re black and I&amp;rsquo;m white like Cassie and Jake. No one but a moron cares about that. We are . . . we can&amp;rsquo;t hold hands, Tobias. We can&amp;rsquo;t dance. We can&amp;rsquo;t go to a movie together.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Even find love? (I enjoy their growing relationship.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What it all comes down to?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It suddenly occurred to me, right then, for the first time, that what I thought was so unique about me - that I was half instinctive predator, and half human being - wasn&amp;rsquo;t so unique after all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every human - Jake. Rachel. Marco. Cassie, all humans - kind of lives on that edge between savage and saint. And the thing is that sometimes when you get pushed you do have to push back. And other times, you have to turn the other cheek.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A solid story.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hork-Bajir Chronicles</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/10/the-hork-bajir-chronicles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/10/the-hork-bajir-chronicles/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, I do enjoy the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/animorphs-chronicles/">Animorphs Chronicles&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/">The Andalite Chronicles&lt;/a> were good, but if anything, The Hork-Bajir Chronicles are even better! If nothing else, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot less time travel. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this one, we get not only the story of the Hork-Bajir, but to a large extent the story of how the Yeerks came to be as well:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Alloran turned all four of his eyes on my father. &amp;lt;Prince Seerow, you are relieved of duty.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;You can&amp;rsquo;t relieve me!&amp;gt; my father cried.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;When a commander has become incapacitated due to injury or mental defect, his subordinates may relieve him,&amp;gt; Alloran quoted from the regulations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;What mental defect?&amp;gt; my father demanded.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Stupidity,&amp;gt; Alloran said harshly. &amp;lt;The stupidity of kindness. Charity to potential enemies. You&amp;rsquo;re a fool, Seerow. A soft, sentimental, well-meaning fool. And now my men are dead and the Yeerks are loose in the galaxy. How many will die before we can bring this contagion under control? How many will die for Seerow&amp;rsquo;s kindness?&amp;gt;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s Alloran and his family (especially his daughter) sent to the Hork-Bajir world&amp;ndash;and them that end up directly participating in the terrible mess that we all knew had to be coming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But up until then, I love the worldbuilding in this one. The Hork-Bajir world is &lt;em>weird&lt;/em>. I love the idea of a shattered world and giant (kilometers tall) trees keeping it barely habitable. I love the (minor spoilers) reasons &lt;em>why&lt;/em> the world and the Hork-Bajir are the way they are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then eventually, I love the conflict. Andalite versus Hork-Bajir, not fighting, but morally and ethically. And the Yeerks in all their soon to be overwhelming numbers. It&amp;rsquo;s an invasion rather unlike that of Earth&amp;ndash;far more out in the open.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As an added bonus, our first point of view of how the Yeerks do their thing:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>My sonar found the head quite easily, of course. And I&amp;rsquo;d been taught how to pinpoint the opening into the head by extending two palps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was quite a small entryway. I had to squeeze myself down and work my way slowly inside the ear canal. From there on, it was all by feel. My sonar didn&amp;rsquo;t work, of course. And the smells encountered were unfamiliar, useless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But then, after what seemed far too long a time, my palps encountered a surface alive with electricity!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The brain. I could feel the activity, the snapping neurons, the arcs of microvoltage between synapses. I had to flatten myself all the way. My palps sought for trenches, gaps, openings around the brain. And I found them. I pushed my body down inside each wrinkle of the brain. Just as I&amp;rsquo;d been taught to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And slowly at first, then faster and faster, I began to make contact! I felt the neurons connecting to me!&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Still&amp;hellip; a bit weird. But it&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see for once.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I mentioned, one of my favorites, at least up until we get to &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/09/the-ellimist-chronicles/">The Ellimist Chronicles&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Solution</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-solution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-solution/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so The Solution to the David Trilogy (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-discovery/">The Discovery&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-threat/">The Threat&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sometimes there &lt;em>are&lt;/em> no good solutions. This becomes increasingly clear as the series goes on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But oh, this one. This is one of the hardest to justify.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It do not like this storyline. It&amp;rsquo;s well written and I think needed to be told. Still don&amp;rsquo;t like it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Threat</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-threat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-threat/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Aww, shut up, Marco,&amp;gt; Rachel said good-naturedly. &amp;lt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of fun. The wind whistling through the chinks in my body armor, rustling the spikes on my legs . . .&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;You people are all crazy,&amp;gt; David said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;At one level, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of fascinating, you know?&amp;gt; Cassie said. &amp;lt;I mean, did anyone ever read the Miss Spider books? Miss Spider&amp;rsquo;s Tea Party, Miss Spider&amp;rsquo;s New Car? This could be Miss Spider Goes Flying.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;You people are &lt;em>all&lt;/em> crazy,&amp;gt; David repeated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Dragonfly Airlines,&amp;gt; Rachel said with a laugh.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And so continues the David saga (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-discovery/">The Discovery&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-solution/">The Solution&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this one, the new Animorph is put &lt;em>entirely&lt;/em> under the test. A meeting of world leaders. One (at least) is already a Controller&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing David fit in&amp;ndash;and even more so when he doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Discovery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-discovery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so David&amp;ndash;oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Apparently the morphing cube (I&amp;rsquo;m sure it has a better name) survived. That seems&amp;hellip; impressive, but it does work well enough as a plot device.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this kid (the aforementioned David) found it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing leads to another and in the end, there&amp;rsquo;s no choice. They need to make a new Animorph. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even be the first time, they added Ax after all. And Tobias has a bit of the same feel. But man. It&amp;rsquo;s quite the thing to be doing now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course everything goes well&amp;ndash;well enough for a 3 part story anyways, with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-threat/">The Threat&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/08/the-solution/">The Solution&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do not like this plotline. David feels less well developed than the rest of the Animorphs (for good reason to be fair) and it&amp;rsquo;s a mess from the beginning. It&amp;rsquo;s more of the &amp;rsquo;this is a terrible situation&amp;rsquo; that the Animorphs really start digging into as we go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Departure</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/07/the-departure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/07/the-departure/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Andalites, humans, theres no difference. Youre both smug, moralizing, superior races. You both live in beautiful worlds. You have hands and eyes, and the freedom to move about wherever you like. And you hate us for wanting all those same things.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Cassie is done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Frankly, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of amazing she lasted as long as she did. At her heart, Cassie is a healer&amp;hellip; and now she&amp;rsquo;s spent months (years? who knows) in a war. Literally taking lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So she&amp;rsquo;s done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course that&amp;rsquo;s when things go sidewise in all the best story appropriate ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating look into the stress that all of the Animorphs are under, but what&amp;rsquo;s more&amp;hellip; a surprising look into Yeerks &lt;em>that could be more&lt;/em>. They &lt;em>aren&amp;rsquo;t all evil&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that&amp;rsquo;s what makes the story all the better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I enjoyed this one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>In the Time of Dinosaurs</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/06/in-the-time-of-dinosaurs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/06/in-the-time-of-dinosaurs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s right there in the title right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Animorphs try to do the right thing and instead get blown back 65 million years in the past. They almost get eaten, find a bunch of aliens no one has ever heard of (and we&amp;rsquo;ll never see again I expect), almost get eaten, go steal a nuke, almost get eaten, and eventually get home. Because what sort of series would this be if they didn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m starting to think that the Animorphs might have a time travel problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although, I guess it&amp;rsquo;s been longer than than I thought since last time (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/11/the-stranger/">The Stranger&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/21/the-forgotten/">The Forgotten&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/">The Andalite Chronicles&lt;/a>; alternatively, it was last 65 million years from now!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s certainly an exciting story. And we get a touch of the moral issues involved in potentially changing the timeline&amp;ndash;or having to allow something terrible to happen to preserve it. Along with some much more interesting aliens than we often see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So a good story. Worthy of the heftier Megamorphs page count I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward and back&amp;hellip; TO THE FUTURE!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Decision</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/04/the-decision/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/04/the-decision/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I know it seems impossible even to conceive of Andalites as traitors. I know the very idea makes any decent Andalite sick inside. But I am telling the truth. The Ascalin incident happened. We were betrayed by one of our own.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Quite the introduction, that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another high level person threatened with a Yeerkening. A mad plan to get in and turn it to their advantage&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then suddenly &lt;em>yoink&lt;/em>. You&amp;rsquo;re in a war on another planet, a billion miles away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out even vanishingly unlikely things can happen if you&amp;rsquo;re the protagonists of a book!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a neat book. Shades our relationships with the Andelites a bit more, gives Ax some hard choices to make, and perhaps&amp;ndash;just perhaps&amp;ndash;gets a good word about what&amp;rsquo;s going on on Earth to someone that may be able to help.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Underground</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/02/the-underground/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/02/the-underground/</guid><description>&lt;p>A secret weapon against the Yeerks?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Cassie suddenly laughed. It was a cynical laugh. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know she was capable of a cynical laugh. &amp;ldquo;And all the rights and wrongs, and all the lines between good and evil, just go wafting and waving and swirling around, don&amp;rsquo;t they?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yeah. Of course things couldn&amp;rsquo;t be that easy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s another in the series continuing to dig into just how terrible some of the things these kids (and don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong&amp;ndash;they are &lt;em>so&lt;/em> young for &lt;em>any&lt;/em> of this) find themselves doing. For the most part, they&amp;rsquo;ve survived unscathed. And they have a certain amount of plot immunity. But even that, you can&amp;rsquo;t expect to hold out forever.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s an intense book, somewhat offset (and at times I would even say weakened) by the constant ridiculousness of said &amp;lsquo;secret weapon&amp;rsquo;. One strange bit, so far as I remember&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s never mentioned again. Perhaps I&amp;rsquo;m just not remembering it, it has been a while, but it seems a weird thing to drop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But worth the (re-)read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Warning</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/31/the-warning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/31/the-warning/</guid><description>&lt;p>The one with the (mid-90s) Internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So much of the technology in this book is weird and dated&amp;ndash;primarily since it comes on the tale end of the AOL-style internet, with chat rooms and email clients baked into your connection itself and before the more free-for-all (glorious) mess of the early 2000s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, bragging about 38400 baud modems. Talking about &amp;lsquo;code words&amp;rsquo; instead of passwords. Associating cookies with your &amp;lsquo;screen name&amp;rsquo;. A search result (even for a weird &amp;lsquo;made up&amp;rsquo; term) returning exactly &lt;em>one&lt;/em> hit. It&amp;rsquo;s such a weird mix of now dated technology of the time&amp;ndash;some done slightly wrong. And it&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also the one (of many) where they start to touch on the moral complexities of (teenagers fighting a) war.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It was the best you could do,&amp;rdquo; I said. &amp;ldquo;It was all you could do. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s hard to fight evil without doing some along the way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We saw a bit of this in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/28/the-escape/">The Escape&lt;/a>, but it&amp;rsquo;s really coming home now:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I just want to get back to a life someday where I don&amp;rsquo;t have to make decisions that might get people killed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Do you?&amp;rdquo; Now Marco&amp;rsquo;s smile was definitely of the mocking variety. &amp;ldquo;You really think someday we can all go back to being regular kids? You think after being the leader of the Animorphs you can go back to being Joe Average Student?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Yes, I do.&amp;rdquo; I said it forcefully. I meant it.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And&amp;hellip; yeah.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s hard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it&amp;rsquo;s not going to get any easier over the remaining dozens of books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy for them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Escape</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/28/the-escape/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/28/the-escape/</guid><description>&lt;p>Marco books have some of the best snippets.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I jumped in, feet first, around the eight-foot marker. I bobbed back up to the surface and said, &amp;ldquo;This is insane, Marco.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To which I answered, &amp;ldquo;So I&amp;rsquo;ll be careful.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To which I countered, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re talking to yourself, do you know that?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Oh, shut up,&amp;rdquo; I said.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You know, sometimes there&amp;rsquo;s just a very fine line between us and the Three Stooges,&amp;rdquo; I said.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;What are stooges?&amp;gt; Ax asked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;A stooge is a guy stupid enough to run around inside a Yeerk stronghold wearing a pair of bike shorts and accompanied by a Deer-man from outer space and a mouse-eating Bird-boy. That&amp;rsquo;s a stooge.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Also, SHARKS!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re the Hork-Bajir of the sea! Apparently literally. It&amp;rsquo;s an odd one to pair right fater &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/25/the-unknown/">The Unknown&lt;/a>. Back to back books talking about non-human/animal Controllers, although with rather different outcomes. And now I want to look up the differences between shark and horse brains&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus, we get an appearance by a new, interesting race (mind reading amphibians!), more Visser One scenes (of course, it&amp;rsquo;s a Marco points of view)/Visser Three politics, and some underwater adventures, which are neat.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, a decent entry. Up from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/24/the-change/">The Change&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/25/the-unknown/">The Unknown&lt;/a>, I think.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unknown</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/25/the-unknown/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/25/the-unknown/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>One way you can judge a person is by looking at their friends . . . and their enemies. I have wonderful friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And terrible enemies.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The one with Area &lt;del>51&lt;/del> 91.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is such a silly book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the conspiracy theories are right (more or less)! So of course the Yeerks need a way in to learn the truth&amp;ndash;and the obvious answer isn&amp;rsquo;t to take over &lt;em>anyone&lt;/em> on the base. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s why they take over high school basketball players and assistant principals. They can&amp;rsquo;t get anyone higher placed&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, the Yeerks are going in, so of course the Animorphs have to as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whee!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Change</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/24/the-change/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/24/the-change/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And what do you want, Tobias?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know what I want, I said, almost choking on the words. You know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes. But do YOU know what you want, Tobias?, the Ellimist asked. And if you get it, will you still know?&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes. Spoilers. The Ellimist is around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And since this originally released the same day as &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/">The Andalite Chronicles&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;and because it&amp;rsquo;s a Tobias book, you had to expect it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In short, the Ellimist is (totally not &amp;#x1f609;) interfering to free some Hork-Bajir. Tobias gets roped in. We do learn a lot more about Hork-Bajir (more than we will really until somewhat later in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/10/the-hork-bajir-chronicles/">The Hork-Bajir Chronicles&lt;/a>). It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing to be doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, I still totally get Tobias lamenting getting jerked around like that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But in the end&amp;ndash;it was all worth it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Andalite Chronicles</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/23/the-andalite-chronicles/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something new! (If you not on a reread :))&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rather than the shared points of view of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/12/the-andalites-gift/">The Andalites Gift&lt;/a>, we now have the first [[Animorphs Chronicles|chronicle]] book: a book written from a completely alien (heh) point of view to fill in some other part of the universe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this case Elfangor-Sirinial-Shamtul. The one who in a lot of ways started this whole mess. And after reading this book&amp;ndash;apparently in more ways than we could believe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the plus side, we get a lot of fascinating world building. Learning more about Andelite culture directly, as opposed to via our normal human filters. Learning about Yeerks. Visser Three (before he was Three!). And Taxxons. And Skrit Na.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Skrit Na ship was round, with tapered sides. It looked like a fat disc. You could hardly even see where the engines were, and the Skrit Na had blinking colored lights all around it. I guess they find that attractive or something.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>(it&amp;rsquo;s a typical saucer shaped UFO)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand (minor spoilers, but it becomes obvious fairly early), time travel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve done that already&amp;ndash;and not that long ago (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/21/the-forgotten/">The Forgotten&lt;/a>). And&amp;hellip; while it&amp;rsquo;s got some interesting points here, it makes things a bit too messy and convenient, at least in my opinion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Reaction</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/22/the-reaction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/22/the-reaction/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s kind of amazing how many different one off plot lines this series introduces and just never (so far as I remember) deals with again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around&amp;hellip; being (somehow) allergic to newly acquired DNA!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a neat idea and does enough to support the story by itself&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So of course we have to deal with some random made up teenage heartthrob storyline.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I ignored Marco. I almost always do. Instead I made sure Jake was paying attention, and I said, &amp;ldquo;Jake, you&amp;rsquo;re not getting it. About half the girls in our school have a poster of Jeremy Jason McCole in their bedrooms or in their lockers, or both. He is the number one cute guy in the country. He has like twenty Web sites just about him. If he endorses The Sharing, it would be as if . . .&amp;rdquo; I looked to Cassie for help.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; weird. I get it. They&amp;rsquo;re teenagers. But it&amp;rsquo;s still not something I really understood even then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such is life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>