<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jonathan Goldstein on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/jonathan-goldstein/</link><description>Recent content in Jonathan Goldstein on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/jonathan-goldstein/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dungeons &amp; Dragons: Honor Among Thieves</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/08/dungeons-dragons-honor-among-thieves/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/08/dungeons-dragons-honor-among-thieves/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Edgin: We must never stop failing, because the minute we do, we&amp;rsquo;ve failed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s such a fun movie. It takes the delightful chaos of an idolized Dungeons and Dragons session, leans hard into the worldbuilding of the Forgotten Realms (without strictly requiring you know anything about it); and cranks up the visuals up to 11.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s gobs of humor, some pretty crazy action scenes, and a big &amp;rsquo;evil skybeam&amp;rsquo; action scene that every movie nowdays seems to have. Really, there are just so many great individual scenes. The initial view of the prison&amp;ndash;and the prison break. Fighting a certain dragon. Asking exactly five questions of the dead (it goes exactly as you&amp;rsquo;d expect).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The characters and casting were really quite fun too. Chris Pine&amp;rsquo;s Edgin the bard really sells teh movie, but I loved the over the top paladin feel of Regé-Jean Page&amp;rsquo;s Xenk and Daisy Head&amp;rsquo;s bonkers Sofina. Michelle Rodriguez as a barbarian? Yes please. Hugh Grant as Hugh Grant? A delightful surprise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s great. Give it a watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Xenk: You may have forsworn your oath, but your oath hasn&amp;rsquo;t forsworn you.&lt;br>
&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
Edgin: Just because that sentence is symmetrical, it doesn’t make it not nonsense.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Spider-Man: Homecoming</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/29/spider-man-homecoming/</guid><description>That is a truly delightful Spider-Man movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird seeing him introduced after the events of Captain America: Civil War) and completely skipping how he became Spider-Man in the first place&amp;hellip; but it works. I really like the entire plot, dealing with the fallout of the Avengers / super-hero activity and how normal people try to live their lives around it&amp;ndash;and what happens when the powers that be step in and take that away from them.</description></item></channel></rss>