<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Paul Jenkins on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/paul-jenkins/</link><description>Recent content in Paul Jenkins on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/paul-jenkins/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 12: How to Play with Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/07/hellblazer-vol.-12-how-to-play-with-fire/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/07/hellblazer-vol.-12-how-to-play-with-fire/</guid><description>Three multiple parters? No single issues? Sweet. Up the Down Staircase want my favorite, but both How to Play with Fire and Son of Man were excellent.
Mini reviews, pretty (horrifying) pictures and spoilers:
Up the Down Staircase Memes? I feel like I missed something. Interesting character development, but no real pay off.
Part One You are dating the wrong man.
Other than that, we have a fairly standard meet the family type scene.</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 11: Last Man Standing</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/03/hellblazer-vol.-11-last-man-standing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/03/hellblazer-vol.-11-last-man-standing/</guid><description>A solid one. Big stories are interesting, little ones are touching_weird_sweet, and Constantine’s got some new people and problems to deal with. Nothing too surreal either, which I appreciate.
Mini-reviews (spoilers):
Days of Wine and Roses A little bit of Constantine, a little bit of regular human terror.
The Wild Hunt Oh my.
Also: Colts!
Last Man Standing Argue and his men as ancient immortals? Merlin as a dragon? Sign me up!</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 10: In the Line of Fire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/01/hellblazer-vol.-10-in-the-line-of-fire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/01/hellblazer-vol.-10-in-the-line-of-fire/</guid><description>Fortune telling, Constantine’s father, more evil demons and arguably worse angels, and of course dead soldiers who can’t find rest.
Not a standout volume, but still pretty good.
Mini reviews (spoilers):
The Nature of the Beast Sure…
Reading the future is a common enough trope in this genre, but I enjoyed it.
Walking the Dog Another ghost story&amp;hellip;
…ish.
Oops. A neat twist.
Punkin’ Up the Great Outdoors Going to be a weird one:</description></item><item><title>Hellblazer, Vol. 9: Critical Mass</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/hellblazer-vol.-9-critical-mass/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/hellblazer-vol.-9-critical-mass/</guid><description>Two big stories, a few really trippy dreams, and Constantine managing to push off damnation a bit longer. A neat collection. Critical Mass in particular is worth the read.
Mini reviews (spoilers):
In Another Part of Hell Chas’ mother… quite a figure.
Warped Notions Part One: The Delicate Power of Terror Allllll right then.
Same thing.
Part Two: The Everything Virus They’re really going into the weird this time around…</description></item></channel></rss>