<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Garth Ennis on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/garth-ennis/</link><description>Recent content in Garth Ennis on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/garth-ennis/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Boys: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/05/the-boys-season-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/05/the-boys-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things just keep getting more bonkers and bloody. Really, if you made it this far, you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to love Season 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Boys are (still) out to deal with Homelander&amp;hellip; and they may just have found the weapon to do it. Only this time the solution is perhaps eve more expensive than the cost.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Homelander is really the (wonderful terrible) heart of the show. Anthony Starr is amazing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have a few new supes running around (in secret). And all sorts of ones we knew about doing even more terrible and deprived things in general.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And in the end, the more things change, the more things stay the same. But worse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Season 4. It&amp;rsquo;s weird to be caught up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Boys: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/the-boys-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/26/the-boys-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Managed to get away for a bit since [[The Boys: Season 1|season 1]]; sometimes life happens (but not for everyone in the Boys&amp;hellip;). But I finally made it through season 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man this is a violent bloody show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still quite the exploration for &amp;lsquo;what if superheroes were real&amp;hellip; and terrible&amp;rsquo; that really draws you in, but now with more terrible corporations. And Nazis. Because of course we had to go there. It actually works really well, the conflict of benefiting from Nazi science is a &lt;em>big deal&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still really enjoy (in a twisted way) how terrifying Antony Starr plays Homelander. If he goes off the rails, what &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> are you going to do to stop him?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plus show Hughie (really all of the &amp;rsquo;the Boys&amp;rsquo;) is far better than his comic counterpart. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see him well out of his comfort zone, both in relationships (especially with Starlight) and all the madcap shenanigans Butcher&amp;rsquo;s gang gets up to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, mostly Nazis, but Compound V not only getting revealed the the characters, but also going public? We haven&amp;rsquo;t nearly seen the ramifications of that. Hoping to see more of &lt;em>that&lt;/em> in Season 3.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, great show. Very much deserves the R rating. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Boys: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/09/the-boys-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/09/the-boys-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve previously watched the first season and read the comics, but with season 3 out now (and I haven’t reviewed the show previously), let’s watch it again. Should be interesting seeing what’s different this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow that&amp;rsquo;s violent. Just as bad if not worse than the comics, since you get to see it all on screen. But in a way that actually has some solid visuals and crazy scenes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Constantine</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/constantine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/17/constantine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I went through and read the entire (modern) catalogue of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/14/hellblazer-vol.-1-original-sins/">Hellblazer&lt;/a> and rewatched &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-matrix/">The Matrix&lt;/a>. So&amp;hellip; let&amp;rsquo;s give the 2005 Constantine film another try!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>