<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Scholomance on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-scholomance/</link><description>Recent content in The Scholomance on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-scholomance/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Last Graduate</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/the-last-graduate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/the-last-graduate/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Mum spent a lot of time in my formative years gently reminding me that people don’t think about us nearly as much as we think they do, because they’re all busy worrying what people are thinking about them.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>El is a super dramatic senior&amp;ndash;and she&amp;rsquo;s got her reasons, with the whole potential Dark Goddess thing she has going on&amp;ndash;and life is only getting weirder. She&amp;rsquo;s determined to get &lt;em>everyone&lt;/em> out, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the least bit of sense and she&amp;rsquo;s absolutely going to do it in world ending style. Oh, and of course there&amp;rsquo;s Orion. What&amp;rsquo;s up with that relationship, am I right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, if you loved &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/">A Deadly Education&lt;/a> (as I did), you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to love The Last Graduate. It turns the whole Scholomance craziness up to 11, gives us a dark chosen one that actually kind of works within the world building, and I really do love and care for the characters. And if the cliff hanger at the end of book 1 wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough&amp;hellip; THERE&amp;rsquo;S AN EVEN WORSE ONE AND THE NEXT BOOK ISN&amp;rsquo;T EVEN OUT YET.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways. Read it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Deadly Education</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/</guid><description>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s a joy of a book. Saying which I suppose&amp;ndash;after you&amp;rsquo;ve read it&amp;ndash;feels a bit ironic.
It&amp;rsquo;s one part magic school, with your more or less typical teenage protagonists doing more or less typical teenage thing. In my opinion, Novik does this very well. Main character El (short for Galadriel) is so wonderfully snarky and done with it teenage girl that I could practically feel her angst coming off the page&amp;ndash;and it&amp;rsquo;s all the better, because she really does have a good reason for it.</description></item></channel></rss>