<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Scholomance on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-scholomance/</link><description>Recent content in The Scholomance on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-scholomance/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Golden Enclaves</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/07/the-golden-enclaves/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/07/the-golden-enclaves/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; in the same way you know perfectly well you ought to stop reading and go to bed and you’ll feel hideously groggy in the morning if you don’t, and yet you keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I first started &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/"&gt;A Deadly Education&lt;/a&gt;, all we &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; knew was El and the Scholomance. A magic school that seemed to be going whole hog into the &amp;lsquo;what doesn&amp;rsquo;t kill you makes you stronger&amp;rsquo; style of teaching. El managed to not only survive, but thrive. And in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/the-last-graduate/"&gt;The Last Graduate&lt;/a&gt;, things seem to actually be going &lt;em&gt;well&lt;/em&gt;. It all worked out. &lt;em&gt;Everyone&lt;/em&gt;¹ is free, half the world&amp;rsquo;s monsters are dead, El has the book that will teach her how to set up perfect independent Golden Enclaves, and the Scholomance has claimed it&amp;rsquo;s last victims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;¹Except Orion. Stupid boy (not my words) refused to come out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I hadn&amp;rsquo;t lost an ounce of the passionate desire to beat him over the head with a large stick, and surely that was a sign of true love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And oh. There&amp;rsquo;s also some crazy dark malificer out there knocking down Enclaves left and right. The biggest monsters are coming for the wizards&amp;hellip; and only El can deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a lot of ways, that book did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; go ways that I expected it to. It&amp;rsquo;s so much darker and terrible and yet at the same time more &amp;lsquo;human&amp;rsquo; than I ever expected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re all greedy, but children make it easier to be. We feel it&amp;rsquo;s only right to give them everything we can grab, even when you know that anything you feed your own child still comes out of someone else&amp;rsquo;s mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El, on the other hand, is &lt;em&gt;so done&lt;/em&gt; with all that after what she&amp;rsquo;s already been through. She&amp;rsquo;s going to save the world&amp;ndash;and &lt;em&gt;she&lt;/em&gt; is going to pay the price for it this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because that&amp;rsquo;s what she does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a satisfying conclusion to one of the best new series I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a long time. I&amp;rsquo;m saddened that it&amp;rsquo;s over, but it ended well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Last Graduate</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/the-last-graduate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/16/the-last-graduate/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mum spent a lot of time in my formative years gently reminding me that people don’t think about us nearly as much as we think they do, because they’re all busy worrying what people are thinking about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El is a super dramatic senior&amp;ndash;and she&amp;rsquo;s got her reasons, with the whole potential Dark Goddess thing she has going on&amp;ndash;and life is only getting weirder. She&amp;rsquo;s determined to get &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; out, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the least bit of sense and she&amp;rsquo;s absolutely going to do it in world ending style. Oh, and of course there&amp;rsquo;s Orion. What&amp;rsquo;s up with that relationship, am I right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, if you loved &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/"&gt;A Deadly Education&lt;/a&gt; (as I did), you&amp;rsquo;re probably going to love The Last Graduate. It turns the whole Scholomance craziness up to 11, gives us a dark chosen one that actually kind of works within the world building, and I really do love and care for the characters. And if the cliff hanger at the end of book 1 wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough&amp;hellip; THERE&amp;rsquo;S AN EVEN WORSE ONE AND THE NEXT BOOK ISN&amp;rsquo;T EVEN OUT YET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways. Read it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Deadly Education</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/13/a-deadly-education/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s a joy of a book. Saying which I suppose&amp;ndash;after you&amp;rsquo;ve read it&amp;ndash;feels a bit ironic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s one part magic school, with your more or less typical teenage protagonists doing more or less typical teenage thing. In my opinion, Novik does this very well. Main character El (short for Galadriel) is so wonderfully snarky and done with it teenage girl that I could practically feel her angst coming off the page&amp;ndash;and it&amp;rsquo;s all the better, because she &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; does have a good reason for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>