<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Julian Fellowes on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/14/julian-fellowes/</link><description>Recent content in Julian Fellowes on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/14/julian-fellowes/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Downton Abbey</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/14/downton-abbey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/14/downton-abbey/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Royal Family comes to Downton Abbey.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Anna Bates: Is it always like this?&lt;br>
Richard Ellis: A royal visit is like a swan on a lake. Grace and serenity above, demented kicking down below.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s basically a film length episode of Downton Abbey. And that&amp;rsquo;s not a bad thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I would have preferred it stay on the small screen, but if that isn&amp;rsquo;t in the cards, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to at least have a chance to have one last* (grand) hurrah for the characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/25/downton-abbey-season-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/25/downton-abbey-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Downton Abbey Season 6 is a strange beast. On one hand, we have what feels all the cast pairing off, sometimes with long known relationships and in the cast of the Family with guys we only met in the previous season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, I &lt;em>still&lt;/em> do not really understand the relationship between Mary and Henry. I think it&amp;rsquo;s mostly Mary. She certainly ebbs and flows&amp;hellip; but wow she&amp;rsquo;s a (sorry, but Edith says it too) bitch at times. On the other hand, Edith and Bertie? Delightful. If expected for the chaos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, the world is moving on. Is Downton Abbey going to survive? With reductions in expected staff and families around the world failing, it&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But with all those relationships &lt;em>wow&lt;/em> do the last few episodes blitz through what feels like every plotline possible in only a few hours. I do wonder if they thought they&amp;rsquo;d have a 7th season. But so it goes. For the most part, everything is tied off neatly. And for everything else&amp;hellip; apparently there are two movies?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a final note, if you&amp;rsquo;ve been lamenting the torture the writers have put the Bates&amp;rsquo; through over the year&amp;hellip; well, they&amp;rsquo;re not quite done. But there is light at the end of the tunnel, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad for that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I quite enjoyed it. Much more than I expected to, as I seem to say with all non-SF/F shows I end up watching. Still not something I would have chosen, still quite enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/13/downton-abbey-season-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/08/13/downton-abbey-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh goodness. Another season down and only one more to go (plus some movies?). I&amp;rsquo;m not ready!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This one has a few primarily focuses:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mary and her men&amp;hellip; weird. I kind of liked both of them, but so it goes. Hints at what&amp;rsquo;s to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Isobel and Violet (of all people) getting romantically entangled. That I did not expect, much less with who. It&amp;rsquo;s fun, if sad at times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rose, speedrunning the relationship thing, all with yet another new family for people to disapprove of. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that her dating a black man went so poorly, yet this ends up much better?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course the Bates. Oh the Bates. I truly wish that Season 6 could be quiet and happy for them&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m not holding up too much hope for that one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, yet another solid season. Like I said, I&amp;rsquo;m not ready for the end! But all good things must. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/08/downton-abbey-season-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/07/08/downton-abbey-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oy. After all the death and craziness of Season 3 (especially that finale&amp;hellip;), the family is all off kilter now. It takes a bit to settle, and then of course we&amp;rsquo;re on for all the more trouble.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Highlights:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rose brings a touch of chaos Sybil never could. I&amp;rsquo;m glad they didn&amp;rsquo;t clone her. Rose is fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Man, Anna and Bates just don&amp;rsquo;t get an easy life, do they&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Tom is in such a weird situation&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m liking his role as a sort of inbetween, of both worlds and neither. Working with Mary too. I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;hellip; curious where it goes next though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/09/downton-abbey-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/09/downton-abbey-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh, now that&amp;rsquo;s a season. It starts with a marriage, imprisonment, and money problems and only gets crazier from there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;span class="spoiler">Death&lt;/span>
 is a theme as well, not once but twice. I get that sometimes &lt;span class="spoiler">actors move on&lt;/span>
, but they really did &lt;span class="spoiler">Matthew&lt;/span>
 dirty with that one&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall another solid season and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to what happens now!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Per episode reviews. Potential spoilers for the season as a whole.&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-31">Episode #3.1&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-32">Episode #3.2&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-33">Episode #3.3&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-34">Episode #3.4&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-35">Episode #3.5&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-36">Episode #3.6&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-37">Episode #3.7&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-38">Episode #3.8&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#a-journey-to-the-highlands">A Journey to the Highlands&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>

&lt;h2 id="episode-31">Episode #3.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re finally getting married!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/07/downton-abbey-season-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/07/downton-abbey-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>The season with World War I. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of changes, from war wounds to deaths to Downton becoming a temporary hospital.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating getting to know all these stories. Oh I wish the best for them all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Such is life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Per episode reviews. Potential spoilers for the season as a whole.&lt;/p>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-21">Episode 2.1&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-22">Episode 2.2&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-23">Episode 2.3&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-24">Episode 2.4&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-25">Episode 2.5&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-26">Episode 2.6&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-27">Episode 2.7&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#episode-28">Episode 2.8&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="#christmas-at-downton-abbey">Christmas at Downton Abbey&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav>

&lt;h2 id="episode-21">Episode 2.1&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>And so&amp;hellip; war. Brutal away and at home for those that go, those that don&amp;rsquo;t, and those that can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Downton Abbey: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/downton-abbey-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 23:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/24/downton-abbey-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Somehow I&amp;rsquo;m always surprised when a highly rated show is actually good. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From a modern, American, middle-class point of view, the idea of the early 1900s British Aristocracy is just so strange. They do next nothing (useful) and have an entire staff to support it. The entire estate could go to a cousin they&amp;rsquo;d never met and there&amp;rsquo;s nothing they can do about it &amp;hellip; is so strange.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s oddly charming?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Grantham&amp;rsquo;s are fascinating. Sybil seems good people, Edith is certainly going to figure out how to come into her own, Mary is spoiled and needlessly cruel&amp;ndash;but may be learning. Lord and Lady Grantham are fun, if somewhat alien&amp;ndash;and I do love watching Lord Grantham try and completely fail to wrangle three young adult daughters. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The shining jewel of the family Dame Maggie Smith&amp;rsquo;s Dowager Countess of Grantham. Oh she&amp;rsquo;s just wonderful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among the staff, you have a whole &amp;rsquo;nother level of politics. They&amp;rsquo;re all great and terrible (as they should be) and there are every bit as many problems and politics as there are among the &amp;lsquo;family&amp;rsquo;. Turns out people are people no matter how much money they have or do not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a crazy amount to fit into seven episodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward&amp;hellip; to war!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>