<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Byron Simpson on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/byron-simpson/</link><description>Recent content in Byron Simpson on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/writers/byron-simpson/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Rescuers Down Under</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/the-rescuers-down-under/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/17/the-rescuers-down-under/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s an absolute blast of childhood nostalgia. We had this movie on VHS when I was little and I remember watching the heck out of it, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t otherwise seen it in decades now. Truth be told, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until recently that I realized it was even a sequel&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case. The Rescuers (Down Under) is the story of a worldwide society of mice that take it upon themselves to rescue human children in need of help. It&amp;rsquo;s a nutty premise, but just go with it. This time around, it&amp;rsquo;s a boy kidnapped in the Australian outback (with a wonderfully over the top poacher as the villain) and somehow the team they send are two mice from&amp;hellip; New York? There&amp;rsquo;s no one else closer? Only two? Anyways, they have to go rescue the boy, there are a few tense moments, a lot of adventure, and in the end the villain is defeated and the boy goes home free. It&amp;rsquo;s got a number of tense moments&amp;ndash;more than I remember truth be told&amp;ndash;and my younger viewers needed a bit of attention through a few points. But I think they enjoyed it well enough.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>