<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Melinda Metz on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/melinda-metz/</link><description>Recent content in Melinda Metz on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/melinda-metz/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Prophecy</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/27/the-prophecy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/27/the-prophecy/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;An Arn, on Earth? Here? Why? That&amp;rsquo;s the question. What&amp;rsquo;s he up to?&amp;gt; Rachel wondered.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;He had to come. Star Wars: The Phantom Menace isn&amp;rsquo;t coming out on DVD there for, like, two years. He buys up a bunch of copies here, takes &amp;rsquo;em home, makes a fortune.&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Good grief, Marco, you live science fiction, why do you want to watch science fiction?&amp;gt;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be dissing TPM,&amp;gt; Marco said. &lt;Cool is cool.>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; the Arn. Like I said &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/10/the-hork-bajir-chronicles/">The Hork-Bajir Chronicles&lt;/a> was among my favorites of these books, so following up on that storyline is pretty cool. Especially the the Animorphs getting a chance to go offworld entirely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And hey, let&amp;rsquo;s bring back the memory implant of Aldrea (the Andalite from the Hork-Bajir Chronicles, Seerow&amp;rsquo;s daughter) for good measure. Of course bringing back the dead to the source of some of their worst possible memories (although best too I suppose) can&amp;rsquo;t possibly go wrong&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a neat book. Bit weird, but I liked it. I hope something comes of it, but if it does, I don&amp;rsquo;t remember from last time I read these books. We shall have to see!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Sickness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/21/the-sickness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/21/the-sickness/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;You ever notice how many different ways there are to say &amp;rsquo;throwing up&amp;rsquo;?&amp;rdquo; Marco asked as we passed Dunkin&amp;rsquo; Donuts, the first in the row of fast food places dotting the main street running through town. &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s vomiting, of course. Hurling. Tossing your cookies. Puking, a classic. Ralphing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was glad Marco was filling up the silence. Even though I thought he could have come up with a better topic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s cascading. But I prefer the terms that are more real. Like blowing chunks. Spewing your guts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Marco took a deep breath and kept on talking as we made our way past Taco Bell. &amp;ldquo;Tangoing with the toilet. That&amp;rsquo;s a good one,&amp;rdquo; he said reflectively. &amp;ldquo;Technicolor yawn.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The one where everyone gets sick (Ax deathly so) and Cassie has to go on a solo rescue mission to the Yeerk pool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quite a story and quite a bit more Cassie than we often get. Being the action hero no less!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A solid one.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>