<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kate Daniels on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/kate-daniels/</link><description>Recent content in Kate Daniels on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/kate-daniels/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Magic Triumphs</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/03/26/magic-triumphs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/03/26/magic-triumphs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;That was actually somewhat surprising for an ending. I expected a knock down, drag out fight with Roland, but instead&amp;hellip; &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;Dragons. Of course it had to be dragons.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s actually a pretty solid ending to the series, even if the final confrontations/battles did end rather abruptly and solve everything a bit too neatly. I almost want to see yet another book following the aftermath. But there&amp;rsquo;s something to be said for letting an ending be an ending and I can respect that.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Magic Binds</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/03/18/magic-binds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/03/18/magic-binds/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Did you run any of this by Curran?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I told him I was about to do something idiotic and dangerous, and he told me to go ahead and let him know if he could help in any way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t understand your relationship.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Magic Shifts</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/03/06/magic-shifts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/03/06/magic-shifts/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Does everybody think I&amp;rsquo;m an asshole?&amp;rdquo; Curran asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Only people who know you or have met you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Magic Breaks</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/19/magic-breaks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/19/magic-breaks/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Fortune favors the brave,&amp;quot; I told her. It also kills the stupid, but I decided to keep that fact to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curran is out of town, so of course things are going to go wrong. Taking a lot of what&amp;rsquo;s been building, between the Pack having troubles with a non-shifter as essentially second in command, the relationship between the Pack and the People, Kate&amp;rsquo;s trouble with Roland and more particularly with Hugh.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Magic Rises</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/08/magic-rises/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/08/magic-rises/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Kate and gang go to Europe!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world building in the Kate Daniels universe is really top notch. It&amp;rsquo;s set in a modern world where magic has returned. So far, not that unusual. But in this world, magic and tech alternate which set of rules dominate. When tech rules, no fireballs, no tracking spells, etc. But when magic dominates, skyscrapers decay and planes fall from the sky. So you&amp;rsquo;re in a modern world without a lot of the modern conveniences. There are a few issues (like where does the power come from? haven&amp;rsquo;t the power plants fallen apart? who works there&amp;hellip;), but it&amp;rsquo;s still pretty awesome.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Magic Slays</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/04/magic-slays/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/02/04/magic-slays/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Kate&amp;rsquo;s no longer a mercenary and needs something to do with her time and skills, so ends up opening a private investigation business. Which of course takes a while to get going, so when she&amp;rsquo;s hired by Ghastek and the People to track down a runaway vampire&amp;hellip; things of course are going to go from bad to worse. That&amp;rsquo;s quite a thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting twist to see the big bads this time around to be &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;more or less vanilla humans that hate magic&lt;/span&gt;
 . It&amp;rsquo;s been done before, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any less worth exploring in a world where magic (sometimes) reigns supreme.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Magic Bleeds</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/16/magic-bleeds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/16/magic-bleeds/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t give you the white picket fence, and if I did, you&amp;rsquo;d set it on fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh Kate.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Magic Strikes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/13/magic-strikes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/13/magic-strikes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Norse and Hindu mythology (on top of what all we&amp;rsquo;ve had before)! Magical gladiator fights TO THE DEATH! Giant fight scenes! ACTUALLY LEARNING WHAT&amp;rsquo;S UP WITH KATE&amp;rsquo;S BACKSTORY!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s quite a book.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Magic Burns</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/08/magic-burns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/08/magic-burns/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The vampire stared at me, his mouth slack as Ghastek assessed his options. I took a couple of forms from my desk, put them into the vamp&amp;rsquo;s mouth, and pulled them up by their edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What are you doing?&amp;rdquo; Ghastek asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My hole puncher broke.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You have no respect for the undead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Magic Bites</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/03/magic-bites/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/01/03/magic-bites/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On one hand, Magic Bites was pretty much what I expected. Urban Fantasy with a strong female lead (this time a mostly stock standard human mercenary albeit with some sort of so far unspecified magical bloodline) finds some trouble, things go badly, things get better, lead saves the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Kate Daniels is a solid character to read. Despite not knowing whatever it is that gives her a bit of extra oomph, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter. She has a cool sword, a lot of training, and can handle herself even in the presence of some big bads. That&amp;rsquo;s more than enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>