<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rian Johnson on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/directors/rian-johnson/</link><description>Recent content in Rian Johnson on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/directors/rian-johnson/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Star Wars: Episode VIII - The Last Jedi</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/05/star-wars-episode-viii-the-last-jedi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/05/star-wars-episode-viii-the-last-jedi/</guid><description>More Star Wars! I remember being&amp;hellip; somewhat disappointed. Tonally, they got away from the nostalgia of the Force Awakens. There are still some absolutely beautiful/powerful moments (the final battles over the salt flats or whatever those were were pretty cool), but not quite as strong as it was before. And there are all sorts of things that just feel &amp;rsquo;less magical&amp;rsquo; and more movie driven than anything.
This time around, I liked it a lot more.</description></item><item><title>Knives Out</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/24/knives-out/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/24/knives-out/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Lieutenant Elliott: I&amp;rsquo;m sorry this is an open and shut case of suicide and quite frankly Benny we are getting to the point where I have to ask you what we&amp;rsquo;re doing here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Benoit Blanc: The method? Throat slit? Typical for a suicide?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lieutenant Elliott: Yes, I mean, that&amp;rsquo;s dramatic, but look around. I mean, the guy practical lives in a Clue board.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was a surprising yet great fun movie. In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a murder mystery. Heir of the family is found dead&amp;ndash;apparent suicide. But things quickly become more complicated, with a detective (Daniel Craig as Benoit Blanc with a hilarious southern drawl that still somehow works&amp;hellip;) anonymously hired to &amp;lsquo;get to the truth&amp;rsquo;. The family is a nightmare, everyone has a reason to have offed the old man&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Looper</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/01/looper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 04:55:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2012/10/01/looper/</guid><description>&lt;p>Looper did three things really well:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>