<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mr. Robot on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mr.-robot/</link><description>Recent content in Mr. Robot on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mr.-robot/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mr. Robot: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/18/mr.-robot-season-4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/18/mr.-robot-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/mr.robot-season-4.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Wow. That really went quite a fascinating direction. I was wondering where they were going for the last few seasons, but really digging into the aftermath of the season 1 hacks + another big target + dealing with the fallout of the Dark Army + digging deeper into Elliot&amp;rsquo;s troubles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man. Quite a season.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had my doubts in the run up to the final few episodes, but I think they really stuck the landing. This was quite a show, through and through. Well worth the watch.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mr. Robot: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/20/mr.-robot-season-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/20/mr.-robot-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/mr.robot-season-3.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Oh boy. This one really dug into the darker parts of character growth. Elliot finds new ways to be even crazier, Angela is&amp;hellip; off the rails entirely, Moustache Guy (Bobby Cannavale/Irvin) is awesome, and the entire plot of Darlene, Dominque, and the FBI was fascinating to watch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I keep being pleasantly surprised with where this show keeps going. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have expected them to make it past the first season plotwise&amp;hellip; yet here we are. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to where we can go from here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mr. Robot: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/mr.-robot-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/mr.-robot-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/mr.robot-season-2.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>After Season 1 wrapped up, where do you even go from there? They finished their big goal. Dealing with the fallout is the obvious answer&amp;hellip; or ramping things up even further. We get a bit of both in Season 2, mostly with even more big twists from Elliot&amp;rsquo;s entirely confusing mind but also a plot that is both deeper and more terrifying than I would have thought at first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not quite as solid as Season 1, in most part because it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as new and fresh. But it&amp;rsquo;s still very good and well worth the watch. Whatever shall we learn in Season 3?!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mr. Robot: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/mr.-robot-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/10/31/mr.-robot-season-1/</guid><description>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a heck of a show. Given that I&amp;rsquo;m do computer security for a living (albeit with a bit less of the black hat revolutionary mindset) and have my own problems figuring out how brains&amp;ndash;mine and others&amp;ndash;work (albeit not nearly to that extent&amp;hellip;) I feel like the perfect audience for this show. I&amp;rsquo;m honestly impressed with how well they got the hacking in this show. It&amp;rsquo;s not 100%&amp;ndash;that would be boring&amp;ndash;but it&amp;rsquo;s miles closer than two-hackers-typing-on-a-keyboard-is-faster.</description></item></channel></rss>