<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Terry Pratchett on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/terry-pratchett/</link><description>Recent content in Terry Pratchett on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/terry-pratchett/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Shepherd's Crown</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/26/the-shepherds-crown/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/26/the-shepherds-crown/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>FOR I CAN SEE THE BALANCE AND YOU HAVE LEFT THE WORLD MUCH BETTER THAN YOU FOUND IT, AND IF YOU ASK ME, said Death, NOBODY COULD DO ANY BETTER THAN THAT&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And so it ends.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Shall Wear Midnight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/19/i-shall-wear-midnight/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/19/i-shall-wear-midnight/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tiffany Aching is back! Now she&amp;rsquo;s a full witch, out on her own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course things are going to go wrong.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wintersmith</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/15/wintersmith/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/15/wintersmith/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The trouble is you can shut your eyes but you can’t shut your mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Tiffany returns, this time slightly older and in just a bit more trouble than before. This time around, she accidentally danced with the Wintersmith (the very embodiment of winter) and, as one thing leads to another, the Wintersmith beings to fall in love, trying to become human along the way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Hat Full of Sky</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/12/a-hat-full-of-sky/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/12/a-hat-full-of-sky/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Why do you go away? So that you can come back. So that you can see the place you came from with new eyes and extra colors. And the people there see you differently, too. Coming back to where you started is not the same as never leaving.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="618145" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/618145.a-hat-full-of-sky"> A Hat Full of Sky &lt;/a> takes &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="34494" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34494.the-wee-free-men"> The Wee Free Men &lt;/a> and grows from there, following Tiffany Aching as she actually starts to learn a bit more witching, while at the same time having to deal with some of the fall out from her actions in The Wee Free Men.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Wee Free Men</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/10/the-wee-free-men/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/10/the-wee-free-men/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Open your eyes and then open your eyes again.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The Wee Free Men is a wonderful book. It&amp;rsquo;s the Witches again, done YA this time around. It follows the story of Tiffany Aching&amp;ndash;young witch to be&amp;ndash;as she begins to discovers her powers and finds that the world may be just a bit more complicated than she (or the adults around her) thinks it is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Small Gods</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/04/small-gods/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/04/small-gods/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The turtle moves.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Small Gods is a bit odd in the greater Discworld universe, being one of only a handful of one-off stories (Pyramids and Amazing Maurice are the other two if you count the Industrial Revolution subseries as a series) and being relatively early in the reading order. So with the exception of offhand references (such as to the Great God Om), it&amp;rsquo;s one of the books you could easily read anywhere in your reading order.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Raising Steam</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/02/raising-steam/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/05/02/raising-steam/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64222" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64222.going-postal">Going Postal&lt;/a>, Moist von Lipwig rebuilt the post office. In &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="116296" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/116296.making-money">Making Money&lt;/a>, he took on the banks. Now? Steam engines are coming to the Discworld!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see more and more technology come to the Discworld, especially watching it blend with the magic that&amp;rsquo;s already there. You have goblins running the clacks (telegraphs) and now the trains and a engine that might just be alive. On top of that, we&amp;rsquo;re dealing with some of the fall out of the recent (bookwise) war between the Trolls and the Dwarves.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making Money</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/18/making-money/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/18/making-money/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It was sad, like those businessmen who came to work in serious clothes but wore colorful ties in a mad, desperate attempt to show there was a free spirit in there somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64222" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64222.going-postal">Going Postal&lt;/a>, &amp;lsquo;former&amp;rsquo; conman Moist von Lipwig rebuilt Ankh-Morpork post from the ground up&amp;hellip; but now he&amp;rsquo;s bored. Everything is running as it should; there&amp;rsquo;s nothing left to fix. So when Vetinari offers him the chance to do the same to the bank&amp;hellip; of course he runs the other way. One thing leads to another though and eventually the Moist ends up with a new dog who just so happens to own the majority share in the bank. Good times.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Going Postal</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/12/going-postal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/12/going-postal/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the time of writing this, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64222" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64222.going-postal">Going Postal&lt;/a> is tied for the second highest rated Discworld book on Goodreads (tied with &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="400354" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/400354.men-at-arms">Men at Arms&lt;/a> at 4.37, behind &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="47989" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/47989.night-watch">Night Watch&lt;/a> at 4.48). There&amp;rsquo;s a reason for this&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Essentially, Going Postal takes a small pile of topics&amp;ndash;technical innovation and traditional technology versus the new hotness; conmen and businessmen; the postal service itself&amp;ndash;and squishes them together with the wonderful latter book Discworld flair Pratchett is so known for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monstrous Regiment</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/04/monstrous-regiment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/04/04/monstrous-regiment/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Do you think it&amp;rsquo;s possible for an entire nation to be insane?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Truth</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/08/the-truth/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/08/the-truth/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>There are, it has been said, two types of people in the world. There are those who, when presented with a glass that is exactly half full, say: this glass is half full. And then there are those who say: this glass is half empty.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world belongs, however, to those who can look at the glass and say: What&amp;rsquo;s up with this glass? Excuse me? Excuse me? This is my glass? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so. My glass was full! And it was a bigger glass! Who&amp;rsquo;s been pinching my beer?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And at the other end of the bar the world is full of the other type of person, who has a broken glass, or a glass that has been carelessly knocked over (usually by one of the people calling for a larger glass) or who had no glass at all, because he was at the back of the crowd and had failed to catch the barman&amp;rsquo;s eye.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Moving Pictures</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/03/moving-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/03/03/moving-pictures/</guid><description>&lt;p>Discworld goes Hollywood. Or perhaps Hollywood comes to Discworld?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, Hollywood is a manifestation of a &amp;lsquo;Great Old Ones&amp;rsquo; esque cult where the final cultist keeping the Holy Wood from arising once again dies. One thing leads to another, trolls get dressed up as elephants, and a movie hero has to save the day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Snuff</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/10/snuff/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/10/snuff/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Yes, sir, thank you, sir, and I wouldn’t trust me one little inch, sir. I knows a bad one when I sees them. I have a mirror.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Thud!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/03/thud/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/02/03/thud/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Quis custodiet ipsos custodes? Your grace.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I know that one,&amp;rdquo; said Vimes. &amp;ldquo;Who watches the watchmen? Me, Mr. Pessimal.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Ah, but who watches you, your grace?&amp;rdquo; said the inspector, with a brief smile.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I do that, too. All the time,&amp;rdquo; said Vimes. &amp;ldquo;Believe me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Night Watch</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/31/night-watch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/31/night-watch/</guid><description>&lt;p>Night Watch starts with Vimes and a few others visiting a number of otherwise forgotten graves. When asked what was going on: &amp;ldquo;you had to have been there.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One magical lightning storm later and Vimes ends up &amp;lsquo;having been there&amp;rsquo; for a second time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Fifth Elephant</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/23/the-fifth-elephant/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2018/01/23/the-fifth-elephant/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>So this is diplomacy. It’s like lying, only to a better class of people.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>More than most of the Guards series (or Discworld in general), &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="63720" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/63720.the-fifth-elephant">The Fifth Elephant&lt;/a> is driven by a strong plot rather than leaning on characters and jokes. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a nice change from many of the other books, although I do like both styles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jingo</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/28/jingo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/28/jingo/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Always be wary of any helpful item that weighs less than its operating manual.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Such is modern life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Feet of Clay</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/20/feet-of-clay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/20/feet-of-clay/</guid><description>&lt;p>Feet of Clay&amp;rsquo;s central story tackles one key idea: What makes a person a person?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this case, the idea is personified by the golems&amp;ndash;a constructed race of humanoids made of clay, animated by a religious text stored inside of their head, and bound to service (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golem">inspired by Jewish folklore&lt;/a>). According to just about everyone, golems aren&amp;rsquo;t alive. They are nothing more than tools.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Men at Arms</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/13/men-at-arms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/12/13/men-at-arms/</guid><description>&lt;p>Continuing the story of &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="64216" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/64216.guards-guards">Guards! Guards!&lt;/a>, &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="400354" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/400354.men-at-arms">Men at Arms&lt;/a> follows all of my favorite characters from that former on a grand new adventure (of sorts).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have Corporal Carrot:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guards! Guards!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/09/12/guards-guards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/09/12/guards-guards/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a reason that many people who suggesting a starting point for Discworld suggest people start with the City Watch subseries and &lt;em>Guards! Guards!&lt;/em> in particular. It&amp;rsquo;s hilarious.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>They may be called the Palace Guard, the City Guard, or the Patrol. Whatever the name, their purpose in any work of heroic fantasy is identical: it is, round about Chapter Three (or ten minutes into the film) to rush into the room, attack the hero one at a time, and be slaughtered. No one ever asks them if they want to. This book is dedicated to those fine men.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Pyramids</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/09/04/pyramids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/09/04/pyramids/</guid><description>&lt;p>Pyramids is essentially Discworld versus Ancient Egypt. The entire idea of a kingdom that has been stable for so long that they do everything because they always have combined with the idea of spending basically everything on giant pyramids for the dead. Throw in some reality unstability, some worldbuilding on the Assassin&amp;rsquo;s guild,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worldbuildingwise, pyramids on the Discworld have this tendency to store time. Each king must have the greatest pyramid of all time. This time around, the pyramid is so big that reality gets a bit broken, sending the kingdom of Djelibeybi into a parallel reality where beliefs become reality.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thief of Time</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/31/thief-of-time/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/31/thief-of-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>A slightly shorter entry into the Discworld universe and the last of the Death subseries, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t get into Thief of Time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are some interesting ideas in there. The fifth horseman of the apocalypse. Mrs. War. The Auditors (again) trying to simplify their jobs. The personification of Time. A clock that can keep &amp;lsquo;perfect&amp;rsquo; time and the trouble that would cause. History monks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hogfather</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/29/hogfather/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/08/29/hogfather/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Humans need fantasy to be human. To be the place where the falling angel meets the rising ape.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Short version: the Hog Father (twisted Santa Clause) is missing, extra belief is sloshing about causing all sorts of trouble, and Death has stepped up to fill the roll.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Soul Music</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/27/soul-music/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/27/soul-music/</guid><description>&lt;p>Soul Music fell somewhat flat for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One one hand a Death story that only barely involves Death&amp;ndash;although the parts that do are pretty amusing. It&amp;rsquo;s yet another story of Death stepping down, this time getting temporarily replaced by his granddaughter of sorts, who just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem that interesting to me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reaper Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/12/reaper-man/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/12/reaper-man/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No one is finally dead until the ripples they cause in the world die away—until the clock wound up winds down, until the wine she made has finished its ferment, until the crop they planted is harvested. The span of someone’s life is only the core of their actual existence.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>If it were your time to go, yet Death didn&amp;rsquo;t come for you&amp;hellip; what then?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mort</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/05/mort/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/06/05/mort/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Tʜᴇʀᴇ&amp;rsquo;s ɴᴏ ᴊᴜsᴛɪᴄᴇ, ᴛʜᴇʀᴇ&amp;rsquo;s ᴊᴜsᴛ ᴍᴇ. —Death&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Another day, another subseries of Discworld. This time: &lt;strong>DEATH&lt;/strong>. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen him in a few other series, but this is the first point we really get to look at the skeletal anthropomorphization itself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maskerade</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/05/09/maskerade/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/05/09/maskerade/</guid><description>&lt;p>The witches are back! Or at least Granny Weatherwax and Nanny Ogg. Magrat&amp;rsquo;s off being queen or somesuch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short version of the plot: Phantom of the Opera, Discworld style.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Carpe Jugulum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/05/08/carpe-jugulum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/05/08/carpe-jugulum/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Carpe Jugulum,&amp;quot; read Agnes aloud. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; well, Carpe Diem is &amp;lsquo;Sieze the Day,&amp;rsquo; so this means-&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Go for the throat”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Lords and Ladies</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/03/29/lords-and-ladies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/03/29/lords-and-ladies/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lords and Ladies continues more or less directly the events of Witches Abroad. It follows the trials and tribulations of the witches Weatherwax, Ogg, and Garlick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, a decent chunk of the book is dedicated to the Discworld idea of the Fae&amp;ndash;which are just about as terrifying as they should be.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Witches Abroad</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/03/03/witches-abroad/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/03/03/witches-abroad/</guid><description>&lt;p>The witches are a lot of fun to read about, especially in how they interact with one another. Granny is hilariously no-nonsense, but too stubborn to admin when she doesn&amp;rsquo;t know something. Nanny Ogg is much more worldly (for a witch) and a good counterpoint. Magrat is the young witch, still learning, and has the advantage of not knowing quite so well as the two older witches just when something is &lt;em>supposed&lt;/em> to be impossible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, we get a story that is basically a pile of stereotypical fairy tales (mostly Cinderella) tossed into a blender with a heaping helping of Discworld for seasoning. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of bizarre, but in a greatly entertaining way. Even better, given that half the time the witches seem to realize they are living out storybook tales and half the time they are amusingly unaware.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wyrd Sisters</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/02/17/wyrd-sisters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/02/17/wyrd-sisters/</guid><description>&lt;p>Witches, take two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Upside: more of Granny Weatherwax! She remains as awesome as she was in Equal Rites.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Equal Rites</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/02/13/equal-rites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/02/13/equal-rites/</guid><description>&lt;p>Equal Rites follows the story of what was assumed to be an automatic wizard&amp;ndash; the eighth son of an eighth son&amp;ndash;except&amp;hellip; she&amp;rsquo;s a girl. And everyone knows that women can&amp;rsquo;t be witches&amp;hellip; although no one can quite put a finger on why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite an enjoyable book, both exploring some of the parts of Discworld that we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen as much yet (if you, like I, have only read the Rincewind books thus far) and gives a bit more heft to the ones we have seen. We see a lot more of the earlier wizards that we already saw in the first two Rincewind novels, but this time it&amp;rsquo;s from an outsider&amp;rsquo;s perspective, which is refreshing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unseen Academicals</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/02/03/unseen-academicals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/02/03/unseen-academicals/</guid><description>&lt;p>Officially, Unseen Academicals is the 8th and final novel in the Rincewind subseries of the Discworld novels. Unfortunately, Rincewind isn&amp;rsquo;t in particularly much of it. A few pages? He&amp;rsquo;s a professor now&amp;hellip; and that&amp;rsquo;s about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, the entire story is about football.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Last Hero</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/27/the-last-hero/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/27/the-last-hero/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Last Hero is a quick read, much shorter than some of the other Discworld books. It does manage to say relatively self contained though, which is nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically Cohen the Barbarian and his Silver Horde have conquered the world. Next up? The gods. Unfortunately that will apparently have negative consequences, so Rincewind and friends have to stop them. Once again Rincewind goes over the edge, this time in a &lt;del>rocket&lt;/del> DRAGON powered spaceship. That&amp;rsquo;s certainly a thing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Last Continent</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/25/the-last-continent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/25/the-last-continent/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Last Continent is something of a disappointment after Interesting Times. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that it&amp;rsquo;s strictly speaking &amp;lsquo;bad&amp;rsquo;, just that it&amp;rsquo;s not quite as good as many of the other Rincewind novels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Basically, this time around, Rincewind&amp;rsquo;s adventures have dropped him off on XXXX, the &amp;lsquo;Last Continent&amp;rsquo; of the Discworld. Basically, it&amp;rsquo;s bizarroworld Australia with something of a funny relationship with the whole time-space thing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Interesting Times</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/23/interesting-times/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/23/interesting-times/</guid><description>&lt;p>Interesting Times is a fantastic Discworld novel, an excellent example of everything people expect when they talk about Terry Pratchett and the Discworld novels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, Twoflower has taken everything he learned in The Color of Magic and The Light Fantastic and written a book about it. One thing leads to another and suddenly Rincewind is being summoned across the world to lead a revolution. The ending is a bit convenient, but it&amp;rsquo;s really it&amp;rsquo;s all about the journey, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eric</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/18/eric/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/18/eric/</guid><description>&lt;p>Eric is an amusing enough story and an interesting continuation of Rincewind&amp;rsquo;s story, after the events back in Sourcery. Not entirely long story slightly shorter, Rincewind gets accidently summoned by a budding 14 year old summoner. Unfortunately for all involved, this seems to actually grant him some demonic powers&amp;hellip; and hijinks ensue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The basic plot leaves something to be desired. Basically Eric makes three wishes and things go badly about as one might expect. It&amp;rsquo;s even more random feeling than many of the previous Rincewind novels, which is saying something. Characterwise, Eric just isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly interesting, so we&amp;rsquo;re just left with Rincewind. As amusing as he is, he&amp;rsquo;s not quite enough to carry an entire novel all by himself. Previously, we had Twoflower or Cohen&amp;hellip; Not so much this time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sourcery</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/02/sourcery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2017/01/02/sourcery/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sourcery is the first of the Rincewind subseries of Discworld not to also feature Twoflower. It makes sense&amp;ndash;his story seems to have been told&amp;ndash;but it still does feel a bit different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, we deal with the 8th son of a wizard (already the 8th son of an 8th son themselves)&amp;ndash;a Sourcerer. Basically, one who can intuitively do magic on a scale wizards literally cannot dream of. They&amp;rsquo;re the entire reason that wizards are banned from having sex (see the 8th son bit above). And now there&amp;rsquo;s a new one in the world&amp;ndash;a ten year old boy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Light Fantastic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/30/the-light-fantastic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/30/the-light-fantastic/</guid><description>&lt;p>I still feel like The Light Fantastic and The Color of Magic could really be combined into a single larger novel, given that the second takes off running pretty much where there first went off&amp;hellip; and promptly dumps Rincewind and Twoflower back onto the disc somehow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an odd little story, jumping from section to section with a whole cast of new bizarre and amusing character (including the spell in Rincewind&amp;rsquo;s head and a small pile of trees) and locations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Color of Magic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/22/the-color-of-magic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2016/12/22/the-color-of-magic/</guid><description>&lt;p>Once upon a time, I tried to read the Discworld books, starting (against several people&amp;rsquo;s advise) with the first and working through all of them. I made it a few books in and put them down, saying that some day I would give them another chance. Well, this is that chance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time around, I&amp;rsquo;m listening to them all on audiobook. This actually seems to help quite a lot, since it allows me to keep listening while at the same time doing something with my hands and, unless I stop it myself, will keep going without me. It turns out that, given those circumstances, I quite enjoyed the Color of Magic this time around.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>