<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NUMA Files on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/numa-files/</link><description>Recent content in NUMA Files on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/numa-files/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Medusa</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/04/medusa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/04/medusa/</guid><description>&lt;p>Swallowed by a sperm whale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s quite the introductory seen. Starts with whaling, full on Moby Dick (I should read that at some point). It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting story, with just enough weird science to see where it&amp;rsquo;s going in the &amp;lsquo;present day&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Corona Virus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This&amp;hellip; felt all the more real in this post Covid world. And a sign of how it could have been so much worse&amp;ndash;if only we didn&amp;rsquo;t have weird ocean life and a super well funded, run, and liked NUMA to save the world. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Hermaphrodite third triplet as a big bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; just lazy. The Chinese Triad / mafia stuff, pretty cool. This reveal? Meh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, at this point? It&amp;rsquo;s Clive Cussler. The books are enjoyable enough, but I want to listen to something else for a while. So I&amp;rsquo;m moving on to something else. Perhaps one day I&amp;rsquo;ll return.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Navigator</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/28/the-navigator/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/28/the-navigator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s take a quick break from all the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/animorphs/">Animorphs&lt;/a> I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading recently and instead talk about the Phoenicians again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean NUMA/Kurt Austin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But they even call it out in the book, &amp;rsquo;the Phoenicians again'.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really, this book is kind of hilariously on point when it calls out it&amp;rsquo;s own weirdness. We have a big bad:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The big man with the face like an evil baby.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And the other big bad later saying:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;I have no intention of taking over the world like some James Bond villain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Uh huh. Sure now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, the plot is interesting enough. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I like or not how many of these books are tied together (all about pre-Columbian contact and the Phoenicians). It&amp;rsquo;s interesting, I&amp;rsquo;ll give them that. But the additions of new (weirdly named) secret societies, secret messages, and hidden gold mines? I&amp;rsquo;ll take it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And more Thomas Jefferson than you can shake a stick at. It&amp;rsquo;s not James Bond, it&amp;rsquo;s National Treasure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a decent enough story, but I think &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/11/lost-city/">Lost City&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/03/polar-shift/">Polar Shift&lt;/a> may have spoiled me a bit. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Polar Shift</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/03/polar-shift/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/02/03/polar-shift/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another hit, and back to back with &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/11/lost-city/">Lost City&lt;/a> as well!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a bonkers plot (aren&amp;rsquo;t they all?), based around the idea of &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nikola%20Tesla">Nikola Tesla&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s doomsday weapons were REAL&amp;rsquo; (albeit assigned to a made up Hungarian scientist instead), evil anarchists inadvertently teaming up with the very elite they&amp;rsquo;re trying to overthrow, and&amp;hellip; for some reason throwing mysterious cities and living fossils in for good measure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The science is&amp;hellip; messy at best. There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of electromagnetism which they handwave as not directly causing a lot of the issues we see, but rather setting things that could otherwise have happened in motion, but&amp;hellip; the sense of scale never quite works. The code work involved in the secret solution to it all is&amp;hellip; just not good (it&amp;rsquo;s barely a code and there&amp;rsquo;s no way to tell they interpreted it correctly at that). The mammoth parts and new entire-field-of-archeology-upsetting discoveries are&amp;hellip; convenient and yet barely make an impact.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, &amp;lsquo;Uncle Karl&amp;rsquo; here is such a delight. An old soldier trying to do the right thing one last time. He&amp;rsquo;s a fun contrast to the young action heroes in most of these books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The action is, for the most part, fine. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing nearly as spectacular as the castle/island escape scenes from the last book, but there&amp;rsquo;s a nice sense of tension through this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet, it&amp;rsquo;s still a surprisingly good book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lost City</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/11/lost-city/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/01/11/lost-city/</guid><description>&lt;p>Given how super formulaic these books are, I was actually really surprised with how &lt;em>good&lt;/em> this one is. You have a (very) old arms family with a flare for the dramatic, the lost city (no, not &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atlantis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">that one&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lost_City_Hydrothermal_Field" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this one&lt;/a>), killer &amp;hellip; algae?, all the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edgar%20Allen%20Poe">Edgar Allen Poe&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The%20Island%20of%20Dr.%20Moreau">The Island of Dr. Moreau&lt;/a> references you could want (plus some!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man there are some awesome action scenes in this book (which is really a large part about why you read them). Escaping from the castle? Excellent. (Actually the whole castle scene leading up to it was delightfully creepy). Escaping from the island? Even better.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I had vaguely considered giving up on this series after the last few, but this one is more than good enough to keep me going for a while longer. Onward and NUMAward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>White Death</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/31/white-death/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/31/white-death/</guid><description>&lt;p>No one expects the Spanish Inquisition&amp;hellip; or a German expedition to the North Pole? Also, if that weren’t enough, we have Basque independence and frankenfish!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s formulaic as any of these are and the inciting historical events are at once a bit weird&amp;ndash;and not nearly as earth shattering as they often are? This time around, the modern threat is perhaps a bigger one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s really not much more to say about these at this point. If you&amp;rsquo;ve liked the first three (or the whole of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/dirk-pitt/">Dirk Pitt&lt;/a>), you&amp;rsquo;ll probably enjoy this one! If not&amp;hellip; how did you get here?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A weird one to end the year on, but I enjoyed it well enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fire Ice</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/18/fire-ice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/18/fire-ice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another day (week?), another Cussler. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve read this one before, but that&amp;rsquo;s sort of the appeal of all of these books&amp;ndash;some quasihistorical inciting incident (that happens on or near the oceans) then jump to the present time to find the resulting shipwreck and deal with the secret organization (for example) that&amp;rsquo;s trying to RULE THE WORLD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time with more Russia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have the daughters of Nikolai II, last Emperor of Russia&amp;ndash;on the run with all the royal jewels, including one very shiny crown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cut to the modern era, we have a Russian spy who&amp;rsquo;s gone toe to toe with Kurt Austin several times over the years, a manic trying to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/methane%20clathrate">blow up the ocean floor&lt;/a> and cause &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/tsunamis">tsunamis&lt;/a>, and gangs of modern neo-&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cossacks">Cossacks&lt;/a> trying to bring back Mother Russia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s exactly what it says on the tin&amp;ndash;a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/numa-files/">NUMA Files&lt;/a> novel&amp;ndash;and quite the adventure for all that. Formulaic, but a fun listen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blue Gold</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/03/blue-gold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/03/blue-gold/</guid><description>In this century wars will not be fought over oil, as in the past, but over water. The situation is becoming desperate. The world&amp;rsquo;s water is strained by population growth. There is no more fresh water on earth than two thousand years ago when the population was three percent of its current size.
Oof.
Serpent started us down the road of an alternative to Dirk Pitt with the NUMA Files.</description></item><item><title>Serpent</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/25/serpent/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/25/serpent/</guid><description>“Nereus, the Old Man of the Sea,” Nina murmured, cocking her head in thought. “There’s a quote from Hesiod, the Greek poet: ‘A trusty and gentle god who thinks just and kindly thoughts and never lies.”
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve read any Clive Cussler. Turns out there are even a few new Dirk Pitt books I&amp;rsquo;ll have to catch up on. But even then, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t actually read any of his second related series: The NUMA Files.</description></item></channel></rss>