<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NUMA Files on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/numa-files/</link><description>Recent content in NUMA Files on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/numa-files/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fire Ice</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/18/fire-ice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/18/fire-ice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another day (week?), another Cussler. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve read this one before, but that&amp;rsquo;s sort of the appeal of all of these books&amp;ndash;some quasihistorical inciting incident (that happens on or near the oceans) then jump to the present time to find the resulting shipwreck and deal with the secret organization (for example) that&amp;rsquo;s trying to RULE THE WORLD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time with more Russia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have the daughters of Nikolai II, last Emperor of Russia&amp;ndash;on the run with all the royal jewels, including one very shiny crown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cut to the modern era, we have a Russian spy who&amp;rsquo;s gone toe to toe with Kurt Austin several times over the years, a manic trying to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/methane%20clathrate">blow up the ocean floor&lt;/a> and cause &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/tsunamis">tsunamis&lt;/a>, and gangs of modern neo-&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cossacks">Cossacks&lt;/a> trying to bring back Mother Russia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s exactly what it says on the tin&amp;ndash;a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/numa-files/">NUMA Files&lt;/a> novel&amp;ndash;and quite the adventure for all that. Formulaic, but a fun listen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blue Gold</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/03/blue-gold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/03/blue-gold/</guid><description>In this century wars will not be fought over oil, as in the past, but over water. The situation is becoming desperate. The world&amp;rsquo;s water is strained by population growth. There is no more fresh water on earth than two thousand years ago when the population was three percent of its current size.
Oof.
Serpent started us down the road of an alternative to Dirk Pitt with the NUMA Files.</description></item><item><title>Serpent</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/25/serpent/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/25/serpent/</guid><description>“Nereus, the Old Man of the Sea,” Nina murmured, cocking her head in thought. “There’s a quote from Hesiod, the Greek poet: ‘A trusty and gentle god who thinks just and kindly thoughts and never lies.”
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve read any Clive Cussler. Turns out there are even a few new Dirk Pitt books I&amp;rsquo;ll have to catch up on. But even then, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t actually read any of his second related series: The NUMA Files.</description></item></channel></rss>