<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-tv-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-tv-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2022 Year in Reviews</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/31/2022-year-in-reviews/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/31/2022-year-in-reviews/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year&amp;rsquo;s over&amp;hellip; and a new one just begun. In years past, I&amp;rsquo;ve done a seperate post for my &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-reading-retrospective/">2021 Reading Retrospective&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/31/2021-tv-movies-retrospective/">2021 TV &amp;amp; Movies Retrospective&lt;/a>, but&amp;hellip; that seems silly. Let&amp;rsquo;s do them all together this year!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In summary:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>126 total books: 40 graphic novels, 52 audiobooks, and 8 short stories / children&amp;rsquo;s books)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>24 seasons of TV shows&lt;/li>
&lt;li>31 movies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2245 (!) plays across 207 different board games, 88 of them new to me!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>45 different games played on Steam, 29 of them new to me&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I really should add board games and Steam games to my lists. Not sure how to do that though. We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/h2>
&lt;nav id="TableOfContents">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#table-of-contents">Table of Contents&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#books">Books&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#particularly-awesome">Particularly awesome&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#full-list">Full list&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#tv">TV&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#particularly-awesome-1">Particularly awesome&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#full-list-1">Full list&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#movies">Movies&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#particularly-awesome-2">Particularly awesome&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#full-list-ranked">Full list (ranked)&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#board-games">Board Games&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#steam-games">Steam Games&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#summary">Summary&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/nav></description></item><item><title>The Orville: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/30/the-orville-season-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/30/the-orville-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a Star Trek parody that&amp;rsquo;s more Star Trek than most (new) Star Trek. It&amp;rsquo;s got a really rough start while it&amp;rsquo;s still trying to lean into the humor, but as the show goes on and it gets more serious, it&amp;rsquo;s so much better. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to what they can do in season 2!&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="reviews-by-episode">Reviews by Episode&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="1-old-wounds">1. &lt;em>Old Wounds&lt;/em>&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The truth is, you’re nobody’s first choice for this job. We have 3000 ships to staff and we need captains.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Wow. That was an awkward meet and greet. Supposed to be funny and an introduction to the characters I suppose, but… who would possibly think that’s okay?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Arts and crafts meets tardigrade redwood. Hilarious.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trigun</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/07/trigun/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/07/trigun/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No one ever has the right to take the life of another.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But perhaps, sometimes, you do have the responsibility to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So that&amp;hellip; was certainly a show.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s an absolutely fascinating combination of weird anime sci-fi and more than a touch of weird western. There&amp;rsquo;s quite a few memorable characters (some perhaps&amp;hellip; too memorable), some weirdly wonderful worldbuilding and setting moments, and all sorts of gunfights.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I can really recommend it. It started out weird, took a while to make any particular sense, and just when I felt it was getting there&amp;hellip; it ended. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly interesting, I&amp;rsquo;ll give it that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few question I still have after the show (spoilers):&lt;/p>
&lt;span class="spoiler">Where in the world did the names Vash and Millions Knives even come from? They're so different.&lt;/span>
&lt;p>And:&lt;/p>
&lt;span class="spoiler">Who (or what) were the Gung-Ho Guns? Literal demons? Natives? Weird humanity? What's with the vastly differently sized people.&lt;/span></description></item><item><title>She-Hulk: Attorney at Law</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/14/she-hulk-attorney-at-law/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/14/she-hulk-attorney-at-law/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not easy being green.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a strange one. She&amp;rsquo;s the Hulk&amp;rsquo;s cousin. One things lead to another, and she gets all Hulked out&amp;hellip; but without any of the downsides?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The contrast between being a Hulk and being a lawyer (and being a big green lawyer) is pretty cool, Tatiana Maslany does a wonderful job in the titular role, and it was great fun to see Tim Roth&amp;rsquo;s Abomination again, not to mention Charlie Cox&amp;rsquo;s Daredevil. Fun casting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a really weird show. And they&amp;rsquo;re rather solidly into the whoe 4th wall breaking thing, which is kind of amusing. Weird. But amusing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I enjoyed the show. Not my favorite of the MCU TV shows, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have watched it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Boys: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/09/the-boys-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/09/the-boys-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve previously watched the first season and read the comics, but with season 3 out now (and I haven’t reviewed the show previously), let’s watch it again. Should be interesting seeing what’s different this time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wow that&amp;rsquo;s violent. Just as bad if not worse than the comics, since you get to see it all on screen. But in a way that actually has some solid visuals and crazy scenes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shadow and Bone: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/25/shadow-and-bone-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/25/shadow-and-bone-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Saints become martyrs before they get to be heroes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really sure what to expect. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually read the books (although now I really wanted to) and for the first episode or two, I really thought it was some sort of cheesy YA fantasy, a la Hunger Games and the ilk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But a few episodes in&amp;hellip; and it really started to grow on me. The world building is fascinating, primarily the basis on a broad Asian setting, but with an emphasis on Russian roots, with some influences (in other nations) from China and India. The magic system is a bit cheesey and somewhat unexplained (so far), but at the very least it&amp;rsquo;s pretty?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, you have absolutely wonderful characters/actors. Jessie Mei Li nails it as lead Alina Starkov, Ben Barnes as General Kirigan&amp;ndash;plays his character rather well (&lt;span class="spoiler">he actually has the gravitas of old, powerful, and twisted, which not everyone can pull off&lt;/span>
). But the ones that really shine are the Crows (I don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;re referred to as such in the show?): Freddy Carter as Kaz, Amita Suman as Inej and Kit Young as Jesper. There are rumors that they might get their own show and that would be &lt;strong>awesome&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, worth a watch. And we&amp;rsquo;re getting Season 2, hopefully sometime next year? Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Star Wars: Visions</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/05/star-wars-visions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/09/05/star-wars-visions/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating expirment. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who got that made, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad they did. Take Star Wars, give it to a bunch of different Japanese (or Japanese inspired) animators, and make sure that nothing in this will be canon (so you can tell all sorts of stories). There aren&amp;rsquo;t any particularly deep, they&amp;rsquo;re too short for that. But beautiful, oh this series has that in spades.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth a watch!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Am Groot</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/28/i-am-groot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/28/i-am-groot/</guid><description>&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re ~3 minute shorts (with 3+ minutes of credits each) about a young reincarnation of a tree-person who can&amp;rsquo;t talk, other than to say &amp;lsquo;I Am Groot&amp;rsquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I was expecting, but for what they are&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;re cute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth the 15 minutes to watch them all. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fruits Basket: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/27/fruits-basket-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/27/fruits-basket-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I started the second season&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, we do get a bit of backstory with parent issues (oh so many parent issues), the rest of the zodiac (more or less), and some answers about Akito.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, there are piles of weird age issues (I know this is apparently an anime staple; that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it better) and episode after episode dedicated to &amp;hellip; the student council of all things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We made it through 15 episodes of this season. Fin. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fruits Basket: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/26/fruits-basket-season-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/26/fruits-basket-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I expect there are those who really love it, but &amp;hellip; this is not a show for me. I don’t like most of the characters (and &lt;em>really&lt;/em> don’t like some of them), most of the plots are entirely too high school, and the magic of the world/zodiac is criminally underused/explored.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ms. Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ms. Marvel is not particularly earth-shattering. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t deal with the end of the world and only barely with the greater MCU (although there is a decent bit of &amp;lsquo;how the world changes with superheroes in it, like Ant-Man&amp;rsquo;s podcast and Avengercon).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What it is though? A awful lot of fun. Iman Vellani as Kamala Khan is just an absolute delight and really looks like she had a great time in the role. The whole supporting cast is great as well, especially Kamala&amp;rsquo;s family and friends Bruno and Nakia.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Kamala Khan: [whispers] I&amp;rsquo;m a super hero.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[She runs off gleefully]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed this. Especially when it leaned into the Muslim + Pakistani culture and the family dynamics of the whole thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: I don’t need anyone on my side. I’m not even concerned if God is on my side as long as I am on His side. God is always right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Agent Deever: I don’t have time for Quranic quotes. Excuse me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: Actually, that was Abraham Lincoln.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The big fights and greater threats were kind of cheesey and didn&amp;rsquo;t mesh as well (especially the big showpiece in the final episode), but the down to earth human parts of being a teenager superhero? Awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so hard to rank these any more, since there&amp;rsquo;s just so much to love in the MCU. I think Ms. Marvel ends up pretty squarely in the middle of the pack&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;d still say it&amp;rsquo;s worth a watch. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Locke &amp; Key: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/locke-key-season-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/06/08/locke-key-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Daaang things escalated. We&amp;rsquo;ve got more history, more direct interactions with the demons (and slight humanization to them, which is an interesting choice), and more character building with both the family and those around it. Man, I just want to give them all a big hug.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I so very look forward to Season 3! (see the end)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Altered Carbon: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/altered-carbon-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/29/altered-carbon-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s a huge bummer. They swapped out most of the cast, kept one that&amp;hellip; is a weird choice, and mostly changed the entire style of the show. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating choice and I wanted to like it&amp;hellip; but I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t. Made it two episodes in. So it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moon Knight</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/moon-knight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/06/moon-knight/</guid><description>&lt;p>That &amp;hellip; was truly bizarre. A main character with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/dissociative%20identity%20disorder">dissociative identity disorder&lt;/a> where their powers deal with but &lt;em>are not&lt;/em> caused by their disorder is fascinating (and truly weird to be watching at the same time as &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/01/altered-carbon-season-1/">Altered Carbon: Season 1&lt;/a>&amp;hellip;), the Egyptian background and characters are great, and there&amp;rsquo;s are some pretty awesome scenes, fight and otherwise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Castingwise, Oscar Isaac is awesome. I&amp;rsquo;m amazed at how he brings both Marc and Steven to life. Ethan Hawke is a great maybe-baddie-but-maybe-just-a-different-point-of-view. And May Calamawy as Layla El-Faouly is a real stand out in just about everyway. I hope that we get to see more of them in the greater MCU, although I have no idea how that&amp;rsquo;s going to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of which, this was so different from other MCU properties. It&amp;rsquo;s got Egyptian gods and powers more or less walking around, which fits, but I do really wander how/if we&amp;rsquo;d see them or their avatars square off against normal MCU level heroes. Tonally, it&amp;rsquo;s rather different too. There&amp;rsquo;s still an end of the world threat, but a lot of it&amp;rsquo;s dealing with the internal struggles of Steven/Marc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s probably my favorite of the MCU TV shows so far&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll have to rewatch it and see if it holds up. It&amp;rsquo;s really quite good.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Altered Carbon: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/01/altered-carbon-season-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/05/01/altered-carbon-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>That is a spectacular show. In a nutshell, it takes a cyberpunk future world where the technology exists to separate the &amp;lsquo;mind&amp;rsquo;/stack/DHF of a person from their body/sleeve. Really, it&amp;rsquo;s primarily a tool for the wealthy to accumulate even more wealth and a number of the characters mention that we aren&amp;rsquo;t meant to live forever&amp;hellip; And that actually made me think. It&amp;rsquo;s been something I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought would be neat: to be able to repair or move into another body if this is damaged, to send me mind to other worlds, etc. But how in the world would people react to that sort of power and change?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the very least, let&amp;rsquo;s hope it&amp;rsquo;s better than what we see in Altered Carbon. Hoo boy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s part detective show that segues into murder/revenge/revolution plots with more than a dash of questions around identity in a world where bodies are quite literally and easily (if not cheaply) replaceable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of rather graphic violence and nudity, but for the most part it makes sense within the context of the show. Certainly not one for the kids though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The casting, I loved. Joel Kinnaman as Takeshi Kovacs nails the &amp;lsquo;Envoy brought back&amp;rsquo;, Dichen Lachman as Reileen Kawahara is a wonderful &lt;span class="spoiler">example of long lives corrupting people&lt;/span>
. My surprise favorite? Chris Conner as &amp;lsquo;Poe&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the AI running an Edgar Allen Poe themed hotel that hasn&amp;rsquo;t seen a guest in years/decades. He&amp;rsquo;s such a surprisingly wonderful character.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s quite a spectacular show. Well worth the watch. Now the confusing it&amp;hellip; &lt;span class="spoiler">apparently almost the entire cast was replaced for S2?&lt;/span>
It&amp;rsquo;s something that the concept of the show certainly allows, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know how in the world they&amp;rsquo;re going to pull that one off. I guess we&amp;rsquo;ll see!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Locke &amp; Key: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/19/locke-key-season-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/19/locke-key-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>I really enjoyed the &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/23/locke-key-vol.-1-welcome-to-lovecraft/">Locke &amp;amp; Key graphic novels&lt;/a>, so of course I had to give the TV show a try. Turns out: also really good. While they changed a few things with the details of how the keys worked that are probably more efficient to do in TV (not opening the tops of people&amp;rsquo;s heads for instance), it&amp;rsquo;s still got the same wonderfully creepy dark magical vibe. I do love the actors&amp;ndash;Bode in particular does his part very well, as do his siblings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a crazy show. Well worth the show (warning, it is dark, although not overly graphic). On to season 2!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 6</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/17/schitts-creek-season-6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/17/schitts-creek-season-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends. As expected, David and Patrick&amp;rsquo;s wedding is a big storyline (and man David is neurotic when stressed), but we also have Alexis continuing to grow in relationships and work (which is such an amazing growth from Season 1), the whole hotel starting to grow (rapidly) and Moira doing Moira things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a good way to end the show. We have some ending up moving back to the lives they once had, hopefully a little more self aware (I doubt so in Moira&amp;rsquo;s case&amp;hellip;) from their time in Schitt&amp;rsquo;s Creek.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not a show I normally would have chosen, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have watched it. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 5</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/01/schitts-creek-season-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/03/01/schitts-creek-season-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>Moira gets a chance to do what she loves&amp;ndash;and is as Moira about it the entire season as possible. So much David and Patrick, which is great. Alexis is really growing, which is awesome&amp;ndash;she has a ways to go yet though. Also Stevie gets a few moments to shine, she&amp;rsquo;s really the surprise soul of this series in a lot of ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Only one more season!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Umbrella Academy: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/28/the-umbrella-academy-season-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/28/the-umbrella-academy-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was quite a continuation. Out of one apocalypse and right into another. This time in the 1960s!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a neat concept and gives the characters a bit more time to grow&amp;ndash;while at the same time the viewers know there&amp;rsquo;s quite the timeline. And with time travel&amp;hellip; you can kill people off and still have to deal with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also instead of Hazel and Cha-Chat, you have three Swedish brothers (less amusing, far more terrifying).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I quite enjoyed it. And there&amp;rsquo;s still &lt;em>plenty&lt;/em> of room left for Season 3. A quick search shows February 2022&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m going to go with a probably not on that. But still soon!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/20/schitts-creek-season-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/20/schitts-creek-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p>Death and pregnancy; the Rose children growing up, Johnny finally has something to do, and Moira is&amp;hellip; Moira. Oy&amp;ndash;ra.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a bit amused that we got the pregnancy storyline &lt;span class="spoiler">without Jocelyn's actress even being pregnant IRL; I feel like that's the more common reason to work in something like this. It works though!&lt;/span>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A fun season. Onward we barrel towards the end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Umbrella Academy: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/17/the-umbrella-academy-season-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/17/the-umbrella-academy-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>On the 12th hour of the first day of October 1989, 43 women around the world gave birth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was unusual only in the fact that none of these women had been pregnant when the day first began.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sir Reginald Hargreeves, eccentric billionaire and adventurer, resolved to locate and adopt as many of the children as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh that&amp;rsquo;s quite a show. After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/11/23/the-umbrella-academy-vol.-1-the-apocalypse-suite/">reading through the graphic novels&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s a rather different experience. The core is the same, even if details are a bit different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Colm Feore as Reginald Hargreeves is my favorite casting. He reminds me as Michael Douglas as Dr. Hank Pym in Ant-Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward to season 2!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/08/schitts-creek-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/08/schitts-creek-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s really picking up now! I&amp;rsquo;m actually starting to really enjoy the relationships between the characters. David is still my favorite, but Alexis ia really growing on me. And I still don&amp;rsquo;t care much for Moira.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The entire idea of David not having a (valid) driver&amp;rsquo;s license or Alexis never having graduated High School because rich/reasons&amp;hellip; actually makes a lot of sense. But Alexis actually &lt;em>going&lt;/em> to High School? In what universe would that happen&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s what GEDs are for. Really pulled me out of the plotline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, an enjoyable enough season. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how quickly shows with shorter episodes go by&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/30/schitts-creek-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/30/schitts-creek-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Much better than season 1! It&amp;rsquo;s still cringe, but at least David is trying, Alexis is failing, and their parents are&amp;hellip; surviving?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I appreciate about this season is how the rest of the cast is getting slightly less caricaturish. Roland is still full on Roland, but Jocelyn is really growing into a good person who&amp;rsquo;s still perfectly fine at snarking at the Rose&amp;rsquo;s. Even Bob is starting to fire back. Makes the town council &amp;lsquo;main plot&amp;rsquo; amusing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still a very quick watch. Onward to season 3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/24/schitts-creek-season-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/24/schitts-creek-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tonally&amp;hellip; &lt;em>very&lt;/em> different from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/18/mr.-robot-season-4/">Mr. Robot&lt;/a>. Bit of whiplash from that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, a rich family loses everything&amp;hellip; but the town they bought for a joke (see? rich). Now they have to go live there, with the overblown locals. A whole new way of life to learn and all the hilarious complications that come from that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not the kind of show that I usually like, since it&amp;rsquo;s just so &amp;hellip; cringey/awkward. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to watch people lose everything and just seem so &amp;hellip; bad at being human. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know anyone in that income bracket or especially anyone that&amp;rsquo;s lost so much. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any easier to believe. They&amp;rsquo;re each quick watches at around 20 minutes though. That&amp;rsquo;s something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, there are a number of really funny moments in there. David is great, Stevie is great. Johnny&amp;ndash;I can&amp;rsquo;t get American Pie out of my head. Alexis and especially Moira aren&amp;rsquo;t great, but so it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth giving a few episodes a try. It gets better throughout the season.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Arcane</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/23/arcane/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/23/arcane/</guid><description>&lt;p>That is an absolutely beautiful delight of a show. I love the asthetic/worldbuilding, with a mix of steampunk/magic plus a major cyberpunk visual style. It&amp;rsquo;s something that I really could do with some more of and the animated style &lt;em>really&lt;/em> lends itself nicely to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, there&amp;rsquo;s a mix of a few different plots (family troubles, class war, magic versus tech, corruption in politics / power corrupts) that each work by themselves, but are particularly good when you get crossovers. Class war and politics complicated by magic versus tech. (Found and blood) family troubles through it all. Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the worst part of it all? It ended! And now I have to wait for Season 2!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth a watch.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>