<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-tv-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 TV Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2022-tv-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/20/schitts-creek-season-4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/20/schitts-creek-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/schitts-creek-season-4.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Death pregnancy; the Rose children growing up, Johnny finally has something to do, and Moira is&amp;hellip; Moira. Oy&amp;ndash;ra.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a bit amused that we got the pregnancy storyline &lt;span class="spoiler">without Jocelyn's actress even being pregnant IRL; I feel like that's the more common reason to work in something like this. It works though!&lt;/span>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A fun season. Onward we barrel towards the end.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Umbrella Academy: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/17/the-umbrella-academy-season-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/17/the-umbrella-academy-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/umbrella-academy-1.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>On the 12th hour of the first day of October 1989, 43 women around the world gave birth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was unusual only in the fact that none of these women had been pregnant when the day first began.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sir Reginald Hargreeves, eccentric billionaire and adventurer, resolved to locate and adopt as many of the children as possible.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh that&amp;rsquo;s quite a show. After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/11/23/the-umbrella-academy-vol.-1-the-apocalypse-suite/">reading through the graphic novels&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s a rather different experience. The core is the same, even if details are a bit different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Colm Feore as Reginald Hargreeves is my favorite casting. He reminds me as Michael Douglas as Dr. Hank Pym in Ant-Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward to season 2!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/08/schitts-creek-season-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/08/schitts-creek-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/schitts-creek-season-3.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s really picking up now! I&amp;rsquo;m actually starting to really enjoy the relationships between the characters. David is still my favorite, but Alexis ia really growing on me. And I still don&amp;rsquo;t care much for Moira.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The entire idea of David not having a (valid) driver&amp;rsquo;s license or Alexis never having graduated High School because rich/reasons&amp;hellip; actually makes a lot of sense. But Alexis actually &lt;em>going&lt;/em> to High School? In what universe would that happen&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s what GEDs are for. Really pulled me out of the plotline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Other than that, an enjoyable enough season. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how quickly shows with shorter episodes go by&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/30/schitts-creek-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/30/schitts-creek-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/schitts-creek-season-2.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Much better than season 1! It&amp;rsquo;s still cringe, but at least David is trying, Alexis is failing, and their parents are&amp;hellip; surviving?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing I appreciate about this season is how the rest of the cast is getting slightly less caricaturish. Roland is still full on Roland, but Jocelyn is really growing into a good person who&amp;rsquo;s still perfectly fine at snarking at the Rose&amp;rsquo;s. Even Bob is starting to fire back. Makes the town council &amp;lsquo;main plot&amp;rsquo; amusing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still a very quick watch. Onward to season 3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Schitt's Creek: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/24/schitts-creek-season-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/24/schitts-creek-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/schitts-creek-season-1.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Tonally&amp;hellip; &lt;em>very&lt;/em> different from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/18/mr.-robot-season-4/">Mr. Robot&lt;/a>. Bit of whiplash from that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, a rich family loses everything&amp;hellip; but the town they bought for a joke (see? rich). Now they have to go live there, with the overblown locals. A whole new way of life to learn and all the hilarious complications that come from that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not the kind of show that I usually like, since it&amp;rsquo;s just so &amp;hellip; cringey/awkward. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to watch people lose everything and just seem so &amp;hellip; bad at being human. I don&amp;rsquo;t really know anyone in that income bracket or especially anyone that&amp;rsquo;s lost so much. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any easier to believe. They&amp;rsquo;re each quick watches at around 20 minutes though. That&amp;rsquo;s something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, there are a number of really funny moments in there. David is great, Stevie is great. Johnny&amp;ndash;I can&amp;rsquo;t get American Pie out of my head. Alexis and especially Moira aren&amp;rsquo;t great, but so it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth giving a few episodes a try. It gets better throughout the season.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Arcane</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/23/arcane/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/23/arcane/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/tv/arcane.jpg"/>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>That is an absolutely beautiful delight of a show. I love the asthetic/worldbuilding, with a mix of steampunk/magic plus a major cyberpunk visual style. It&amp;rsquo;s something that I really could do with some more of and the animated style &lt;em>really&lt;/em> lends itself nicely to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, there&amp;rsquo;s a mix of a few different plots (family troubles, class war, magic versus tech, corruption in politics / power corrupts) that each work by themselves, but are particularly good when you get crossovers. Class war and politics complicated by magic versus tech. (Found and blood) family troubles through it all. Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the worst part of it all? It ended! And now I have to wait for Season 2!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth a watch.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>