<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Marie Brennan on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/marie-brennan/</link><description>Recent content in Marie Brennan on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/marie-brennan/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Voyage of the Basilisk</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/07/the-voyage-of-the-basilisk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/04/07/the-voyage-of-the-basilisk/</guid><description>&lt;p>The third book of [[The Memoirs of Lady Trent]]. First she went to studing dragons in rocky mountanious islands&amp;ndash;and almost died. And then she spent some time studying river dragons deep in the jungle&amp;ndash;and almost died.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now she&amp;rsquo;s off on a voyage around the world&amp;ndash;akin to Darwin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voyage%20of%20the%20Beagle">Voyage of the Beagle&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;to study dragons. Only to almost die not once, not twice, but at least three times. Assuming I didn&amp;rsquo;t miss any.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and have all manner of other adventures along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“I have never attempted to hide that I have had two husbands in my life. I have, however, neglected to mention that in between them, I had a wife.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In &lt;em>any&lt;/em> case.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“That should be my epitaph when I die: &amp;lsquo;she did not have to do it&amp;rsquo;.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m still loving riding along with the titular Lady Trent on her adventures and learning all about how dragons work in this world right along with her. And this time, she&amp;rsquo;s actually bringing her son along, which gives a whole new dimension to the journeys&amp;ndash;for the most part.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A fun book. I expect if you&amp;rsquo;ll like the first two, you&amp;rsquo;ll continue to enjoy this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Tropic of Serpents</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/23/the-tropic-of-serpents/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/03/23/the-tropic-of-serpents/</guid><description>A Natural History of Dragons set out an interesting world. It&amp;rsquo;s more or less our world (although with all the names rewritten, so you&amp;rsquo;re always playing a game so is &amp;lsquo;xxx&amp;rsquo; just like &amp;lsquo;yyy&amp;rsquo;), but with dragons. And of course the titular Isabela Trent just wants to study them, like any Natural Historian would!
Give me dragons any day; I understand their ways far better than those of my fellow human beings.</description></item><item><title>A Natural History of Dragons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/29/a-natural-history-of-dragons/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/29/a-natural-history-of-dragons/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s not really at all the sort of book I expected, but I ended up quite enjoying it.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I believed myself to be ready then; now, with the hindsight brought by greater age, I see myself for the naive and inexperienced young woman I was. We all begin in such a manner, though. There is no quick route to experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s a roughly Victorian period piece (feels fairly like Downton Abbey for the rough time period and most recent media I&amp;rsquo;ve experience with) in a secondary world that strongly echoes our own with some new names and one big difference&amp;ndash;dragons!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>