<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2022/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2022/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/29/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/29/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. That&amp;rsquo;s what what you get if you take a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/directors/sam-raimi">director best known for his horror movies&lt;/a>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and let them loose in the MCU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like it. 😄&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ms. Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ms. Marvel is not particularly earth-shattering. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t deal with the end of the world and only barely with the greater MCU (although there is a decent bit of &amp;lsquo;how the world changes with superheroes in it, like Ant-Man&amp;rsquo;s podcast and Avengercon).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What it is though? A awful lot of fun. Iman Vellani as Kamala Khan is just an absolute delight and really looks like she had a great time in the role. The whole supporting cast is great as well, especially Kamala&amp;rsquo;s family and friends Bruno and Nakia.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Kamala Khan: [whispers] I&amp;rsquo;m a super hero.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[She runs off gleefully]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed this. Especially when it leaned into the Muslim + Pakistani culture and the family dynamics of the whole thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: I don’t need anyone on my side. I’m not even concerned if God is on my side as long as I am on His side. God is always right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Agent Deever: I don’t have time for Quranic quotes. Excuse me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: Actually, that was Abraham Lincoln.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The big fights and greater threats were kind of cheesey and didn&amp;rsquo;t mesh as well (especially the big showpiece in the final episode), but the down to earth human parts of being a teenager superhero? Awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so hard to rank these any more, since there&amp;rsquo;s just so much to love in the MCU. I think Ms. Marvel ends up pretty squarely in the middle of the pack&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;d still say it&amp;rsquo;s worth a watch. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>