<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2022/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2022/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>She-Hulk: Attorney at Law</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/14/she-hulk-attorney-at-law/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/10/14/she-hulk-attorney-at-law/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not easy being green.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s a strange one. She&amp;rsquo;s the Hulk&amp;rsquo;s cousin. One things lead to another, and she gets all Hulked out&amp;hellip; but without any of the downsides?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The contrast between being a Hulk and being a lawyer (and being a big green lawyer) is pretty cool, Tatiana Maslany does a wonderful job in the titular role, and it was great fun to see Tim Roth&amp;rsquo;s Abomination again, not to mention Charlie Cox&amp;rsquo;s Daredevil. Fun casting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, it&amp;rsquo;s a really weird show. And they&amp;rsquo;re rather solidly into the whoe 4th wall breaking thing, which is kind of amusing. Weird. But amusing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I enjoyed the show. Not my favorite of the MCU TV shows, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have watched it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Am Groot</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/28/i-am-groot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/28/i-am-groot/</guid><description>&lt;p>They&amp;rsquo;re ~3 minute shorts (with 3+ minutes of credits each) about a young reincarnation of a tree-person who can&amp;rsquo;t talk, other than to say &amp;lsquo;I Am Groot&amp;rsquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what I was expecting, but for what they are&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;re cute.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worth the 15 minutes to watch them all. :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Everything Everywhere All at Once</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/23/everything-everywhere-all-at-once/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/08/23/everything-everywhere-all-at-once/</guid><description>&lt;p>Laundry and taxes. Hotdog fingers and Raccacoonie. Googly third eyes and sex toy fueled kung fu fights. The truest &lt;em>everything&lt;/em> bagel there ever was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well that was a delightfully &lt;em>weird&lt;/em> movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If anything at all of that sounds interesting (especially the &lt;em>weird&lt;/em> part) and you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen this movie yet, go see it. Don&amp;rsquo;t spoil it. I&amp;rsquo;ll wait.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thor: Love and Thunder</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/31/thor-love-and-thunder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/31/thor-love-and-thunder/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/28/thor/">Thor&lt;/a> was probably the most underwhelming of Phase 1, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/12/thor-the-dark-world/">Thor: The Dark World&lt;/a> tried to go more fantasy and was mostly forgettable, and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/16/thor-ragnarok/">Thor: Ragnarok&lt;/a> was a blast. Getting better all the time, so &amp;hellip; what about &lt;em>Thor: Love and Thunder&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good question. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to love about the movie: Hemsworth&amp;rsquo;s sense of humor, Portman back and then some, Thompson&amp;rsquo;s awesome and slightly awkward Valkyrie. And of course Bale plays a solidly terrifying baddy in Gorr.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, there is a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of movie to get through here, probably more than a bit too much. A cancer plot, succession jealousy, a threat spanning across the Galaxy (or at least the gods thereof)&amp;ndash;heck, the idea that gods are just &lt;em>a thing&lt;/em> now, Thor unpacking even more trauma. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot to put into a single movie and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>quite&lt;/em> work. It&amp;rsquo;s still a solid enough flick, but not nearly up to what &lt;em>Ragnarok&lt;/em> did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, pretty impressive for the first 4th solo outing in the MCU. Because that&amp;rsquo;s a thing we can say now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/29/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/29/doctor-strange-in-the-multiverse-of-madness/</guid><description>&lt;p>So. That&amp;rsquo;s what what you get if you take a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/directors/sam-raimi">director best known for his horror movies&lt;/a>&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and let them loose in the MCU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like it. 😄&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ms. Marvel</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/07/23/ms.-marvel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ms. Marvel is not particularly earth-shattering. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t deal with the end of the world and only barely with the greater MCU (although there is a decent bit of &amp;lsquo;how the world changes with superheroes in it, like Ant-Man&amp;rsquo;s podcast and Avengercon).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What it is though? A awful lot of fun. Iman Vellani as Kamala Khan is just an absolute delight and really looks like she had a great time in the role. The whole supporting cast is great as well, especially Kamala&amp;rsquo;s family and friends Bruno and Nakia.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Kamala Khan: [whispers] I&amp;rsquo;m a super hero.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[She runs off gleefully]&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I really enjoyed this. Especially when it leaned into the Muslim + Pakistani culture and the family dynamics of the whole thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: I don’t need anyone on my side. I’m not even concerned if God is on my side as long as I am on His side. God is always right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Agent Deever: I don’t have time for Quranic quotes. Excuse me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sheikh Abdullah: Actually, that was Abraham Lincoln.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The big fights and greater threats were kind of cheesey and didn&amp;rsquo;t mesh as well (especially the big showpiece in the final episode), but the down to earth human parts of being a teenager superhero? Awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s so hard to rank these any more, since there&amp;rsquo;s just so much to love in the MCU. I think Ms. Marvel ends up pretty squarely in the middle of the pack&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;d still say it&amp;rsquo;s worth a watch. Onward.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>