<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interpreters on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/programming/topics/interpreters/</link><description>Recent content in Interpreters on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/programming/topics/interpreters/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CodeCrafters: Build Myself an Interpreter</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/04/codecrafters-build-myself-an-interpreter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/09/04/codecrafters-build-myself-an-interpreter/</guid><description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t I just do one of these? Well, yes. Yes I did. But I love building compilers and interpreters, so when I saw this one was in beta (and thus free 😉), I had to try it!
It&amp;rsquo;s directly an implemention of the Lox languages from the Crafting Interpreters website / book (my review), if incomplete. By the end of the lesson, we&amp;rsquo;ll have:
A tokenizer that handles parentheses, braces, operators (single and multiple character), whitespace, identifiers, string literals, numeric literals, and keywords A parser that can take those tokens and build an abstract syntax tree using recursive descent parsing A simple tree walking interpreter for some subset of the language It doesn&amp;rsquo;t handle all of the syntax (yet).</description></item><item><title>CodeCrafters: Build Myself a Grep</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/28/codecrafters-build-myself-a-grep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/08/28/codecrafters-build-myself-a-grep/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently stumbled across &lt;a href="https://codecrafters.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CodeCrafters&lt;/a> again&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. In a nutshell, they give a number of &amp;lsquo;Build Your Own&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; courses, each of which will automatically create a repo for you, guide you through solving the program step by step, and provide some feedback on the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a freemium (one problem a month is free) / paid service. I wish they had tiers. I really think their monthly fee is a bit steep for what they offer (we&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that). But on the other hand, it&amp;rsquo;s a neat tool and I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting some more larger programming projects to learn more Rust on, so away we go!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First up, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/grep">grep&lt;/a>!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>