<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Libba Bray on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/22/libba-bray/</link><description>Recent content in Libba Bray on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/22/libba-bray/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Sweet Far Thing</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/22/the-sweet-far-thing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/06/22/the-sweet-far-thing/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>With a sigh, I resign myself to combing through it page by page, though 502
pages is so many to wade through, and I curse authors who write such lengthy
books when a few neat pages of prose would do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; Roughly halfway through a nearly 1000 page book&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Rebel Angels</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/14/rebel-angels/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/05/14/rebel-angels/</guid><description>&lt;p>Goodness. That&amp;rsquo;s quite a story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/11/a-great-and-terrible-beauty/">A Great and Terrible Beauty&lt;/a> primarily focused around the boarding school life with hints of a relatively benign magic (with a fair few hints of darkness under the surface), Rebel Angels expands the world both to the greater society of the time and delves much deeper into the dark, creepy bits of the Realms&amp;ndash;not the least of which is Pippa. Dead&amp;hellip; but not? It&amp;rsquo;s a way to deal with loss, but there&amp;rsquo;s no way this is possible going to end well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Great and Terrible Beauty</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/11/a-great-and-terrible-beauty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/11/a-great-and-terrible-beauty/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Shall I tell you a story? A new and terrible one? A ghost story? Are you
ready? Shall I begin? Once upon a time there were four girls. One was
pretty. One was clever. One charming, and one&amp;hellip;one was mysterious. But they
were all damaged, you see. Something not right about the lot of them.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That was not at all what I expected. Granted, I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect much. I&amp;rsquo;ve had this book on my to read list for years and decided to finally try it without looking at anything but the cover. Instead, we got a slow building paranormal boarding school / historic urban fantasy set in around the turn of the 20th century with a portal fantasy turned surprisingly dark.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>