<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2024 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2024/</link><description>Recent content in 2024 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2024/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wicked</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/23/wicked/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/23/wicked/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Munchkinland Kid: But, Miss Glinda?&lt;br>
Glinda: Yes?&lt;br>
Munchkinland Kid: Why does wickedness happen?&lt;br>
Glinda: That&amp;rsquo;s a good question, one many people find confusifying. Are people born wicked? Or do they have wickedness thrust upon them? After all, The Wicked Witch had a childhood. She had a father, who, by the way, had been appointed governor of Munchkinland. And she had a mother, as so many do.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The story of the Wicked Witch of the West (who wasn&amp;rsquo;t always so Wicked), her time at university (which, for some reason, is called Shiz), and her unlikely friendship with Galinda (before she was Glinda).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s basically the Broadway play writ silver screen and you know, it actually works pretty well. There is room for a lot of visuals you can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>really&lt;/em> pull off on a stage, along with some face work and camera shots likewise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Storywise, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly classic (at this point), &amp;lsquo;what if the villan wasn&amp;rsquo;t evil, how did they get here?&amp;rsquo; sort of story.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Fiyero: I&amp;rsquo;ll say this much, she doesn&amp;rsquo;t give a twig what anyone thinks.
Glinda: Of course she does. She just pretends not to.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Mix all that with a sassy Elphaba (who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be the Wicked one) and a somewhat clueless entirely self centered Glinda (who&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be the Good one)&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Elphaba: Fine, let&amp;rsquo;s get this over with: no, I am not seasick; no, I did not eat grass as a child; and yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been green.&lt;br>
Glinda: Well, I, for one, am&amp;hellip; So sorry, that you have been forced to live with&amp;hellip; this.&lt;br>
Elphaba: Is that so?&lt;br>
Glinda: Yes! And it is my intention to major in sorcery. So, if at some point, you wanted to address the, um&amp;hellip; Problem&amp;hellip;&lt;br>
Elphaba: Problem.&lt;br>
Glinda: &amp;hellip; perhaps I could help.&lt;br>
[the whole Shiz students clap and praise her, while Elphaba analyzes the reaction]&lt;br>
Elphaba: Offering to help someone that you don&amp;rsquo;t know with skills that you don&amp;rsquo;t have, I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone is duly impressed.&lt;br>
Glinda: I could care less what others think.&lt;br>
Elphaba: Couldn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;br>
Glinda: What?&lt;br>
Elphaba: You couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less what other people think. Though, I&amp;hellip; I doubt that.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t really expect anything new and interesting, but it&amp;rsquo;s solidly done. And hey, some great songs!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And best of all? By finally watching it now, part 2 is already out. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dune: Part Two</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/03/dune-part-two/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/03/dune-part-two/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You are not prepared for what is to come.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Dune: Part Two is a lot like &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/20/dune-movie/">the first half&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s visually stunning and there are some intense scenes&amp;hellip; but it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a complete movie, even if this one actually does have a decent ending compared to the first. On to part 3 I suppose!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Scenewise, I love seeing the deserts. The sandworms. The Fremen&amp;rsquo;s homes in the sand.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moana 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/16/moana-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/08/16/moana-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Moana 2! Now with more &amp;rsquo;this was supposed to be a TV show'.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So basically, we have the introduction&amp;ndash;oh how great was the first Moana?!&amp;ndash;, the baby sister, the quest&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, collecting the party and heading out, a series of semi-connected adventures, the fake out failure, and the season finale.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moana 2 was apparently supposed to be a TV show and&amp;hellip; in a lot of ways, it shows? The film has the feel of a bunch of plot lines one after another, none particularly given room to breathe (or dopped entirely) and only a bit related. Which&amp;hellip; is exactly how TV shows are structured.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Agatha All Along</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/21/agatha-all-along/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/21/agatha-all-along/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh that was a delight. Take Agatha (and the general fallout of her created world) from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/03/19/wandavision/">WandaVision&lt;/a>, turn up the witchiness, and go on a magical mystical, somewhat terrifying adventure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating story and, honestly, if you would have left out a few scenes it would have worked perfectly well completely outside of the Marvel Cinematic Universe as well. And at this point, that&amp;rsquo;s a strong point in its favor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man Kathryn Hawn does great in this. I loved the supporting witch cast, especially Aubrey Plaza. She does unsettling and off kilter so well. And Teen&amp;ndash;he was an interesting counterpoint. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure about the worldbuilding around either Rio (Plaza) or Teen (Locke), those parts felt weird, but the actors were awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course&amp;hellip; &lt;strong>the song&lt;/strong> (I don&amp;rsquo;t see this version as spoilers, but some might).&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VnjYeJ5blxo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>Man that song has been stuck in my head for weeks now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I personally would have dropped the last half of the last episode, the penultimate really works better as a conclusion. This really doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a sequel (although apparently there will be a third show as a &amp;lsquo;TV trilogy&amp;rsquo; sort of thing?), but so it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Man on the Inside</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/05/a-man-on-the-inside/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/02/05/a-man-on-the-inside/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was a fun show. Created by the Michael Schur (who also did the Good Place, check it out!) and with many overlapping cast members from the Good Place, I had high hopes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I learned that it was about a man learning to live in an assisted living center, I &amp;hellip; wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure. Was there a supernatural element?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then when it dropped (in the first episode and all the promotional materials, so I don&amp;rsquo;t see it as a spoiler) that he&amp;rsquo;s going in to assisted living as a SPY! Well, I&amp;rsquo;m intriuged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fun show, hilarious at times (especially with just how &lt;em>bad&lt;/em> Charles is at all this) and sad at others (it&amp;rsquo;s about old folks. Death, loneliness, and memory loss are just part of it). But it&amp;rsquo;s quite the ride all the way through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do love the cast, Ted Danson as Charles is amazing. I enjoyed Mary Elizabeth Ellis
as his daughter Emily, even if her family troubles were a weird B plot. Lilah Richcreek Estrada as Julie did &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to solve this problem whatever it takes&amp;rsquo; wonderfully, and it was fascinating to see Stephanie Beatriz as head of staff Didi. I really need to watch Brooklyn Nine-Nine at some point&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then all of the old folks inhabiting those halls&amp;hellip; Man those were some performances. I honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize any of them from other roles but I expect there are some well known names in there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a wonderful show and goes by quick. Well worth the watch!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Rings of Power: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/14/the-rings-of-power-season-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/14/the-rings-of-power-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are &lt;em>way&lt;/em> too many storylines in this show. For episodes at a time, we may not see elves. Or dwarves. Or Gandalf-but-still-not-Gandalf. I keep getting to the start of an episode and thinking &amp;lsquo;oh hey, we haven&amp;rsquo;t seen them in a while&amp;rsquo;. But the interesting thing is that I got to the end of the episodes!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s what we saw in the first season, but even more so. There are so many different threads and events&amp;ndash;things separated by decades if not centuries in the original works all crammed together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But on the other hand, we get more rings! (Up from zero &amp;#x1f604;) We get bigger battles! (Not quite Helm&amp;rsquo;s Deep, but close) More Tom Bombadil! (You&amp;rsquo;ll just have to watch to see if you think I&amp;rsquo;m making that one up) And we get more &amp;hellip; humanized orcs with families and children? I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;hellip; not entirely sure what to think about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall&amp;hellip; it mostly reminds me just &lt;em>good&lt;/em> the Peter Jackson movies were. But it&amp;rsquo;s certainly watchable and I&amp;rsquo;ll catch whatever season(s) come next. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadpool &amp; Wolverine</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/02/deadpool-wolverine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/02/deadpool-wolverine/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so here it is, (almost) the entire reason I rewatched &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/deadpool/">Deadpool&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/28/deadpool-2/">Deadpool 2&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much exactly what you get if you took the (crass) humor of Deadpool, jammed in as many cameos as you could, and shoved it into the modern &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/marvel-cinematic-universe/">MCU&lt;/a>, multiverse, TVA, and all&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Deadpool: Welcome to the MCU. You&amp;rsquo;re joining at a bit of a low point.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m still not &lt;em>actually&lt;/em> sure if that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>