<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>David Farland on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/david-farland/</link><description>Recent content in David Farland on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/david-farland/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Wyrmling Horde</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/the-wyrmling-horde/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/02/04/the-wyrmling-horde/</guid><description>I think that for the most part The Wyrmling Horde takes everything I mentioned in Worldbinder and does a bit more of that. There are some really fascinating worldbuilding ideas being explored here, although I miss the smaller scope of just the Endowments and possibly the wizards of the early books. The characters are cool&amp;ndash;and I do actually find the inversions of several of them fascinating&amp;ndash;but we&amp;rsquo;re also missing a few faces that I really wish we would see more of.</description></item><item><title>Worldbinder</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/14/worldbinder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/12/14/worldbinder/</guid><description>Where Sons of the Oak could arguably considered a continuation of the first four books, what with references and plots revolving around the Earth King and his wife and a focus on Borenson, Myrrima, and their children, now in Worldbinder we&amp;rsquo;re really getting into the changes&amp;ndash;and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;m okay with that.
For one, the first real &amp;lsquo;binding of worlds&amp;rsquo; happens fairly early in the book. In a nutshell, that means that any character alive in both worlds is now a mix of memories, experiences, et al of both characters, while those only in one are initially weaker for it.</description></item><item><title>Sons of the Oak</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/sons-of-the-oak/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/18/sons-of-the-oak/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sons of the Oak is an odd one. After saving the world in Lair of Bones, Gaborn and Iome are loaded with enough metabolism to curse them to die in the next few years&amp;ndash;which ends up happening relatively early on. That of course leaves a power vacuum. There are those who would love to see the Earth King&amp;rsquo;s son take the crown&amp;ndash;and just as many who&amp;rsquo;d rather see him dead and take power of their on. On top of that, there&amp;rsquo;s a whole new level of darkness in the world. From Loci to strengi-saats, it&amp;rsquo;s an ever darkening world, with the Torch of Humanity having been passed down to the next generation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve actually finished this book before. The time skip made it hard to read and I just moved on. But this time around, I&amp;rsquo;ve actually really enjoyed it. We&amp;rsquo;ll have to see how it continues. I think reading it as an audiobook has helped. It just keeps going unless you actually stop rather than stopping unless you push on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Lair of Bones</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/04/the-lair-of-bones/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/11/04/the-lair-of-bones/</guid><description>The Lair of Bones is an epic and fitting conclusion1 to the Runeslords saga. It takes the story of Gaborn and Raj Ahten, of Runelords and reavers, of elemental powers and far darker things, and brings it all together in a series of rather epic journeys and battles, culminating with an epic&amp;ndash;if bittersweet&amp;ndash;victory of light over dark, of good over evil.
Or does it?
Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a solid conclusion and I quite enjoyed it.</description></item><item><title>Wizardborn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/16/wizardborn/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/09/16/wizardborn/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man these stories keep escalating. It&amp;rsquo;s really kind of impressive. From the story of a powerful invading lord to bugs from the depths of the Earth to dark magic, super powerful evil beings from another world, and perhaps even worse&amp;hellip; Man there&amp;rsquo;s a lot here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On top of that, we&amp;rsquo;re digging a lot more into the various magic systems of this universe. Averan is &lt;span class="spoiler">Earth Wizardborn and can eat the brains of Reavers to learn from them&lt;/span>
, which gives us a much better idea of how the Revears work internally. We&amp;rsquo;re seeing a lot more about the Air powers, along with the continued Earth (Gaborn) and Fire (Raj Ahten). Even Water, although that&amp;rsquo;s a bit more subtle thus far (which fits).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brotherhood of the Wolf</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/26/brotherhood-of-the-wolf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/26/brotherhood-of-the-wolf/</guid><description>&lt;p>Wooo boy things ramp up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/25/the-runelords/">The Runelords&lt;/a>, with the invasion by uber powerful Raj Ahtan, finally driven off by the rise of Earth King Gaborn, it was hard to believe that we could ramp up even far. Now Gaborn is coming into his powers, while Raj Ahtan has to figure out how to strike back and/or regroup.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Runelords</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/25/the-runelords/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/25/the-runelords/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A wise king does not garner all wit, instead he also allows his cunselors to
be wise.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I last read the first few books of the Runelords probably more than a decade ago. I forgot how &lt;em>good&lt;/em> these books are.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>