<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jeff VanderMeer on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/jeff-vandermeer/</link><description>Recent content in Jeff VanderMeer on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/jeff-vandermeer/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Authority</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/12/authority/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/12/authority/</guid><description>&lt;p>After how much I enjoyed &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="17934530" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17934530.annihilation">Annihilation&lt;/a>, I had high hopes for &lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="18077769" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18077769.authority">Authority&lt;/a>. A chance to get out of Area X and explore the organization sending people in / to their deaths over and over again&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But unfortunately, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t get into it. I missed the limited focus and the mystery of the first book. Even, for what very little we knew about them, the characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Annihilation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/01/annihilation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/07/01/annihilation/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>You must understand how I felt then, how the surveyor must have felt: We &amp;gt; were scientists, trained to observe natural phenomena and the results of &amp;gt; human activity. We had not been trained to encounter what appeared to be the &amp;gt; uncanny. In unusual situations there can be a comfort in the presence of &amp;gt; even someone you think might be your enemy. Now we had come close to the &amp;gt; edges of something unprecedented, and less than a week into our mission we &amp;gt; had lost not just the linguist at the border but our anthropologist and our &amp;gt; psychologist.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Now that is a fascinating sort of book. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially a slice of life mixed with cosmic horror. The entire story follows an expedition into the mysterious, alien Area X. There&amp;rsquo;s not really any overarching plot, other than exploring and perhaps surviving&amp;hellip; and maybe if you&amp;rsquo;re really really lucky, coming back without going mad.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>