<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Six of Crows on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/six-of-crows-/</link><description>Recent content in Six of Crows on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/six-of-crows-/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crooked Kingdom</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/02/crooked-kingdom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/10/02/crooked-kingdom/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Crows remember human faces. They remember the people who feed them, who are kind to them. And the people who wrong them too. They don’t forget. They tell each other who to look after and who to watch out for.”&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/">Six of Crows&lt;/a> took the world of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> and instead gave us one heck of a heist book. Really, it all circled around one big, impossible heist. Plan everything, get in, plans fall apart, make new plans, and pull off the impossible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s one heck of an impressive book and I really enjoyed it, but it left an awful lot of plot thread hanging open&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Which makes Crooked Kingdom all the more cathartic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Six of Crows</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/27/six-of-crows/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>No mourners.&lt;br>
No funerals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Among them, it passed for &amp;lsquo;good luck.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oh, that&amp;rsquo;s such a good book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It takes the world of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/09/12/shadow-and-bone/">Shadow and Bone&lt;/a> and completely ignores the at times overly YA political and religions machinations of that particular trilogy in favor of a somewhat darker and grittier heist novel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the most part, you really don&amp;rsquo;t need to have read Shadow and Bone first. There are a few references to the &amp;lsquo;Ravkan Civil War&amp;rsquo; and even to Sankta Alina, but other than that, it&amp;rsquo;s a new world. There are still Grisha, but they&amp;rsquo;re far less &amp;lsquo;miliary&amp;rsquo;, instead using (and hiding) their powers in all manner of interesting ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And while the heist elements were &lt;em>strong&lt;/em> (an impossible job, planning going absolutely sideways, and double triple crossing left and right) we also get all sorts of interesting backstory. Each of the main characters has chapters in their voice, but in the action going now, and explaining how they got into this mess in the first place. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot, but in a good way!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One gotcha is that, while the main heist plot is more than adequately contained in the book, it very much is the first half of a duology. It managed to just make me want to read the second&amp;hellip; but don&amp;rsquo;t go into this looking for a stand alone novel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But what really shines are the characters.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>