<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2018 on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2018/</link><description>Recent content in 2018 on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/year/2018/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ready Player One</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/19/ready-player-one/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/12/19/ready-player-one/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh hey, that&amp;rsquo;s a DeLorean! I should go re-watch Back to the Future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ready Player One is a very pretty movie (I seem to be saying that [a lot]) recently) and absolutely chock full of pop culture references&amp;hellip; which honestly felt rather overdone. The plot is thin and the world doesn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>really&lt;/em> make sense, although I did enjoy the characters well enough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deadpool 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/28/deadpool-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2024/11/28/deadpool-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>language warning&lt;/strong> (duh?)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well that certainly started with a bang.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After the surprsing (to some I suppose) success of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/deadpool/">Deadpool&lt;/a>, of course they&amp;rsquo;re going to make another. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; pretty much exactly what you&amp;rsquo;d expect if you took Deadpool and turned it up to, well, as far as Cable&amp;rsquo;s gun goes. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have more X-Men! Well, we have Yukio. And a delightful blink and you&amp;rsquo;ll miss it group cameo. And Cable! He&amp;rsquo;s from the X-Men comics at least?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Grinch</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/02/the-grinch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/01/02/the-grinch/</guid><description>&lt;p>Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s nostalgia speaking, but I really miss the 1966 How the Grinch Stole Christmas! It was basically a reading of the book with a great narrator (Boris Karloff, who amusingly is best known for a bunch of 1930-40s horror films) and a few new songs that really fit the Seuss style. Given that the Grinch is probably in my top 5 Seuss books overall, of course I like it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ant-Man and the Wasp</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/25/ant-man-and-the-wasp/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ant-Man and his daughter are adorable. Especially with Luis&amp;rsquo; help. Luis is wonderful. Everyone playing Luis as he describes everyone. And Paul Rudd playing Janet van Dyne. Add to that the interactions with/introduction of Jimmy Woo.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Scott Lang: Come on, Woo. I&amp;rsquo;ve got three days left. Why would I try to escape?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jimmy Woo: Sorry, Scott, but rules are rules. You trip the perimeter alarm, we search the place. Keel to stern, soup to nuts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Avengers: Infinity War</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/19/avengers-infinity-war/</guid><description>&lt;p>All that. Ten years. 18 movies. Dozens of huge name actors and crossovers, all leading to this. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/04/04/the-avengers/">The Avengers&lt;/a> gave us a team up, but Infinity War turned it all up to 11. The battle scenes are insane (especially that final battle in Wakanda, especially especially the return of Thor), the villain&amp;ndash;Josh Brolin as Thanos&amp;ndash;is powerful and &lt;span class="spoiler">ACTUALLY GETS A CHANCE TO WIN&lt;/span>
, and I absolutely love seeing the interplay between all of the characters.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Panther</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2021/08/18/black-panther/</guid><description>&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s a very solid movie. The casting is top notch, the style is wonderfully afrofuturistic, and the plot/motivation is interesting enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting with the plot/motivation, I think that the choice to have Wakanda separated from the rest of the world, all through centuries of slavery and inequality is certainly an interesting one. And I&amp;rsquo;m not at all alone.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nakia: I came to support you, and to honor your father. But I can&amp;rsquo;t stay. It&amp;rsquo;s just &amp;hellip; ! found my calling out there. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen too many in need just to turn a blind eye. I can&amp;rsquo;t be happy here knowing that there&amp;rsquo;s people out there who have nothing .&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>