<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Yoon Ha Lee on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/yoon-ha-lee/</link><description>Recent content in Yoon Ha Lee on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/yoon-ha-lee/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Phoenix Extravagant</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/12/phoenix-extravagant/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/12/phoenix-extravagant/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jebi was torn between saying &amp;lsquo;You are embarrassing me&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;I am going to take up my brush and make a painting of you that they will talk about for the next 10,000 years&amp;rsquo;. They said neither.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A world chock full of the history of China/Japan/China of a hundred years and change ago. Racism, colonialism, occupation, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major take on artists during war. Both from the main character Gyen Jebi, an artist who fails to pass the examination for the Ministry of Art&amp;ndash;and ends up the perhaps much more interesting Ministry of Armor, making magical automata for the government. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating seeing a relatively common job turned extraordinary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, the mechanical dragon on the cover. Arazi. &lt;span class="spoiler"&gt;Who is also a philosopher and pacifist, because of course they are.&lt;/span&gt;
. There&amp;rsquo;s always something fun about relatively non-human characters like that. Probably the coolest part of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course of course, there&amp;rsquo;s love. The relationship between Jebi and their captors, Vei especially. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing the people who are perhaps all the more aware of the situation at hand and their relationships with the at times amusingly clueless Jebi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, an interesting book. I like the magic of the setting and the characters. The ending felt a little weird and weak, but it did wrap up well enough I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The studio also featured a large wall calendar with cryptic abbreviations, presumably reminders. Also doodles of gears, sprockets, and malformed genitalia, because artists were artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Vela</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/22/the-vela/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/02/22/the-vela/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eratos wasn’t the only dying world, just the one dying fastest—the tiny colony on Samos had been gone for a decade, and after Eratos would be Hypatia and then Gan-De, and maybe the Inner Ring would finally come to care when it was their turn to freeze to death as the sun collapsed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A leisurely extinction. One that allowed everyone to push any inconvenience to another place or another generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Vela is part of a fascinating sort of new/old model: serialized fiction. In this case &lt;a href="https://www.realm.fm/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Realm.fm (formerly Serial Box)&lt;/a&gt; is putting out piles of audio fiction by a number of well known authors chapter by chapter. And yet&amp;hellip; somehow I read the ebook version from the library. I really should check out the audio versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, The worldbuilding (as in the above quote) in the Vela is fascinating. A nearish-future tech sci-fi universe where humanity has managed to extract enough resources from the local star to freeze out the outer planets, wrecking all manner of havoc among the people that live out there. There&amp;rsquo;s all manner of classism, racism, and other racisms to digest&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set against the backdrop of a missing starship (the Vela) and the two unlikely companions (Asala and Niko) who are sent to go find it. I&amp;rsquo;m glad to see Becky Chambers as one of the authors here, I really love how she does &amp;lsquo;people stories&amp;rsquo;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet read the other three authors, but they&amp;rsquo;re all on my to-read shelf already and higher up now. &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between Asala (hard bitten mercenary/sniper) and Nike (child of the president; hacker) throughout the stories is really the shining jewel of the series. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see the slight (IMO) variations between how the different authors see and write them, but it&amp;rsquo;s still well worth reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well well worth a read. Or a listen. And Season 2 is on Realm? Onward!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People spoke about the death of planets as if the rock itself would shatter, but the truth was never so dramatic. The entire sphere wasn&amp;rsquo;t in danger of ceasing to exist. All that mattered was the inner goings-on of that tiny strip of gauze, that onion skin of atmosphere clinging to the rocky surface like morning dew. The narrowest of margins on which everything depended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>