<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clive Cussler on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/clive-cussler/</link><description>Recent content in Clive Cussler on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/clive-cussler/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>White Death</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/31/white-death/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/31/white-death/</guid><description>&lt;p>No one expects the Spanish Inquisition&amp;hellip; or a German expedition to the North Pole? Also, if that weren’t enough, we have Basque independence and frankenfish!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s formulaic as any of these are and the inciting historical events are at once a bit weird&amp;ndash;and not nearly as earth shattering as they often are? This time around, the modern threat is perhaps a bigger one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s really not much more to say about these at this point. If you&amp;rsquo;ve liked the first three (or the whole of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/dirk-pitt/">Dirk Pitt&lt;/a>), you&amp;rsquo;ll probably enjoy this one! If not&amp;hellip; how did you get here?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A weird one to end the year on, but I enjoyed it well enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fire Ice</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/18/fire-ice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/18/fire-ice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another day (week?), another Cussler. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve read this one before, but that&amp;rsquo;s sort of the appeal of all of these books&amp;ndash;some quasihistorical inciting incident (that happens on or near the oceans) then jump to the present time to find the resulting shipwreck and deal with the secret organization (for example) that&amp;rsquo;s trying to RULE THE WORLD.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This time with more Russia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have the daughters of Nikolai II, last Emperor of Russia&amp;ndash;on the run with all the royal jewels, including one very shiny crown.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cut to the modern era, we have a Russian spy who&amp;rsquo;s gone toe to toe with Kurt Austin several times over the years, a manic trying to &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/methane%20clathrate">blow up the ocean floor&lt;/a> and cause &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/tsunamis">tsunamis&lt;/a>, and gangs of modern neo-&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cossacks">Cossacks&lt;/a> trying to bring back Mother Russia.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s exactly what it says on the tin&amp;ndash;a &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/numa-files/">NUMA Files&lt;/a> novel&amp;ndash;and quite the adventure for all that. Formulaic, but a fun listen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blue Gold</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/03/blue-gold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/12/03/blue-gold/</guid><description>In this century wars will not be fought over oil, as in the past, but over water. The situation is becoming desperate. The world&amp;rsquo;s water is strained by population growth. There is no more fresh water on earth than two thousand years ago when the population was three percent of its current size.
Oof.
Serpent started us down the road of an alternative to Dirk Pitt with the NUMA Files.</description></item><item><title>Serpent</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/25/serpent/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/11/25/serpent/</guid><description>“Nereus, the Old Man of the Sea,” Nina murmured, cocking her head in thought. “There’s a quote from Hesiod, the Greek poet: ‘A trusty and gentle god who thinks just and kindly thoughts and never lies.”
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve read any Clive Cussler. Turns out there are even a few new Dirk Pitt books I&amp;rsquo;ll have to catch up on. But even then, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t actually read any of his second related series: The NUMA Files.</description></item><item><title>Celtic Empire</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/12/celtic-empire/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/12/celtic-empire/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends. I think I enjoyed the book more and rated it more highly knowing it was the last of the series, although I guess Dirk Cussler could easily continue it, given that he&amp;rsquo;s been the co-author on these books for years now. But for now, it&amp;rsquo;s over and it&amp;rsquo;s time for me to move on to other books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, there are a lot of threads that feel familiar, but there are only so many different ancient civilizations you can dig up treasures for&amp;ndash;and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure Cussler hit them all. This time around, an ancient Egyptian princess apparently made it to Celtic Ireland somehow. A mummy is stolen, bioengineered bacteria try to take over the world, someone is taking militant feminism to an extreme, and wacky (destructive) highjinks ensue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Odessa Sea</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/07/odessa-sea/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 12:56:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/06/07/odessa-sea/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man of action Permutter saves the day!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wait. What?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Havana Storm</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/27/havana-storm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/27/havana-storm/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“When power is up for grabs,” Pitt said, “the first casualty is often liberty.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Oof.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Poseidon's Arrow</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/16/poseidons-arrow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/05/16/poseidons-arrow/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well. I listened to it. It had something to do with a big conspiracy to control rare earth metals and a lost submarine. &amp;hellip; That&amp;rsquo;s really about all that stuck in my head.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s got a lot of solid crazy action: in particular there&amp;rsquo;s a battle in the Panama Canal, which is pretty awesome. But I&amp;rsquo;m really getting burnt out on this series. But I&amp;rsquo;m so close to finishing it&amp;hellip; I think I&amp;rsquo;ll still go for it, but I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to it less than I had.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crescent Dawn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/25/crescent-dawn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 14:11:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/25/crescent-dawn/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The deliveryman smiled as he eyed the thick stack of currency. “I wonder if the Germans would pay this much to sink a ship and murder a general,” he said. “You wouldn’t happen to be working for the Kaiser, now, would you?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The minister firmly shook his head. “No, this is a theological matter. Had you been able to locate the document, this would not have been necessary.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Arctic Drift</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/13/arctic-drift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/13/arctic-drift/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“You heard what the man said,” Giordino replied. “We’re going to Anchorage. Anchorage, Alaska,” he repeated lovingly. “South of the Arctic Circle. Did ever a place sound so warm and inviting?” he asked with a contented grin.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve done ice before&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>). We&amp;rsquo;ve done mines before[^mine]. We&amp;rsquo;ve done oil before[^oil]. We&amp;rsquo;ve even done global warming before[^warming]. At some point, these books have really started to blend together. Almost done though, so at this point I&amp;rsquo;ll see them through.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Treasure of Khan</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/05/treasure-of-khan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/04/05/treasure-of-khan/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If a satellite in space ever mapped the myriad of lone tracks and trails across Mongolia, it would resemble a plate of spaghetti dropped on the floor.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Haven&amp;rsquo;t we done this before? With the desert and Khans?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Black Wind</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/31/black-wind/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/31/black-wind/</guid><description>&lt;p>After 18 of these, they&amp;rsquo;re starting to sound awfully familiar. Basically, combine a bit of the Japanese influence from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/10/dragon/">Dragon&lt;/a> and a bit of the mysterious deaths on islands from &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/26/shock-wave/">Shock Wave&lt;/a> and you have &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/31/black-wind/">Black Wind&lt;/a>. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it bad by any stretch of the imagination&amp;hellip; just samey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the crazies part of listening to this book was doing so while on lockdown from COVID-19. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite as bad as a weaponized smallpox by a long shot, but Cussler&amp;rsquo;s descriptions of the world shutting down, health facilities and morgues being overloaded was disturbingly prescient. Given that he passed in February, before the full extent of what was coming had really hit the United States, I wonder if he could have imagination it coming to life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trojan Odyssey</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/26/trojan-odyssey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/26/trojan-odyssey/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>He smiled to himself at remembering what a reporter wrote about him, in one of the few times his feats had gained distinction. There is a touch of Dirk Pitt in every man whose soul yearns for adventure. And because he is Dirk Pitt, he yearns more than most.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So. Homer&amp;rsquo;s Odyssey was real. But they weren&amp;rsquo;t Greeks but rather Celts and they weren&amp;rsquo;t in the Mediterranean but rather in the Americas? Sure. The baddies are a cult of Celtic Druid superwomen, all hot as heck kickass redheads? Sure. The evil plot is to dig a giant tunnel to redirect the Atlantic Current and freeze Europe?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Valhalla Rising</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/16/valhalla-rising/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/16/valhalla-rising/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s one heck of an opening. A ship on fire! Trying to fit thousands on a ship normally crewed by dozens! Mysterious baddies! Action on the high seas! One of the things I like most about these series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Get through all that and&amp;hellip; rescue in a submarine! More adventure! And a rescue by Clive Cussler! He gives them a bit more direct help than sometimes, but it works. Plus you get a line like this:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Atlantis Found</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/12/atlantis-found/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/12/atlantis-found/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the things Clive Cussler does really well is take some bit of knowledge or lore and turn it up to eleven and see where that takes the world. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/24/raise-the-titanic/">Raise the Titanic!&lt;/a> A treaty that sold Canada to the US. Lincoln kidnapped and shipped to Africa.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to be that accurate to what actually happened, but almost all of the stories make a good &amp;lsquo;well it would be cool if it was true&amp;rsquo;. &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/12/atlantis-found/">Atlantis Found&lt;/a> is exactly that sort of book. You have a lost advanced civilization well before the earliest known examples that eventually became the story of Atlantis with a [reasonable enough reason](&lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/science/2014/04/massive-asteroid-may-" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://arstechnica.com/science/2014/04/massive-asteroid-may-&lt;/a> have-kickstarted-the-movement-of-continents/) why we haven&amp;rsquo;t found any examples of them in modern day (until now!). The science isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect, but it&amp;rsquo;s close enough to make a good story. Add in some neo-Nazis and a doomsday plot? And you have classic Dirk Pitt.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flood Tide</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/05/flood-tide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/03/05/flood-tide/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Pitt also studied the shattered windshield, the splintered engine hatch, the holes stitched across the bow, the wisp of dark smoke rising from the engine compartment. &amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;d arrived two seconds later, Admiral Sandecker would be stuck with the chore of writing my eulogy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Again?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shock Wave</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/26/shock-wave/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/26/shock-wave/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/26/shock-wave/">Shock Wave&lt;/a> is yet another crazy book. Par for the course at this point. This time around, we have shipwrecks, sea serpents, diamonds, and a strange &amp;lsquo;acoustic plague&amp;rsquo; that kills every living thing within a hundred kilometers. The bad guys are evil, the good guys are going to win in the end, and it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a crazy story along the way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Characterwise, it&amp;rsquo;s more of the same. It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to see a fairly believable love interest for Pitt in Maeve&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. And we have more and more from the side characters, in particular Giordino with Pitt and Rudy Gunn and Admiral Sandecker doing their own part to save the world. Giordino even gets a big show hand to hand fight at the end, although why in the world &lt;span class="spoiler">he didn't just shoot her, I'll never know&lt;/span>
. Also &lt;span class="spoiler">another transgender villain?&lt;/span>
Why? Again, it&amp;rsquo;s just a few lines, but &amp;hellip; why?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Inca Gold</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/21/inca-gold/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/21/inca-gold/</guid><description>&lt;p>Man these are getting long. 20 hours on the audiobook. Even at 2.5x, that&amp;rsquo;s a while. It probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that every. single. time. a measurement is mentioned, it has to be converted. Is that the same in the print version? Because it&amp;rsquo;s maddening&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Pitt&amp;rsquo;s heart pumped a good five liters (a gallon) of adrenaline through his system, but he remained calm and clinically surveyed the towering figure that looked like a monstrosity out of a science fiction horror movie.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Sahara</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/14/sahara/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/14/sahara/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Prologue 1.&amp;rdquo; Oh my.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Lincoln&amp;hellip;?&amp;rdquo; Double oh my.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dragon</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/10/dragon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/10/dragon/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Dirk Pitt] had always believed that insurmountable odds were surmountable.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>These books are so ridiculous.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Treasure</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/23/treasure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/23/treasure/</guid><description>&lt;p>How do you connect a plane crash based on two overlapping terrorist plots, hidden mob-like family, a Mexican revolution based on bringing back the might of the Aztec empire, an Egyptian revolution based on fundamental Islam, a Roman ship far from where any Roman ship has any right to be, and the lost Library of Alexandria?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Carefully. Very very carefully.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cyclops</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/13/cyclops/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/13/cyclops/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, Cussler really jumped the shark (over the moon?) in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/13/cyclops/">Cyclops&lt;/a> . After the mind control plot of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/09/deep-six/">Deep Six&lt;/a> , I figured things would stay a bit more grounded this time around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nah. Moon colonies. A plot to take over Cuba. El Dorado (or rather La Dorada!). Conversations with Fidel Casto. It&amp;rsquo;s all here. And it&amp;rsquo;s completely ridiculous. I wish there&amp;rsquo;d been a bit more focus on one or two of the plotlines (particular La Dorada, that&amp;rsquo;s the Pitt I prefer), but so it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deep Six</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/09/deep-six/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/09/deep-six/</guid><description>&lt;p>With each Dirk Pitt novels, the world Clive Cussler is building seems to get more and more intense and diverge further from the world we live in. We started with simple salvage and simple enough (although extensive) smuggling and drugs. And then they raised the Titanic. And found a treaty to add Canada to the United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/09/deep-six/">Deep Six&lt;/a> is certainly no exception, with a primary plot essentially resolving around kidnapping and mind controlling the President of the United States. As one does.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Night Probe!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/04/night-probe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/04/night-probe/</guid><description>&lt;p>One one hand, wow can you tell that some of these books were written in the 80s. The energy crisis is top on everyone&amp;rsquo;s mind and the USSR still stands.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This lays the groundwork for a bizarre alternate reality where a North American Treaty was signed between the UK and the US with the former &lt;span class="spoiler">selling Canada to the latter for $1 billion&lt;/span>
. It&amp;rsquo;s a fairly ridiculous premise for a series that otherwise more or less takes place in our world, but that&amp;rsquo;s become something of par for the course for Dirk Pitt. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter (in universe) anyways, since after the treaty was lost, two of the three copies were mysteriously lost: one in the (real life) ship wreck of the RMS Empress of Ireland (only 465 survivors out of 1477); the other lost when a train&amp;ndash;The Manhattan Limited&amp;ndash;falls through a bridge into a river.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vixen 03</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/vixen-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/vixen-03/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/01/vixen-03/">Vixen 03&lt;/a> was a surprisingly good listen. From the reviews, I expected something far worse. It&amp;rsquo;s Pitt to the core, with crazy action scenes, ocean (more lake really) salvage, weird ships where they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be, and Pitt getting himself mixed up in situations he has no reason to be involved in. Oh, and a sprinkling of racism and misogyny. At least it&amp;rsquo;s getting better?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plotwise, the story of the doomed Vixen 03, it&amp;rsquo;s discovery, and the involved salvage mission is the best part of the book. The final conclusion with a retired battleship, retrofitted, and sailed up &lt;span class="spoiler">the Potomac to train their guns on Washington DC&lt;/span>
is ridiculous and would make an excellent blockbuster sequence. The plot about the African revolutionaries feels&amp;hellip; rather racist and bizarre? I&amp;rsquo;m not actually sure, but it certainly feels very strange. That level of hatred between races and peoples is something that I thankfully have little personal experience with and felt odd in the story. It probably could have been traded out for any sort of terrorist group with little change to the plot.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Raise the Titanic!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/24/raise-the-titanic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/24/raise-the-titanic/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/24/raise-the-titanic/">Raise the Titanic!&lt;/a> is one of the Dirk Pitt books that I remember reading years and years ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating story, mixing secret government espionage with the underwater salvage details that are one of the reasons I really do enjoy this series on the greatest salvage mission you could expect: The Titanic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fascinating to realize that this book was published 10 years before the remains of the Titanic were discovered&amp;ndash;and yet it&amp;rsquo;s set in 1987, 2 years after. As such, you realize now that there are a few details that aren&amp;rsquo;t entirely correct (such as the ship breaking in half). Also we&amp;rsquo;re near the fall of the USSR, but they&amp;rsquo;re quite the villains to be reckoned with hereabouts. Still, from the point of view it was written, it all seems reasonable enough. Otherwise, just treat it as a parallel universe and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go. And both the salvage mission plus the harrowing account of &lt;span class="spoiler">Russian agents and a hurricane once the Titanic is raised&lt;/span>
makes it a solid action book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iceberg</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/19/iceberg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/19/iceberg/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/19/iceberg/">Iceberg&lt;/a> opens with a solid enough set piece/action scene: a burnt out wreck of a luxary yacht, long since missing, found melted into an iceberg. One thing leads to another and Dirk Pitt stumbles into a cadre of billionaires with a plot to take over not only businesses but countries. For that&amp;ndash;plot and set pieces&amp;ndash;Iceberg is a solid enough read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then&amp;hellip; you get to the pretty terrible sexism and homophobia. Pitt finds out the woman he&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be getting information out of is in a serious relationship (which for plot reasons he must not threaten), so decides in the spur of the moment to play a caricature of a gay man and&amp;hellip; oof. You can tell this book was published in the 70s and not the particularly progressive sort of 70s either. On top of that, you have sexism wrapped up in a neat little bow with how Pitt and his boss Admiral Sandecker treat Tidi Royal (the latter&amp;rsquo;s secretary). They all treat it so normal that Tidi exists to make coffee and should be yelled at for spilling it on a tossing ship&amp;hellip; oy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Mediterranean Caper</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/14/the-mediterranean-caper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/14/the-mediterranean-caper/</guid><description>&lt;p>The first &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/dirk-pitt/">Dirk Pitt&lt;/a> book published and the second chronologically, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/14/the-mediterranean-caper/">The Mediterranean Caper&lt;/a> is kind of ridiculous. It&amp;rsquo;s 70s action at it&amp;rsquo;s finest, with more of a focus on old airplanes (the novel opens with a dogfight between a World War II flying boat against a World War I fighter plane) and smuggling than ocean salvage, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a enough fun read. I miss the ocean focus and salvage we saw in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/09/pacific-vortex/">Pacific Vortex!&lt;/a> and later books though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The sexism is &amp;hellip; pretty ridiculous in this book, wherein early in the book, Pitt meets a woman, finds out she&amp;rsquo;s a widow of several years, slaps her and tells her to move on with her life, and has sex with her&amp;ndash;all within minutes of meeting her. Add that to all manner of comments about &amp;lsquo;feminine&amp;rsquo; so and such. It&amp;rsquo;s maddening. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that changes as the series continues to advance through the years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pacific Vortex!</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/09/pacific-vortex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2019/12/09/pacific-vortex/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Every ocean takes its toll of men and ships, yet none devours them with the voracious appetitive of the Pacific&amp;hellip;.Despite all this, the world&amp;rsquo;s largest ocean tends to be a tranquil place; even its name means peaceful and mild of temper.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Clive Cussler&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/dirk-pitt/">Dirk Pitt&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/numa-files/">NUMA Files&lt;/a> are two more series, much like Ben Bova&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-grand-tour/">Grand Tour&lt;/a> which I remember reading years (more than a decade now) ago, borrowed from the local library whenever I could find them and often in no particular order. I remember enjoying them then, so let&amp;rsquo;s see how they hold up! I&amp;rsquo;ll be listening to them on audiobook as I go.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>