<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Founders Trilogy on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-founders-trilogy/</link><description>Recent content in The Founders Trilogy on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-founders-trilogy/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shorefall</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/28/shorefall/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/28/shorefall/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Learn what your city has forgotten. What men of power have forgotten time and time again, throughout history—that there is always, always something mightier.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/06/foundryside/">Foundryside&lt;/a> was quite a ride, with an awesome magic system, great characters, and some nice not entirely too dark bits of revolution going on&amp;ndash;and hints of something more. Shorefall takes all that&amp;hellip; and turns it way the heck up to 11.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Foundryside</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/06/foundryside/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/06/foundryside/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Every innovation—technological, sociological, or otherwise—begins as a crusade, organizes itself into a practical business, and then, over time, degrades into common exploitation. This is simply the life cycle of how human ingenuity manifests in the material world. What goes forgotten, though, is that those who partake in this system undergo a similar transformation: people begin as comrades and fellow citizens, then become labor resources and assets, and then, as their utility shifts or degrades, transmute into liabilities, and thus must be appropriately managed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that was delightful. It&amp;rsquo;s been on my list for a while, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d give it a chance and I&amp;rsquo;m so very glad I did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I highly recommend the book, with the disclaimer that there are some dark scenes, bits (sorry) of body horror, and quite a lot of (made up fantasy) swearing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>