<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lauren Beukes on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/lauren-beukes/</link><description>Recent content in Lauren Beukes on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/lauren-beukes/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fairest, Volume 2: The Hidden Kingdom</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/10/16/fairest-volume-2-the-hidden-kingdom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/10/16/fairest-volume-2-the-hidden-kingdom/</guid><description>&lt;p>Back to Fairest (slightly out of order). This time we have Rapunzel in Japan, somehow or another, and another appearance of Jack&amp;ndash;isn&amp;rsquo;t he a Dragon now? Did I miss something?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the influence of Japanese Fables to the mix, this is by far one of the weirder books:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zoo City</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/11/zoo-city/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2015/12/11/zoo-city/</guid><description>&lt;p>Basically, if you kill someone (is that the only way?) you end up with a literal animal manifestation of your guilt. On the plus side, they come with free magical abilities (like the main character&amp;rsquo;s ability to find lost things). On the down side, people know how you got your animal (your zoo) and discrimination is rampant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a really interesting concept; something that I haven&amp;rsquo;t quite seen anywhere else (The Golden Compass is vaguely similar, at least in the animal companions). And the world is just gritty and dark enough that it felt like a dark echo of what our world could be / have been. Unfortunately, a lot of details are left unclear. What exactly is the Undertow? How do people get which animals? What did the main character actually do to get her Sloth? How different are the animals from their wild brethren?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>