<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Night at the Museum on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/night-at-the-museum/</link><description>Recent content in Night at the Museum on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/night-at-the-museum/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Night at the Museum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/26/night-at-the-museum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/04/26/night-at-the-museum/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another on that list of movies I&amp;rsquo;m a little surprised I&amp;rsquo;d never seen before&amp;ndash;yet I&amp;rsquo;ve seen enough random clips on YouTube shorts at this point that I feel like I have.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Side note: This also came back to mind since Ben Stiller wrote a good amount of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/severance/">Severance&lt;/a> of all things.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, it&amp;rsquo;s a ridiculous and fun movie. The whole premise&amp;ndash;that a magical artifact somehow animates all the exhibits at the museum every night&amp;ndash;yet somehow no one has ever noticed this? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the list bit of sense. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any less fun!&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Easter Island Head: HEY!&lt;br>
[pauses]&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: Dum-dum.&lt;br>
Larry: Yes?&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: You give me gum-gum!&lt;br>
Larry: I give you gum-gum?&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: You new Dum-dum. You give me gum-gum.&lt;br>
Larry: Gee, okay, you know what? I have no gum-gum. Sorry. And my name isn&amp;rsquo;t Dum-dum. My name&amp;rsquo;s Larry.&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: No, your name Dum-dum.&lt;br>
[some people are running away]&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: Oh, you in trouble, Dum-dum. You better run-run. From Attila the Hun-hun.&lt;br>
[Attila yells and chases Larry]&lt;br>
Easter Island Head: See you later, Dum-dum!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>There are a lot of fun action scenes in the movie. Just don&amp;rsquo;t think about it all too hard and enjoy the ride. I especially loved the chaos of the dioramas of thousands of tiny men come to life and fighting one another. 😄&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Jedediah: No problemo, Gigantor.&lt;br>
Larry: Um, my name&amp;rsquo;s Larry, first of all okay, Jed? See, I call you Jed, I don&amp;rsquo;t call you tiny, right?&lt;br>
Jedediah: What&amp;rsquo;s that supposed to mean?&lt;br>
Larry: Hey teeny, how does that sound?&lt;br>
Jedediah: I&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t like it. It hurts my feelings.&lt;br>
Larry: Okay, well Gigantor makes me feel like some sort of freak.&lt;br>
Octavius: I don&amp;rsquo;t. I just call you Larry.&lt;br>
Larry: Don&amp;rsquo;t be a kiss-ass.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The casting in this movie is a big strength! Dick Van Dyke was a lot of fun as old former night watchman Cecil. Robin Williams (RIP :sad:) is always a delight and his Teddy Roosevelt was no exception. Rami Malek is certainly no &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/mr.-robot/">Mr. Robot&lt;/a>, but he&amp;rsquo;s got a perfect presence as Ahkmenrah. And Steve Coogan as Octavius and Owen Wilson&amp;rsquo;s Jedediah were hilarious (especially since the latter was originally a minor cameo).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And you know? Apparently &amp;lsquo;The real-life American Museum of Natural History had 20% more visitors during the holiday season following this movie&amp;rsquo;s opening.&amp;rsquo; So good on them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now the sequels? No idea where they go from here, but you know what? Worth a try!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>