<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Murderbot Diaries on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-murderbot-diaries/</link><description>Recent content in The Murderbot Diaries on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/the-murderbot-diaries/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rogue Protocol</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/17/rogue-protocol/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/17/rogue-protocol/</guid><description>(There needs to be an error code that means “I received your request but decided to ignore you.”)
I do love me some Murderbot.
First, we got the origin story and then the one where the mystery deepens. Now&amp;hellip; Muderbot is really digging into where it came from &amp;hellip; and what int eh world GrayCris is doing there. It&amp;rsquo;s a fun story and I really love seeing Murderbot learn and grow as a person*.</description></item><item><title>Artificial Condition</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/15/artificial-condition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/15/artificial-condition/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="36223860" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36223860.artificial-condition">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/artificial-condition.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>When constructs were first developed, they were originally supposed to have a pre-sentient level of intelligence, like the dumber variety of bot. But you can’t put something as dumb as a hauler bot in charge of security for anything without spending even more money for expensive company-employed human supervisors. So they made us smarter. The anxiety and depression were side effects.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Murderbot is out on their own! It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting change of pace from the previous story, where Muderbot was still in the role of SecUnit&amp;hellip; On the way, it runs into ART (a spaceship AI; not it&amp;rsquo;s real name, it stands for Asshole Research Transport; three guesses who that&amp;rsquo;s from&amp;hellip;) who turns out to be a great ally. Muderbot gets a few changes to act slightly less SecUnit and more Augmented Human, goes back to the planet where to some extend it all began, and ends up hiring out it&amp;rsquo;s services as private security&amp;ndash;hey, do what you know.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>All Systems Red</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/04/08/all-systems-red/</guid><description>&lt;figure class="cover-image">
&lt;a data-goodreads-type="book" data-goodreads-id="32758901" href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32758901.all-systems-red">&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/all-systems-red.jpg">&lt;/a>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Okay, I get what all the hype is about. Take a heavily armed cyborg/clone, designed entirely as muscle to defend the more squishy &amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo; humans, have it turn off the software constraining it from killing everyone, add in a wonderfully snarky sense of humor&amp;hellip; and see what happens.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I COULD HAVE BECOME a mass murderer after I hacked my governor module, but then I realized I could access the combined feed of entertainment channels carried on the company satellites. It had been well over 35,000 hours or so since then, with still not much murdering, but probably, I don’t know, a little under 35,000 hours of movies, serials, books, plays, and music consumed. As a heartless killing machine, I was a terrible failure.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>