<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2023 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2023-book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2023 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2023-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ultimate Comics Ultimates by Jonathan Hickman, Vol. 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/19/ultimate-comics-ultimates-by-jonathan-hickman-vol.-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/19/ultimate-comics-ultimates-by-jonathan-hickman-vol.-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so we’re back with the Ultimates…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-comics-ultimates-textbundle-ece1a9.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>… and things are going very. very sideways.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because there’s a new* villain in town.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-comics-ultimates-textbundle-a83ac9.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This should be interesting.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Miles Morales: Ultimate Spider-Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/18/miles-morales-ultimate-spider-man/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/18/miles-morales-ultimate-spider-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Miles Morales!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did not realize that he originally came from the Ultimates universe. So this is actually a new origin story!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pretty cool. It’s interesting seeing what made it into Into the Spider-Verse—and what didn’t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do wish we’d had a chance to see Peter and Miles interact more, but I think this will work out. It’s got a lot of potential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Space Between Worlds</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/18/the-space-between-worlds/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/18/the-space-between-worlds/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hopping between worlds&amp;ndash;with one big caveat. If you visit a world where another you is still alive, you die.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Why have I survived? Because I am a creature more devious than all the other mes put together. Because I saw myself bleeding out and instead of checking for a pulse, I began collecting her things. I survive the desert like a coyote survives, like all tricksters do.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating premise, especially when you dig just a bit deeper: Who are the people most likely able to jump? Who&amp;rsquo;s the most likely to have died on other worlds?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a story about privilege. About a world built for the rich and powerful&amp;ndash;by those who have nothing or less; those that pay everything and get nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And Cara is stuck right in the middle of it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Cartographers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/16/the-cartographers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/16/the-cartographers/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Cartography, at its heart, was about defining one&amp;rsquo;s place in the world by creating charts and measurements. Nell had lived her life by that idea, that everything could be mapped according to references and thereby understood. But she could see now that she had been paying attention to the wrong references.&lt;br>
It was not a map alone that made a place real.&lt;br>
It was the people.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This is a tricky one to review. It&amp;rsquo;ll take some minor spoilers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell (if you want to completely avoid spoilers), it&amp;rsquo;s a decent book with a fascinating premise that could have done so much more for the actual execution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Spider-Man: Death of Spider-Man Fallout</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/14/ultimate-comics-spider-man-death-of-spider-man-fallout/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/14/ultimate-comics-spider-man-death-of-spider-man-fallout/</guid><description>&lt;p>I feel like we’ve &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/16/ultimatum-requiem/">been here before&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-fallout-textbundle-9f0fa2.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this time around, as much as it is about endings… it’s also about new beginnings (see below, spoilers). Which is kind of a bummer. We really needed more time to breath and process, but this all feels like setting up whatever comes next.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still, I’m looking forward to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zeroes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/12/zeroes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/12/zeroes/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Zeroes, not Heroes.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That was fun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a nutshell, it&amp;rsquo;s the story of six American teenagers who discover they have superpowers. And fairly atypical ones too. A Voice that says exactly what needs to be said&amp;ndash;for better or for worse. Being immediately forgotten. Crashing electronics all around you. Controlling mobs. Leadership (somehow different from mobs). Seeing through others&amp;rsquo; eyes.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Maybe Flicker&amp;rsquo;s power made her think differently than most people. She saw the world from so many perspectives, and seeing was half of enlightenment.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Death of Spider-Man</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/death-of-spider-man/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/death-of-spider-man/</guid><description>&lt;p>Death of Spider-Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So. Is he finally going to hang up the mask for good? (again) A metaphorical sort of death?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or, given that it&amp;rsquo;s the Ultimate Marvel Universe&amp;hellip; is Peter Parker himself the next on chopping block?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of all the Ultimate Marvel titles, &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/ultimate-spider-man/">Ultimate Spider-Man&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/ultimate-comics-spider-man-2009/">continued&lt;/a>) has been by far the most consistently good. Often great. He&amp;rsquo;s a good kid and consistently tries to do his best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well worth the read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death of Spider-Man Prelude</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/death-of-spider-man-prelude/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 23:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/death-of-spider-man-prelude/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oh Peter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/death-of-spider-man-prelude-textbundle-1876e6.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/death-of-spider-man-prelude-textbundle-05237e.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that time living a double life and causing absolute chaos along the way…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We all know what’s coming. It’s in the title for crying out loud.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But for once, it’s nice to see things sort of working out.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lost Souls</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/lost-souls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/lost-souls/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Pride can become arrogance. Arrogance is the father of cruelty. But in the beginning, there was also an idealism, a hope that he could change the human condition.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Victor Helios (né Frankenstein) is dead. Victor Leben (né Helios (né Frankenstein)) is &lt;em>alive&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the events at the end of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/25/dead-and-alive/">Dead and Alive&lt;/a>, we all knew there would be another book. Here it is!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; fine. It&amp;rsquo;s got all the bits you&amp;rsquo;d need for a thriller, but I don&amp;rsquo;t feel the villains as much. And there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>not really and ending&lt;/em>. It&amp;rsquo;s very much part 1 of 2. At this point, you could easily stop at book 3&amp;hellip; or read on to finish book 5. I suppose I&amp;rsquo;m in the latter camp. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Handmaid's Tale</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/the-handmaids-tale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/09/the-handmaids-tale/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Nolite te bastardes carborundorum.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Take the extremist end of the American Protestant religious right. Give them everything they want (plus some) over the span of years (if not months).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Men have taken absolute power. In a world with (dramatically) declining birth rates, women are owned by the state. Their bodies are nothing more than a vessel for their wombs. They can&amp;rsquo;t travel alone, can&amp;rsquo;t be seen, can&amp;rsquo;t own property.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like any good story of this sort, it takes a potential problem&amp;ndash;an idea&amp;ndash;and turns it up to eleven. It goes steps further than anything we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in modern times&amp;ndash;or at least differently. The closest analogue I&amp;rsquo;m aware of is probably the events around the Iranian Revolution in 1979. By 1981, hijab were mandatory (there&amp;rsquo;s more to the history there; even before, hijab were seen as a method of protest against Westernization). Given this book was released in 1985, it seems&amp;hellip; potentially related.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; terrifying.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All the more so, for all those men (often in positions of power) that even today see it less as a cautionary tale and more something to aspire to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t let the bastards grind you down.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Avengers, Vol. 3: Blade vs. The Avengers</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/08/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-3-blade-vs.-the-avengers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/08/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-3-blade-vs.-the-avengers/</guid><description>&lt;p>You’ve heard of Marvel Zombies? Well if that wasn’t terrifying enough… what about Marvel Vampires!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s actually a really neat story. Blade shows up, so vampires are real. Only this time around, they’ve figured out that turning Super Vampires might just be their big shot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neat idea. Solid execution. A few more deaths. Marvel Ultimate yo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By far my favorite Ultimate Avengers so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Girl, Serpent, Thorn</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/07/girl-serpent-thorn/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/07/girl-serpent-thorn/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Stories always begin the same way: There was and there was not. There is possibility in those words, the chance for hope or despair.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Take Persian mythology and worldbuilding, more than a touch of fairy tale feel, a cursed princess, demons, div (what in a Euro-centric story would be probably be fae), a touch of romance, and the spark of revolution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Thor</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/06/ultimate-comics-thor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/06/ultimate-comics-thor/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ultimate Thor. Ages ago, in Asgard. Decades ago, attacked by Nazis. And not that long ago, having a conversation with Dr. Blake—an old friend?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-comics-thor-textbundle-65439b.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s not a bad story, although it feels weird as both a stand-alone and where it is in the Ultimate universe. What with Thor dead in Ultimatum and all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or is he…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Captain America</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/05/ultimate-comics-captain-america/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/05/ultimate-comics-captain-america/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-comics-captain-america-textbundle-61bba0.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well that’s a thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No matter the universe, Marvel seems chock full of Super Soldiers. Here’s one more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given the subject matter, it could have used a bit more nuance. A bit more time to breathe. Captain America represents what America could have/should have been. Vietnam is anything but.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Doomsday</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/04/ultimate-comics-doomsday/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/04/ultimate-comics-doomsday/</guid><description>&lt;p>It hasn’t been that long since Magneto and the Ultimatum wave killed millions. But apparently long enough.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So now another threat is popping out of nowhere and wrecking just about everyone. Time for those left to save the day… yet again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I always knew that Reed Richards was up to no good. Perhaps not intentionally, but that much brains combined with a seemingly complete inability to know when something is too much… not a great combination.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s fine. Not great. Not terrible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Under the Whispering Door</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/03/under-the-whispering-door/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/06/03/under-the-whispering-door/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The first time you share tea, you are a stranger.&lt;br>
The second time you share tea, you are an honored guest.&lt;br>
The third time you share tea, you become family.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>So&amp;hellip; what do you call a slice of life story when the protagonist dies at the end of the first chapter?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whatever you do, &lt;em>Under the Whispering Door&lt;/em> is a delightful example thereof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wallace starts out a kind of terrible person.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The machine had broken down, and though no one was infallible, Wallace needed to switch out the part for a new one. He’d worked too hard to let it fail now. Last year had been the most profitable in the firm’s history. This year was shaping up to be even better. No matter what condition the world was in, someone always needed to be sued.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And then he dies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chameleons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/31/chameleons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/31/chameleons/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that’s a fun hodge podge. Nova (remember the Watchers choosing someone? Me neither)! Spider-Woman! Kitty on the run!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then finally… Chameleons!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s going to be some fallout from this one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>League of Dragons</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/31/league-of-dragons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/31/league-of-dragons/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends. Not with a bang, nor with a whimper, but with a roar. Mostly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, we get the end of Napolean and the wars that have engulfed Europe and a good chunk of the world. Dragons from all over, thousands of them, fighting in the air and on the ground. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty epic and what I had hoped the series would be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, we don&amp;rsquo;t actually get a number of those big moments. There is plenty of dragon conflict, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, but there&amp;rsquo;s also a lot missing. Lien. There&amp;rsquo;s an ending, but how did we get there? No big speeches, no dragon generals squaring off, no big final battle. Just fait accompli. Fin.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blood of Tyrants</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/29/blood-of-tyrants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/29/blood-of-tyrants/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first half or so of the book follows Laurence in Japan (cool!) and back to China (cool!) who&amp;hellip; lost all memories of the last eight years (oy!). I don&amp;rsquo;t know if there&amp;rsquo;s a series that&amp;rsquo;s had a serious amnesia storyline I actually liked and this wasn&amp;rsquo;t the exception. A third of the entire reason of the series is Temeraire and Laurence and their relationship. To lose all of that&amp;ndash;even if it gives a chance to rebuild and explore it again? Not shiny.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Avengers, Vol. 2: Crime and Punishment</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/28/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-2-crime-and-punishment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/28/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-2-crime-and-punishment/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the Ultimates universe, the Avengers are the team that takes the dirty jobs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like, apparently, teaming up with the Punisher (temporarily) and a proto Hulk gang boss (not sure why) against Ghost Rider?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s certainly a thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s the kind of story where no one wins and I’m not really sure the point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Avengers, Vol. 1: Next Generation</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/27/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-1-next-generation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/27/ultimate-comics-avengers-vol.-1-next-generation/</guid><description>&lt;p>Captain American’s back. With a bit of unexpected past come to haunt him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we need a new team to bring him in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Introducing: the Avengers! This time around the BlackOps version of the Ultimates. And &lt;strong>oh&lt;/strong> that’s a team. Hawkeye, a new drugged up bug girl, a new Widow, War Machine (transformers style), Nerd-Hulk (seriously), and another Stark—with issues all his own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can’t possibly go well…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The World According to Peter Parker</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/26/the-world-according-to-peter-parker/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/26/the-world-according-to-peter-parker/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Today, Peter is dating Gwen Stacy instead of Mary Jane and working at a mall food court instead of the now defunct Daily Bugle. Mutants are outlawed and the growing threat of the mysterious Mysterio takes the life of the once untouchable Kingpin of crime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that and after all these months, Johnny Storm, aka the Human Torch, reappears at Peter&amp;rsquo;s doorstep, exhausted and homeless.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that’s a switch. Especially considering at first everyone thought him dead… but I suppose in this case at least we never actually saw the body.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, I’m aware of the irony, given for example Gwen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fun. Making up a team of sorts? Getting back to normalcy in a seriously screwed world?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like it. I hope we get more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while at least. I can see the titles coming up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Crucible of Gold</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/25/crucible-of-gold/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/25/crucible-of-gold/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“They are ours,” he said, “although not properly the sailors: they are only along because we would not leave them to drown, and ought to be more grateful for it than they are. Laurence,” he said, turning, “this is Palta, and that man is called Taruca: Iskierka snatched him, and I cannot find she asked him in the least.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s an interesting one. On one hand, I&amp;rsquo;m glad they&amp;rsquo;re out of Australia. Instead, they&amp;rsquo;re off across the Pacific&amp;hellip; to Brazil and the Portuguese royal family. Of course things don&amp;rsquo;t go as expected. Crossing the Pacific is one mess and meeting up with the Inca and how they deal with dragons was pretty fascinating&amp;ndash;they&amp;rsquo;re still a power to be reckoned with in this world, mostly on the backs of their local dragons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s still not up to the strengths of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/13/victory-of-eagles/">Victory of Eagles&lt;/a>, mostly because the travels and exploration was never the original draw of the series&amp;ndash;the Napoleon but &lt;em>dragons&lt;/em> was, and we&amp;rsquo;ve scant little of that. This time around&amp;hellip; we do at least get the war, which is pretty cool. So it&amp;rsquo;s a decent book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dead and Alive</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/25/dead-and-alive/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/25/dead-and-alive/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that is most certainly a book. A hard one to rate at that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On one hand, we get a conclusion of sorts of Victor Helios né Frankenstein&amp;rsquo;s mad plan to take over New Orleans (and then the world!) and replace all us flawed Old Race with his New Race&amp;hellip; and various other critters. It&amp;rsquo;s a story that&amp;rsquo;s been quite building up for three books now and it&amp;rsquo;s great to see it come to a head of sorts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really, these should all have been one giant omnibus. Cut out a few plotlines and it works. At it was, they only sort of end, up until now. And even that is generous&amp;ndash;there are an awful many plotlines still unresolved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, an awful lot of this book really seemed to get away from Victor&amp;rsquo;s master plan and dig more into all of the weird things that have been going wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We get Harker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;hellip; baby? of sorts! And it&amp;rsquo;s played more for laughs than anything, which I did &lt;em>not&lt;/em> expect. Takes a bit away from the previous scenes, IMO. We get the continuation of security man turns chimera, which is still pretty cool and terrifying, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t really go where I&amp;rsquo;d hope. There&amp;rsquo;s some chameleon monster. Again, cool but really underused. And we get a trash dump monster. They&amp;rsquo;ve been dumping all of these horrors&amp;ndash;and they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em>designed&lt;/em> to survive. So this makes sense. But I&amp;rsquo;m not at all happy with how it went. As it was, that plot alone needed an entire book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, the &amp;lsquo;good guys&amp;rsquo; seem much less impactful than I&amp;rsquo;d like. Deucalion&amp;rsquo;s bouncing around causing Victor trouble, but without any &lt;em>really&lt;/em> satisfying pay off (in my opinion). Carson and Michael and still delightful with the banter&amp;ndash;and totally outclassed&amp;ndash;but again, it only sort of goes anywhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a bit disappointed, but I suppose at this point, I&amp;rsquo;ll give the last two books a try, although I&amp;rsquo;m curious where &lt;em>in the world&lt;/em> you go from here. There&amp;rsquo;s an opening, but how do you tie them together?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics X: Origins</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/23/ultimate-comics-x-origins/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/23/ultimate-comics-x-origins/</guid><description>&lt;p>And now, more aftermath.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-comics-x-textbundle-7043fb.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So… they’re going to build a new team, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course they are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s got potential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tongues of Serpents</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/21/tongues-of-serpents/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/21/tongues-of-serpents/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>It seems to me after a fellow has been mutinied against three or four times, there is something to it besides bad luck.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Convicted of Treason in Napoleonic Era Britain? Where else to go next but&amp;hellip; Australia!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s another travelog of a book, showing off yet another continent, although this time without much in the way of native dragons at all. We get a lot of very minor politics, a very long chase sequence across much of the continent following a stolen egg, a few interesting newly hatched dragons (probably the highlight of the book honestly). I do miss a lot of the old crew, but it&amp;rsquo;s something.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Notice anything missing?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s painfully little in the way of big Napoleonic battles (with dragons!). Slightly more exploration of Chinese dragons and that end of the world, but not that much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In theory, it&amp;rsquo;s a way for Laurence to deal with his actions in previous books&amp;hellip; but we&amp;rsquo;ve already done a chunk of that in &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/13/victory-of-eagles/">Victory of Eagles&lt;/a> and we really don&amp;rsquo;t get much of it here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem quite like something we need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward. Fingers crossed.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I am sick of the quarrels of nations and kings, and I would not give a ha&amp;rsquo;pence for any empire other than our valley, if that can content your ambition.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Tress of the Emerald Sea</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/tress-of-the-emerald-sea/</guid><description>&lt;p>Take one part Princess Bride (a modern fairly tale for a grown up audience), one part Hoid as the narrator (even more Wit-like than in Stormlight), and add in weird world&amp;ndash;Sanderson style. It&amp;rsquo;s funny. It&amp;rsquo;s touching. And it&amp;rsquo;s a delight to read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Voilá. Tress of the Emerald Sea.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a really good book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Comics Iron Man: Armor Wars</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/ultimate-comics-iron-man-armor-wars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/19/ultimate-comics-iron-man-armor-wars/</guid><description>&lt;p>There’s so much to unpack from the events of Ultimatum…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So instead let’s introduce some new foe in the Mandarin. Hacking in and taking over Stark Tech. The Iron Man suit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Neat idea but feels incomplete. Both in what I expected post Ultimatum and in the resolution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimatum: Requiem</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/16/ultimatum-requiem/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:04:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/16/ultimatum-requiem/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>requiem&lt;/em> - a mass for the dead; a solemn chant (such as a dirge) for the repose of the dead&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimatum: X-Men/Fantastic Four</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/16/ultimatum-x-men/fantastic-four/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/16/ultimatum-x-men/fantastic-four/</guid><description>&lt;p>Death and destruction on a massive scale. And to make it worse…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimatum-x-menfantastic-four-textbundle-9587e2.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have zealots blaming all mutants and going on a rampage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So much death.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And on the Fantastic Four side:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimatum-x-menfantastic-four-textbundle-24175b.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mole Man and Grimm, going in. Such a weird time for it. But I suppose it’s otherwise all the time Sue has left.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimatum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/16/ultimatum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/16/ultimatum/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well. That’s a thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wrapped up in the events of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/16/ultimate-spider-man-volume-22-ultimatum/">Ultimate Spider-Man&lt;/a>, we have Ultimatum: Magneto flipped the poles and killed millions—including a number of heroes we know. Knew.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a bloody transition. A lot of it feels more designed to sock than anything. And it certainly does that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If this were the beginning of the Marvel Ultimate Universe… the fallout could have been fascinating. I just hope what’s left is worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 22: Ultimatum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/16/ultimate-spider-man-volume-22-ultimatum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/16/ultimate-spider-man-volume-22-ultimatum/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that escalated quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-spider-man-v22-textbundle-15de64.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seems Magneto decided to kill everyone. Good times. Oy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s quite the sudden tonal shift. So much death and destruction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Given enough time to breathe, this could be quite a story line. I’m not confident it will though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Origins</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/15/ultimate-origins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:03:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/15/ultimate-origins/</guid><description>&lt;p>And now we learn…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-origins-textbundle-5be231.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How it’s all connected.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s an awful lot of a story. The origin of super heroes and mutants in the entire Ultimate Marvel Universe. And the Black Panther. And the Hulk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a lot for one volume and… I really wish they’d established this earlier. It’s different enough to make a fascinating world and we’ve only gotten hints thus far. I want more! And we’re near the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a side note (minor spoilers!), tying the origin of super soldiers to military experimentation of a young black man against his will… that’s kind of gross. It feels like taking a dark truth and trying to make something better of it. But there’s not enough room for the nuance that would need.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimatum: March On Ultimatum</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/15/ultimatum-march-on-ultimatum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/15/ultimatum-march-on-ultimatum/</guid><description>&lt;p>More Annuals! Mixed stories!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>X-Men/Fantastic Four hints at Ultimatum. Everything goes wrong. And a team back to stop it… but no luck there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Captain America. And really the origin of Ultimate Black Panther. Is that all we’ll get of him?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hulk. Naked. Fights. Eats. That’s really it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Spider-Man and MJ being teenagers. Cute. But hardly earth shattering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, as always, a weird mix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>City of Night</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/15/city-of-night/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/15/city-of-night/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so we continue with the adventures of Helios né Frankenstein and all the troubles he&amp;rsquo;s causing for modern day New Orleans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of the main plotlines, we get a lot more of Randall Six and Arnie. I like the story in general, but the pacing is strange, stretching across two books and then sort of ending.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We get Helios and yet another Erika, along with all sorts of things starting to go wrong with the New Race. It&amp;rsquo;s pushing increasingly into Horror, especially Body Horror, and I like it. The only gotcha is that it feels rather weird for it all to be going wrong &lt;em>now&lt;/em>. I do like seeing more variations and points of view among the New Race. They&amp;rsquo;re not all the same, no matter how much Helios wants them to be and that is fascinating. Especially when you bring Deucalion into the mix.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We get more of Carson and Michael, now off the rails and going straight cop turned vigilante. It makes sense, given the complete inability to know who&amp;rsquo;s Old and who&amp;rsquo;s New, but it still is a bit jarring. I do love their banter. At this point, I wholly expect one or both not to survive the series, which is a bummer, but expected in this sort of thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the weirdest thing about this book (and the series thus far) is that it really all feels like one very very long single novel. The &amp;rsquo;endings&amp;rsquo; do tend to end at least one plot thread, but there are always new things being brought up and random threads ending well before the end of a book. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I care for the style. But I&amp;rsquo;m too into the series now to stop!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All that being said, it&amp;rsquo;s a good book and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to where we go next!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 19: Absolute Power</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-19-absolute-power/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/14/ultimate-x-men-vol.-19-absolute-power/</guid><description>&lt;p>What if mutants… but &lt;strong>more&lt;/strong>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s the idea behind the Banshee drug. Quite the power up for a lot of them. And secrets for the rest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interesting story, if weird time. Needs more space to breathe. If it were a standalone or much earlier in the series, this would be a much better volume. As it is, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite feel right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Fantastic Four, Volume 11: Salem's Seven</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/14/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-11-salems-seven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/14/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-11-salems-seven/</guid><description>&lt;p>You know, that might actually be my favorite Ultimate Fantastic Four? Team drama, mysterious new threat, tie backs to Atlantis and Namor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s actually pretty good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weird. But good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s a pity that this is the last of the series&amp;hellip; Why couldn&amp;rsquo;t we have had more of this? Or really a more coherent storyline throughout the run.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Ultimates 3: Who Killed the Scarlet Witch?</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/13/the-ultimates-3-who-killed-the-scarlet-witch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/13/the-ultimates-3-who-killed-the-scarlet-witch/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Ultimates are back! With new faces, new foes, and new deaths.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More or less.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s certainly a jam packed volume with lots of twists and action. Really, it’s mostly a prequel to Ultimatum. And that’s okay.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Victory of Eagles</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/13/victory-of-eagles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/13/victory-of-eagles/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>If they cannot be woken to a natural affection for their country, such as we feel, it is our fault and not theirs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Where Laurence is condemned for Treason for trying to prevent war crimes and Temeraire is on his own&amp;ndash;and ends up starting a sort of soft revolution among the dragons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite a story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laurence having to go against loyalty, against king and country was a Big Thing last book, so seeing the fallout of that goes about as expected. It&amp;rsquo;s dark. And we&amp;rsquo;re still not done with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And seeing Temeraire come into his own, basically take over the breeding grounds, and speak for dragonkind in Britain? Love it. Plus, a whole bunch of Temeraire point of view! Couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it any other way and the voices are as distinct as I expected. But it&amp;rsquo;s lovely to see.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s quite a book and well worth the read in the series.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward to see what happens next!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Side note:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Maximus] put his head down and said in a conspiratorial whisper, “Tell Temeraire that Lily and I have not forgotten our promise; we will not let them hang you at all.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Laurence stared up at the immense Regal Copper. All his crew looked deeply distressed, as well they might, the outlaw remark being perfectly audible several clearings over.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It continues being delightful to read about the largest dragons trying to be sneaky.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 21: War of the Symbiotes</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/12/ultimate-spider-man-volume-21-war-of-the-symbiotes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/12/ultimate-spider-man-volume-21-war-of-the-symbiotes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Venom and Carnage! And all the chaos that ensues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-spider-man-v21-textbundle-a1a552.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a fascinating story line. Quintessentially Spider-Man.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Setting up something big too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 20: And His Amazing Friends</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/12/ultimate-spider-man-volume-20-and-his-amazing-friends/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/12/ultimate-spider-man-volume-20-and-his-amazing-friends/</guid><description>&lt;p>A cute volume. Mostly turning down the stakes a bit. Give them all a chance to be normal. Go on a beach date. Reveal the hidden mutant among them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know. Normal teen stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Add to that Kitty, Peter, and MJ all learning how to get along together?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 18: Apocalypse</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/10/ultimate-x-men-vol.-18-apocalypse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/10/ultimate-x-men-vol.-18-apocalypse/</guid><description>&lt;p>Apocalypse!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That would be more exciting if he got more than a couple issues to build up—or be defeated.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I suppose I’ll hold judgement until we see what comes next, but I’m underwhelmed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Empire of Ivory</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/08/empire-of-ivory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/08/empire-of-ivory/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/21/throne-of-jade/">There&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/04/29/black-powder-war/">back again&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; and now everydragon left behind in Britain is deathly ill! So of course it&amp;rsquo;s up to Laurence and Temeraire to save the day!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As it seems to be the case in each of these books past the first, we&amp;rsquo;re off on an adventure! Novik really does like showing off the world as it was in that time period. This time around, to the Cape of Africa (and eventually across the interior). We get to meet new and interesting friends, enemies, and dragons along the way; along with all sorts of fun* moral problems of the era (and in general).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another solid entry in the series and worth the read.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward! And who even knows whereto next?!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 18: Ultimate Knights</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/08/ultimate-spider-man-volume-18-ultimate-knights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/08/ultimate-spider-man-volume-18-ultimate-knights/</guid><description>&lt;p>So what have are today?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-spider-man-v18-555ad9.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New friends!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>New enemies!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All brought together by Fisk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All characters I’d like to see more of. And while it’s not really a conclusive end to the story, it’s certainly a fascinating step forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and also Peter and May finally have… the Talk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No. Not that one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-spider-man-v18-84f624.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That one.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Prodigal Son</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/prodigal-son/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/prodigal-son/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Knowledge is knowing that Frankenstein is not the monster.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wisdom is knowing that Frankenstein is the monster.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>A questionable phrase when applied to the original book. Full of hubris. A coward. Not really a &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; person, sure. But a monster?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, in Dean Koontz&amp;rsquo;s version&amp;hellip; yeah. Victor Frankenstein (now Victor Helios)&amp;ndash;totally the monster.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Hulk vs. Iron Man: Ultimate Human</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/ultimate-hulk-vs.-iron-man-ultimate-human/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/07/ultimate-hulk-vs.-iron-man-ultimate-human/</guid><description>&lt;p>A way to cure the Hulk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What could possibly go wrong?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-hulk-v-iron-man-textbundle-0fe034.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Not quite being ripped in half (yet).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More of a team up than anything and ends rather abruptly. Fine, but nothing special.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 17: Sentinels</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/06/ultimate-x-men-vol.-17-sentinels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/06/ultimate-x-men-vol.-17-sentinels/</guid><description>&lt;p>Bishop, stuck in the past. A whole new band of X-Men. Sentinels. Fenris Twins. Betrayal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Time travel gets weird, yo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No one ever stays dead in comics. Except Bucky, Jason Todd, and Uncle Ben. And even two of those eventually came back…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward to the &lt;strong>real&lt;/strong> big bad.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate X-Men, Vol. 16: Cable</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/06/ultimate-x-men-vol.-16-cable/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/06/ultimate-x-men-vol.-16-cable/</guid><description>&lt;p>Time travel. It always seems to come back&amp;ndash;have come back? will come back? will have come backend? &amp;ndash;to that in the end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this case, Xavier did… something to bring Ultimate Cable back to stop him. And who is Cable? Well that’s the question, isn’t it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An interesting story, with quite the stakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Going to have to see where it goes from here!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Spider-Man, Volume 17: Clone Saga</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/06/ultimate-spider-man-volume-17-clone-saga/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/06/ultimate-spider-man-volume-17-clone-saga/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well that was absolutely wild. Characters back from the dead! Carnage! A whole bunch of Spider-Men (-Women, -Abominations)! Secret government projects… that may or may not be SHIELD related! The Fantastic Four! X-Men! Fury! Ultimates!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t know if any of this is something that’s happened before in Spider-Man story lines, but it’s certainly not one I’ve heard of before. Probably the biggest shake up I’ve had through the Ultimate Marvel read through.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well well worth the read!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ultimate Fantastic Four, Volume 10: Ghosts</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/04/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-10-ghosts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/05/04/ultimate-fantastic-four-volume-10-ghosts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Will he ever learn?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.jverkamp.com/embeds/books/attachments/ultimate-fantastic-four-v10-textbundle-ef591a.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No he will not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, a quick trip to Siberia to meet the Crimson Dynamo, and a few other bizarre friends. Then in the other half, Reed Richards’ project comes to fruition—Giant Cube of Doom. Thanos. The end of the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a good issue, as often the case, resolved perhaps a little bit too quickly. But interesting. Onward!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>