<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2023 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2023-book-reviews/</link><description>Recent content in 2023 Book Reviews on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/lists/2023-book-reviews/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Wicked + The Divine, Vol. 9: Okay</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/03/the-wicked--the-divine-vol.-9-okay/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/03/the-wicked--the-divine-vol.-9-okay/</guid><description>&lt;p>And so it ends. And a touch of Volume 8 actually came back to pull everything together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think I preferred the journey to the destination. It’s interesting to have closure, but still, I want to know what could possibly be next in this world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>C’est la vide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Wicked + The Divine, Vol. 8: Old Is the New New</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/03/the-wicked--the-divine-vol.-8-old-is-the-new-new/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/03/the-wicked--the-divine-vol.-8-old-is-the-new-new/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a penultimate volume … that was strange. It’s not part of the main story, but rather a number of loosely connected shorts. There are a lot of interesting stories to be told there… but not in such short snippets with so little time left.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Onward to the conclusion!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bone Ship's Wake</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/02/the-bone-ships-wake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/02/the-bone-ships-wake/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>And what is life for us if we are not lurching from one life-or-death situation to another?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Maes is MIA and Joron picks up the slack in quite the way&amp;ndash;as the well named Black Pirate. It&amp;rsquo;s such a huge growth to see from him, from the very beginning when he and Maes first met and probably the best part of the books.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s also great to see how the increasing worldbuilding around the Guillame and the Keyshan come to bear. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more there than the reader or the characters really had to deal with at first.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the other hand, I do feel somewhat let down by the latter half of the book. There&amp;rsquo;s an awful lot of interesting in the beginning; however, as everything builds and builds, despite plenty of action&amp;ndash;the story just sort of ends. I feel like there could have been more, but so it goes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Locklands</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/01/locklands/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2023/01/01/locklands/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>We’re all the result of countless actions and choices made throughout the centuries, and the odds of those actions and choices going the exact same way again are basically nil.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Well that&amp;rsquo;s certainly a finale! After &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/06/foundryside/">Foundryside&lt;/a> started out as a nice bit of worldbuilding wrapped around a heist and &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2022/12/28/shorefall/">Shorefall&lt;/a> turned things up to 11 with the return of the old, almost alien magic&amp;hellip; Now we have Locklands with hive minds, epic immortal duals, and finally&amp;hellip; a few answers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Man that&amp;rsquo;s a crazy (awesome) book.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>