<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lost on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/lost/</link><description>Recent content in Lost on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/series/lost/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lost: Season 4</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/17/lost-season-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/12/17/lost-season-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Survival. Mysteries. The Others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, just possibly&amp;hellip; rescue?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as they said in the end of the previous season, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;not Penny&amp;rsquo;s boat&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So who&amp;rsquo;s is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy this season. We get a chance to have some new characters (from the freighter come to rescue them), a bit of a shake up in terms of who&amp;rsquo;s on which side on th island, and a whole pile of &amp;lsquo;what is even going on&amp;rsquo;, split a bit between Desmond and newcomer Daniel Faraday&amp;ndash;I do enjoy his character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, we really are starting to get into the point where you question &amp;lsquo;so&amp;hellip; were they planning that all along? do even the &lt;em&gt;writers&lt;/em&gt; know what&amp;rsquo;s going on?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure the answer is no? That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s a bad season though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, because of the 2008 writer&amp;rsquo;s strike, it&amp;rsquo;s a shorter season as well&amp;gt; Ramps of the tension that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favorite episodes this season?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first flashes off the island&amp;ndash;with their own level of *you did &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; now. &lt;em&gt;The Constant&lt;/em&gt;, with timey-whimey shenanigans and &lt;em&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s No Place Like Home&lt;/em&gt;, with everything coming to a tense, sometimes magical, and always chaotic end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting seeing Lost straddle the line between science fiction and more supernatural/fantasy. I tend to like the former, but a lot of times, it&amp;rsquo;s the contrast that really does the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only two seasons left!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Onward!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lost: Season 3</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/30/lost-season-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/11/30/lost-season-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Season 1 was all about surviving on the island.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 2 was all about mysteries. More survivors. The Hatch. A monster made of smoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now we get Season 3: All about the Others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, what a season that was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learn how they live in several different guises, from the cages of &lt;em&gt;A Tale of Two Cities&lt;/em&gt; to the village/barracks of &lt;em&gt;Stranger in a Strange Land&lt;/em&gt;, to a sort of mass exodus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom: Hey, you got yourself a fish biscuit! How&amp;rsquo;d you do that?&lt;br&gt;
Sawyer: Figured out your complicated gizmos, thats how.&lt;br&gt;
Tom: It only took the bears two hours.&lt;br&gt;
[Sawyer contemplates briefly]&lt;br&gt;
Sawyer: How many of &amp;rsquo;em were there?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All sorts of medical madness, in &lt;em&gt;Every Man for Himself&lt;/em&gt; and pretty much anything with Juliet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that all, one character who &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; goes through an arc this season is Locke. He&amp;rsquo;s lost his way&amp;hellip; only to find it again. And lose it. And find another. Oh Locke. You&amp;rsquo;re so very interesting, but also so hard to actually root for&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sayid: Kate, if you were looking for help to find Jack, why didn&amp;rsquo;t you ask us?&lt;br&gt;
Kate: Two reasons: you don&amp;rsquo;t know where to look and you&amp;rsquo;re not motivated. And I don&amp;rsquo;t blame you. Why would you want to go on another trek across the island, risk more lives just to get Jack back?&lt;br&gt;
Locke: You&amp;rsquo;re wrong.&lt;br&gt;
Kate: Oh, really? They why didn&amp;rsquo;t you come after-&lt;br&gt;
Locke: Not about the motivation, just about knowing where to look. We got a compass bearing, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure if we follow it, it&amp;rsquo;ll lead us right to &amp;rsquo;em.&lt;br&gt;
Kate: How?&lt;br&gt;
Sayid: Because of the way the sunlight hit Mr. Eko&amp;rsquo;s stick&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my continued favorite though? Desmond. Wakes up naked. Wakes up in his flat. Wakes up and buys a ring. Oh, he&amp;rsquo;s got a complicated life, both on the island and off of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desmond Hume: See you in another life, brother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a less positive note, we have main-character-who-have-obviously-been-there-all-along Nikki and Paulo. I mean, it worked well enough for Desmond and seems to be working okay for Juliet. So why not someone else? But they come out of nowhere and get all &lt;em&gt;Expose&lt;/em&gt;d by the end. So it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that&amp;hellip; to go &lt;em&gt;Through the Looking Glass&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, this is a fun show.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lost: Season 2</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/30/lost-season-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/30/lost-season-2/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Locke: [screaming] What am I supposed to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so my third watch of Lost continues!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 1 was all about the crash on the island. About survival, with only the beginnings of weirdness around the edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Season 2? Now we&amp;rsquo;re really getting into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Orientation&lt;/em&gt;, we get our first hints of the Hatch. Desmond is such a fun character, even if (&lt;em&gt;spoilers&lt;/em&gt;!) he&amp;rsquo;s not in as much of this seasons as later ones. And oh, later on, we have &lt;em&gt;Lockdown&lt;/em&gt;. Now &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; is a wonderful mystery of an episode. And the whole season does have an excellent dynamic between Jack and Locke. Man of Science. Man of Faith. (And really, which is which?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Locke: Why do you find it so hard to believe?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack Shephard: Why do you find it so easy?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Locke: It&amp;rsquo;s never been easy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get a few new characters from the tail section (&lt;em&gt;The Other 48 Days&lt;/em&gt;). Mr. Eko is such an intense foil to Locke in particular. And the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do also get two amazing Hugo backstory centered episodes: &lt;em&gt;Everybody Hates Hugo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dave&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo: Did either of you see a bald guy in slippers with a coconut come through here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlie: No. But I did see a polar bear on roller skates with a mango.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s such a fun character, in spite (because?) of everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Maternity Leave&lt;/em&gt;, we get a bit more about the medical mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then in the end&amp;hellip; we &lt;em&gt;Live Together, Die Alone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Season 3!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lost: Season 1</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/07/lost-season-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2025/10/07/lost-season-1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man this show was huge when it first came out. I watched it then and once since, so this will be my third watch. And this time around I&amp;rsquo;m watching it with someone who (somehow) has never seen it before. To experience all the twists and turns anew with someone? Oh, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first season is awesome. We don&amp;rsquo;t get quite as much mystery and the larger story as later seasons&amp;ndash;but that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we need. Instead, the first season is all about survival&amp;ndash;they did just crash onto a island far &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; away from land after all&amp;ndash;and introducing our cast. And oh, they did that in spades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pilot was, of course&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; awesome. And I do love the first season giving each main character a flashback episode. Locke&amp;rsquo;s (Walkabout) in particular was quite a twist. And oh Hurley&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the characters. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing, with a main cast of over a dozen, how they managed to give each of them (well, most of them) their own over the top backstories and room to breath. I suppose part of that is a side effect of an older style TV season&amp;ndash;when you have over 20 episodes, you have room to actually &lt;em&gt;build&lt;/em&gt; to something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack is great, even if he&amp;rsquo;s got entirely too much of the perfect &amp;lsquo;Doctor savior&amp;rsquo; personality at times. Kate is great, even when she can&amp;rsquo;t stop running. Sawyer is great&amp;ndash;you love to hate him, but he might just be a good man under all that. Locke is a great mystery all around. Hurley is just great. Full stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I don&amp;rsquo;t like the rest of the characters on the island. There&amp;rsquo;s isn&amp;rsquo;t a main cast member in the first season that I don&amp;rsquo;t find worth watching&amp;ndash;and some of them still have room to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I love the slow burn introduction of &amp;lsquo;what is even going &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; on this Island&amp;rsquo;. Monsters in the woods, mysterious noises, hidden structures. It has it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just when they get a chance to leave&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>