<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andrew Rowe on jverkamp.com</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/andrew-rowe/</link><description>Recent content in Andrew Rowe on jverkamp.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/reviews/authors/andrew-rowe/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the Shoulders of Titans</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/05/on-the-shoulders-of-titans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/05/on-the-shoulders-of-titans/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/02/05/on-the-shoulders-of-titans/">On the Shoulders of Titans&lt;/a> is everything &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/28/sufficiently-advanced-magic/">Sufficiently Advanced Magic&lt;/a> was, only bigger and more so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Crazy magical battles chock full of colorful spells, summoned beings, and magic items? Oh yeah.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sufficiently Advanced Magic</title><link>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/28/sufficiently-advanced-magic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/28/sufficiently-advanced-magic/</guid><description>&lt;p>Without reading more than the summary and without having read much if at all from the LitRPG genre before, the first 10% or so of &lt;a href="https://blog.jverkamp.com/2020/01/28/sufficiently-advanced-magic/">Sufficiently Advanced Magic&lt;/a> felt rather strange. We open with the protagonist, Corin Cadence, going into the Serpent Spire, &amp;ldquo;a colossal tower with ever-shifting rooms, traps, and monsters&amp;rdquo;. The description of the tower and the rooms and especially the magic of the world feels rather like someone took a role-playing game rulebook and wrote a book about it. And&amp;hellip; it turns out that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what LitRPG novels are supposed to feel like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That part of the book continues to feel weird to me throughout&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s the hardest of hard magic systems, with overly specified classes of mana and magic, with well defined levels and powers for each of them. I actually like that sort of thing, but there are long sections of exposition that get a bit hard to stay focused on.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>